<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621682-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621682</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12282079</doc-number>
<date>20070306</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>06 50788</doc-number>
<date>20060307</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1149</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4625</main-classification>
<further-classification>  4626</further-classification>
<further-classification>  4602</further-classification>
<further-classification>220530</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">System for dispensing and recovering liquids and device comprising same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3931907</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Henle</name>
<date>19760100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>220530</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5199594</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Obara et al.</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2291173</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5465438</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Allman et al.</name>
<date>19951100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  4626</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6253394</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Goyette et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  4626</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0019031</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mosis</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  4625</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>8716514</doc-number>
<kind>U1</kind>
<date>19880400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2807745</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20011000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4602</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4625</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4626</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>220530</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090090420</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090409</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maximilien</last-name>
<first-name>Richard</first-name>
<address>
<city>Romorantin Lanthenay</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Legrand</last-name>
<first-name>Marc</first-name>
<address>
<city>Romorantin Lanthenay</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>FR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maximilien</last-name>
<first-name>Richard</first-name>
<address>
<city>Romorantin Lanthenay</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Legrand</last-name>
<first-name>Marc</first-name>
<address>
<city>Romorantin Lanthenay</city>
<country>FR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Browdy and Neimark, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Huson</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory</first-name>
<department>3751</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Heitzer</last-name>
<first-name>Lauren</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/FR2007/000394</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20070306</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20081201</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2007/101938</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20070913</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention concerns a system for dispensing and recovering liquids designed to be arranged in a rigid container, comprising a liquid dispensing tank (<b>16</b>) and a tank (<b>17</b>) for recovering liquid after use, each tank (<b>16, 17</b>) including an envelope (<b>18</b>). Each envelope (<b>18</b>) includes two similar walls (<b>19, 20</b>) comprising each an outer surface and a peripheral edge (<b>23</b>). Each envelope (<b>18</b>) has a retracted configuration wherein said walls (<b>19, 20</b>) are deployed one proximate the other and in an inflated configuration wherein said outer surfaces of each said wall (<b>19, 20</b>) are convex. At least one envelope (<b>18</b>) is capable, in its inflated configuration, to be nested in the other envelope (<b>18</b>) in its retracted configuration.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="132.67mm" wi="137.08mm" file="US08621682-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.31mm" wi="166.88mm" file="US08621682-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="214.88mm" wi="141.99mm" file="US08621682-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="223.86mm" wi="129.12mm" file="US08621682-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="222.67mm" wi="145.03mm" file="US08621682-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention is generally concerned with systems for dispensing and recovering liquids in a rigid container.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The document FR 2 807 745 discloses a hydraulic device including a system of this kind disposed in a container. The system includes an upper tank for receiving waste water and a lower tank in which clean water is stored. The two tanks are expandable and compressible and are separated by a disk that compresses the lower tank against the walls of the container by means of a spring disposed at the perimeter of the upper tank, in particular to distribute water under pressure. When empty, the upper tank has a usable volume able to receive waste water before the lower tank begins to be emptied. As the lower tank is emptied, the volume it occupies decreases while the usable volume of the upper tank increases.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention aims to provide a system of the same kind for dispensing and recovering liquids but having a simplified structure and an enhanced volume for storing liquid as well as being particularly practical and convenient to manufacture and to use.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">To this end, the invention proposes a system for dispensing and recovering liquids adapted to be disposed in a rigid container, including a tank for dispensing liquid to be used and a tank for recovering liquid after use, each of said tanks including an envelope and an orifice through which liquid passes, characterized in that each of said envelopes includes a first wall and a second wall which are similar and each of which includes an external surface and a peripheral rim, said walls of one of said envelopes being connected to each other by said peripheral rim, each of said envelopes being adapted to have a contracted configuration in which said walls are close to each other and said external surface of said second wall is convex while said external surface of said first wall is concave, and an expanded configuration in which contact between said two walls is limited to said peripheral rims and said external surfaces of each of said walls are convex, at least one of said envelopes being adapted, in its expanded configuration, to be nested in the other of said envelopes in its contracted configuration, said two first walls being in contact with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As the dispensing tank is emptied and the recovery tank is filled, the convex shape of the external surface of each first wall is reversed. The evolution of the configuration of the envelopes corresponds to this reversing of the convex shape that occurs entirely because of the effect of the increase in the volume of liquid. During this evolution, the first walls remain in mutual contact.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">This evolution occurs without the total volume occupied by the system changing. The volume of a tank in the expanded configuration corresponds overall to the total volume because this kind of tank becomes nested inside the other tank which, in its contracted configuration, occupies a negligible volume compared to the total volume of the system.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to implementation features that are particularly simple and convenient as much for manufacture as for use:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0008">said envelopes have similar dimensions and each of said envelopes is adapted, in its expanded configuration, to be nested in the other of said envelopes in its contracted configuration, said two first walls being in contact with each other; and where appropriate</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0009">each of said first walls and each of said second walls includes two rectangular panels and two lateral panels adapted so that in their expanded configuration each of said envelopes is parallelepipedal; and where appropriate</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0010">each of said first walls is thinner in its corners formed at the junction of two of said rectangular panels and one of said transverse panels.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0011">The variation in the thickness of the panels achieves a flexibility that facilitates the change of the convex shape of the first wall as well as enabling the tanks to offer a combined stiffness that contributes to making the system durable in use in the container and when emptying and filling it outside the container.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0012">According to implementation features that are particularly simple and convenient as much for manufacture as for use:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0004" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0004-0001" num="0013">each of said tanks includes a cap adapted to close a respective one of said orifices, said caps having different diameters; and where appropriate</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0002" num="0014">the system includes a dispensing hose one end of which is situated in said dispensing tank and pumping means for the liquid to be used adapted to evacuate that liquid from said dispensing tank via said hose; and where appropriate</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0003" num="0015">said pumping means include a pump disposed inside said dispensing tank and an electrical power supply cable of said pump adapted to be connected to electrical power supply means, said cap including at least one hole for said cable and said hose to pass through; or</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0004" num="0016">said pumping means include a pump disposed outside said dispensing tank and an electrical power supply cable of said pump adapted to be connected to electrical power supply means, said hose being connected to said pump and said cap including a hole for said hose to pass through.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0017">The invention further proposes a device for dispensing and recovering liquids characterized in that it comprises a rigid container and a system as disclosed hereinabove disposed in said container.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0018">The evolution of the configuration of the tanks is the result of the interaction of the tanks themselves through the mutual contact of the first walls. Thus the system is simply disposed in the container or removed from the container, connecting or disconnecting the dispensing and recovery means as necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0019">According to implementation features that are particularly simple and convenient as much for manufacture as for use:
<ul id="ul0005" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0005-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0006" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0006-0001" num="0020">said container is parallelepipedal; and/or</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0002" num="0021">said container includes a sink and a plughole situated in the bottom of said sink, said recovery tank including a cap adapted to close said orifice of the recovery tank, said system further including recovery means including a hose a first end of which is connected to said plughole and a second end of which is connected to said cap of said recovery tank; and/or</li>
        <li id="ul0006-0003" num="0022">the device includes a removable wall for access to said system.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0014" num="0023">The features and advantages of the invention will emerge from the following description, given by way of preferred but nonlimiting example, with reference to the appended drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a device of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a system of the invention with the dispensing hose connected to the dispensing tank in its expanded configuration and the recovery hose connected to the recovery tank in the contracted configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the dispensing tank from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in its expanded configuration, partially cut away to show the pump located inside it;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, but with no partial cutaway, the dispensing tank being in a partly filled state;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the tank being in its contracted configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of the recovery tank in its expanded configuration;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a view similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the tank being in its contracted configuration; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a view of a different embodiment of the system, similar to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> embodiment, the dispensing tank being in its contracted configuration and the recovery tank in its expanded configuration, the dispensing tank being shown with the pump disposed outside it.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0023" num="0032">The device <b>1</b> includes a plastic material container <b>2</b> and has a generally parallelepipedal shape. It has four lateral walls, one of which includes a removable portion <b>3</b>, and a top wall <b>4</b> with a depression that forms a sink <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0033">The portion <b>3</b> is rectangular and, when it is mounted in the container <b>2</b>, it extends the entire width of the lateral wall of which it is part. In the heightwise direction, it extends from the bottom of the container <b>2</b>, i.e. from the side opposite the wall <b>4</b>, to an edge spaced from the wall <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0034">The portion <b>3</b> has a cut-out <b>6</b> on its edge facing the wall <b>4</b>. This cut-out <b>6</b> forms a handle useful for grasping the portion <b>3</b> to separate it from the rest of the container <b>2</b> or to replace it thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0035">The portion <b>3</b> also includes clipping means (not shown) cooperating with corresponding clipping means on the rest of the container <b>2</b> so that the portion <b>3</b> is removable.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0036">In variants of this embodiment that are not shown, the portion <b>3</b> includes fixing means with magnets or hinges for removably fixing it to the rest of the container.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0037">The sink <b>5</b> is L-shaped, extending along two edges of the wall <b>4</b>. The sink <b>5</b> delimits a rectangular portion <b>9</b> of the wall <b>4</b> that is globally in the same plane as the common edges of that wall <b>4</b> and the lateral walls.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0038">The wall <b>4</b> includes two orifices <b>10</b>, <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0039">The orifice <b>10</b> is situated in a corner of the wall <b>4</b> that is also a corner of the rectangular portion <b>9</b>. This orifice <b>10</b> is adapted to allow one of the liquid dispensing means to move from inside the container <b>2</b> to outside it.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0040">The orifice <b>11</b> is situated in the bottom of the sink <b>5</b>. It is a circular orifice serving as a plughole.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0041">The wall <b>4</b> is molded in one piece with the edge portion of the four lateral walls, this edge portion extending from the wall <b>4</b> toward the bottom of the container <b>2</b> as far as the portion <b>3</b>. The height of this edge portion corresponds to the depth of the sink <b>5</b>. The portion including the wall <b>4</b> and the portion including the three lateral walls are fixed together by appropriate mechanical connection means.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0042">Inside the container <b>2</b> is the system <b>15</b> for dispensing and recovering liquids. It includes a liquid dispensing tank <b>16</b> and a liquid recovery tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0043">The tank <b>16</b> is described next.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0044">The tank <b>16</b> includes an envelope <b>18</b> in a drinking water grade plastic material.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0045">This envelope <b>18</b> has two walls <b>19</b> and <b>20</b>. The wall <b>19</b> includes two rectangular panels <b>21</b> and two triangular lateral panels <b>22</b>. In the expanded configuration shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the panels <b>21</b> are disposed transversely to each other and each panel <b>22</b> extends transversely to each panel <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0046">The wall <b>19</b> has the overall shape of a cube cut in two on a plane passing through two opposite edges and through the center of the cube.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0047">The wall <b>19</b> has no sharp edge between the two panels <b>21</b> or between a panel <b>22</b> and a panel <b>21</b>, the areas in which these panels are joined together being rounded. In these joining areas, and primarily in the corners <b>24</b> formed at the junction of two panels <b>21</b> and a panel <b>22</b>, the panels are thinner than in the rest of the panel, with the result that the wall <b>19</b> is more flexible in these areas.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0048">The wall <b>19</b> has a rim <b>23</b> along the free edge that extends with a closed contour along the four panels <b>21</b>, <b>22</b>. The rim <b>23</b> extends along a rectangular contour with rounded corners.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0049">A circular orifice passes through one panel <b>21</b> of the wall <b>19</b>. The plane containing the contour of this orifice is slightly offset relative to the principal plane of the panel <b>21</b>, the area in which the contour of the orifice is joined to the rest of the panel <b>21</b> being globally frustoconical.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0050">The wall <b>20</b> is similar to the wall <b>19</b> and includes panels <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> and a rim <b>23</b>. On the other hand, the wall <b>20</b> does not include a circular orifice.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0051">The two walls <b>19</b>, <b>20</b> are joined together at their rim <b>23</b>. The foregoing description of the envelope <b>18</b> of the tank <b>16</b> is also valid for the envelope <b>18</b> of the recovery tank <b>17</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), which includes two walls <b>19</b> and <b>20</b>, each wall <b>19</b>, <b>20</b> including two panels <b>21</b>, two panels <b>22</b> and a peripheral rim <b>23</b> by which the two walls <b>19</b>, <b>20</b> are joined together. On the other hand, it is the wall <b>20</b> of the envelope of the recovery tank <b>17</b> that includes a panel <b>21</b> with an orifice through it.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0052">The tank <b>16</b> further includes a plastic material cap <b>25</b> that can be screwed to a threaded neck connected to the orifice. The cap <b>25</b> further includes a hole for a hose to pass through.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0053">The tank <b>17</b> also includes a plastic material screw-on cap <b>26</b> which cooperates with a threaded neck connected to the orifice. The cap <b>26</b> also has a hole in it for connecting a hose.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0054">The cap <b>26</b> has a diameter smaller than that of the cap <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0055">The system <b>15</b> further includes dispensing means: a pump <b>30</b> and a dispensing hose <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0056">The pump <b>30</b> is disposed inside the tank <b>16</b> and connected to a first end of the hose <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). Here the pump <b>30</b> pumps 10 liters per minute, draws an electrical current of 3 A, and has an electrical power rating of 36 W.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0057">The hose <b>31</b> passes through the hole in the cap <b>25</b> provided for this purpose. Sealing means are provided on the cap <b>25</b>. Part of the hose <b>31</b> is outside the tank <b>16</b> and its second end is connected to a spray head <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0058">The spray head <b>32</b> is adapted to pass through the orifice <b>10</b> in the wall <b>4</b> so that when the tank <b>16</b> is situated in the container <b>2</b> the spray head <b>32</b> is outside the container <b>2</b> above the sink <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0059">The pump <b>30</b> is connected by a cable, not shown, to electrical power supply means. The cable also exits the tank <b>16</b> via the cap <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0060">The tank <b>17</b> includes liquid recovery means in the form of a recovery hose <b>34</b>, one end of which is connected to the cap <b>26</b> which is itself connected to the neck of the orifice. At its other end, the hose <b>34</b> includes a ring <b>35</b> that is adapted to cooperate with the plughole <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0061">The envelope <b>18</b> of each tank <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> has an expanded configuration and a contracted configuration and more generally a tank <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> is in its expanded or contracted configuration when its envelope <b>18</b> is in the expanded or contracted configuration, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0062">When the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> are in their expanded configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>6</b>), the walls <b>19</b> and <b>20</b> are away from each other, with the result that the tank has a parallelepipedal shape. This shape corresponds to a full state of the tank.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0063">In their contracted configuration (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref>, <b>7</b>), the tanks <b>16</b> and <b>17</b> have a negligible volume. The wall <b>19</b> lies against the wall <b>20</b>, in other words the panel <b>21</b> of the wall <b>19</b> and the panel <b>21</b> of the wall <b>20</b> separated by the peripheral rim <b>23</b> lie one against the other. Similarly, the panel <b>22</b> of the wall <b>19</b> and the panel <b>22</b> of the wall <b>20</b> lie one against the other, with the result that the wall <b>19</b> is folded into the wall <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0064">In this configuration, each of the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> has a wall <b>20</b> having a convex external surface and a wall <b>19</b> having a concave external surface, the shape of the wall <b>19</b> espousing the shape of the wall <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0065">Because of their similar shape, when the tank <b>16</b> is in the expanded configuration and the tank <b>17</b> in the contracted configuration, the tank <b>17</b> can be nested in the tank <b>16</b>, in other words the tank <b>17</b> covers the external surface of the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0066">When the tank <b>16</b> is in its contracted configuration and the tank <b>17</b> is in its expanded configuration, the tank <b>17</b> is nested in the tank <b>16</b>, in other words the tank <b>16</b> covers the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>17</b>, the external surface of the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>16</b> being in contact with the external surface of the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0067">Just like the tank <b>17</b>, the tank <b>16</b> can assume all intermediate configurations between the expanded configuration and the contracted configuration. In one possible intermediate configuration (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a panel <b>21</b> of the wall <b>19</b> is partly in contact with the adjacent panel <b>21</b> of the wall <b>20</b>, as are the panels <b>22</b> of the wall <b>19</b> with the adjacent panels <b>22</b> of the wall <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0068">Each of the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> has a volume of about twenty liters. Here the container <b>2</b> has a volume of about fifty liters.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0069">The use of the system <b>16</b> and more generally of the device <b>1</b> is described next.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0070">The device <b>1</b>, which can in particular be used in recreational vehicles, is provided with the system <b>15</b> placed in the container <b>2</b> with the tank <b>16</b> full and the tank <b>17</b> empty (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Here the tank <b>16</b> is a clean water tank and the tank <b>17</b> is a waste water tank.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0071">To cause water to flow through the spray head <b>32</b>, a switch <b>36</b> located above the cut-out <b>6</b> is operated. The switch <b>36</b> is connected by means, not shown, to the pump <b>30</b>. Operating the switch <b>36</b> starts the pump <b>30</b> with the result that clean water rises up the hose <b>31</b> until it flows through the spray head <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0072">If the water flows into the sink <b>5</b>, it is evacuated via the plughole and then via the hose <b>34</b> until it arrives in the tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0073">As waste water arrives in the tank <b>17</b>, the tank goes from its contracted configuration to an intermediate configuration, in other words the tank <b>17</b> is progressively expanded by the incoming waste water. At the same time, the tank <b>16</b> which was originally in its expanded configuration is emptied of liquid.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0074">With the tank <b>16</b> emptying and the tank <b>17</b> filling, the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>16</b> begins to collapse toward the wall <b>20</b> and the wall <b>19</b> of the tank <b>17</b> begins to move away from the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0075">On the other hand, the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>16</b> and the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>17</b> are not deformed and remain in place. As the tank <b>17</b> is filled, the tank <b>16</b> contracts until its envelope <b>18</b> is in its contracted configuration and the envelope of the tank <b>17</b> is expanded to its expanded configuration by the accumulated waste water.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0076">The originally convex external surface of the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>16</b> is then concave and the originally concave external surface of the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>17</b> is then convex.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0077">Here the volume of waste water stored in the tank <b>17</b> corresponds to the volume of clean water originally stored in the tank <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0078">When the tank <b>17</b> is full and the tank <b>16</b> is empty, the tank <b>16</b> is nested in the tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0079">When the tank <b>16</b> is empty, it is no longer possible to obtain water. Users are therefore informed that they must refill the clean water tank <b>16</b> and empty the waste water tank <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0080">To do this, the wall <b>3</b> is detached from the container <b>2</b>. The caps <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> are unscrewed and the pump <b>30</b> is removed from the tank <b>16</b>. The system <b>15</b> can then be removed from the container <b>2</b> to empty the tank <b>17</b> and to fill the tank <b>16</b> with clean water, the hoses <b>31</b>, <b>34</b> remaining with the device <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0081">To facilitate transporting the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b>, handles (not shown) can be provided on the walls of the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b>, such handles being molded in one piece with the wall of which they form part.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0082">If the clean water is drinking water, then water can be drawn off to drink it and, more generally, water can be extracted from the tank <b>16</b> without all of it ending up as waste water in the tank <b>17</b>. In this case, the volume of water recovered in the tank <b>17</b> is less than the maximum volume of water that this tank can hold. Even if waste water does not occupy the whole of the usable volume of the tank <b>17</b> in the expanded configuration, the force exerted on the walls <b>19</b> by that quantity of waste water is sufficient to push them toward the wall <b>20</b> of the tank <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0083">That force is incidentally very much lower than would be required to crush a tank with no wall adapted to turn inside out to come into contact with the other wall. In such a case, two spaced-apart principal walls would move together by crushing at least one lateral wall. The two principal walls could not come into contact with each other because of the height occupied by the crumpled lateral wall(s). A resulting empty volume much larger than that obtained in the contracted configuration would then be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0084">The evolution of the configuration of the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> is linked to how full the adjacent tank is.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0085">When the tanks <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> are replaced in the container <b>2</b>, it is not possible to use the recovery tank <b>17</b> instead of the dispensing tank <b>16</b>. Because the caps <b>25</b>, <b>26</b> have different diameters, the dispensing hose <b>31</b> cannot be connected to the tank <b>17</b> and the hose <b>34</b> cannot be connected to the tank <b>16</b>. Also, the pump <b>30</b> cannot be placed inside the tank <b>17</b> because the diameter of the orifice is too small.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0086">A different embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is described next. The same references as before are used for similar elements in this embodiment, increased by 100.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0087">The pump <b>130</b> is disposed outside the tank <b>116</b>. A first hose <b>131</b> has one end inside the tank <b>116</b> and a second end connected to the pump <b>130</b>, to pump the liquid out of the tank <b>116</b>. A second hose <b>137</b> runs from the pump <b>130</b> to the spray head <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0088">In another embodiment, the device <b>1</b> is of cylindrical shape and the walls <b>19</b>, <b>20</b> are also of cylindrical shape in their expanded configuration, these walls <b>19</b>, <b>20</b> being thinner along areas joining the panels that constitute them.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0089">In a further embodiment, the caps have the same diameter and visual polarizing means are provided with caps and threads of a particular color for each respective cap.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0090">In a further embodiment, the system <b>15</b> can include one or more additional tanks, for example a soap tank of small volume compared to the volume of the tanks <b>16</b> and <b>17</b>. A dispensing hose is also provided for these additional tanks, with pumping means, for example mechanical pumping means.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0091">In a further embodiment, not shown, the walls <b>20</b> are rigid and undeformable and the thickness of the panels <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> of the walls <b>20</b> is constant.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0092">In a further embodiment, the container is onboard a wheeled cleaning machine with a tank of soapy water and a soiled water recovery tank with the soapy water tank connected to a hose extended by a handle and a cleaning head. The handle includes aspiration means for recovering waste water rising up a hose in said handle, the hose being connected to the waste water tank.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0093">The device has been described as a module on board a recreational vehicle for terrestrial applications. Other embodiments of the device are installed on board an air or sea transportation vehicle.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system for dispensing and recovering liquids configured to be disposed in a rigid container, including a tank for dispensing liquid to be used and a tank for recovering liquid after use, each of said tanks including an envelope and an orifice through which liquid passes, wherein each of said envelopes includes a first wall and a second wall which are similar, the first wall of one of the two envelopes being separate and distinct from the first wall of the other of the two envelopes, and each of which includes an external surface and a peripheral rim, said walls of one of said envelopes being connected to each other by said peripheral rim, each of said envelopes being configured to have a contracted configuration in which said walls are close to each other and said external surface of said second wall is convex while said external surface of said first wall is concave, and an expanded configuration in which contact between said two walls is limited to said peripheral rims and said external surfaces of each of said walls are convex, at least one of said envelopes being configured, in its expanded configuration, to be nested in the other of said envelopes in its contracted configuration, said two first walls being in contact with each other, wherein the first wall and the second wall of the two envelopes are exclusively connected to each other exclusively by the peripheral rim.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said envelopes have similar dimensions and each of said envelopes is configured, in its expanded configuration, to be nested in the other of said envelopes in its contracted configuration, said two first walls being in contact with each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of said first walls and each of said second walls includes two rectangular panels and two lateral panels configured so that in their expanded configuration each of said envelopes is parallelepipedal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein each of said first walls is thinner in its corners formed at the junction of two of said rectangular panels and one of said transverse panels than in the rest of the first walls.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said tanks includes a cap configured to close a respective one of said orifices, the respective caps having different diameters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a dispensing hose one end of which is situated in said dispensing tank and pumping means for the liquid to be used configured to evacuate that liquid from said dispensing tank via said hose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said pumping means include a pump disposed inside said dispensing tank , said cap including at least one hole for said cable and said hose to pass through.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said pumping means include a pump disposed outside said dispensing tank, said hose being connected to said pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said container is parallelepipedal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said container includes a sink and a plughole situated in the bottom of said sink, said recovery tank including a cap configured to close said orifice of the recovery tank, said system further including recovery means including a hose, wherein a first end of said hose is connected to said plughole and a second end of said hose is connected to said cap of said recovery tank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a removable wall for access to said system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> disposed in said container.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A device for dispensing and recovering liquids, comprising a rigid container and a system according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> disposed in said container. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
