<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627410-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627410</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11960240</doc-number>
<date>20071219</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1107</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>726  3</main-classification>
<further-classification>726  1</further-classification>
<further-classification>726  2</further-classification>
<further-classification>709225</further-classification>
<further-classification>380247</further-classification>
<further-classification>380248</further-classification>
<further-classification>380249</further-classification>
<further-classification>380250</further-classification>
<further-classification>713155</further-classification>
<further-classification>713156</further-classification>
<further-classification>713157</further-classification>
<further-classification>713158</further-classification>
<further-classification>713159</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Dynamic radius</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0187018</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Owen et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713200</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0005964</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Grosse et al.</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713168</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0208718</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Javid et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>707  3</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0040491</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Minodier et al.</name>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709229</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0077447</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Dholakia et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>726  3</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>726  1- 21</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709225</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>380247-250</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713155-159</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090165096</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090625</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hughes</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Green Mountain Falls</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bates</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Peyton</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Allison</last-name>
<first-name>Jared M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Amherst</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hughes</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey W.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Green Mountain Falls</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bates</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Peyton</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Allison</last-name>
<first-name>Jared M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Amherst</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Verizon Patent and Licensing Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Basking Ridge</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Brown</last-name>
<first-name>Christopher J.</first-name>
<department>2439</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Tolentino</last-name>
<first-name>Roderick</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system includes a remote authentication dial in user service (RADIUS) server in communication with a network access server. The network access server provides an authentication request to the RADIUS server. The authentication request includes at least a user identifier and a device identifier. The RADIUS server determines an authentication format utilized by the network access server based on the received authentication request. The system may also determine an authorization level to provide with an authentication response.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="145.03mm" wi="188.21mm" file="US08627410-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="187.62mm" wi="148.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627410-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="204.05mm" wi="158.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627410-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="223.60mm" wi="174.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627410-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="216.15mm" wi="144.95mm" file="US08627410-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Network Access Servers and network devices, such as internet servers, network printers, file servers, and Virtual Private Network Servers, often require an approved authorization request before they may be accessed by a user. In its simplest form, an authorization request consists of a username and password. One common method of processing an authorization request to a network device is via a Remote Authentication Dial-In User Service (RADIUS) server. Generally, a user wishing to access a network device or Network Access Server (NAS) connects through a client software program residing on a user-based computing device, such as a personal computer, a personal digital assistant (PDA), etc. A NAS is a device that can act as an access point for a user device. Many types of NAS devices are known. For example, among other things a NAS may be a dial-in modem, an internet protocol (IP) router, a secure shell (SSH) based remote access appliance, a network firewall appliance, a secure socket layer (SSL) remote access gateway appliance, or a virtual private network (VPN) server. Generally, to initiate a connection with a network device, the user device selectively transmits a series of data items to a NAS. The transmitted data items may include, for example, a user identifier and authentication code associated with the network device to be accessed. The authentication code may be, for example, a network password, a Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) authentication mechanism, a hardware token identifier, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In known RADIUS systems, each unique user identifier is tied to a single authentication mechanism. In addition, each unique user identifier can only store one set of data attributes, which may or may not be compatible across different classes of devices. Accordingly, for an end user to access a network device through more than one NAS and/or more than one authentication mechanism, the user must create separate user accounts having unique user identifiers for each class of NAS and/or authentication method. Thus, for a user to be able to access a network device, e.g., from home over a home IP router, and also to be able to access the network device, e.g., from a work site over a VPN server, the user generally must create separate user accounts using separate, unique user identifiers for each of these connections.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exemplary RADIUS server system;</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary RADIUS server system;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary user account;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary process for authentication.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In conventional RADIUS systems, the NAS connects to a RADIUS server. Based on a configured list, the RADIUS server determines if the NAS is approved to use the RADIUS server for authentication. If it is, the NAS provides the user identifier and the authentication code received from the user device to the RADIUS server. The RADIUS server communicates the user identifier and the authentication code to an authentication module. The authentication module analyzes the received user identifier and authentication code to determine the legitimacy of the authentication request. If the authentication module determines that the provided authentication code is an approved authentication code defined for the particular user identifier, the authentication module notifies the RADIUS server that the authorization request is accepted. Upon a successful authorization request, the RADIUS server may be configured to return connection attribute data, such as a connection attribute indicator, to the NAS. This connection attribute indicator may be used by the NAS to assign different levels of access, configure the session settings, such as controlling the length of time that a session may be maintained, or assignment of other environmental variables specific to that connection/authorization request. A limitation of conventional RADIUS servers is that a single user account can only store one unique set of data attributes. The problem that this brings up is that the data may be appropriate to return when a user is authenticating from a first class of device, such as a dial-in server, but not appropriate when authenticating from a different class of device, such as a network router.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The authentication response communicated by the RADIUS server must be provided to the NAS in a format specific to the type of NAS through which the authentication request is initiated, and must include attributes specific to the type of NAS. That is, a first NAS device, such as a VPN server, may require that an authentication response be provided in a first format and include a first set of attributes, such as through a LDAP authentication mechanism, while a second NAS device, such as an IP router, may require that an authentication response be provided in a second format and include a second set of attributes, such as through an encrypted password authentication mechanism. Thus, each NAS may require an authentication response provided using a specific authentication mechanism, which may require specific sets of parameters to be returned in predefined formats for authentication.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Further, with conventional RADIUS systems comprising multiple NAS devices, similar NAS devices on a common RADIUS system generally must authenticate using a common authentication mechanism. User accounts accessed through those similar NAS devices generally are provided with a common level of authentication or access,</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Moreover, in typical RADIUS systems, a RADIUS server generally is configured to communicate with NAS devices using a single authentication mechanism. Thus, in order to implement a system including multiple NAS devices, using multiple authentication mechanisms, each authentication mechanism requires a dedicated RADIUS server configured to communicate in the format required by the respective NAS devices.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exemplary RADIUS system <b>100</b> which may be useful for authentication of a user-based computing device <b>110</b> accessing a network device. System <b>100</b> includes a user-based computing device <b>110</b> configured to selectively communicate with a network access server (NAS) <b>120</b>. User-based computing device <b>110</b> may include, by way of example and not of limitation, a mobile or non-mobile personal computer, a workstation, a cellular telephone, an automated teller machine (ATM), a television set top box (STB), etc. NAS <b>120</b> may be, for example, a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) Remote Access Gateway Appliance, a virtual private network (VPN) server, a network firewall appliance, a Secure Shell (SSFH) Remote Access Gateway, an Internet Protocol (IP) router, a dial-in modem, etc. User-based computing device <b>110</b> may selectively communicate with NAS <b>120</b>, for instance, over a network. The network may be a local area network (LAN), generally a packet switch network, a wide area network (WAN), or other network as may be known. Alternatively, user-based computing device <b>110</b> may communicate with NAS <b>120</b> directly over a wired connection or a wireless connection.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">NAS <b>120</b> may be configured to selectively communicate with a RADIUS server <b>130</b>. NAS <b>120</b> may communicate with RADIUS server <b>130</b> over a network <b>125</b>. Network <b>125</b> may be a local area network (LAN), generally a packet switch network, a wide area network (WAN), or other network as may be known. Such network <b>125</b> may, but need not, include the Internet. NAS <b>120</b> may be configured to selectively transmit data to RADIUS server <b>130</b> to authenticate a user or user-based computing device <b>110</b> attempting to access a network or network device, such as an internet server, a file server, a database, a software application, a printer, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an exemplary user account <b>160</b> is illustrated having a user identifier <b>305</b> and including a first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>and a second user profile <b>310</b><i>b</i>. A user profile <b>310</b>, such as first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>or second user profile <b>310</b><i>b</i>, may include a device identifier <b>320</b>, which may uniquely identify a NAS <b>120</b>. By way of example, and not of limitation, device identifier <b>320</b> may include an IP address corresponding to a specific NAS <b>120</b>, as illustrated in <b>320</b><i>a </i>and <b>320</b><i>b</i>. Each user profile <b>310</b> may also include a profile identifier <b>330</b>, which may be a combination of the user identifier <b>305</b>, and device identifier <b>320</b>. User profile <b>310</b> may further include a NAS type indicator <b>340</b>, indicating the type of NAS <b>120</b> associated with the profile <b>310</b>, an authentication mechanism indicator <b>350</b>, indicating the method of authentication required for the NAS <b>120</b>, a connection attribute indicator <b>360</b>, indicative of the nature of the access to be granted to the user upon successful authentication, and a group indicator <b>370</b> indicative of a group to which the user profile may belong.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As illustrated, the first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>includes a first device identifier <b>320</b><i>a </i>corresponding to a first NAS <b>120</b>. Profile identifier <b>330</b><i>a </i>is identified by the combination of user identifier <b>305</b> and first device identifier <b>320</b><i>a</i>. First user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>further includes NAS Type indicator <b>340</b><i>a </i>indicating the type of network access server <b>120</b> associated with the first user profile <b>310</b><i>a</i>, an authentication mechanism indicator <b>350</b><i>a </i>indicating the authentication mechanism used by NAS <b>120</b>, a connection attribute indicator <b>360</b><i>a </i>indicating the nature of the access to be granted to the user-based computing device <b>110</b> upon successful authentication, and a group indicator <b>370</b><i>a </i>which may indicate a group to which the user profile may belong.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Similarly, the second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>includes a second device identifier <b>320</b><i>b </i>corresponding to a second NAS <b>120</b>. Profile identifier <b>330</b><i>b </i>is identified by the combination of user identifier <b>305</b> and second device identifier <b>320</b><i>b</i>. Second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>further includes NAS Type indicator <b>340</b><i>b </i>indicating the type of network access server <b>120</b> associated with the second user profile <b>310</b><i>b</i>, an authentication mechanism indicator <b>350</b><i>b </i>indicating the authentication mechanism used by NAS <b>120</b>, a connection attribute indicator <b>360</b><i>b </i>indicating the nature of the access to be granted to the user-based computing device <b>110</b> upon successful authentication, and a group indicator <b>370</b><i>b </i>which may indicate a group to which the user profile may belong.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">While user account <b>160</b> is shown as including two user profiles <b>310</b><i>a</i>, <b>310</b><i>b</i>, it is to be understood that this is by way of example and not of limitation, and that user account <b>160</b> may include any number of user profiles as is required. In one exemplary approach, an administrator may selectively access user profile database <b>150</b> to input additional user accounts <b>160</b>, or additional user profiles <b>310</b> within existing user accounts <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Considering <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in combination with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be configured to selectively receive one or more data parameters from the NAS <b>120</b>. For example, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be configured to receive a NAS identifier, such as an IP address of the NAS <b>120</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be in selective communication with a NAS database <b>155</b>. Upon receipt of the NAS identifier, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may communicate with NAS database <b>155</b> to determine whether NAS <b>120</b> is permitted to use RADIUS server <b>130</b> for authentication purposes. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may also receive an authentication request from NAS <b>120</b>. The authentication request may include at least a user identifier <b>305</b> representing the user of user-based computing device <b>110</b>, a device identifier <b>320</b> corresponding to NAS <b>120</b>, which may be the IP address of the NAS <b>120</b>, as well as at least one authentication parameter. The authentication parameter may include, e.g., a user supplied password, which may be encrypted, a token ring identifier, a SecurID identifier, a LDAP authentication identifier, etc., associated with a specific user and/or user-based computing device <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be in selective communication with a user profile database <b>150</b>, e.g., through a network. In some situations, however, a user profile database <b>150</b> may be directly associated with RADIUS server <b>130</b>. User profile database <b>150</b> may include one or more user accounts <b>160</b>. The one or more user accounts <b>160</b> may include one or more user profiles <b>310</b>. The user profiles <b>310</b> within a given user account <b>160</b> may be uniquely defined using a profile identifier <b>330</b>, which may be defined as a combination of a common user identifier <b>305</b> and a device identifier <b>320</b> of a NAS device <b>120</b>. User account <b>160</b> may thus include information such as a user identifier <b>305</b> associated with a user, and one or more device identifiers <b>320</b> corresponding to one or more NAS devices <b>120</b> associated with the user identifier <b>305</b> and through which the user may access the RADIUS server <b>130</b>. User profiles <b>310</b> may include one or more connection attribute indicators <b>360</b>, which may be used by NAS <b>120</b> to define the nature of access given to a user accessing a network device over a respective one or more NAS <b>120</b>, as well as an indicator of one or more authentication mechanisms <b>350</b> used by respective one or more NAS devices <b>120</b>. Such authentication mechanisms may include a password, LDAP, SecurID, and the like as noted above. A given authentication mechanism may require that certain specific data parameters be provided to NAS <b>120</b>, and that the specific parameters be provided in a specific format. The specific data parameters and the specific formats may, but need not, differ for each NAS <b>120</b> and/or each authentication mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">User profiles <b>310</b> may also include one or more group indicators <b>370</b>. Group indicators <b>370</b> may indicate a group to which a particular user, user device <b>110</b> or NAS <b>120</b> may belong. Group identifiers may include, e.g., attribute data common to members of the group. For instance, a number of unique user profiles <b>310</b> may be included in a single group, and all members of the group may have one or more common attributes. For example, members may share a common authentication method, a common connection attribute indicator <b>360</b> indicative of connection attributes which are to be used for connections groups members, etc. Group indicators <b>370</b> may be used in conjunction with, or in lieu of, other indicators, such as authentication mechanism indicator <b>350</b>, connection attribute indicator <b>360</b>, etc. In this manner attributes, such as connection attribute indicator <b>360</b>, corresponding to a series of users or user devices can be controlled or edited by selectively editing group attribute information. Group attribute may be stored in a group database (not picture) which may be selectively accessible by RADIUS server <b>130</b>. Group information may also be stored on a database, such as NAS database <b>155</b>, or user profile database <b>150</b>, directly on RADIUS server <b>130</b>, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">User profile database <b>150</b> may include a series of user accounts <b>160</b>. User accounts <b>160</b> may each include one or more user profiles <b>310</b> associated with a given user identifier <b>305</b>. For instance, a single user account <b>160</b> may include a user identifier <b>305</b>, which user identifier <b>305</b> may be tied to both a first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>and a second user profile <b>310</b><i>b</i>. The first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>may be defined by the combination of the user identifier <b>305</b> and a device identifier <b>320</b><i>a </i>of a first NAS device <b>120</b>. The second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>may be defined by the combination of the user identifier <b>305</b> and a device identifier <b>320</b><i>b </i>of a second NAS device <b>120</b>. The first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>may include authentication information useful for authentication and access through the first NAS device <b>120</b>. For example, the first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>may indicate the authentication mechanism to be used when access is requested through the first NAS device <b>120</b>, as well as the connection attribute <b>360</b> to be provided to the first NAS device <b>120</b> when the network device is so accessed. The second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>may include authentication information related to authentication and access through the second NAS device <b>120</b>. For example, the second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>may indicate the authentication mechanism to be used when authentication is requested through the second NAS device <b>120</b>, as well as the connection attribute <b>360</b> to be provided to the second NAS device <b>120</b> when the network device is so accessed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The NAS device <b>120</b> associated with the first user profile <b>310</b><i>a </i>and the NAS device <b>120</b> associated with the second user profile <b>310</b><i>b </i>may, but need not, be the same type of NAS device <b>120</b> and may, but need not, use a common authentication mechanism. Similarly, the connection attribute <b>360</b> provided when authentication is requested by a user through a first NAS device <b>120</b> may differ from the connection attribute <b>360</b> when authentication is requested through a second NAS device <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Upon receiving an authentication request from NAS <b>120</b>, the RADIUS server <b>130</b> may access a corresponding user account <b>160</b> located in user profile database <b>150</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may then access a specific user profile <b>310</b> stored within user account <b>160</b> using a profile identifier <b>330</b>, which is the combination of a user identifier <b>305</b> and device identifier <b>320</b> provided by NAS device <b>120</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may thus determine from the user account <b>160</b> the type of NAS <b>120</b> associated with the provided device identifier <b>320</b>, as well as the authentication mechanism to be utilized for the requested authentication, including parameters required and the format in which the parameters must be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The RADIUS server <b>130</b> may also be in selective communication with one or more authentication modules <b>140</b>. Authentication modules <b>140</b> may be software or hardware modules configured to perform authentication tasks related to one or more authentication mechanisms. Authentication modules <b>140</b> may reside on RADIUS server <b>130</b>. Alternatively, authentication modules <b>140</b> may be located on a database or server accessible to RADIUS server <b>130</b>, including but not limited to user profile database <b>150</b>, or NAS database <b>155</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Each of the one or more authentication modules <b>140</b> may be configured to process authentication requests received in a particular authentication format or through a particular authentication mechanism. For instance, a first authentication module <b>140</b> may be configured to process authentication requests received in LDAP format, whereas a second authentication module <b>140</b> may be configured to process authentication requests received in a Hardware Token (HT) format.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The RADIUS server <b>130</b> may selectively transmit information related to a user authentication request received from a NAS device <b>120</b> to an authentication module <b>140</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may determine an appropriate authentication module <b>140</b> through which a given authentication request may be processed based, at least in part, on information retrieved from the user profile <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Authentication module <b>140</b> may process a received user identifier <b>305</b> and authentication parameter to determine whether the user is to be given access to the requested network or network device. Authentication module <b>140</b> may subsequently transmit an authentication signal to RADIUS server <b>130</b> to indicate whether user-based computing device <b>110</b> is to be granted access. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be configured such that additional authentication modules <b>140</b> may be subsequently added to system <b>100</b> to allow authentication requests to be processed in additional manners.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">When it has been determined by authentication module <b>140</b> that user-based computing device <b>110</b> is to be given access to the requested network device, RADIUS server <b>130</b> develops an authentication response to be sent to NAS <b>120</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may format the authentication response based in part on the format and the parameters required for NAS <b>120</b>, which may be determined at least in part through information stored in a user profile <b>310</b> of user account <b>160</b>, and which may include the connection attribute indicator <b>360</b> that will govern a connection through NAS <b>120</b>. NAS <b>120</b> may thereby determine a level of access which the user-based computing device <b>110</b> is to be given to the network or network device. For instance, a user-based computing device <b>110</b> may be granted full access to a network device. Alternatively, user-based computing device <b>110</b> may be granted access to a subset of functions available through a network device, or, despite being authenticated, may be granted no access to network device functions.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Accordingly, a single RADIUS server <b>130</b> may selectively communicate with multiple network access servers <b>120</b>, even though the multiple network access servers <b>120</b> may each require authentication responses to be provided in unique formats. By selectively receiving a user identifier <b>305</b> and a device identifier <b>320</b> associated with each authentication request, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may determine required authentication mechanisms for each authentication request.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Further, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may selectively authenticate a user having a single user identifier <b>305</b> over each of a plurality of network access servers <b>120</b>. Upon receiving a request from a NAS <b>120</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may compare a received NAS identifier against NAS database <b>155</b>. When NAS <b>120</b> is approved, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may subsequently receive an authentication request, As an authentication request is received, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may communicate with user profile database <b>150</b> to access a user account <b>160</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may then determine from the account <b>160</b> the type of NAS <b>120</b>, and the authentication mechanism required, based on the device identifier <b>320</b> received.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary RADIUS system <b>100</b>&#x2032; which may be useful for a single user authenticating a user-based computing device <b>110</b> such as a laptop computer <b>110</b><i>a</i>, a personal digital assistant (PDA) <b>110</b><i>b</i>, or a computer workstation <b>110</b><i>c</i>, to access a network or network device, such as an internet server, a network printer, etc, through a network access server <b>120</b> such as VPN server <b>120</b><i>a</i>, network firewall appliance <b>120</b><i>b</i>, or IP router <b>120</b><i>c</i>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c </i>may receive an authentication request from a user-based computing device <b>110</b><i>a</i>, <b>110</b><i>b</i>, <b>110</b><i>c</i>. The authentication request may include a user identifier <b>305</b> and an authentication parameter. The NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c </i>may be in selective communication with RADIUS server <b>130</b>. The NAS <b>120</b> may transmit a NAS identifier, such as an IP address to the RADIUS server <b>130</b>, which may compare the NAS identifier to a NAS database <b>155</b> to determine whether the NAS <b>120</b> is permitted to access RADIUS server <b>120</b>. Upon being granted access, NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c </i>may transmit the authentication request, as well as the device identifier <b>320</b> of the NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c </i>to RADIUS server <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">RADIUS server <b>130</b> may be in selective communication with one or more user profile databases <b>150</b>. Upon receiving an authentication request from NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may locate a user account <b>160</b> associated with the received user identifier <b>305</b>. Upon retrieving the user account <b>160</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may locate a user profile <b>310</b> associated with the user identifier <b>305</b> and the device identifier <b>320</b> of the requesting NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>, From the user profile <b>310</b> stored within user account <b>160</b>, the RADIUS server <b>130</b> may determine the type of NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>, as well as the authentication mechanism incorporated by the NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may further determine the connection attribute indicator <b>360</b> associated with the user-based computing device <b>110</b><i>a</i>, <b>110</b><i>b</i>, <b>110</b><i>c</i>, indicative of the nature of the connection to be provided should the authentication be successful.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Once RADIUS server <b>130</b> determines the authentication mechanisms incorporated by NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> may then transmit the authentication request to the appropriate authentication module <b>140</b> to process the authentication request, such as, in one illustrative example, LDAP authentication module <b>140</b><i>a</i>, hardware token authentication module <b>140</b><i>b</i>, or password authentication module <b>140</b><i>c</i>. Authentication module <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, may process the authentication request to determine whether the requesting user-based computing device <b>110</b> should be granted access. Authentication module <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c</i>, may then provide an authentication signal to RADIUS server <b>130</b>, indicating whether user-based computing device <b>110</b><i>a</i>, <b>110</b><i>b</i>, <b>110</b><i>c </i>has successfully been authenticated.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The RADIUS server <b>130</b> may then transmit the response to the requesting NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c </i>in the format required by that particular NAS <b>120</b>. That is, when it has been determined by authentication module <b>140</b><i>a</i>, <b>140</b><i>b</i>, <b>140</b><i>c </i>that the user-based computing device <b>110</b><i>a</i>, <b>110</b><i>b</i>, <b>110</b><i>c </i>is to be given access to the requested network or network device, the RADIUS server <b>130</b> develops an authentication response to be sent to NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c</i>. The authentication response may include the connection attribute indicator <b>360</b>. The RADIUS server <b>130</b> formats the authentication response based on the required parameters and the required format for the particular NAS <b>120</b><i>a</i>, <b>120</b><i>b</i>, <b>120</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Computing devices, such as those mentioned above, may employ any of a number of known computer operating systems. For example, such devices may use any known versions and/or varieties of the Microsoft Windows operating system; the Unix operating system (e.g., the Solaris operating system distributed by Sun Microsystems of Menlo Park, Calif.); the AIX UNIX operating system distributed by International Business Machines of Armonk, N.Y.; and the Linux operating system. Computing devices may include any one of a number of computing devices that are known, including, without limitation, a computer workstation, a desktop, notebook, laptop, handheld computer, or some other computing device.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Computing devices generally include instructions executable by one or more computing devices such as those listed above. Computer-executable instructions may be compiled or interpreted from computer programs created using a variety of known programming languages and/or technologies, including, without limitation, and either alone or in combination, Java, C, C++, Visual Basic, Java Script, Perl, etc. In general, a processor (e.g., a microprocessor) receives instructions, e.g., from a memory, a computer-readable medium, etc., and executes these instructions, thereby performing one or more processes, including one or more of the processes described herein. Such instructions and other data may be stored and transmitted using a variety of known computer-readable media.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A computer-readable medium includes any medium that participates in providing data (e.g., instructions), which may be read by a computer. Such a medium may take many forms, including, but not limited to, non-volatile media, volatile media, and transmission media. Non-volatile media include, for example, optical or magnetic disks and other persistent memory. Volatile media include dynamic random access memory (DRAM), which typically constitutes a main memory. Transmission media include coaxial cables, copper wire and fiber optics, including the wires that comprise a system bus coupled to the processor. Transmission media may include or convey acoustic waves, light waves and electromagnetic emissions, such as those generated during radio frequency (RF) and infrared (IR) data communications. Common forms of computer-readable media include, for example: a floppy disk, a flexible disk, hard disk, magnetic tape, any other magnetic medium, a CD-ROM, DVD, any other optical medium, punch cards, paper tape, any other physical medium with patterns of holes, a RAM, a PROM, an EPROM, a FLASH-EEPROM, any other memory chip or cartridge, a carrier wave, or any other medium from which a computer can read.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary process <b>400</b> for authentication of a user-based computing device <b>110</b> within system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At step <b>405</b>, the RADIUS server <b>130</b> receives data from NAS <b>120</b>. The data includes a device identifier, such as the IP address of the NAS <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">At step <b>410</b>, the RADIUS server compares the device identifier to a list of acceptable device identifiers stored in a database, such as NAS database <b>155</b>, to determine whether NAS <b>120</b> is approved to access RADIUS server <b>130</b>. In addition, the data received from NAS <b>120</b> may include one or more authentication parameters to ensure validity or credibility of the received information.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">At step <b>415</b>, if the received NAS identifier is not included in the NAS database, the NAS <b>120</b> is denied access and the process ends. If the NAS identifier is included in the list of approved identifiers, the NAS <b>120</b> is allowed to continue with authentication request.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">At step <b>420</b>, an authentication request is received by RADIUS server <b>130</b> from NAS <b>120</b>. The authentication request may include a user identifier, a device identifier associated with NAS <b>120</b>, and an authentication parameter, such as a password, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Next, at step <b>425</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> accesses a user profile database <b>150</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> may access user profile database <b>150</b> over a network, such as a LAN or a WAN.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Next, at step <b>430</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> accesses the user account <b>160</b> associated with the received user identifier <b>305</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> further accesses an appropriate user profile <b>310</b> stored within user account <b>160</b>, the user profile <b>310</b> identified by the profile identifier <b>330</b>, which may be the combination of user identifier <b>305</b> and device identifier <b>320</b> of NAS <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At step <b>435</b>, when the appropriate user profile <b>310</b> has been located within user account <b>160</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> determines the authentication mechanism associated with NAS <b>120</b> through authentication type indicator <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Next, at step <b>440</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> determines an appropriate authentication module <b>140</b> configured to process the received authentication request using the authentication mechanism identified in step <b>435</b>. RADIUS server <b>130</b> then transmits the authentication request to the identified authentication module <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">At step <b>445</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> determines authentication status based on an authentication signal received from authentication module <b>140</b>. Further, RADIUS server <b>130</b> determines connection attribute indicator <b>360</b> stored within user profile.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Next, at step <b>450</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> formats the authentication response to provide the parameters required by NAS <b>120</b>, and to provide the parameters in the format required by NAS <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Finally, at step <b>455</b>, RADIUS server <b>130</b> transmits the authentication response to NAS <b>120</b>, which determines the nature of the device <b>110</b> access based on the connection attribute indicator <b>360</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">CONCLUSION</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">With regard to the processes, systems, methods, heuristics, etc. described herein, it should be understood that, although the steps of such processes, etc. have been described as occurring according to a certain ordered sequence, such processes could be practiced with the described steps performed in an order other than the order described herein. It further should be understood that certain steps could be performed simultaneously, that other steps could be added, or that certain steps described herein could be omitted. In other words, the descriptions of processes herein are provided for the purpose of illustrating certain embodiments, and should in no way be construed so as to limit the claimed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Accordingly, it is to be understood that the above description is intended to be illustrative and not restrictive. Many embodiments and applications other than the examples provided would be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reading the above description. The scope of the invention should be determined, not with reference to the above description, but should instead be determined with reference to the appended claims, along with the full scope of equivalents to which such claims are entitled. It is anticipated and intended that future developments will occur in the arts discussed herein, and that the disclosed systems and methods will be incorporated into such future embodiments. In sum, it should be understood that the invention is capable of modification and variation and is limited only by the following claims.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">All terms used in the claims are intended to be given their broadest reasonable constructions and their ordinary meanings as understood by those skilled in the art unless an explicit indication to the contrary in made herein. In particular, use of the singular articles such as &#x201c;a,&#x201d; &#x201c;the,&#x201d; &#x201c;said,&#x201d; etc. should be read to recite one or more of the indicated elements unless a claim recites an explicit limitation to the contrary.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a remote authentication dial in user service (RADIUS) server configured to:
<claim-text>receive an authentication request from a network access server, the authentication request including a user identifier and a device identifier of the network access server,</claim-text>
<claim-text>access a user profile of a set of user profiles stored within a user account based on the received user identifier and device identifier of the network access server to retrieve, from the user profile, information specific to the network access server including an authentication type indicator stored within the user profile,</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine, from the information specific to the network access server and based on the authentication type indicator, an authentication mechanism associated with the network access server to be used to process the authentication request and an authentication format for an authentication response to be provided to the network access server, the authentication format and the authentication response being specific to the type of network access server from which the authentication request is received, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide the authentication response to the network access server in the determined authentication format,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the authentication mechanism is chosen from a plurality of available authentication mechanisms that include a hardware token ring mechanism, an LDAP mechanism, a SecurID mechanism, a secure-shell-based mechanism, a secure socket layer-based mechanism and a password based mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an authentication module configured to use the authentication mechanism to process the authentication request, wherein the RADIUS server is further configured to access the authentication module to determine an authentication status to include in the authentication response.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising, a plurality of authentication modules, wherein each of the plurality of authentication modules is configured to process an authentication request using one of a plurality of authentication mechanisms
<claim-text>wherein the RADIUS server is configured to access and select an authentication module from the plurality of authentication modules based on the determined authentication mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a user profile database selectively accessible by the RADIUS server;
<claim-text>the user profile database including at least one user account;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one user account including a plurality of user profiles, each one of the plurality of user profiles being uniquely defined by a combination of a user identifier and a device identifier of a network access server.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the RADIUS server is further configured to determine the authentication format for the authentication response by sending a query, to the user profile database for information specific to the network access server included in one of the plurality of user profiles, the query being configured to select the one of the plurality of user profiles corresponding to the user identifier and the device identifier of the network access server included in the authentication request.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein each user profile within the at least one user account is associated with a single unique network access server.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein each user profile within the at least one user account identifies authentication formats for respective devices, the respective devices identified by respective device identifiers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one user profile further includes a connection attribute indicator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of user profiles, wherein a first user profile connection attribute indicator is different from a second user profile connection attribute indicator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the authentication response includes at least one connection attribute indicator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an authentication module configured to process the authentication request using the determined authentication mechanism,
<claim-text>wherein the RADIUS server is further configured to
<claim-text>retrieve from the authentication module an authentication signal configured to indicate whether access is granted, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide the authentication response to the network access server based on the authentication signal in the determined authentication format.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an authentication request from a network access server by a remote authentication dial in user service (RADIUS) server, the authentication request including at least a user identifier and a device identifier of the network access server;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively accessing a user profile of a set of user profiles stored within a user account based on the received user identifier and device identifier of the network access server to retrieve, front the user profile, information specific to the network access server including an authentication type indicator stored within the user profile;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, from the information specific to the network access server and based on the authentication type indicator, an authentication mechanism associated with the network access server to be used to process the authentication request and an appropriate authentication format for an authentication response to be provided to the network access server, the authentication format and the authentication response being specific to the type of network access server from which the authentication request is received; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>formatting the authentication response based on the appropriate authentication format,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the authentication mechanism is chosen from a plurality of available authentication mechanisms that include a hardware token ring mechanism, an LDAP mechanism, a SecurID mechanism, a secure-shell-based mechanism, a secure socket layer-based mechanism and a password based mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein accessing the user profile includes choosing an appropriate user profile based on a received user identifier and device identifier of the network access server.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein accessing the user profile includes accessing a connection attribute indicator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein formatting an authentication response includes fbrmatting an authentication response based on the connection attribute indicator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein determining the appropriate authentication format includes accessing at least a subset of the information specific to the network access server.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the at least a subset of the information specific to the network access server includes an identifier stored within a selected user account.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the identifier is indicative of an authentication format for the network access server.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising identifying the network access server based at least in part on the received device identifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein identifying a network access server includes comparing the received device identifier with a list of acceptable device identifiers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining an authentication module configured to process the authentication request using the determined authentication mechanism associated with the network access server,</claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieving from the authentication module an authentication signal configured to indicate whether access is granted, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>formatting the authentication response based on the authentication signal in the appropriate authentication format.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a database including at least one user account, each user account including a plurality of user profiles, each one of the plurality of user profiles being uniquely defined by a combination of a user identifier and a device identifier of a network access server and specifying an authentication format and an authentication mechanism via an authentication type indicator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a RADIUS server in selective communication with at least one network access server and the database, the RADIUS server configured to
<claim-text>receive an authentication request from the at least one network access server, the authentication request including at least a user identifier and a device identifier, the device identifier uniquely identifying one of the at least one network access servers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine an authentication format and an authentication mechanism associated with the identified one network access server by sending a query to the database for the authentication type indicator included in one of the plurality of user profiles, the query being configured to identify the at least one user account based on the user identifier, select from the at least one user account the one of the plurality of user profiles corresponding to the device identifier, and retrieve, from the user profile, information specific to the identified one network access server including the authentication format and the authentication mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine an authentication module configured to process the authentication request using the determined authentication mechanism associated with the identified one network access server;</claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieve from the authentication module an authentication signal configured to indicate whether access is granted; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fashion an authentication response based on the authentication signal in the determined authentication format to return to the at least one network access server,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the authentication mechanism is chosen from a plurality of available authentication mechanisms that include a hardware token ring mechanism, an LDAP mechanism, a SecurID mechanism, a secure-shell-based mechanism, a secure socket layer-based mechanism and a password based mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
