<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621728-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621728</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13569201</doc-number>
<date>20120808</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>45</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>44</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 246001</main-classification>
<further-classification> 245995</further-classification>
<further-classification> 245997</further-classification>
<further-classification>294 822</further-classification>
<further-classification>294 8223</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Locking carabiner</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8117721</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Yang</name>
<date>20120200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 245995</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0105190</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Diehl et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>523201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0143945</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Christianson</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 246001</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0005876</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Christianson</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 246001</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2012/0102688</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang</name>
<date>20120500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 246001</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0025095</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang</name>
<date>20130100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 245995</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245991</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245999</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 246001</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245995</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245996</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245997</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 245981</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>294 8219</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>294 822</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>294 8233</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>21</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61574825</doc-number>
<date>20110809</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61685376</doc-number>
<date>20120316</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130036579</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130214</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Christianson</last-name>
<first-name>Tony</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yosemite</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Christianson</last-name>
<first-name>Tony</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yosemite</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Sandy</last-name>
<first-name>Robert J</first-name>
<department>3677</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A locking carabiner having an eccentric pivot that when rotated causes a reciprocating motion that moves the opening end of the gate into or out of locking engagement with the carabiner body. Rotation of the eccentric is controlled by a short lever that can be easily moved by a fingertip, consequently the gate can be conveniently manipulated and locked with the fingers of one hand. The locking mechanism adds negligible weight and bulk to the carabiner. The locking mechanism can be incorporated on bent gate, straight gate and wire gate carabiners.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="88.48mm" wi="276.44mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="236.56mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="213.11mm" wi="156.13mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="234.10mm" wi="181.95mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="238.51mm" wi="191.01mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.15mm" wi="158.50mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="230.80mm" wi="200.83mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="197.95mm" wi="136.06mm" file="US08621728-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The instant invention is related to Provisional Application No. 61/574,825 entitled &#x201c;Cam Lock Carabiner,&#x201d; filed Aug. 9, 2011, and Provisional Application No. 61/685,376 entitled &#x201c;Locking Wiregate Carabiner&#x201d; filed Mar. 16, 2012, the disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The instant invention is generally related to climbing aids for rock climbers. More particularly, this invention is related to carabiners that link climbing aids together.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Climbers utilize rope, slings and a variety of mechanical devices as climbing aids to assist and protect their movement over rock. The climbing aids serve as a means to anchor the climber to the rock for the purpose of either preventing or arresting a fall.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A carabiner is a mechanical device used to link rope, slings and other climbing aids together. A carabiner is essentially a device used, for example, to attach a climber's body harness to the climbing rope. It is also used to link the climbing rope to anchors placed in or over the rock.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">During a climb and especially in the event of a fall, the climber's safety is dependent on the security of numerous carabiner links. Consequently, it is imperative that every carabiner in the chain be able to withstand not only the weight of the climber but also the inertial forces generated when the rope arrests a fall.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A typical carabiner is palm sized, and either an oblong, oval or &#x201c;D&#x201d; shaped ring of a lightweight, high strength material, usually a heat-treated aluminum alloy. One side of the carabiner has a hinged arm that serves as an inward opening gate. The gate is spring loaded to remain normally closed. The normally closed, inward opening gate facilitates insertion of climbing aids such as rope or slings, but impedes inadvertent removal. Climbing aids are released from the carabiner by manually opening the gate.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">There are two types of carabiner gates, wire gates and solid gates. A wire gate is a simple loop of corrosion-resistant spring-wire bent in a the shape of an elongated &#x201c;U&#x201d;. A solid gate is a short bar of a rigid high strength material, usually a heat-treated aluminum alloy.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The wire loop itself provides the closing force for a wire gate. This is accomplished by bending the legs of the &#x201c;U&#x201d; slightly off-parallel with unequal lengths, and bending the staggered ends 90-degrees inward. The wire loop must be slightly twisted for the ends to pass through correspondingly offset holes in the body of the carabiner. Twisting the wire loop causes a cantilevered spring force that holds the gate normally closed. Opening the wire gate additionally twists the wire which increases the spring force working to close the gate.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The closing force of a solid gate is provided by a stout compression spring that is housed within the gate. The spring axis is offset from a pivot pin so that the spring force is directed to close the gate. A spring link is employed to transfer the spring force to the carabiner body at an appropriate distance from the pivot pin. Opening the solid gate compresses the spring.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The opening end of the carabiner gate incorporates an interlocking mechanism that engages the carabiner body when the gate is closed. For wire gates the interlock is provided by the wire's looped nose mating with a hooked notch on the carabiner body. For solid gates the interlocking mechanism is typically a transverse pin that mates with a hooked notch on the carabiner body. Another popular configuration for solid gates is a keyed arrangement that mates a bulbous nose of the gate's opening end with a correspondingly shaped recess in the carabiner body. These interlocking arrangements allow a closed gate to carry part of the load imposed on the carabiner. Consequently, the carabiner is significantly stronger when the gate is closed. The ultimate strength of a carabiner with the gate open is typically 65% lower than with the gate closed.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Wire gate carabiners have several advantages over those with a rigid gate . Wire gate carabiners typically weigh less than rigid gate carabiners. Furthermore, a wire gate consists of only one working part, whereas a rigid gate is an assembly of at least four (4) parts: bar, spring, spring link, and pivot pin. The inherent simplicity of the wire gate makes it more reliable and less prone to problems of breakage, contamination or icing.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As the climber progresses upward, the carabiners in a protective chain of climbing aids often rub against the rock. Occasionally, a carabiner gate will catch on a rock or other object, or the rope itself, and may be temporarily pushed or pulled open without the climber's knowledge. Additionally, a carabiner can slap against the rock during a fall causing inertial loads that overcome the closing force of the spring and momentarily open the gate. Also, a rope moving rapidly through a carabiner during a fall can cause the carabiner body to vibrate sufficiently to shake the gate open.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Whenever the gate is opened, even momentarily, there is significant risk that a rope or other attached climbing aid will be inadvertently released. Furthermore, if a sudden load is applied to the carabiner at the instant that the gate is open, the ultimate strength of the carabiner will be significantly compromised and possibly fail. Such occurrences are well known by the climbing community and are considered a significant problem. Consequently, climbers pay careful attention to the placement and orientation of carabiners in order to minimize the chance of an inadvertent opening of the gate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Climbers often use two carabiners joined by a short length of looped webbing, a combination called a quickdraw. One of the quickdraw carabiners is clipped to an anchor placed in or on the rock. The other quickdraw carabiner is clipped to the climber's rope. The quickdraw allows the rope to pull toward the centerline between staggered anchors thereby providing a less resistive path from the belay point to the climber.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A quickdraw requires the use of two carabiners to attach a rope to a single anchor. Assembling a quickdraw with smaller, lightweight carabiners minimizes the weight and bulk penalty of using two carabiners. Wire gate carabiners are often used for quickdraw configurations because they weigh less than solid gate carabiners.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A properly placed quickdraw may have the additional benefit of reducing the chance of an inadvertent opening of the gate. Unfortunately this is often not the case. For example, if the rope is incorrectly threaded through the carabiner, a moving rope can twist the carabiner and expose the gate to a sideward opening force. Also, if the rope is pulled across or around the gate, the gate can be inadvertently opened.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A climber must be very careful when placing and clipping into a quickdraw. The dangling carabiner (the carabiner that will be clipped to the climbers rope) must be oriented so that its gate is away from the rock face. When the rope is clipped in, it must run along the spine of the carabiner, not across the gate.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Many solid gate carabiners have a bend to facilitate clipping the rope. The bent gate's center is curved inward slightly which allows the gate to open wider and serves to guide the rope to the opening end. Bent gate carabiners are often used as the dangling carabiner of quickdraw configurations.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Placing the rope into the quickdraw's dangling carabiner requires skill and dexterity. Usually the climber is hanging on to the rock surface with one hand, and has only one hand free to clip in the rope. Depending on which hand is free, and the location and orientation of the carabiner relative to the climber, a variation of two techniques is typically used: 1. The carabiner is stabilized with the middle finger, and the rope is clipped in with the thumb and index fingers; or 2. Stabilize the carabiner with the thumb, and clip the rope using the index and middle fingers. No matter the technique used, the carabiner gate must open easily and without hesitation.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">There are situations where the risk of an inadvertent opening of the gate is totally unacceptable, For example, the carabiner used to attach the climbing rope to the climber's body harness must never open inadvertently. Similarly, the carabiner used to attach a belay device to the climber's harness must never open inadvertently. Consequently, harness attachments and the like require greater security, for example, two parallel carabiners or a single carabiner with a locking gate.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Greater security can be obtained by using two carabiners side-by-side with the gates opening in opposite directions. However, extra carabiners solely for the purpose of parallel placement are undesirable because they double the weight and bulk that the climber must carry.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">To avoid the need for side-by-side carabiners, various mechanical means have been developed to lock solid gates closed. For example, a popular locking configuration incorporates a sleeve that is threaded, nut like, to the gate. The sleeve can be screwed along the length of the gate, either toward the hinge, or toward the opening end. The sleeve is screwed into the locking position after the rope or other climbing aids have been clipped into the carabiner and the gate closed. In one configuration the gate is locked by screwing the sleeve until it crosses the opening end of the gate and moves over or jams against the adjacent body of the carabiner. In an alternate configuration the gate is immobilized when the sleeve is screwed over the hinge. Locking or unlocking a carabiner with a threaded sleeve is not instantaneous, that is, it takes time to thread the sleeve from the unlocked position to the locked position and the reverse.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Threaded locking sleeves undesirably add bulk and weight to the carabiner. Threaded locking sleeves are also inherently troublesome. The threads can become clogged with dirt or ice. The sleeve can inadvertently screw out of the locked position when the carabiner rubs across the rock. Furthermore, the gate and threaded sleeve mechanism require precise machining and assembly alignment, both of which add to manufacturing cost.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Other solutions of the prior art include solid gates equipped with spring loaded sliding and/or rotary sleeves called auto-lockers. Sliding and/or rotary sleeves function similarly to threaded sleeves, and are designed to lock automatically and nearly instantaneously when the gate closes. Sliding and rotary sleeves share the same problems as threaded sleeves, and are especially costly to manufacture. A critical problem of auto-lockers is that the gate can jam and not correctly close.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The increased bulk, weight and expense of the prior art limits the number of locking carabiners that a climber carries during a climb or is willing to buy. Consequently, there may be situations during a climb when the climber is compelled to use a non-locking carabiner although a locking type would be preferable or safer.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The security of quickdraw applications would benefit from the use of locking carabiners, but most quickdraw configurations utilize at least one wire gate or bent gate carabiner. Due to its wire construction, threaded or sliding/rotary sleeves cannot be incorporated on wire gate carabiners. And the bend interferes with mounting locking sleeves on bent gates. The prior art only has the means to lock a straight gate closed.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Quickdraw configurations do not incorporate state-of-the-art locking straight gate carabiners because they are considered too heavy and bulky for this application. The need to be able to easily and instantly clip a rope using only one hand make auto-locking gates especially inappropriate for quickdraw use.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The instant invention is a locking means ideally suited for quickdraw applications because it adds negligible weight and bulk to the carabiner and can be incorporated on bent gate, straight gate and wire gate configurations. The instant invention is a locking mechanism that can securely, reliably and quickly lock a carabiner gate by flipping a short lever with a fingertip. Furthermore, compared to state-of-the-art locking means, the instant invention is less susceptible to jamming and is easily manufactured.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The instant invention has an eccentric pivot that when rotated causes a reciprocating motion that moves the opening end of the gate into or out of locking engagement with the carabiner body. Rotation of the eccentric is controlled by a short lever that can be easily moved by a fingertip, consequently the gate can be conveniently manipulated and locked with the fingers of one hand. The locking mechanism adds negligible weight and bulk to the carabiner. The inventive locking mechanism can be incorporated on bent gate, straight gate and wire gate carabiners.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">A detailed description of the invention is made with reference to the accompanying drawings wherein like numerals designate corresponding parts in the several FIGS.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a pictorial view of a quickdraw configuration featuring inventive straight and bent gate carabiners linking rope with an anchor.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side elevation view of a bent gate carabiner incorporating the inventive locking mechanism. The inventive carabiner is pictured locked.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view of the carabiner as seen in the direction <b>3</b>-<b>3</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial sectional view of the inventive carabiner showing the gate unlocked, taken along a cut corresponding to line <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an exploded wireframe isometric drawing showing the main components of the inventive locking solid gate carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a partial close-up sectional view of the carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> showing the gate unlocked.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a partial close-up sectional view of the carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> showing the gate locked.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a wireframe isometric drawing of the eccentric pivot of the inventive carabiner viewed in the approximate direction <b>8</b>-<b>8</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a wireframe isometric drawing of an alternative eccentric pivot of the inventive carabiner viewed in the approximate direction <b>8</b>-<b>8</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a diagram of the eccentric mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a side elevation view of a typical straight gate carabiner incorporating the inventive locking mechanism. The carabiner is pictured unlocked.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a partial close-up sectional view of the carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> showing the gate unlocked and open.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a isometric wireframe drawing of an inventive locking wire gate carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an exploded isometric wireframe drawing showing the components of the inventive carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is close-up isometric wireframe drawing of the locking eccentric of the inventive carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a partial close-up side view of the locked carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> viewed at the approximate location and in the direction <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref></p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a partial close-up side view of the unlocked carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> viewed at the approximate location and in the direction <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a side view showing a comparison of the wire gate locking eccentric in both the locked and unlocked positions.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> is a partial close-up side view of the wire gate carabiner body viewed in the approximate location and direction <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a pictorial view showing one hand manipulating the locking arm while holding the inventive carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is a partial sectional view of a typical Prior Art locking carabiner.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The following detailed description is of the best presently contemplated modes of carrying out the invention. This description is not to be taken in a limiting sense, but is made merely for purposes of illustrating the general principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-12</figref> show the invention applied to solid gate carabiners. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13-19</figref> show the invention applied to wire gate carabiners.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, carabiners <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>b</i>, both incorporating the inventive locking mechanism, are shown linked by looped webbing <b>14</b> to form a quickdraw configuration. Carabiner <b>10</b><i>a </i>has a straight gate and is clipped to piton <b>16</b>, which is anchored to a crack in rock wall <b>18</b>. Carabiner <b>10</b><i>b </i>has a bent gate and is clipped to climbing rope <b>12</b>. Piton <b>16</b> is representative of one of many types of anchors used by climbers. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> exemplifies one of the many ways that carabiners are used to link climbing aids together.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, solid gate carabiner <b>10</b> includes body <b>20</b>, gate <b>30</b>, and eccentric <b>40</b>. Body <b>20</b> and gate <b>30</b> are typically fabricated from a lightweight, high strength material, for example aluminum alloy type 7075 heat treated to condition T6.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The preferred configuration of the inventive locking mechanism for solid gate carabiners is illustrated by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-10</figref>. The terms &#x201c;top&#x201d; and &#x201c;bottom&#x201d;; &#x201c;above&#x201d; and &#x201c;below&#x201d;; &#x201c;right&#x201d; and &#x201c;left&#x201d; refer to the orientation of carabiner <b>10</b> shown by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-10</figref> feature the inventive locking mechanism on a bent gate carabiner, the inventive locking mechanism can be incorporated on straight gate carabiners as well.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, gate <b>30</b> is slotted at both ends by slots <b>32</b> and <b>34</b>. Leg end <b>22</b> of body <b>20</b> nests loosely within the confines of slot <b>32</b>. Gate <b>30</b> is hinged to body <b>20</b> through eccentric <b>40</b> by pin <b>50</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). Pin <b>50</b> passes through hole <b>28</b> in leg end <b>22</b> with clearance sufficient to allow easy rotational movement. Pin <b>50</b> is typically steel and peened at both ends to secure it in place.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, gate <b>30</b> is urged to the closed position by the combined action of compression spring <b>60</b> and spring link <b>70</b>. Compression spring <b>60</b> and part of spring link <b>70</b> are loosely contained within blind hole <b>62</b> that opens into slot <b>32</b>. One end of compression spring <b>60</b> rests against hole bottom <b>64</b>, the other end of the spring engages a notch (not shown) on spring link <b>70</b> so that movement of spring link <b>70</b> toward hole <b>62</b> causes spring <b>60</b> to be correspondingly compressed. Compression spring <b>60</b> is typically fabricated by coiling a corrosion resistant material, for example 17-7 PH stainless steel spring wire. Spring link <b>70</b> is fabricated by stamping stainless steel sheet or molding plastic or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>, and the diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, eccentric <b>40</b> has outer cylindrical surfaces <b>46</b> and inner cylindrical surfaces <b>48</b>. The diameter of cylindrical surface <b>46</b> is approximately double the diameter of cylindrical surface <b>48</b>. Cylindrical surface <b>48</b> is a hole that snugly holds pin <b>50</b>. The central axis of surface <b>48</b> is offset from the central axis of surface <b>46</b> so that the surface of cylinder <b>48</b> coincides approximately with the center of cylindrical surface <b>46</b>. Cylindrical surfaces <b>46</b> and <b>48</b> have a central gap to enable insertion of body leg end <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Pin <b>50</b> passes through hole <b>48</b> (of eccentric <b>40</b>) and hole <b>28</b> (of body leg end <b>22</b>). Cylindrical surface <b>46</b> passes through hole <b>38</b> in the hinged end of gate <b>30</b> (best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) with clearance to allow easy rotational movement of gate <b>30</b>. The arrangement of the eccentric surfaces can be reversed without affecting the functional operation of the inventive locking mechanism. That is, cylindrical surface <b>46</b> can pass through an appropriately sized hole in body leg end <b>22</b>, and pin <b>50</b> through an appropriately sized hole in the hinged end of gate <b>30</b>. For example, the inventive locking wire gate carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13-19</figref> features eccentric <b>150</b> mounted in hole <b>128</b> of carabiner body <b>120</b> with gate <b>130</b> pinned to offset hole <b>158</b> in eccentric <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Relative to body <b>20</b>, an approximately 180-degree rotation of eccentric <b>40</b> around pin <b>50</b> causes a reciprocating motion that moves the center of surface <b>46</b> the distance labeled &#x201c;d&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. The distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; is approximately equal to the diameter of pin <b>50</b>, typically &#x215b;-inch. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> depicts cylindrical surface <b>46</b> in the unlocked position as a solid circle. Cylindrical surface <b>46</b> is depicted in the locked position as a dashed-line. The arced line with an arrow at each end and the captions &#x201c;lock&#x201d; and &#x201c;unlock&#x201d; show the direction of rotation of the eccentric to either lock or unlock gate <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Control arm <b>42</b> provides controlled rotational movement of eccentric <b>40</b> and thereby movement of cylindrical surface <b>46</b> around pin <b>50</b>. Control arm <b>42</b> is pictured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> as being formed by bending wire into a &#x201c;U&#x201d; shape that is attached to eccentric surfaces <b>46</b>. Other configurations of control arm <b>42</b> accomplish the same function, for example the arm can be a curved wire that partially wraps around the gate, or the arm can stamped from sheet-metal or forged as a single piece or molded or the like. Ideally, the size and shape of control arm <b>42</b> is chosen for compactness and convenience of motion. The alternate control arm configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows control arm <b>42</b><i>a </i>formed by stamping sheet-metal, or the like, and folded to fit snugly around the exterior of gate <b>30</b> when locked, advantageously minimizing the overall width of the assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Movement of control arm <b>42</b> with subsequent movement of eccentric <b>40</b> over an approximately 180-degree arc causes gate <b>30</b> to move right or left as depicted by the outline arrows &#x201c;B&#x201d; and &#x201c;D&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref> respectively. For example, when control arm <b>42</b> is moved in the arc direction depicted by the outline arrow &#x201c;A&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, gate <b>30</b> will move the distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; to the right as depicted by outline arrow &#x201c;B&#x201d;. Similarly, when control arm <b>42</b> is moved in the arc direction depicted by the outline arrow &#x201c;C&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, gate <b>30</b> will move the distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; to the left as depicted by outline arrow &#x201c;D&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The carabiner pictured in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-7</figref> features a keyed arrangement to interlock the opening end of gate <b>30</b> to leg end <b>24</b> of body <b>20</b>. Slot <b>34</b> is machined or formed wider at <b>34</b><i>a </i>to interlockingly and loosely engage the corresponding bulbous leg end <b>24</b> (best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). When the gate is closed, the interlocking relationship serves to solidly join the gate opening end and body <b>20</b> when high tensile loads stretch and deform the body, thereby causing closed gate <b>30</b> to carry part of the load transmitted through body <b>20</b>. Consequently, the carabiner is strongest when the gate is closed, either locked or unlocked.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Although not strictly necessary, for additional security, included with the bulbous leg end <b>24</b> is secondary protrusion <b>26</b>. A matching undercut <b>36</b> is provided in the keyed slot portion <b>34</b><i>a </i>of gate <b>30</b> to mate with protrusion <b>26</b>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, when gate <b>30</b> is unlocked, protrusion <b>26</b> does not engage undercut <b>36</b> and the resultant clearance enables opening movement of the gate end. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, when gate <b>30</b> is locked, gate <b>30</b> has moved to the right and protrusion <b>26</b> nests firmly within undercut <b>36</b> thereby preventing opening movement of gate <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Reciprocating movement of gate <b>30</b> from the locked to the unlocked position, and the reverse, is provided by rotating eccentric <b>40</b>. The dimensions of eccentric <b>40</b> are chosen to provide an appropriate distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; of arm <b>30</b> movement so that adequate opening clearance is provided in the unlocked position, and there is a solid and secure joining of the opening end of the gate to the body when in the locked position.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Advantageously the interlocking parts of the gate and body will fully engage just before eccentric <b>40</b> is rotated completely to the locked position. Early engagement will cause gate <b>30</b> to be pulled tightly against body <b>20</b>, and put gate <b>30</b> in tension when the fully locked position of eccentric <b>40</b> is reached. Furthermore, the tension of engagement can be utilized to hold control arm <b>42</b> in the locked position by having eccentric <b>40</b> come to rest somewhat over-center.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The inventive carabiner is locked or unlocked by moving control arm <b>42</b>. A single finger can be used to move control arm <b>42</b> in the approximately 180-degree arc centered on eccentric <b>40</b>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, control arm <b>42</b> rests adjacent body <b>20</b> when the inventive locking mechanism is unlocked. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, control arm <b>42</b> rests adjacent gate <b>30</b> when the inventive locking mechanism is locked.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Part of spring link <b>70</b> extends loosely down the center of spring <b>60</b>, terminating at end <b>72</b>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, when gate <b>30</b> is closed and unlocked, end <b>72</b> in hole <b>62</b> is located a short distance away from hole bottom <b>64</b>, that distance being at least the distance &#x201c;d&#x201d; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. Locking movement of control arm <b>42</b> causes spring link <b>70</b> to compress spring <b>60</b>, moving end <b>72</b> deeper into hole <b>62</b>. Consequently, when completely locked end <b>72</b> is very close to or touching hole bottom <b>64</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Similarly, (referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) opening movement (depicted by the outline arrow in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>) of unlocked gate <b>30</b> causes spring link <b>70</b> to compress spring <b>60</b>, moving end <b>72</b> deeper into hole <b>62</b>. When gate <b>30</b> is completely open, end <b>72</b> is very close to or touching hole bottom <b>64</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>. Consequently, when gate <b>30</b> is at least partially open, there will not be enough clearance between end <b>72</b> and bottom <b>64</b> to allow lever <b>42</b> to also be moved completely to the locked position because the additional movement of end <b>72</b> due to locking movement of lever <b>42</b> is blocked by hole bottom <b>64</b>. This is a safety feature that prevents the carabiner from being inadvertently locked with the gate open.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-7</figref> picture gate <b>30</b> as slightly bent at mid-length, however as seen as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the inventive locking mechanism can be incorporated in carabiners having a solid straight gate. Furthermore, the keyed interlocking arrangement of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-7</figref> can be replaced as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> with a pin and slot arrangement that interlocks the gate to the carabiner body when the gate is closed. The pin and slot arrangement of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> serves the same locking and unlocking function as the key-shaped arrangement of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the opening end of gate <b>30</b> includes pin <b>37</b> which transverses slot <b>34</b>. When gate <b>30</b> is closed, pin <b>37</b> rests against the top of notch <b>27</b> in body <b>20</b>, thereby limiting the closing movement of gate <b>30</b>. The undercut of notch <b>27</b> also serves to capture pin <b>37</b> when high tensile loads deform body <b>20</b>, or when the inventive carabiner gate is moved by the eccentric to the locked position. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> pictures the carabiner unlocked. In the locked position pin <b>37</b> will be pulled firmly into the undercut of notch <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">It is conceivable to change the location of control arm <b>42</b> with respect to the eccentric surfaces so that the inventive carabiner is locked when the control lever is adjacent body <b>20</b> as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. This reversed alternate configuration will function to lock and unlock the same as described for the preferred configuration. However, having control arm <b>42</b> adjacent the top of the locked gate as shown in the preferred configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-7</figref> is a safety feature because any outside forces working to inadvertently open the gate will additionally firmly hold control arm <b>42</b> in the locked position.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The instant invention can be applied to wire gate carabiners as well. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a isometric wireframe drawing of an inventive locking wire gate carabiner. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an exploded isometric wireframe drawing showing the components of the inventive carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>. The inventive wire gate carabiner comprises body <b>120</b>, wire gate <b>130</b>, control lever <b>140</b> and eccentric <b>150</b>. Body <b>120</b> is typically fabricated from a lightweight, high strength material, for example heat treated aluminum alloy type 7075. Wire gate <b>130</b> is typically fabricated from spring wire, for example stainless type 302. Eccentric <b>150</b> is typically fabricated from a copper alloy, or other material of sufficient rigidity. Control lever <b>140</b> is typically fabricated from stainless spring wire.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Wire gate <b>130</b> is a loop of wire having nearly parallel unequal length legs <b>135</b> and <b>137</b> joined by looped end <b>132</b>. Legs <b>135</b> and <b>137</b> have their staggered ends bent inward to form pivots <b>136</b> and <b>138</b> respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">One side of body <b>120</b> has hook-shaped notch <b>122</b> with overhanging lip <b>124</b>. The other side of body <b>120</b> has a keyhole-shaped opening formed by hole <b>128</b> and channel <b>126</b>. The width of channel <b>126</b> is slightly greater than the diameter of pivot <b>136</b> so that pivot <b>136</b> can easily slide along and rotate within the confines of channel <b>126</b>. Channel <b>126</b> is needed because a wire gate has two separated pivots and only one of the pivots is controlled by the eccentric, the other pivot is guided by the channel to move in unison with the eccentric controlled pivot.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Control lever <b>140</b> is a short loop of wire having approximately equal length parallel legs with ends bent inward to form staggered parallel ends <b>144</b> and <b>146</b> opposite joining side <b>142</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Eccentric <b>150</b> is slightly smaller in diameter than hole <b>128</b> so that it can easily rotate within hole <b>128</b>. Three holes <b>154</b>, <b>156</b> and <b>158</b> are each drilled through the length of eccentric <b>150</b>, parallel to its central axis. The diameter of hole <b>158</b> is slightly greater than the diameter of pivot <b>138</b> so that pivot <b>138</b> can easily rotate within hole <b>158</b>. Movement of hole <b>158</b>, which is offset relative to the central axis of eccentric <b>150</b>, provides reciprocating motion when eccentric <b>150</b> is rotated. The diameters of holes <b>154</b> and <b>156</b> are sized to provide a tight fit for mounting wire ends <b>144</b> and <b>146</b>, respectively, of control lever <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is an enlarged isometric wireframe drawing showing the assembly of control lever <b>140</b> and eccentric <b>150</b>. Because staggered wire ends <b>144</b> and <b>146</b> are firmly fixed in parallel holes <b>154</b> and <b>156</b> respectively, movement of lever <b>140</b> causes a corresponding rotational movement of eccentric <b>150</b> in hole <b>128</b>. The size and shape of control lever <b>140</b> is chosen for compactness and convenience of motion. Although control arm <b>140</b> is depicted as a simple U-shape formed wire, it can also be other shapes or constructions, for example a curved arm. Although a two piece assembly is shown, the same function can be achieved with a single part fabricated by machining, molding, forging, stamping and joining sheet-metal or wire, or-the-like. Similarly, the same locking function can be achieved with an assembly of more than two parts.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The assembly of lever <b>140</b> with eccentric <b>50</b>, or its equivalent, is the locking mechanism of the inventive carabiner. Incorporating this locking mechanism on a wire gate carabiner adds insignificant weight and bulk to the carabiner. Similarly, Incorporating this locking mechanism on a rigid gate carabiner adds insignificant weight and bulk to the carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">When the inventive carabiner is assembled, wire gate pivot <b>138</b> is located in hole <b>158</b> of eccentric <b>150</b>. Wire gate pivot <b>136</b> is located in channel <b>126</b> adjacent hole <b>128</b> of body <b>120</b>. The ends of pivots <b>136</b> and <b>138</b> are peened to secure them in place. Rotational movement of eccentric <b>150</b> causes back and forth movement of wire gate <b>130</b>. Concurrently, pivot <b>136</b> slides back and forth in channel <b>126</b>. Also concurrently, wire gate end <b>132</b> reciprocates within notch <b>122</b> toward or away from lip <b>124</b>. When wire gate end <b>132</b> is pulled into the undercut of notch <b>122</b>, lip <b>124</b> blocks opening movement of the wire gate. When wire gate end <b>132</b> is moved away and clear of lip <b>124</b>, wire gate <b>130</b> is free to open.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The wire loop itself provides the closing force for wire gate <b>130</b>. The wire loop must be slightly twisted for pivots <b>136</b> and <b>138</b> to pass respectively through channel <b>126</b> of body <b>120</b> and hole <b>158</b> of eccentric <b>150</b>. Twisting the wire loop causes a cantilevered spring force that holds the gate normally closed. Opening the wire gate additionally twists the wire which increases the spring force working to close the gate.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The length of wire gate <b>130</b> is chosen so that when eccentric <b>150</b> is in the locked position, end <b>132</b> is pulled tight into the undercut of notch <b>122</b> and opening movement of wire gate <b>130</b> is blocked by protruding lip <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Advantageously, the length of wire gate <b>130</b> is slightly undersize so that when locked the engagement pulls against body <b>120</b>, causing tension in wire gate <b>130</b>. Furthermore, when locked, pivot hole <b>158</b> is rotated a small distance past over-center so that the wire gate tension serves to hold eccentric <b>150</b> in the locked position.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, to unlock wire gate <b>130</b>, movement of control lever <b>140</b> in the direction depicted by the outline arrow &#x201c;A&#x201d; correspondingly rotates eccentric <b>150</b> which causes forward movement of wire gate <b>130</b> in the direction depicted by outline arrow &#x201c;B&#x201d;. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> shows lever <b>140</b> and eccentric <b>150</b> rotated approximately 180-degrees (with respect to the orientation depicted by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>) to the unlocked position.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">To lock wire gate <b>130</b>, movement of control lever <b>140</b> in the direction depicted by the outline arrow &#x201c;C&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> correspondingly rotates eccentric <b>150</b> which causes backward movement of wire gate <b>130</b> in the direction depicted by outline arrow &#x201c;D&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> shows a comparison of eccentric <b>150</b> in the locked and unlocked positions and shows the movement of hole <b>158</b> as a consequence of approximately 180-degree rotation of eccentric <b>150</b>. Hole <b>158</b> is moved forward or backward the distance a-b depicted by the line with double arrows. The distance a-b must be sufficient to move wire gate end <b>132</b> into and out of engagement with lip <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Furthermore, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>, the length of channel <b>126</b> is chosen to accommodate the corresponding back and forth sliding movement a-b of pivot <b>136</b>. When unlocked, pivot <b>136</b> is located in channel <b>126</b> at <b>136</b><i>a. </i>When locked, pivot <b>136</b> is located at <b>136</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">When wire gate <b>130</b> is closed but not locked, the interlocking relationship with hooked notch <b>122</b> serves to solidly join wire gate end <b>132</b> and body <b>120</b> when high tensile loads deform body <b>120</b>, thereby enabling closed wire gate <b>130</b> to carry part of the load transmitted through body <b>120</b>. Consequently, when the gate is closed the carabiner has the same strength whether locked or unlocked.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The inventive carabiner is locked or unlocked by moving control arm <b>140</b>. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, control arm <b>140</b> rests adjacent wire gate <b>130</b> when the inventive locking mechanism is locked. This is a safety feature because any outside force working to inadvertently push open the gate will also push and hold control arm <b>140</b> in the locked position. Conversely, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, control arm <b>140</b> rests adjacent body <b>120</b> completely away from wire gate <b>130</b> when the inventive locking mechanism is unlocked, which enables wire gate <b>130</b> to be easily opened without interference.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Climbers are often in precarious positions in which only one hand is available to insert a rope into a carabiner (typically the other hand is occupied holding on to another climbing aid or the rock surface). Under such circumstances it is imperative that the carabiner be easily manipulated with one hand. Because the inventive locking carabiner has a control arm that can be easily locked with one finger; a climber can open and close gate <b>30</b> (or gate <b>130</b>) as need, and when appropriate, lock the carabiner, all with the use of one hand. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> illustrates one of the many ways the inventive carabiner can be held and locked with one hand.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is a partial cross section of a typical prior art locking carabiner. Sleeve <b>80</b> is threaded nut-like to gate <b>30</b> and can be screwed along the length of gate <b>30</b> either toward or away from leg end <b>28</b> of body <b>20</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> pictures sleeve <b>80</b> in the locked position against nose <b>90</b> of leg end <b>28</b>, thereby immobilizing gate <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The prior art configuration illustrated by <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is considered by climbers to be the &#x201c;gold standard&#x201d; of locked security and is the preferred configuration for attaching climbing rope, rappelling and belay equipment and-the-like to the climber's body harness. However the locking carabiner of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is not suitable for quickdraw use due to its weight and bulk and the possibility that the gate may be locked or will lock when a climber is trying to clip a rope. Furthermore, the locking sleeve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> will not work on a bent gate carabiner or a wire gate carabiner.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Other variations on the shape and/or relative locations of the carabiner body, gate, or eccentric mechanism are contemplated. For example, gate slot <b>32</b> can be widened to accommodate the placement of control arm <b>42</b> within slot <b>32</b> of gate <b>30</b> instead of outside.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">It is understood that those skilled in the art may conceive of other modifications and/or changes to the invention described above. Any such modifications or changes that fall within the purview of the description are intended to be included therein as well. This description is intended to be illustrative and is not intended to be limitative. The scope of the invention is limited only by the scope of the claims appended hereto.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What I claim is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A locking carabiner, comprising:
<claim-text>a carabiner body comprising:
<claim-text>a first body leg end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second body leg end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a gap separates the first body leg end and the second body leg end;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate comprising:
<claim-text>an opening end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hinged end;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a locking mechanism comprising:
<claim-text>an eccentric having an offset hole, where the eccentric is configured to rotate with respect to a hole in the second body leg end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control arm connected to the eccentric and configured to control rotation of the eccentric between an unlocked position and a locked position;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the hinged end of the gate is pinned through the offset hole in the eccentric to pivotally attach the hinged end of the gate to the second body leg end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the gate spans the gap separating the first and second body leg ends of the carabiner body and is configured to pivot away from the first body leg end when the eccentric is in the unlocked position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein rotation of the eccentric from the unlocked position to the locked position pulls the gate toward the second body leg end so that the opening end of the gate forms an interlocking relationship with the first body leg end in which the gate cannot pivot away from the first body leg end.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the eccentric is contained within the hole in the second body leg end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the gate is a wire gate constructed from a loop of wire having unequal length legs joined by a looped end, where the ends of the unequal length legs are bent;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the bent end of a first of the unequal length legs is pinned to the offset hole in the eccentric;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the bent end of a second of the unequal length legs of the wire gate is configured to slide within a channel in the second body leg end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first body leg end includes a hooked notch that forms an interlocking relationship with the looped end of the wire gate when the eccentric is in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the channel in the second body leg end connects to the hole in the second body leg end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the eccentric has second and third offset holes and the control arm is constructed from a loop of wire having legs joined by a looped end, where the ends of the control arm's legs are bent and pinned to the second and third offset holes in the eccentric.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control arm fits adjacent the gate when in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the control arm is sheet-metal folded around the exterior of the gate when in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the control arm is constructed from a loop of wire having legs joined by a looped end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The locking carabiner in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the eccentric is pivotally mounted to the second body leg end by a pin that passes through the offset hole in the eccentric and the hole in the second body leg end; the gate is a solid gate that further comprises a blind hole that contains a spring assembly that engages against the bottom of the blind hole; the second body leg end also comprises a notch; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the spring assembly engages the second body leg end notch which urges the solid gate to pivot toward the first body leg end.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, where the spring assembly comprises a spring and a spring link, the spring link having an end inside the blind hole configured to substantially make contact with the blind hole bottom when the gate is fully open thereby preventing the control arm from moving from the unlocked position to the locked position when the gate is at least partially open.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first body leg end includes a hooked notch that forms an interlocking relationship with a pin in the opening end of the solid gate when the eccentric is in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the opening end of the solid gate includes a hooked notch that forms an interlocking relationship with a pin in the first body leg end when the eccentric is in the locked position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the solid gate is a bent gate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The locking carabiner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the solid gate is a straight gate. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
