<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627031-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627031</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13167609</doc-number>
<date>20110623</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-150340</doc-number>
<date>20100630</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>209</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711163</main-classification>
<further-classification>711103</further-classification>
<further-classification>711154</further-classification>
<further-classification>711167</further-classification>
<further-classification>711168</further-classification>
<further-classification>711169</further-classification>
<further-classification>711E12001</further-classification>
<further-classification>711E12008</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Semiconductor memory device and method of reading data from and writing data into a plurality of storage units</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6563734</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Taki</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7490192</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sugimoto et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>711103</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0024088</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Taki</name>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0172345</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Allen et al.</name>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>711208</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-254292</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19951000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-281952</doc-number>
<date>19951000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-073407</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Notice of Reasons for Rejection for Japanese Patent No. 2010-150340 Mailed Oct. 25, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Information Sheet for preparing an Information Disclosure Statement, Toshiba (English Abstract for JP 3699890).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711103</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711154</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711163</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711167-169</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711E12001</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711E12008</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120005414</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120105</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moro</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hachioji</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moro</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hachioji</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Knobbe Martens Olson &#x26; Bear LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kabushiki Kaisha Toshiba</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Song</last-name>
<first-name>Jasmine</first-name>
<department>2188</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">According to one embodiment, a semiconductor memory device includes a command processing module, a plurality of storage units, a plurality of control modules, an adjustment circuit, and a setting register. The adjustment circuit is configured to exclude the control module connected to the storage unit of a second group from a write operation in accordance with identification data, and to cause the control module connected to the storage unit of the second group to perform a read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed by the control module connected to the storage unit of a first group.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="167.30mm" wi="243.33mm" file="US08627031-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="245.19mm" wi="166.20mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627031-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.32mm" wi="134.20mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627031-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="228.18mm" wi="179.83mm" file="US08627031-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="243.16mm" wi="136.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627031-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="241.05mm" wi="134.20mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627031-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based upon and claims the benefit of priority from Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-150340, filed Jun. 30, 2010; the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Embodiments described herein relate generally to a semiconductor memory device and a data read and write method.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Various types of semiconductor memory devices are generally used. One type is a solid-state drive (SSD). The SSD has a plurality of NAND flash memories. NAND flash memories are nonvolatile memories, each capable of storing a great amount of data at high density. They are memory devices expected to be used in place of the hard disk drive.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Data can indeed be read from each NAND flash memory provided in the SSD. In some cases, however, data must be written into all NAND flash memories. This is why data is read from the SSD during a period, and is written into the SSD during another period not overlapping the first-mentioned period.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Since data cannot be read and written from and into the SSD in any overlapping periods, more time is spent to write and read data than otherwise. A demand is therefore made for a technique that can write and read at high efficiency.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A general architecture that implements the various features of the embodiments will now be described with reference to the drawings. The drawings and the associated descriptions are provided to illustrate the embodiments and not to limit the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exemplary block diagram showing a solid state drive (SSD) according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of channels provided in the SSD;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of logic blocks provided in the SSD;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of the Null block provided in setting register group of the SSD;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an exemplary timing chart schematically explaining read operation and write operation at the SSD; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is another exemplary timing chart schematically explaining read operation and write operation at a comparative example of the SSD.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Various embodiments will be described hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings. In general, according to one embodiment, there is provided a semiconductor memory device comprising a command processing module configured to process data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request which are externally input, and to output processed data, a plurality of storage units, a plurality of control modules connected, in one-to-one relation, to the storage units and configured to perform a read operation and a write operation with reference to the storage units, an adjustment circuit connected between the command processing module and the control modules and configured to cause the control modules to perform the read operation and the write operation in accordance with the processed data obtained at the command processing module, and a setting register connected to the adjustment circuit and configured to hold identification data identifying whether each of the storage units belongs to a first group for which the write operation is permitted, or to a second group for which the write operation is prohibited. The adjustment circuit is configured to exclude the control module connected to the storage unit of the second group from the write operation in accordance with identification data, and to cause the control module connected to the storage unit of the second group to perform the read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed by the control module connected to the storage unit of the first group.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to another embodiment, there is provided a method of reading data from and writing data into a plurality of storage units, comprising processing data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request, and outputting processed data, and performing a read operation and a write operation with reference to the storage units in accordance with the processed data. The performing the read and write operations comprising identifying whether each of the storage units belongs to a first group for which a write operation is permitted or to a second group for which the write operation is prohibited, excluding the storage unit of the second group from the write operation in accordance with identification data, and causing the storage unit of the second group to perform the read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed for the storage unit of the first group.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">One embodiment will be described with reference to the drawings appended hereto. The embodiment discloses a semiconductor memory device and a data read and write method. More specifically, the semiconductor memory device according to this embodiment is a solid state drive (SSD), which is used as a semiconductor drive. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram showing the SSD.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the SSD <b>10</b> comprises a plurality of flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn and an SSD controller <b>11</b>. Flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn are NAND type memories used as storage units. In this embodiment, n is a natural number equal to or greater than 4. Flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn are nonvolatile memories produced by using semiconductor. Flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn are connected to the SSD controller <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The SSD controller <b>11</b> comprises a host interface <b>12</b>, a command processing module <b>13</b>, a microprocessor <b>14</b>, a setting register group <b>15</b> such as a setting register, and a control unit <b>16</b>. The host interface <b>12</b> is connected to a host system <b>18</b> of an outside. The control unit <b>16</b> is connected to flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The control unit <b>16</b> comprises control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn and an adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f</i>. Control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn are connected to flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn, in one-to-one relation. Control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn hold a program which is concerned with operation of read, write, delete, etc. Using this program, control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn control flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn, respectively. Thus, control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn can perform a read operation and a write operation to flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The command processing module <b>13</b> processes data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request input from the host system <b>18</b> (exterior) through the host interface <b>12</b>. The command processing module <b>13</b> outputs processed data.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>is connected between the command processing module <b>13</b> and control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn. The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>adjusts the time control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn control flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn, by using the above-mentioned program. Hence, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>can cause control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn to perform the read operation and the write operation, in accordance with the processed data obtained at the command processing module <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The host interface <b>12</b>, command processing module <b>13</b>, setting register group <b>15</b> and control unit <b>16</b> are connected to the system bus (not shown) of the microprocessor <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The setting register group <b>15</b> is connected to the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f</i>. The microprocessor <b>14</b> outputs values, which are set in the setting register group <b>15</b>. The setting register group <b>15</b> is configured to hold identification data, identifying whether each of flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn belongs to a first group for which the write operation is permitted, or to a second group for which the write operation is prohibited.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Therefore, the setting register group <b>15</b> may have a Null block <b>19</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The Null block <b>19</b> can inform the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>which control modules are connected to the flash memories that have Null blocks <b>19</b>. The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>is configured to uses the data of the Null block <b>19</b>, to exclude control module connected to flash memory having the Null block, from the write operation, and can cause control module connected to flash memory having the Null block, only to perform the read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>can exclude every control module connected to every flash memory of the second group from the write operation, in accordance with the data (i.e., data in the Null block <b>19</b>) stored in the setting register group <b>15</b>. The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>can cause control module connected to flash memory of the second group, to perform the read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed by control module connected to flash memory of the first group.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of channels. As seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the control modules and the flash memories are combined in one-to-one relation, constituting channels <b>0</b> to n. More precisely, channel <b>0</b> is a combination of control module CM<b>0</b> and flash memory FM<b>0</b>; channel <b>1</b> is the combination of control module CM<b>1</b> and flash memory FM<b>1</b>; channel <b>2</b> is the combination of control module CM<b>2</b> and flash memory FM<b>2</b>; channel <b>3</b> is the combination of control module CM<b>3</b> and flash memory FM<b>3</b>. Thus, channel n is the combination of control module CMn and flash memory FMn.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows exemplary block configurations BF<b>0</b> to BFn associated with flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn of channels <b>0</b> to n, respectively. The block of the block configurations BF<b>0</b> to BFn is data units, each of which can be deleted atone deleting action.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of logic blocks. As seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, each of logic blocks LB<b>0</b> to LBm is constituted by n+1 blocks selected from channels <b>0</b> to n, respectively. In this embodiment, m is a natural number equal to or greater than 4.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">More specifically, logic block <b>0</b>_LB<b>0</b>, is constituted by block <b>0</b> of channel <b>0</b>, block <b>3</b> of channel <b>1</b>, block <b>7</b> of channel <b>2</b>, block <b>1</b> of channel <b>3</b>, . . . , and block <b>3</b> of channel n. Logic block <b>1</b>_LB<b>1</b>, is constituted by block <b>2</b> of channel <b>0</b>, block <b>1</b> of channel <b>1</b>, block <b>4</b> of channel <b>2</b>, block <b>4</b> of channel <b>3</b>, . . . , and block <b>7</b> of channel n.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Logic block <b>2</b>_LB<b>2</b>, is constituted by block <b>6</b> of channel <b>0</b>, block <b>0</b> of channel <b>1</b>, block <b>1</b> of channel <b>2</b>, block <b>0</b> of channel <b>3</b>, . . . , and block <b>1</b> of channel n.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Similarly, logic block m_LBm, is constituted by block <b>7</b> of channel <b>0</b>, block <b>4</b> of channel <b>1</b>, block <b>0</b> of channel <b>2</b>, block <b>6</b> of channel <b>3</b>, . . . , and block <b>5</b> of channel n.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an exemplary diagram illustrating the concept of the Null block provided in setting register group <b>15</b>. The setting register group <b>15</b> has a logic block each, in which an identification data is set. The Null block <b>19</b> is a flag that indicates any one of logic blocks LB<b>0</b> to LBm that cannot be write because of its fatigue (that is, cannot be accessed to be write). Logic blocks <b>0</b> to m_LB<b>0</b> to LBm are those selected from channels <b>0</b> to n, respectively. Any logic block only needs to have information as to which channel has the Null block.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Therefore, logic blocks <b>0</b> to m_LB<b>0</b> to LBm only need to have as many flags as the channels. Assume that each flag is &#x201c;0&#x201d; indicating that the channel does not have the Null block, or &#x201c;1&#x201d; indicating that the channel has the Null block. Then, Null block information BI<b>0</b> of logic block <b>0</b>, Null block information BI<b>2</b> of logic block <b>2</b>, and Null block information BIm of logic block m indicate that all blocks constituting the logic block are all valid. In other words, these information items shows that control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn for all respective channels are not excluded from the write operation.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Null block information BI<b>1</b> of logic block <b>1</b> indicates that channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b> are invalid. In other words, this information BI<b>1</b> shows that control modules CM<b>1</b> and CM<b>3</b> for channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b>, respectively, are excluded from the write operation. Similarly, Null block information BI<b>3</b> of logic block <b>3</b> indicates that channel n is invalid. In other words, this information BI<b>3</b> shows that control module CMn for channel n is excluded from the write operation.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The SSD <b>10</b> is configured as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A method of reading data from and writing data into a plurality of the storage units by the SSD <b>10</b> will be explained. In this method, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>excludes control modules CM<b>1</b> and CM<b>3</b> connected to flash memories FM<b>1</b> and FM<b>3</b> belonging to the second group, from the write operation, in accordance with Null block information BI<b>1</b> of logic block <b>1</b>. Further, the command processing module <b>13</b> processes data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request in such a specific order as will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">(1) Data write request</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">(2) Data write request</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">(3) Data read request to channel <b>3</b></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">(4) Data write request</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">(5) Data read request to Channel <b>0</b></p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">(6) Data read request to Channel <b>0</b></p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">(7) Data read request to Channel <b>1</b></p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">(8) Data read request to Channel <b>3</b></p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">(9) Data read request to Channel <b>1</b></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The data read request (4) is received after the write operation starts in response to the data write request (3). The data read request (6) is received after the write operation starts in response to the data write request (5).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an exemplary timing chart schematically explaining read operation and write operation at the SSD <b>10</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, read operation and write operation are allocate on the time axis. Of &#x201c;Write A B&#x201d; shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, &#x201c;A&#x201d; is the number of the channel in which data should be written, and &#x201c;B&#x201d; is the number of times data has been written in the channel. Of &#x201c;Read C D&#x201d; shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, &#x201c;C&#x201d; is the number of the channel in which data should be read, and &#x201c;D&#x201d; is the number of times data has been read in the channel.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, first, Write <b>0</b> <b>0</b>, Write <b>2</b> <b>0</b> and Write n <b>0</b> are performed in response to the data write request (1). At this point, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>detects that channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b> are invalidated, from the information about the Null block <b>19</b> (i.e., Null block information BI<b>1</b>). The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>therefore determines that channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b> may be allocated to read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Then, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>excludes channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b> from object for the writing, and allows the read operation to control modules CM<b>1</b> and CM<b>3</b>. Thus, the read operation can be performed in channels <b>1</b> and <b>3</b> even while the data write request (1) is being executed. That is, the response to the data read request (2) is paralleled with the response to the data write request (1) in parallel. Thus, Read <b>1</b> <b>0</b> can be completed while Write <b>0</b> <b>0</b>, Write <b>2</b> <b>0</b> and Write n <b>0</b> are being performed. The write operation which complied with the data write request (3) is performed in three channels (i.e., Write <b>0</b> <b>1</b>, Write <b>2</b> <b>1</b> and Write n <b>1</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Read <b>3</b> <b>0</b>, i.e., process performed in response to the data read request (4) issued after the write operation has started in response to the data write request (3), is performed in channel <b>3</b> excluded from the write operation. Therefore, Read can be completed while Write <b>0</b> <b>1</b>, Write <b>2</b> <b>1</b> and Write n <b>1</b> are being performed.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Next, Write <b>0</b> <b>2</b>, Write <b>2</b> <b>2</b> and Write n <b>2</b> are performed in response to the data write request (5). While these write processes are being performed, Read <b>1</b> <b>1</b>, i.e., process performed in response to the data read request (8), and Read <b>3</b> <b>1</b>, i.e., process performed in response to the data read request (9) can be performed in parallel. The other processes are performed in response to the data read requests (6), (7) and (10), when any channels are available for read operation.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">A method of reading data from and writing data into a plurality of the storage units at a comparative example of the SSD <b>10</b> will be explained. In the comparative method, too, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>excludes control modules CM<b>1</b> and CM<b>3</b> connected to flash memories FM<b>1</b> and FM<b>3</b> belonging to the second group, from the write operation, in accordance with Null block information BI<b>1</b> of logic block <b>1</b>. However, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>does not cause control modules CM<b>1</b> and CM<b>3</b> to perform the read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed by control modules CM<b>0</b>, CM<b>2</b> and CMn.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is another exemplary timing chart schematically explaining read operation and write operation at a comparative example of the SSD <b>10</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, read operation and write operation are allocate on the time axis. As seen from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, data is read during a period, and is written during another period not overlapping the first-mentioned period. Consequently, data cannot be written and read as efficiently as in the comparative example of the SSD <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As described above, the SSD <b>10</b> has the command processing module <b>13</b>, flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn, control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn, adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>and setting register group <b>15</b>. In the method of reading data from and writing data into the SSD <b>10</b> so configured, the adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>excludes the control module connected to the flash memory of the second group, from the write operation, in accordance with the identification data of the setting register group <b>15</b>. The adjustment circuit <b>16</b><i>f </i>can cause the control module connected to the flash memory of the second group to perform the read operation in a period overlapping the write operation performed by the control module connected to the flash memory of the first group.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Thus, data can be read in a period overlapping the period other data is being written. This increases the efficiency of writing and reading data in the SSD <b>10</b>. The overall performance of the SSD <b>10</b> can therefore be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Hence, an SSD and a data writing/reading method can be provided, which excel in efficiency of writing and reading data.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">While certain embodiments have been described, these embodiments have been presented by way of example only, and are not intended to limit the scope of the inventions. Indeed, the novel embodiments described herein may be embodied in a variety of other forms; furthermore, various omissions, substitutions and changes in the form of the embodiments described herein may be made without departing from the spirit of the inventions. The accompanying claims and their equivalents are intended to cover such forms or modifications as would fall within the scope and spirit of the inventions.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">For example, the SSD <b>10</b> may not incorporate the host interface <b>12</b> and the microprocessor <b>14</b>. In such a case, host interface <b>12</b> and the microprocessor <b>14</b> are provided outside the SSD <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Further, flash memories FM<b>0</b> to FMn may be either integrated altogether or formed independent of one another. Similarly, control modules CM<b>0</b> to CMn may be either integrated altogether or formed independent of one another.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">If data is read while other data is being written, the period of reading data may overlap the period of writing data, only a little.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Moreover, the setting register group <b>15</b> may hold data other than the above-mentioned identification data. For example, the setting register group <b>15</b> may hold various blocks (various data items) other than the Null block <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The semiconductor memory device according to the invention is not limited to the SSD <b>10</b> described above. Various changes and modifications can be made to provide semiconductor memory devices of various types.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor memory device comprising:
<claim-text>a command processor configured to process data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request, and to output processed data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of storage units;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of controllers connected and corresponding to the plurality of storage units and configured to execute a read operation and a write operation with reference to the storage units;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment module connected between the command processor and the controllers and configured to cause the controllers to execute the read operation and the write operation in accordance with the processed data from the command processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a setting register connected to the adjustment module and configured to hold identification data identifying whether each storage unit belongs to a first group for which the write operation is permitted, or to a second group for which the write operation is prohibited,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, when the processed data in accordance with the data write request is outputted from the command processor, the adjustment module is configured to exclude the controller connected to the storage unit of the second group from the write operation in accordance with the identification data, and to cause the controller connected to the storage unit of the second group to execute the read operation in a period while the write operation is executed by the controller connected to the storage unit of the first group.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of storage units are flash memories.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the setting register comprises a logic block comprising the identification data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method of reading data from and writing data into a plurality of storage units, comprising:
<claim-text>processing data in accordance with a data read request and a data write request, and outputting processed data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>executing a read operation and a write operation with reference to the plurality of storage units in accordance with the processed data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the executing the read and write operations comprising:
<claim-text>identifying whether each storage unit belongs to a first group for which a write operation is permitted or to a second group for which the write operation is prohibited;</claim-text>
<claim-text>excluding the storage unit of the second group from the write operation in accordance with identification data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>causing the storage unit of the second group to execute the read operation in a period while the write operation is executed for the storage unit of the first group. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
