<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622679-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622679</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13350440</doc-number>
<date>20120113</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>138</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>37</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411437</main-classification>
<further-classification>248 741</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Speed fastener</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1106096</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hunt</name>
<date>19140800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2066541</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Schenk</name>
<date>19370100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411437</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2153474</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Naylor et al.</name>
<date>19390400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2736227</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Stroble</name>
<date>19560200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3038366</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hindman</name>
<date>19620600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411433</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3708145</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pestka</name>
<date>19730100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>248499</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4048897</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Price, Jr.</name>
<date>19770900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4125049</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Price, Jr.</name>
<date>19781100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4132146</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Uhlig</name>
<date>19790100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411433</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4521144</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ginter</name>
<date>19850600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>409218</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4802804</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hirohata</name>
<date>19890200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4978261</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wright, III</name>
<date>19901200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5118237</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wright</name>
<date>19920600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5324150</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fullerton</name>
<date>19940600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5800108</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cabahug</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5967008</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Daniels</name>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 82153</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6062791</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Simon</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411535</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6146076</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bodin</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>411433</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7431252</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Birli et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>26</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411432</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411433</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>411437</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>248 741</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>248 744</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>292305</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130181103</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130718</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jette</last-name>
<first-name>Roger</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Islip</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jette</last-name>
<first-name>Roger</first-name>
<address>
<city>West Islip</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Carter, DeLuca, Farrell &#x26; Schmidt, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Estremsky</last-name>
<first-name>Gary</first-name>
<department>3677</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A fastener includes a body defining a central aperture and an insertion opening in communication with the central aperture. The body includes a threaded inner surface defining at least a portion of the central aperture and extending approximately 180 degrees about the central aperture. The body further defines a transverse aperture extending radially inwardly from an outer peripheral surface of the body in general alignment with the transverse aperture and in communication with the central aperture. An engagement screw is selectively engagable within the transverse aperture of the body and is movable relative to the body between a retracted position, wherein the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture, and an extended position, wherein the engagement screw extends radially inwardly towards the threaded inner surface of the body for engaging a threaded rod within the central aperture of the body between the threaded inner surface and the engagement screw.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="142.49mm" wi="107.02mm" file="US08622679-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="266.45mm" wi="184.23mm" file="US08622679-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="266.70mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US08622679-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.37mm" wi="191.52mm" file="US08622679-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates generally to threaded rods and fasteners and, more particularly, to a threaded fastener configured for rapid engagement about a threaded rod at any position therealong.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Threaded rods and fasteners are commonly used to facilitate the suspension of signage, equipment, cable trays, and other items from a ceiling or other supporting structure. Typically, the item to be suspended is positioned such that the threaded rod extends through an engagement aperture of the item. The fastener is then threaded onto the rod from the free end of the rod and is moved into position adjacent the item to retain the item in a desired position relative to the rod. As can be appreciated, such a procedure is relatively quick in instances where the item is to be attached towards the free end of the rod. However, where the item is to be suspended further up on the rod, the user is required to thread the fastener onto the rod and rotate the fastener to move the fastener up the rod to the desired position. This is a slow and arduous process, particularly considering the cumulative effort required to suspend an item from multiple rods.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Various fasteners have been developed that obviate the need to engage and rotate the fastener relative to the rod to translate the fastener axially along the rod to the desired position. However, while many of these fasteners succeed in reducing the time and effort required to engage the fasteners about the rod at a desired position, it is often the case that this reduced time and effort comes at the price of reduced holding strength. As such, users needing to suspend heavier equipment or signage, cable trays supporting a plurality of cables therein, or other relatively heavy items, are relegated to the use of conventional fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It would therefore be desirable to provide a fastener that is configured for rapid engagement about a threaded rod at any axial position therealong and that provides a holding strength at least as great as the equivalent conventional fasteners.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In accordance with the present disclosure, a fastener for engagement about a threaded rod is provided. The fastener includes a body defining a central aperture therethrough and an insertion opening defined therethrough in communication with the central aperture. The body includes a threaded inner surface defining at least a portion of the central aperture. The threaded inner surface extends approximately 180 degrees about the central aperture. The body further defines a transverse aperture extending radially inwardly from an outer peripheral surface of the body in general alignment with the transverse aperture and in communication with the central aperture. An engagement screw is selectively engagable within the transverse aperture of the body and is movable relative to the body between a retracted position, wherein an inner end of the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture of the body, and an extended position, wherein the inner end of the engagement screw extends radially inwardly towards the threaded inner surface of the body for centrally engaging a threaded rod within the central aperture of the body between the threaded inner surface of the body and the engagement screw. In the extended position, the engagement screw and the threaded inner surface are disposed in general opposition relative to one another to engage a threaded rod therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one embodiment, the engagement screw is threadingly engaged within the transverse aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another embodiment, an outer end of the engagement screw includes a tool-receiving recess defined therein that is configured to receive an engagement tool to facilitate movement of the engagement screw between the retracted position and the extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In another embodiment, the insertion opening defines a longitudinal axis that is offset relative to a radial line segment defined through the body and extending centrally through the transverse aperture by an oblique angle. The oblique angle may be about 45 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In another embodiment, the insertion opening includes a mouth that extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface of the body into communication with the central aperture. The mouth is configured to facilitate insertion of a threaded rod therethrough and into the central aperture of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In still another embodiment, the insertion opening includes an offset aperture partially overlapping the central aperture and offset from a center of the body. The offset aperture is generally aligned between the center of the body and the transverse aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In yet another embodiment, the engagement screw, in the extended position, extends centrally through the offset aperture to centrally engage a rod within the central aperture between the threaded surface of the body and the engagement screw.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In still yet another embodiment, a groove is defined within and extends about the outer peripheral surface of the body. The groove may be configured to releasably engage a clip therein that is configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the body of the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A fastener provided in accordance with the present disclosure and configured for engagement about a rod includes a body defining an upper surface, a lower surface, and an outer peripheral surface. The body defines a central aperture that is centered about a center of the body and extends between the upper and lower surfaces thereof. The body also defines a mouth that extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface thereof into communication with the central aperture. The body further defines a transverse aperture that extends radially inwardly from the outer peripheral surface thereof. The transverse aperture is disposed in communication with the central aperture and the mouth. The mouth is configured to facilitate insertion of a rod therethrough and into the central aperture of the body. The mouth extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface of the body at an oblique angle, e.g., approximately 45 degrees, relative to a radial line segment defined through the body and extending centrally through the transverse aperture. An engagement screw is selectively engagable within the transverse aperture of the body and is movable relative to the body between a retracted position, wherein an inner end of the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture of the body, and an extended position, wherein the inner end of the engagement screw extends radially inwardly into the mouth of the body to centrally engage a rod within the central aperture between an inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture and the inner end of the engagement screw.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one embodiment, the engagement screw is threadingly engaged within the transverse aperture.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one embodiment, an outer end of the engagement screw includes a tool-receiving recess defined therein that is configured to receive an engagement tool to facilitate movement of the engagement screw between the retracted position and the extended position.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In another embodiment, the inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture extends approximately 180 about the central aperture and is generally aligned with the transverse aperture such that the inner surface of the body and the engagement screw engage the rod therebetween in general opposition to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In still another embodiment, the inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture is threaded to facilitate engagement with a threaded rod.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In yet another embodiment, an elbow is defined at the interface between the mouth and the central aperture of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In still yet another embodiment, a groove is defined within and extends about the outer peripheral surface of the body. The groove may be configured to releasably engage a clip therein that is configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the body of the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A fastener assembly provided in accordance with the present disclosure and configured for suspending an item from a rod includes a fastener and a clip. The fastener is configured for positioning about a rod and is releasably engagable with the rod for retaining the fastener in fixed position relative to the rod. The clip includes a fastener-engaging portion configured for engagement about the fastener, a rod-engaging portion configured for engagement about the rod, and an connecting portion interconnecting the fastener-engaging portion and the rod-engaging portion. The clip is configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In embodiments, the fastener is configured similarly to any of the above embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In one embodiment, the fastener-engaging portion of the clip includes first and second resilient arms configured to snap into engagement within a groove defined within the fastener.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In another embodiment, the clip is formed from a single piece of wire.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Various illustrative embodiments of the present disclosure are described herein with reference to the drawings wherein like reference numerals identify similar or identical elements:</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of one embodiment of a fastener assembly provided in accordance with the present disclosure and shown engaged about a threaded rod;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the fastener assembly and threaded rod of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, wherein the fastener assembly is in a disassembled condition;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a pair of cable trays supported by a plurality of threaded rods;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a greatly enlarged, perspective view of the area of detail indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a perspective view of a fastener of the fastener assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a top view of the fastener of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> is a side view of the fastener of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a top view of another embodiment of a fastener provided in accordance with the present disclosure and configured for engagement about a threaded rod.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, a fastener assembly provided in accordance with the present disclosure and configured for releasable engagement about a threaded rod <b>20</b> is shown generally identified by reference numeral <b>10</b>. Fastener assembly <b>10</b> includes a fastener <b>100</b>, a clip <b>200</b>, and an engagement screw <b>300</b>. An engagement tool <b>30</b> may also be provided to facilitate further engagement/disengagement of engagement screw <b>300</b> to engage/disengage fastener <b>100</b> about rod <b>20</b>, as will be described in greater detail below. Fastener assembly <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>, for example, may be configured to suspend one or more cable trays <b>40</b>, <b>50</b> from rods <b>20</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>, or may be used for engaging, e.g., suspending, any other suitable equipment, structure, or other item from a threaded rod <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5C</figref>, in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, fastener <b>100</b> defines a generally disc-shaped configuration having first and second generally circular, planar surfaces <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, respectively, and an annular outer peripheral surface <b>106</b>, although other configurations are also contemplated. A central aperture <b>110</b> is defined through the center &#x201c;C&#x201d; of fastener <b>100</b> such that central aperture <b>110</b> and fastener <b>100</b> define a common center &#x201c;C.&#x201d; Central aperture <b>110</b> extends between and is generally perpendicular to first and second surfaces <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, respectively, of fastener <b>100</b>. Further, the diameter of central aperture <b>110</b> generally approximates, or is slightly larger than the diameter of rod <b>20</b>, and inner surface <b>112</b> of fastener <b>100</b> defined by central aperture <b>110</b> is threaded, to facilitate engagement of fastener <b>100</b> to rod <b>20</b>, as will be described in greater detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Fastener <b>100</b> further includes a cut-out, or mouth <b>120</b> defined therein that extends inwardly from outer peripheral surface <b>106</b> of fastener <b>100</b> and into communication with central aperture <b>110</b> so as to define a passage <b>122</b> for lateral insertion of rod <b>20</b> through mouth <b>120</b> and into central aperture <b>110</b> of fastener <b>100</b>. Passage <b>122</b> defines a substantially uniform width along its length that is similar to or slightly larger than the diameter of central aperture <b>110</b>. Further, passage <b>122</b> extends inwardly from outer peripheral surface <b>106</b> of fastener <b>100</b> in a non-radial direction, e.g., the longitudinal axis &#x201c;X-X&#x201d; of passage <b>122</b> is offset by an angle &#x201c;&#x3b1;&#x201d; relative to a radial line segment extending from the center &#x201c;C&#x201d; of central aperture <b>110</b> and fastener <b>100</b> through transverse aperture <b>130</b>, thereby defining an elbow <b>124</b> that interconnects passage <b>122</b> and central aperture <b>110</b> to one another. Angle &#x201c;&#x3b1;&#x201d; may be about 45 degrees, although other angles are also contemplated. Due to this offset configuration, the about 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>112</b> of fastener <b>100</b> that defines central aperture <b>110</b> is positioned at an oblique angle &#x201c;&#x3b1;,&#x201d; e.g., 45 degrees offset, relative to the longitudinal axis &#x201c;X-X&#x201d; of passage <b>122</b>, the importance of which will become more apparent below.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Continuing with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5C</figref>, in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, fastener <b>100</b> further includes a transverse aperture <b>130</b> defined through outer peripheral surface <b>106</b> thereof that extends radially inwardly through fastener <b>100</b> towards center &#x201c;C&#x201d; thereof in general opposition to the 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>112</b> of fastener <b>100</b> that defines central aperture <b>110</b>. Transverse aperture <b>130</b> ultimately communicates with passage <b>122</b> and central aperture <b>110</b> and defines a threaded inner surface (not explicitly shown) configured to threadingly receive engagement screw <b>300</b> therein such that engagement screw <b>300</b> may be selectively further engaged/disengaged from transverse aperture <b>130</b> to engage/disengage fastener <b>100</b> about rod <b>20</b>. Due to the above-described configuration of fastener <b>100</b>, rod <b>20</b> is capable of being centrally engaged within central aperture <b>110</b> (and centrally disposed relative to fastener <b>100</b>) while being retained therein via opposing engagement features, e.g., the 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>112</b> of central aperture <b>110</b> engaging the threading of rod <b>20</b> on one side thereof and engagement screw <b>300</b> engaging rod <b>20</b> on the other side thereof, that substantially engage rod <b>20</b> about the entire outer periphery thereof. Further, with engagement screw <b>300</b> extending through passage <b>122</b> and to central aperture <b>110</b> when in the extended position to engage rod <b>20</b> therein, passage <b>122</b> is substantially blocked by engagement screw <b>300</b>. This configuration of fastener <b>100</b> provides increased holding strength to the engagement between fastener <b>100</b> and rod <b>20</b> and inhibits rod <b>20</b> from backing out of passage <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Screw <b>300</b>, as mentioned above, is configured for threaded engagement within transverse aperture <b>130</b> of fastener <b>100</b>. More specifically, screw <b>300</b> includes a threaded exterior surface (not explicitly shown) that is configured complementarily to the threaded interior surface (not explicitly shown) defining transverse aperture <b>130</b> of fastener <b>100</b> such that screw <b>300</b> may be selectively retained in any suitable position relative to transverse aperture <b>130</b>, e.g., between a retracted position, wherein screw <b>300</b> does not protrude inwardly from transverse aperture <b>130</b> into passage <b>122</b>, and an extended position, wherein screw <b>300</b> protrudes radially inwardly from transverse aperture <b>130</b>, through passage <b>122</b>, and to or into central aperture <b>110</b> of fastener <b>100</b> to engage rod <b>20</b> within central aperture <b>110</b> of fastener <b>100</b>. As such, inner end <b>310</b> of screw <b>300</b> may define any suitable configuration to facilitate engagement with the threaded exterior surface of rod <b>20</b>. Outer end <b>320</b> of screw <b>300</b>, on the other hand, may define a tool-engagement recess <b>322</b>, e.g., a hexagonal-shaped recess, configured to complementarily receive a hexagonal-shaped engagement tool <b>30</b> for selectively advancing or retracting engagement screw <b>300</b> through transverse aperture <b>130</b> and relative to fastener <b>100</b>. Other suitable complementary engagement features for releasably engaging a complementary engagement tool with engagement screw <b>300</b> are also contemplated.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, fastener <b>100</b> further includes an annular groove <b>140</b> defined within outer peripheral surface <b>106</b> thereof. Annular groove <b>140</b> defines a generally circular cross-sectional configuration and is configured to receive clip <b>200</b> therein to releasably engage clip <b>200</b> about fastener <b>100</b>, although annular groove <b>140</b> may define any other suitable configuration for engaging a clip or other coupling component to fastener <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Clip <b>200</b> is formed from a single wire of material (although other configurations are contemplated) and generally includes a fastener-engaging portion <b>210</b>, a rod-engaging portion <b>220</b>, and a connecting portion <b>230</b> that interconnects fastener-engaging portion <b>210</b> and rod-engaging portion <b>220</b>. Fastener-engaging portion <b>210</b> includes first and second resilient arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b>, respectively, that are curved to define a generally-circular opening therebetween for receipt of fastener <b>100</b>. Arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> define cross-sectional configurations that are complementary to the cross-sectional configuration of annular groove <b>140</b> of fastener <b>100</b>, e.g., both define circular cross-sectional configurations, and the generally-circular opening defined by arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> is dimensioned so as to permit arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> to substantially surround fastener <b>100</b> and to resiliently snap into engagement within annular groove <b>140</b>, to thereby engage clip <b>20</b> about fastener <b>100</b>. Arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> may further include fingers <b>213</b>, <b>215</b>, respectively, extending from the free ends thereof to facilitate flexion of arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> to engage/disengage clip <b>200</b> to/from fastener <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, and in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>, connecting portion <b>230</b> of clip <b>200</b> includes a first pair of spaced-apart rails <b>232</b>, <b>236</b> extending from arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b>, respectively, a second pair of spaced-apart rails <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> disposed above and vertically-spaced from first rails <b>232</b>, <b>236</b>, respectively, and a pair of generally U-shaped portion <b>235</b>, <b>239</b> that interconnect respect rails <b>232</b>, <b>234</b> and <b>236</b>, <b>238</b>. Connecting portion <b>230</b> of clip <b>200</b>, as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and as will be described in greater detail below, is configured to transversely receive spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> (or suitable structure of any component to be suspended from rod <b>20</b> via fastener <b>100</b> and clip <b>200</b>) between the pairs of rails <b>232</b>, <b>236</b> and <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Rod-engaging portion <b>220</b> of clip <b>200</b> includes a U-shaped connector <b>222</b> that interconnects the ends of rails <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> to one another and is vertically aligned with the generally-circular opening defined by arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> such that rod <b>20</b>, when engaged within fastener <b>100</b>, extends between rails <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> of rod-engaging portion <b>220</b> of clip <b>200</b> adjacent U-shaped connector <b>220</b> thereof. As can be appreciated, the above-described configuration of clip <b>200</b> inhibits substantial movement of cable tray <b>40</b> relative to rod <b>20</b> and fastener <b>100</b> without requiring rod <b>20</b> to be engaged to cable tray <b>40</b> on both the upper and lower sides thereof, e.g., without requiring a pair of fasteners <b>100</b> (although in some embodiments, above and below fasteners <b>100</b> may be provided, where necessary). More specifically, with fastener <b>100</b> engaged about rod <b>20</b> and clip <b>200</b> engaged about both fastener <b>100</b> and rod <b>20</b>, support spines <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> are retained in substantially fixed vertical position relative to rod <b>20</b> between fastener <b>100</b> and rod-engaging portion <b>220</b> of clip <b>200</b>, and in substantially fixed lateral position between U-shaped portions <b>235</b>, <b>239</b> of connecting portion <b>230</b> of clip <b>200</b> and fastener <b>100</b> and between rails <b>232</b>, <b>236</b> and <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> of clip <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, another embodiment of a fastener provided in accordance with the present disclosure is shown generally identified by reference numeral <b>1000</b>. Fastener <b>1000</b> is similar to fastener <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5C</figref>) and may include any of the features thereof. Accordingly, only the differences between fastener <b>1000</b> and fastener <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5C</figref>) will be described in detail below, while similarities will be only summarily described or omitted entirely for purposes of brevity.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Fastener <b>1000</b> includes a central aperture <b>1100</b> defined through the center &#x201c;CC&#x201d; of fastener <b>1000</b> such that central aperture <b>1100</b> and fastener <b>1000</b> define a common center &#x201c;CC.&#x201d; Inner surface <b>1120</b> of fastener <b>1000</b> defined by central aperture <b>1100</b> is threaded to facilitate engagement of fastener <b>1000</b> to a threaded rod, e.g., rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>). Fastener <b>1000</b> further includes an offset aperture <b>1200</b> that partially overlaps central aperture <b>1100</b> such that offset aperture <b>1200</b> and central aperture <b>1100</b> are in communication with one another. More specifically, central aperture <b>1100</b> and offset aperture <b>1200</b> are overlapped such that the remaining about 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>1120</b> of fastener <b>1000</b> faces in the general direction of offset aperture <b>1100</b>. Inner surface <b>1210</b> of fastener <b>1000</b> that defines offset aperture <b>1200</b> defines a generally-smooth configuration, e.g., is non-threaded, and defines a diameter sufficiently greater than rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) such that fastener <b>1000</b> may be freely translated along rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) to a desired position when rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) is disposed within offset aperture <b>1200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Fastener <b>1000</b> further includes a transverse aperture <b>1300</b> defined through outer peripheral surface <b>1060</b> thereof that extends radially inwardly through fastener <b>1000</b> towards center &#x201c;CC&#x2032;&#x201d; thereof in general alignment with offset aperture <b>1300</b> and in general opposition to the 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>1120</b> of fastener <b>1000</b> that defines central aperture <b>1100</b>. Transverse aperture <b>1300</b> is configured to threadingly receive an engagement screw <b>3000</b> therein such that engagement screw <b>3000</b> may be selectively further engaged/disengaged from transverse aperture <b>1300</b> to centrally engage rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) within central aperture <b>1100</b> while being retained therein via opposing engagement features, e.g., the 180 degrees of threaded inner surface <b>1120</b> of central aperture <b>1100</b> engaging the threading of rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) on one side thereof and engagement screw <b>3000</b> engaging rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) on the other side thereof, that substantially engage rod <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>) about the entire outer periphery thereof. Fastener <b>1000</b> is otherwise similar to and may include any of the features of fastener <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5C</figref>), described above.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, the installation and use of fastener assembly <b>10</b> for suspending cable tray <b>40</b> from rod <b>20</b> is described, although fastener assembly <b>10</b> may similarly be used for suspending/engaging any suitable item from/to rod <b>20</b>. Obviously, different considerations apply depending on the particular item to be suspended from or engaged to rod <b>20</b>; however, the general installation and use of fastener assembly <b>10</b> remains generally consistent regardless of the particular item used.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Initially, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, fastener <b>100</b> is disengaged from rod <b>20</b> and clip <b>200</b> is disengaged from both fastener <b>100</b> and rod <b>20</b>. Further, engagement screw <b>300</b> is initially disposed in the retracted position, wherein engagement screw <b>300</b> does not protrude inwardly into passage <b>122</b>. In order to suspend cable tray <b>40</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>) from rod <b>20</b>, rod <b>20</b> is first positioned between first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>) and is advanced or translated along rod <b>20</b> to a desired position, e.g., the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring additionally to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>, with cable tray <b>40</b> disposed in the desired position, fastener <b>100</b> is inserted about rod <b>20</b> beneath first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b>. More specifically, rod <b>20</b> is inserted through mouth <b>120</b> and passage <b>122</b> of fastener <b>100</b> and into central aperture <b>110</b> thereof. Once rod <b>20</b> is positioned within central aperture <b>110</b> of fastener <b>100</b>, engagement tool <b>30</b> may be engaged with engagement screw <b>300</b> and manipulated, e.g., rotated, to advance engagement screw <b>300</b> radially inwardly through transverse aperture <b>130</b> from the retracted position to the extended position. Engagement screw <b>300</b> is advanced radially inwardly through passage <b>122</b> and to or into central aperture <b>110</b> sufficiently so as to urge rod <b>20</b> into engagement with threaded inner surface <b>112</b> defining central aperture <b>110</b>. In this engaged position, rod <b>20</b> is retained in engagement within threaded inner surface <b>112</b> via engagement screw <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, with fastener <b>100</b> engaged about rod <b>20</b> beneath first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b>, cable tray <b>40</b> is suspended from rod <b>20</b>. More specifically, with rod <b>20</b> extending between first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b>, and with fastener <b>100</b> engaged about rod <b>20</b> beneath spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b>, cable tray <b>40</b> is inhibited from translating downwardly along rod <b>20</b> since fastener <b>100</b> defines a diameter greater than the opening defined between first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b>. That is, spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> are seated atop fastener <b>100</b>, thereby maintaining cable tray <b>40</b> in the desired position relative to rod <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">With cable tray <b>40</b> suspended from rod <b>20</b>, as described above, clip <b>200</b> is positioned about rod <b>20</b> and relative to first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> such that rod <b>20</b> is positioned adjacent U-shaped connector <b>222</b> of clip <b>200</b> between rails <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> of clip <b>200</b> and such that first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> are positioned between the pairs of rails <b>232</b>, <b>236</b> and <b>234</b>, <b>238</b> adjacent U-shaped portions <b>235</b>, <b>239</b> thereof. Subsequently or prior to positioning of clip <b>200</b> as described above, arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> of clip <b>200</b> are resiliently flexed outwardly to pass about the outer peripheral surface <b>106</b> of fastener <b>100</b> and into engagement within annular groove <b>140</b> of fastener <b>100</b> to engage clip <b>200</b> to fastener <b>100</b>. With clip <b>200</b> engaged about fastener <b>100</b>, rod <b>20</b>, and cable tray <b>40</b>, cable tray <b>40</b> is inhibited from substantial movement, e.g., in the instance of vibrations or other movement of rod <b>20</b>. That is, while fastener <b>100</b> inhibits cable tray <b>40</b> from moving downwardly relative to rod <b>20</b>, cable tray <b>40</b> is still permitted to move upwardly along rod <b>20</b>. Although gravity and the weight of cable tray <b>40</b> is typically sufficient to retain spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> in vertical position abutting fastener <b>100</b>, e.g., inhibiting upward movement of cable tray along rod <b>20</b>, vibrations, movement, or other external forces acting on rod <b>20</b> or cable tray <b>40</b> may urge cable tray <b>40</b> to move in this manner. However, clip <b>200</b>, due to its engagement about fastener <b>100</b> beneath spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> and about rod <b>20</b> above spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b>, inhibits substantial upward movement of cable tray <b>40</b> relative to rod <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In order to disengage cable tray <b>100</b> from rod <b>20</b>, clip <b>200</b> is removed via flexing arms <b>212</b>, <b>214</b> outwardly to disengage clip <b>200</b> from fastener <b>100</b> and is then manipulated relative to first and second spine supports <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of cable tray <b>40</b> and rod <b>20</b> to disengage clip <b>20</b> therefrom. Next, engagement tool <b>30</b> is engaged within engagement recess <b>322</b> of engagement screw <b>300</b> and is manipulated, e.g., rotated, to move engagement screw <b>300</b> radially outwardly relative to fastener <b>100</b> from the extended position back to the retracted position, thereby disengaging fastener <b>100</b> from rod <b>20</b> and allowing fastener <b>100</b> to be removed from rod <b>20</b> via passage <b>122</b> of mouth <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">From the foregoing and with reference to the various figure drawings, those skilled in the art will appreciate that certain modifications can also be made to the present disclosure without departing from the scope of the same. While several embodiments of the disclosure have been shown in the drawings, it is not intended that the disclosure be limited thereto, as it is intended that the disclosure be as broad in scope as the art will allow and that the specification be read likewise. Therefore, the above description should not be construed as limiting, but merely as exemplifications of particular embodiments. Those skilled in the art will envision other modifications within the scope and spirit of the claims appended hereto.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fastener for engagement about a threaded rod, the fastener comprising:
<claim-text>a body defining a central aperture centrally therethrough and an insertion opening defined therethrough in communication with the central aperture, the body including a threaded inner surface defining at least a portion of the central aperture, the threaded inner surface extending approximately 180 degrees about the central aperture, the body further defining a transverse aperture extending radially inwardly from an outer peripheral surface of the body in general alignment with the transverse aperture and in communication with the central aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an engagement screw selectively engagable within the transverse aperture of the body and movable relative to the body between a retracted position, wherein an inner end of the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture of the body, and an extended position, wherein the inner end of the engagement screw extends radially inwardly towards the threaded inner surface of the body for centrally engaging a threaded rod within the central aperture of the body between the threaded inner surface of the body and the engagement screw, wherein, in the extended position, the engagement screw and the threaded surface are disposed in general opposition relative to one another to engage a threaded rod therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the engagement screw is threadingly engaged within the transverse aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an outer end of the engagement screw includes a tool-receiving recess defined therein that is configured to receive an engagement tool to facilitate movement of the engagement screw between the retracted position and the extended position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion opening defines a longitudinal axis that is offset relative to a radial line segment defined through the body and extending centrally through the transverse aperture by an oblique angle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the oblique angle is approximately 45 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion opening includes a mouth that extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface of the body into communication with the central aperture, the mouth configured to facilitate insertion of a threaded rod therethrough and into the central aperture of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the insertion opening includes an offset aperture partially overlapping the central aperture and offset from a center of the body, the offset aperture generally aligned between the center of the body and the transverse aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein, in the extended position, the engagement screw extends centrally through the offset aperture to centrally engage a rod within the central aperture between the threaded surface of the body and the engagement screw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a groove defined within and extending about the outer peripheral surface of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the groove is configured to releasably engage a clip therein, the clip configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the body of the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener further includes a groove defined within and extending about the outer peripheral surface thereof, the groove configured to releasably engage the fastener-engaging portion of the clip therein.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener-engaging portion of the clip includes first and second resilient arms configured to snap into engagement within the groove of the fastener.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A fastener for engagement about a rod, the fastener comprising:
<claim-text>a body defining an upper surface, a lower surface, and an outer peripheral surface, the body defining a central aperture that is centered about a center of the body and extends between the upper and lower surfaces thereof, the body defining a mouth that extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface thereof into communication with the central aperture, the body defining a transverse aperture that extends radially inwardly from the outer peripheral surface thereof, the transverse aperture disposed in communication with the central aperture and the mouth, wherein the mouth is configured to facilitate insertion of a rod therethrough and into the central aperture of the body, the mouth extending inwardly from the outer peripheral surface of the body at an oblique angle relative to a radial line segment defined through the body and extending centrally through the transverse aperture; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an engagement screw selectively engagable within the transverse aperture of the body and movable relative to the body between a retracted position, wherein an inner end of the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture of the body, and an extended position, wherein the inner end of the engagement screw extends radially inwardly into the mouth of the body to centrally engage a rod within the central aperture between an inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture and the inner end of the engagement screw.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the engagement screw is threadingly engaged within the transverse aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein an outer end of the engagement screw includes a tool-receiving recess defined therein that is configured to receive an engagement tool therein to facilitate movement of the engagement screw between the retracted position and the extended position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture extends approximately 180 about the central aperture and is generally aligned with the transverse aperture such that the inner surface of the body and the engagement screw engage the rod therebetween in general opposition to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the oblique angle is approximately 45 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture is threaded to facilitate engagement with a threaded rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein an elbow is defined at the interface between the mouth and the central aperture of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising a groove defined within and extending about the outer peripheral surface of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The fastener according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the groove is configured to releasably engage a clip therein, the clip configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the body of the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A fastener assembly for suspending an item from a rod, the fastener assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a fastener configured for positioning about a rod, the fastener releasably engagable with the rod for retaining the fastener in fixed position relative to the rod the faster defining a central aperture that is configured to receive the rod therein and a transverse aperture in communication with the central aperture, the faster further including an engagement screw selectively engagable within the transverse aperture and moveable relative to the fastener between a retracted position, wherein an inner end of the engagement screw is disposed within the transverse aperture of the fastener, and an extended position, wherein the inner end of the engagement screw extends radially inwardly towards the central aperture to centrally engage the rod within the central aperture between an inner surface of the body that defines the central aperture and the inner end of the engagement screw; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clip including a fastener-engaging portion configured for engagement about the fastener, a rod-engaging portion configured for engagement about the rod, and an connecting portion interconnecting the fastener-engaging portion and the rod-engaging portion, the clip configured for positioning about an item suspended from the rod via the fastener to substantially inhibit movement of the item relative to the rod.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener further defines a mouth that extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface thereof into communication with the central aperture, the mouth configured to facilitate insertion of the rod therethrough and into the central aperture of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the mouth extends inwardly from the outer peripheral surface of the body and defines a longitudinal axis that is offset relative to a radial line segment defined through the body and extending centrally through transverse aperture by an oblique angle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener further defines an offset aperture that partially overlaps the central aperture, the offset aperture configured to receive the rod therein and to permit free translation of the fastener along the rod when the rod is disposed within the offset aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The fastener assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein the clip is formed from a single piece of wire. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
