<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624629-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624629</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13528148</doc-number>
<date>20120620</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2011-0146281</doc-number>
<date>20111229</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327  3</main-classification>
<further-classification>327270</further-classification>
<further-classification>327271</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Phase difference quantization circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7978111</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Sun et al.</name>
<date>20110700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>341155</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8098085</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wang et al.</name>
<date>20120100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327  8</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0226189</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Choi</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>1020100049943</doc-number>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327  2</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327  3</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327269-271</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130169337</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130704</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shin</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Suk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shin</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Suk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>IP &#x26; T Group LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>SK hynix Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hernandez</last-name>
<first-name>William</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A delay value control circuit of a phase difference quantization circuit, wherein the phase difference quantization circuit has first to N<sup>th </sup>(N is an integer equal to or greater than 2) delay units with binary weights. The delay value control circuit includes a replica delay unit replicating an A<sup>th </sup>(2&#x2266;A&#x2266;N) delay unit; and a delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a first output signal generated from delaying an input signal with an A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit and a phase of a second output signal generated from delaying the input signal with the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and the replica delay unit and configured to control a delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit using a comparison result.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="155.45mm" wi="197.19mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="188.64mm" wi="96.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624629-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="122.60mm" wi="163.66mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="198.37mm" wi="170.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624629-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="184.57mm" wi="183.22mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="131.40mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="266.95mm" wi="159.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624629-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="183.90mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="225.38mm" wi="173.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624629-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="159.51mm" wi="174.92mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="213.87mm" wi="168.91mm" file="US08624629-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="224.71mm" wi="170.94mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624629-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2011-0146281, filed on Dec. 29, 2011, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention relate to a phase difference quantization circuit for quantizing a phase difference between two signals into digital codes, a delay value control circuit of the phase difference quantization circuit, and a delay circuit capable of calibrating a delay value.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A phase difference quantization circuit is a circuit which generates digital codes corresponding to a phase difference between two signals with different phases.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram showing a conventional phase difference quantization circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a phase difference quantization circuit which includes four phase comparison units <b>150</b>, <b>250</b>, <b>350</b> and <b>450</b> and three delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on a first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on a first second-node AD<b>2</b>, generate a first up/down signal Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; and transfer the generated first up/down signal Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; to the first delay unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The first delay unit <b>100</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> to a second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> to a second second-node BD<b>2</b>. At this time, the first delay unit <b>100</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> in response to the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;&#x221d;&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by a first delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The second phase comparison unit <b>250</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, generate a second up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; and transfer the generated second up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; to the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The second delay unit <b>200</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> to a third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to a third second-node CD<b>2</b>. At this time, the second delay unit <b>200</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by a second delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, generate a third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; and transfer the generated third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; to the third delay unit <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The third delay unit <b>300</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> to a fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to a fourth second-node DD<b>2</b>. At this time, the third delay unit <b>300</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by a third delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The fourth phase comparison unit <b>450</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> and generate a fourth up/down signal Q&#x3c;1&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a timing diagram showing operations of the conventional phase difference quantization circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. For illustration purposes, it is assumed that the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is 40 ps (picoseconds), the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is 20 ps, and the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is 10 ps. Furthermore, it is assumed that the phase of a first input signal IN<b>1</b> is earlier than the phase of a second input signal IN<b>2</b> by 65 ps. The first input signal IN<b>1</b> and the second input signal IN<b>2</b> with difference phases are inputted to the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> through the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b>, respectively. Since the phase of the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> (that is, the first input signal IN<b>1</b>) is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> (that is, the second input signal IN<b>2</b>), the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> outputs the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; of a high level to the first delay unit <b>100</b>. The first delay unit <b>100</b> is inputted with the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b>, delays the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> by 40 ps in response to the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; of the high level, transfers the delayed signal to the second first-node BD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> to the second second-node BD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The second phase comparison unit <b>250</b> compares the phases of the signals loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b>. Since the phase of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> is earlier by 25 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, the second phase comparison unit <b>250</b> outputs the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of a high level to the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The second delay unit <b>200</b> is inputted with the signals loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, delays the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> by 20 ps in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the high level, transfers the delayed signal to the third first-node CD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> compares the phases of the signals loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the third second-node CD<b>2</b>. Since the phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> is earlier by 5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, the third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> outputs the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of a high level to the third delay unit <b>300</b>. The third delay unit <b>300</b> is inputted with the signals loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by 10 ps in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level, transfers the delayed signal to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The fourth phase comparison unit <b>450</b> compares the phases of the signals loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b>. Since the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> is earlier by 5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, the fourth phase comparison unit <b>450</b> outputs the fourth up/down signal Q&#x3c;1&#x3e; of a low level.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As a consequence, binary codes that represent the phase difference between the first input signal IN<b>1</b> and the second input signal IN<b>2</b> are acquired as 1110 by combining the first to fourth up/down signals Q&#x3c;4:1&#x3e;. The fourth bit Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; indicates that the phase of which signal of the input signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b> is earlier. Since the fourth bit is 1, it is meant that the phase of the first input signal IN<b>1</b> is earlier than the phase of the second input signal IN<b>2</b>. The remaining three bits indicate an actual phase difference between the signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b>. That is to say, it can be seen that the phase difference between the signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b> is larger than 1*40 ps+1*20 ps and is smaller than 1*40 ps+1*20 ps+1*10 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The delay values of the delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b> constituting the phase difference quantization circuit generally have a constant ratio (2:1). In other words, the delay value 40 ps of the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the delay value 20 ps of the second delay unit <b>200</b> have the ratio of 2:1, and the delay value 20 ps of the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the delay value 10 ps of the third delay unit <b>300</b> have the ratio of 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">However, the delay values of the delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b> constituting the phase difference quantization circuit are likely to change due to a variation in PVT (process, voltage and temperature). If the delay values of the delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b> change, the delay value ratio between the delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b> may deviate. If the delay value ratio between the delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b> deviates, binary codes which precisely reflect the phase difference between two signals may not be generated.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">An embodiment of the present invention is directed to a delay value control circuit of a phase difference quantization circuit, which can perform a control task in such a manner that the delay value ratios of delay units constituting the phase difference quantization circuit can be kept constant.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Another embodiment of the present invention is directed to a phase difference quantization circuit which can generate digital codes indicating a phase difference between two signals and can keep the delay value ratios of delay units constant.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Another embodiment of the present invention is directed to a delay circuit for delaying a signal, in which delay value ratios of delay units constituting the delay circuit can be kept constant.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, a delay value control circuit of a phase difference quantization circuit, wherein the phase difference quantization circuit has first to N<sup>th </sup>(N is an integer equal to or greater than 2) delay units with binary weights, includes: a replica delay unit replicating an A<sup>th </sup>(2&#x2266;A&#x2266;N) delay unit; and a delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a first output signal generated from delaying an input signal with an A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit and a phase of a second output signal generated from delaying the input signal with the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and the replica delay unit and configured to control a delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit using a comparison result.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In accordance with another embodiment of the present invention, a phase difference quantization circuit includes: a path selection unit configured to transfer a first input signal to a first first-node and a second input signal to a first second-node in a normal mode and transfer the first input signal to the first first-node and the first second-node in a calibration mode; a first phase comparison unit configured to compare a phase of a signal loaded on the first first-node and a phase of a signal loaded on the first second-node and generate a first up/down signal; a first delay unit configured to is transfer the signal loaded on the first first-node to a second first-node and the signal loaded on the first second-node to a second second-node, wherein the first delay unit is further configured to select one of the signal loaded on the first first-node and the signal loaded on the first second-node in response to the first up/down signal, delay the selected signal by a first delay value and transfer the delayed signal; a second phase comparison unit configured to compare a phase of a signal loaded on the second first-node and a phase of a signal loaded on the second second-node and generate a second up/down signal; a second delay unit configured to transfer the signal loaded on the second first-node to a third first-node and the signal loaded on the second second-node to a third second-node, wherein the second delay unit is further configured to select one of the signal loaded on the second first-node and the signal loaded on the second second-node in response to the second up/down signal, delay the selected signal by a second delay value and transfer the delayed signal; a first replica delay unit replicating the second delay unit and configured to transfer a signal loaded on the third first-node to a third third-node and a signal loaded on the third second-node to a third fourth-node, wherein the first replica delay unit is further configured to select one of the signal loaded on the third first-node and the signal loaded on the third second-node in response to the second up/down signal, delay the selected signal by the second delay value and transfer the delayed signal; a first delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a signal loaded on the third third-node and a phase of a signal loaded on the third fourth-node and control the second delay value of the second delay unit using a comparison result; and a third phase comparison unit configured to compare a phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node and a phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node and generate a third up/down signal.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In accordance with yet another embodiment of the present invention, a delay circuit includes: a first delay unit configured to add a delay of K (K is an integer equal to or greater than 2) unit delays; a second delay unit configured to add a delay of one unit delay; K&#x2212;1 replica delay units replicating the second delay unit; a delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a first output signal generated from delaying an input signal with the first delay unit and a phase of a second output signal generated from delaying the input signal with the second delay unit and the K&#x2212;1 replica delay units and configured to control a delay value of the second delay unit using a comparison result.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram showing a conventional phase difference quantization circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a timing diagram showing operations of the conventional phase difference quantization circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing a phase difference quantization circuit and a delay value control circuit in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing an exemplary embodiment of the second delay unit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a timing diagram showing calibrating operations of the delay value control circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in a calibration mode.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram showing a phase difference quantization circuit in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a timing diagram showing a procedure in which the third delay value of the third delay unit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is calibrated in a calibration mode.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram showing an exemplary embodiment of an integrated circuit in which a delay circuit in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention is used.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram showing an exemplary embodiment of the first delay unit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a timing diagram showing calibrating operations of the delay circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> in a calibration mode.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a diagram showing another exemplary embodiment of an integrated circuit in which a delay circuit in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention is used.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention will be described below in more detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. The present invention may, however, be embodied in different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the present invention to those skilled in the art. Throughout the disclosure, like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the various figures and embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing a phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> and a delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> may include N (N is an integer equal to or greater than 2) number of delay units and N+1 number of phase comparison units. The N number of delay units have a certain delay value ratio (in detail, of 2:1). More specifically, the delay value of a first delay unit is two times the delay value of a second delay unit, the delay value of the second delay unit is two times the delay value of a third delay unit, . . . , and the delay value of an N&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit is two times the delay value of the N<sup>th </sup>delay unit. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates that the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> includes two delay units <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> and three phase comparison units <b>150</b>, <b>250</b> and <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on a first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on a first second-node AD<b>2</b>, generate a first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; and transfer the generated first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; to the first delay unit <b>100</b>. The first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> outputs the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of a high level to the first delay unit <b>100</b> when the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> is earlier than the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b>, and outputs the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of a low level to the first delay unit <b>100</b> when the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> is earlier than the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b>. Meanwhile, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> may be designed to perform the above-described phase comparison operation in response to a mode signal MODE. Here, the mode signal MODE is a signal which represents a normal mode or a calibration mode. In detail, the mode signal MODE of a high level may be controlled so as to represent the calibration mode and the mode signal MODE of a low level may be controlled so as to represent the normal mode. In other words, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> may be designed in such a way as to compare the phases of the two input signals and output the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; to the first delay unit <b>100</b> in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) and unconditionally output the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the low level to the first delay unit <b>100</b> without performing the above-described comparison operation in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The first delay unit <b>100</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> to a second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> to a second second-node BD<b>2</b>. At this time, the first delay unit <b>100</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> in response to the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by a first delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The second phase comparison unit <b>250</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, generate a second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; and transfer the generated second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; to the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The second delay unit <b>200</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> to a third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to a third second-node CD<b>2</b>. At this time, the second delay unit <b>200</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by a second delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> and generate a third up/down signal Q&#x3c;1&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> for controlling the delay values of the respective delay units <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> constituting the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> controls the delay values using two signals with the same phase. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the case where a path selection unit <b>10</b> is separately disposed to allow two signals with the same phase to be inputted to the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b>. In detail, the path selection unit <b>10</b> is configured to select the output nodes of two input signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b> in response to the mode signal MODE. Namely, the path selection unit <b>10</b> transfers the first input signal IN<b>1</b> to the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the second input signal IN<b>2</b> to the first second-node AD<b>2</b> in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level), and transfers the first input signal IN<b>1</b> to the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level). Of course, the path selection unit <b>10</b> may be designed such that the second input signal IN<b>2</b> is loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> may include a replica delay unit <b>410</b> configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>200</b> and a delay control unit <b>420</b> configured to control the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. Of course, in the case where the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> includes N number of delay units, the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> may include a first replica delay unit configured in the same way as a second delay unit, a second replica delay unit configured in the same way as a third delay unit, . . . , an N&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>replica delay unit configured in the same way as an N<sup>th </sup>delay unit, a first delay control unit configured to control the delay value of the second delay unit, a second delay control unit configured to control the delay value of the third delay unit, . . . , and an N&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay control unit configured to control the delay value of the N<sup>th </sup>delay unit.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The replica delay unit <b>410</b> is configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>200</b>, and the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> is the same as the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The replica delay unit <b>410</b> is inputted with the two signals outputted from the second delay unit <b>200</b> (that is, the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>), selects any one of the two inputted signals in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by the second delay value and outputs the delayed signal to the delay control unit <b>420</b> and does not delay but output the remaining one signal to the delay control unit <b>420</b> as is.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The delay control unit <b>420</b> is inputted with the signals loaded on a third third-node CD<b>3</b> and a third fourth-node CD<b>4</b>, compares the phases of the signals, and controls the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> using a comparison result. In detail, the delay control unit <b>420</b> may include a calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> and a control section <b>422</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> and the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b>, generate a calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; and output the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; to the control section <b>422</b>. In detail, the calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> may be designed to generate the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of a high level in the case where the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> and generate the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of a low level in an opposite case.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The control section <b>422</b> is configured to generate delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; for controlling the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b> in response to the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e;. In detail, the control section <b>422</b> may be designed in such a way as to increase the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; has the high level and decrease the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; has the low level. This will be described below in detail with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Since the control section <b>422</b> operates in, for example, the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level) only, the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; may be designed so that they are not changed in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) to lock the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The delay control unit <b>420</b> controls the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and transfers the controlled delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; to the second delay unit <b>200</b> during the calibration mode, that is, during a period in which the mode signal MODE is activated to the high level. The second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled in response to the inputted delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;. The second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is finally controlled by the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibration mode is ended, that is, when the mode signal MODE transitions from the high level to the low level.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing an exemplary embodiment of the second delay unit <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The second delay unit <b>200</b> may include a delay path selecting section <b>210</b>, a capacitor section <b>220</b>, and an output path selecting section <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The delay path selecting section <b>210</b> is configured to select the delay paths of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;. In detail, the delay path selecting section <b>210</b> may be designed in such a way as to transfer the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> to a second transmission node TD<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to a first transmission node TD<b>1</b> when the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has a high level and transfer the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> to the first transmission node TD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> when the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has a low level.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The capacitor section <b>220</b> is connected to the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> and is configured to delay the signal loaded on the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> by a delay value determined by total capacitance and transfer the delayed signal to the output path selecting section <b>230</b>. The capacitor section <b>220</b> may include a capacitor C<b>0</b>, a plurality of switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b> and a plurality of capacitors C<b>1</b> to C<b>4</b> which are connected in series to the plurality of switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b>. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an example where the capacitor section <b>220</b> includes the five capacitors C<b>0</b> to C<b>4</b>. The plurality of switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b> are turned on and off in response to delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;. The zeroth capacitor C<b>0</b> has a capacitance of a large level, and the first to fourth capacitors C<b>1</b> to C<b>4</b> have the same capacitance of a relatively small level. The total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> is the sum of the capacitance of the zeroth capacitor C<b>0</b> and the capacitances of capacitors connected to turn-on switches. The signal loaded on the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> is delayed by the delay value determined by the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b>. When the total capacitance is large, it takes a long time to charge/discharge charges and the magnitude of the delay value increases, and when the total capacitance is small, the magnitude of the delay value decreases. Of course, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an example where the capacitances of the capacitors C<b>1</b> to C<b>4</b> connected to the plurality of switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b> have the same magnitude, the capacitances of the capacitors C<b>1</b> to C<b>4</b> may be different according to different design needs. For example, the capacitor section <b>220</b> may be designed such that the capacitance of the first capacitor C<b>1</b> is two times the capacitance of the second capacitor C<b>2</b>, the capacitance of the second capacitor C<b>2</b> is two times the capacitance of the third capacitor C<b>3</b> and the capacitance of the third capacitor C<b>3</b> is two times the capacitance of the fourth capacitor C<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The output path selecting section <b>230</b> is configured to select the output paths of the signal loaded on the first transmission node TD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;. In detail, the output path selecting section <b>230</b> may be designed in such a way as to transfer the signal loaded on the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> to the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first transmission node TD<b>1</b> to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> when the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has the high level and transfer the signal loaded on the first transmission node TD<b>1</b> to the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second transmission node TD<b>2</b> to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> when the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has the low level.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">That is to say, the second delay unit <b>200</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, delays the selected signal using the capacitor section <b>220</b> and outputs the delayed signal, in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Operations of the delay control unit <b>420</b> and the second delay unit <b>200</b> will be described below. For example, it is assumed that the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; currently inputted to the second delay unit <b>200</b> are 0011. The control section <b>422</b> stores 0011 as the default value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;. If the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; has the high level, the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; is increased to 0111 and the increased value is transferred to the second delay unit <b>200</b>. As the increased delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; are inputted to the second delay unit <b>200</b>, the number of capacitors to be turned on increases, and thus, the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> increases. Consequently, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is increased. Conversely, if the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; has the low level, the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; is decreased from 0011 to 0001 and the decreased value is transferred to the second delay unit <b>200</b>. As the decreased delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; are inputted to the second delay unit <b>200</b>, the number of capacitors to be turned on decreases, and thus, the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> decreases. Consequently, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is decreased. In the meanwhile, the control section <b>422</b> may be designed in such a way as to store 0000 as the default value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;, increase/decrease the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; in response to the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; and transfer the increased/decreased value to the second delay unit <b>200</b>. In this case, the second delay value is controlled as the switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b> of the capacitor section <b>220</b> are turned on one by one in response to the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;, from the state in which all of them are turned off.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As a result, the delay control unit <b>420</b> controls the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; and transfers the controlled delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; to the second delay unit <b>200</b>, the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> is controlled in response to the inputted delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;, and thus, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a timing diagram showing calibrating operations of the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level). In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, for illustration purposes, the following assumptions are made. {circle around (1)} The first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is 40 ps and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is changed from 20 ps to 18.5 ps due to a variation in PVT, and {circle around (2)} since the replica delay unit <b>410</b> is configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>200</b> and a change in the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> due to the variation in PVT occurs in the same manner as in the second delay unit <b>200</b>, the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> is also changed from 20 ps to 18.5 ps due to the variation in PVT. Further, {circle around (3)} the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; currently inputted to the second delay unit <b>200</b> are 0001 and the delay control unit <b>420</b> stores 0001 as the default value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;, and {circle around (4)}, as the number of switches to be turned on among the switches S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b> of the capacitor section <b>220</b> in response to the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; increases/decreases by one, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> increases/decreases by 1 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In the case where the mode signal MODE indicates the calibration mode, that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level, the path selection unit <b>10</b> transfers the first input signal IN<b>1</b> to the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b>. The signals loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b> are inputted to the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Actually, the phases of the two signals inputted to the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> may not be perfectly the same with no error. In other words, the phases of the two signals have a shade of difference due to noise, etc. on signal transfer lines, and therefore, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> generates and outputs the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the high or low level. For example, if the phase of the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> is earlier slightly than the phase of the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> due to noise, etc. on signal transfer lines, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> generates the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the high level and outputs it to the first delay unit <b>100</b>. Conversely, if the phase of the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> is earlier slightly than the phase of the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> due to noise, etc. on the signal transfer lines, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> generates the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the low level and outputs it to the first delay unit <b>100</b>. In the meantime, while the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> performs calibrating operations, the level of the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; as the output signal of the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> inputted with the two signals having the same phase is not important. Therefore, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b> may be designed in such a way as to always generate the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the low level without performing the phase comparing operation and output it to the first delay unit <b>100</b> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Here, for illustration purposes, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b>, inputted with the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> which have the same phase, generates the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the low level and outputs it to the first delay unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The first delay unit <b>100</b> delays the signal loaded on the first second-node AD<b>2</b> by the first delay value of 40 ps between the signals loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> and the first second-node AD<b>2</b> and inputted thereto in response to the first up/down signal Q&#x3c;3&#x3e; of the low level and transfers the delayed signal to the second second-node BD<b>2</b> and transfers the signal loaded on the first first-node AD<b>1</b> to the second first-node BD<b>1</b> as is without delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> becomes earlier by 40 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> (STEP<b>1</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The second phase comparison unit <b>250</b> compares the phases of the signals loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b> and inputted thereto, and, since the phase of the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, generates the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The second delay unit <b>200</b> delays the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> by the second delay value of 18.5 ps between the signals loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b> and inputted thereto in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the third first-node CD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> as is without delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> becomes earlier by 21.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> (STEP<b>2</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; and the signals loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the third second-node CD<b>2</b> are inputted to the replica delay unit <b>410</b>. The replica delay unit <b>410</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by the second delay value of 18.5 ps between the signals loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the third second-node CD<b>2</b> and inputted thereto in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the third third-node CD<b>3</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> becomes earlier by 3 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> (STEP<b>3</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> compares, the phases of the signals loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> and the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> and inputted thereto, and, since the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b>, generates the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the control section <b>422</b>. The control section <b>422</b> increases the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; from 0001 to 0011 in response to the calibrating is up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the high level, and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b>. As the third switch S<b>3</b> and the fourth switch S<b>4</b> of the capacitor section <b>220</b> constituting the second delay unit <b>200</b> are turned on, the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> becomes the sum of the capacitances of the zeroth capacitor C<b>0</b>, the third capacitor C<b>3</b> and the fourth capacitor C<b>4</b>. Namely, because the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> in the second delay unit <b>200</b> is increased by the capacitance of the third capacitor C<b>3</b>, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> increases by 1 ps and becomes 19.5 ps. Similarly, the second delay value of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> becomes 19.5 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Subsequently, the above-described operations are repeated. That is to say, the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> is delayed by the second delay value of 19.5 ps through the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the delayed signal is transferred to the third first-node CD<b>1</b>, and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> is not delayed and is transferred to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> as is. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> becomes earlier by 20.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> (STEP<b>4</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The replica delay unit <b>410</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by the second delay value of 19.5 ps in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers, the delayed signal to the third third-node CD<b>3</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> becomes earlier by 1 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> (STEP<b>5</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Since the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b>, the calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> generates the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the control section <b>422</b>. The control section <b>422</b> increases the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; from 0011 to 0111 in response to the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the high level, and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b>. As the second switch S<b>2</b>, the third switch S<b>3</b> and the fourth switch S<b>4</b> of the capacitor section <b>220</b> constituting the second delay unit <b>200</b> are turned on, the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> becomes the sum of the capacitances of the zeroth capacitor C<b>0</b> and the second to fourth capacitors C<b>2</b>, C<b>3</b> and C<b>4</b>. Namely, because the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>220</b> in the second delay unit <b>200</b> is increased by the capacitance of the second capacitor C<b>2</b>, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> increases by 1 ps and becomes 20.5 ps. Similarly, the second delay value of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> becomes 20.5 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Thereupon, the above-described operations are repeated again. That is to say, the signal loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> is delayed by the second delay value of 20.5 ps through the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the delayed signal is transferred to the third first-node CD<b>1</b>, and the signal loaded on the second second-node BD<b>2</b> is not delayed and is transferred to the third second-node CD<b>2</b> as is. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> becomes earlier by 19.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> (STEP<b>6</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The replica delay unit <b>410</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by the second delay value of 20.5 ps in response to the second up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the third third-node CD<b>3</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> becomes earlier by 1 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b> (STEP<b>7</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Since the phase of the signal loaded on the third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the third third-node CD<b>3</b>, the calibrating phase comparing section <b>421</b> generates the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the low level and transfers it to the control section <b>422</b>. The control section <b>422</b> decreases the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; from 0111 to 0011 in response to the calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; of the low level and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">As a result, the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; is consecutively changed from 0111 to 0011 and subsequently from 0011 to 0111 until the calibration mode is ended, that is, the mode signal MODE transitions from the high level to the low level. In other words, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is consecutively changed from 19.5 ps to 20.5 ps and subsequently from 20.5 ps to 19.5 ps until the calibration mode is ended. When the calibration mode is ended, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is determined by the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; at that time. That is to say, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is locked to any one value of 19.5 ps and 20.5 ps. Through the calibrating process as described above, the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> maintain the ratio of 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">While it was exemplarily explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> that the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is decreased due to a variation in PVT, operations opposite to those described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> are performed in the case where the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is increased due to a variation in PVT. In detail, the delay control unit <b>420</b> performs an operation of decreasing the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; and thereby decreasing the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In the meantime, even in the case where the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is changed due to a variation in PVT, the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> may be maintained with the constant ratio of 2:1 through the above-described calibrating operations. For example, in the case where the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is 20 ps and the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is changed from 40 ps to 38 ps due to a variation in PVT, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> may be controlled to 19 ps through the delay value control operation described above.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">While the case in which the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled in response to the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; outputted from the delay control unit <b>420</b> was described as an example, the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> may be controlled in response to the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;. For example, in the case where the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is 40 ps and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is changed from 20 ps to 18.5 ps due to a variation in PVT, the delay control unit <b>420</b> may be controlled to decrease the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; and transfer it to the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> may be controlled to decrease in response to the inputted delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;. Furthermore, in the case where the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is 20 ps and the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is changed from 40 ps to 38 ps due to a variation in PVT, the delay control unit <b>420</b> may increase the value of the delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; and transfer it to the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> may be controlled to increase in response to the inputted delay codes CTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The calibrating operations of the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level) will be summarized below. The delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> for controlling the delay value of the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> including the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay unit <b>200</b> with the delay value ratio of 2:1 may include the replica delay unit <b>410</b> configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the delay control unit <b>420</b> configured to control the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The phases of a first output signal, which is generated as an input signal is delayed by the first delay value through the first delay unit <b>100</b>, and a second output signal, which is generated as the input signal is delayed by (the second delay value*2) through the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b>, are compared with each other, and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled using a comparison result. Through this delay value controlling process, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> may be controlled to be half of the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In other words, in the case where the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> includes first to N<sup>th </sup>delay units with binary weights, the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> for controlling the delay value of the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> may include a replica delay unit configured in the same way as an A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and a delay control unit configured to control the delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit. The phases of a first output signal, which is generated as an input signal is delayed through an A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit <b>100</b>, and a second output signal, which is generated as the input signal is delayed through the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit <b>200</b> and the replica delay unit <b>410</b>, are compared with each other, and the delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled using a comparison result. Through this delay value controlling process, the delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit <b>200</b> may be controlled to be half of the delay value of the A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Meanwhile, in the case where the phase difference quantization circuit <b>1000</b> further includes a third delay unit (not shown), the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> may be designed to further include a second replica delay unit (not shown) configured in the same way as the third delay unit and a second delay control unit (not shown) configured to control the third delay value of the third delay unit (hereinafter, the embodiment designed in this way will be referred to as a first modification of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). An operation for controlling the delay value of the third delay unit may be performed after the control of the delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is completed. The third delay unit may be designed such that, for example, only the delay value thereof and the signals inputted thereto and outputted therefrom are different from and the other configuration and operation are the same when compared to the second delay unit <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In this case, the calibrating operations of the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> are similar to those described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. First, in the case of a mode in which the calibrating operation for the third delay unit is to be performed, two signals with the same phase are loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b>. In detail, a second path selection unit (not shown) configured similar to the path selection unit <b>10</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may be disposed between the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The second path selection unit performs a control task such that signals with the same phase are loaded on the second first-node BD<b>1</b> and the second second-node BD<b>2</b>, in the case of the mode in which the calibrating operation for the third delay unit is to be performed. Subsequently, the phases of the signal delayed by the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the signal delayed by the third delay unit and the second replica delay unit are compared with each other, and the delay value of the third delay unit is controlled using a comparison result. If the calibrating operation for the third delay unit is completed, the third delay value of the third delay unit is controlled to be &#xbd; times the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram showing a phase difference quantization circuit in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The phase difference quantization circuit may include a path selection unit <b>10</b>, N+1 number of phase comparison units <b>150</b>, <b>250</b>, <b>350</b> and <b>450</b>, N number of delay units <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and <b>300</b>, N&#x2212;1 number of replica delay units <b>510</b> and <b>610</b>, and N&#x2212;1 number of delay control units <b>520</b> and <b>620</b>. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the case in which N is 3. The first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is two times the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>, and the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is two times the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The configurations and operations of the path selection unit <b>10</b>, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b>, the second phase comparison unit <b>250</b>, the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay unit <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> are similar to those of the path selection unit <b>10</b>, the first phase comparison unit <b>150</b>, the second phase comparison unit <b>250</b>, the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the second delay unit <b>200</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The first replica delay unit <b>510</b> is configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>200</b>, and the delay value thereof is the same as the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The configuration and operation of the first replica delay unit <b>510</b> are the same as those of the replica delay unit <b>410</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The first delay control unit <b>520</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signals loaded on a third third-node CD<b>3</b> and a third fourth-node CD<b>4</b> and generate first delay codes CTR<b>1</b>&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; for controlling the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>, using a comparison result. In detail, the first delay control unit <b>520</b> may include a first calibrating phase comparing section <b>521</b> configured to compare the phases of the two signals and generate a first calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e; and a first control section <b>522</b> configured to generate the first delay codes CTR<b>1</b>&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the first calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;1&#x3e;. Since the first delay control unit <b>520</b> performs the operation for controlling, for example, the first delay codes CTR<b>1</b>&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; only in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), the delay code controlling operation described above may be designed so as not to be performed in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) to lock the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. The configuration and operation of the first delay control unit <b>520</b> are the same as those of the delay control unit <b>420</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signals loaded on a third first-node CD<b>1</b> and a third second-node CD<b>2</b> and generate a third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The third delay unit <b>300</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> to a fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to a fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;. At this time, the third delay unit <b>300</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, delays the selected signal by the third delay value, and transfers the delayed signal. In detail, the third delay unit <b>300</b> may be designed in such a way as to delay the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by the third delay value and transfer the delayed signal to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, and transfer the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal, when the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has a high level. Furthermore, the third delay unit <b>300</b> may be designed in such a way as to delay the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> by the third delay value and transfer the delayed signal to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b>, and transfer the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> as is without further delaying the signal, when the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; has a low level. Meanwhile, the third delay unit <b>300</b> may be designed such that, for example, only the delay value thereof and the signals inputted thereto and outputted therefrom are different from and the other configuration and operation are the same when compared to the second delay unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is configured in the same way as the third delay unit <b>300</b>, and the delay value thereof is the same as the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b>. In detail, the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is configured to transfer the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> to a fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> to a fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b>. At this time, the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> selects any one of the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e;, delays the selected signal by the third delay value, and transfers the delayed signal.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The second delay control unit <b>620</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> and control the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> using a comparison result. The second delay control unit <b>620</b> may include a second calibrating phase comparing section <b>621</b> configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> and generate a second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; and a second control section <b>622</b> configured to control second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e;. Since the second delay control unit <b>620</b> performs the operation for controlling the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;, for example, only in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), the delay code controlling operation described above may be controlled so as not to be performed in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) to lock the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b>. The second delay control unit <b>620</b> may be designed such that, for example, only the signals inputted thereto and outputted therefrom are different from and the other configuration and operation are the same when compared to the first delay control unit <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The fourth phase comparison unit <b>450</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> and generate a fourth up/down signal Q&#x3c;1&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">The operations of the phase difference quantization circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">First, operations of the phase difference quantization circuit in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) are as follows. In the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level), binary codes Q&#x3c;4:1&#x3e; which reflect the phase differences between two input signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b> are generated. At this time, the first delay control unit <b>520</b> and the second delay control unit <b>620</b> do not operate. The fourth bit Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; among the generated binary codes Q&#x3c;4:1&#x3e; indicates which signal of the two input signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b> has an earlier phase, and the remaining three bits Q&#x3c;3:1&#x3e; indicate an actual phase difference between the two input signals IN<b>1</b> and IN<b>2</b>. For example, when assuming that the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is 40 ps, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is 20 ps, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is 10 ps and the value of the binary codes Q&#x3c;4:1&#x3e; is 1110, since the fourth bit Q&#x3c;4&#x3e; is 1, the phase of the first input signal IN<b>1</b> is earlier than the phase of the second input signal IN<b>2</b>. The phase difference therebetween is larger than 1*40 ps+1*20 ps and smaller than 1*40 ps+1*20 ps+1*10 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Calibrating operations of the phase difference quantization circuit in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level) are as follows. In the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is calibrated based on the first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b>. Moreover, if the control of the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is completed, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is calibrated based on the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b>. For illustration purposes, the following assumptions are made. {circle around (1)} The first delay value of the first delay unit <b>100</b> is 40 ps, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is changed from 20 ps to 18.5 ps due to a variation in PVT and the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is changed from 10 ps to 8.5 ps due to a variation in PVT, {circle around (2)} the delay value of the first replica delay unit <b>510</b> is also changed to 18.5 ps due to the variation in PVT and the delay value of the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is also changed to 8.5 ps due to the variation in PVT, {circle around (3)} each of the first delay codes CTR<b>1</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; and the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; is constituted by 4 bits, and {circle around (4)}, as the number of capacitors to be turned in response to the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; increases/decreases by one, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> increases/decreases by 1 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">An operation for controlling the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is the same as the delay value controlling operation described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Hereinafter, an operation for controlling the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> after the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> is controlled to 19.5 ps will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The third phase comparison unit <b>350</b> compares the phases of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, and, since the phase of the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> is earlier by 20.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b>, generates the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the third delay unit <b>300</b>. The third delay unit <b>300</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by the third delay value of 8.5 ps between the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> is earlier by 12 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> (STEP<b>8</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The second replica delay unit <b>610</b> delays the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> by the third delay value of 8.5 ps between the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> and the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth third-node DD<b>2</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> to the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> is earlier by 3.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> (STEP<b>9</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Since the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b>, the second calibrating phase comparing section <b>621</b> generates the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the second control section <b>622</b>. The second control section <b>622</b> increases the value of the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; in response to the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the third delay unit <b>300</b> and the second replica delay unit <b>610</b>. Accordingly, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is increased to 9.5 ps, and the delay value of the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is also increased to 9.5 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Subsequently, the above-described operations are repeated. That is to say, the third delay unit <b>300</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by 9.5 ps in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal (STEP<b>10</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The second replica delay unit <b>610</b> delays the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> by the third delay value of 9.5 ps in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> to the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> is earlier by 1.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> (STEP<b>11</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Since the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b>, the second calibrating phase comparing section <b>621</b> generates the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the second control section <b>622</b>. The second control section <b>622</b> increases the value of the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; in response to the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers it to the third delay unit <b>300</b> and the second replica delay unit <b>610</b>. Accordingly, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is increased by 1 ps to 10.5 ps. The delay value of the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is also increased to 10.5 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">Thereupon, the above-described operations are repeated again. That is to say, the third delay unit <b>300</b> delays the signal loaded on the third first-node CD<b>1</b> by 10.5 ps in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the third second-node CD<b>2</b> to the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> as is without further delaying the signal (STEP<b>12</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The second replica delay unit <b>610</b> delays the signal loaded on the fourth first-node DD<b>1</b> by the third delay value of 10.5 ps in response to the third up/down signal Q&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the high level and transfers the delayed signal to the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b>, and transfers the signal loaded on the fourth second-node DD<b>2</b> to the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> as is without further delaying the signal. Accordingly, the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> is earlier by 0.5 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b> (STEP<b>13</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Since the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth fourth-node DD<b>4</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the fourth third-node DD<b>3</b>, the second calibrating phase comparing section <b>621</b> generates the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the low level and outputs it to the second control section <b>622</b>. The second control section <b>622</b> decreases the value of the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; in response to the second calibrating up/down signal R&#x3c;2&#x3e; of the low level and transfers it to the third delay unit <b>300</b> and the second replica delay unit <b>610</b>. The delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is decreased by 1 ps and is controlled to 9.5 ps. The delay value of the second replica delay unit <b>610</b> is also decreased by 1 ps and is controlled to 9.5 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">As a result, the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is consecutively changed from 9.5 ps to 10.5 ps and subsequently from 10.5 ps to 9.5 ps until the calibration mode is ended, that is, the mode signal MODE transitions from the high level to the low level. The third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is locked to any one value of 9.5 ps and 10.5 ps by the second delay codes CTR<b>2</b>&#x3c;1:4&#x3e; when the calibration mode is ended (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level). Through this, the second delay value of the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the third delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> may maintain approximately the ratio of 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">In the meantime, the difference between the operation in which the delay value control circuit <b>2000</b> controls the delay value of the third delay unit in the above-described first modification of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and the operation in which the phase difference quantization circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> controls the delay value of the third delay unit <b>300</b> is as follows. In the first modification of the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the phases of the signal generated by delaying an input signal by the second delay value through the second delay unit <b>200</b> and the signal generated by delaying the input signal by (the third delay value*2) are compared with each other, and the third delay value of the third delay unit is controlled using a comparison result. However, in the phase difference quantization circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the phases of the signal generated by delaying an input signal by the first delay value through the first delay unit <b>100</b> and the signal generated by delaying the input signal by (the second delay value+the third delay value*2) are compared with each other, and the third delay value of the third delay unit is controlled using a comparison result.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram showing an exemplary embodiment of an integrated circuit in which a delay circuit <b>3000</b> in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention is used. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows an example of an integrated circuit in which the delay circuit <b>3000</b> is used. The present embodiment may be applied, without limitations, to any circuits so long as the ratio between the two units delay value of a first delay unit <b>810</b> and the one unit delay value of a second delay unit <b>820</b> is constantly maintained at 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The integrated circuit may include a first selection unit <b>801</b>, the delay circuit <b>3000</b>, an internal circuit <b>803</b>, and a second selection unit <b>802</b>. The delay circuit <b>3000</b> according to the present embodiment may include the first delay unit <b>810</b>, the second delay unit <b>820</b>, a replica delay unit <b>830</b>, and a delay control unit <b>840</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">The first selection unit <b>801</b> is configured to select any one of a normal signal NML_SIG and a calibration signal CAL_SIG in response to a mode signal MODE and output the selected signal to the first delay unit <b>810</b>. As described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the mode signal MODE is a signal which represents a normal mode or a calibration mode. In detail, the mode signal MODE of a high level may be controlled so as to represent the calibration mode and the mode signal MODE of a low level may be controlled so as to represent the normal mode. The first selection unit <b>801</b> may be designed in such a way as to output the normal signal NML_SIG to the first delay unit <b>810</b> in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) and output the calibration signal CAL_SIG to the first delay unit <b>810</b> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level).</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The first delay unit <b>810</b> is configured to delay the signal loaded on a first node N<b>1</b> by a two units delay value. The signal delayed by the first delay unit <b>810</b> is transferred to the internal circuit <b>803</b> and the delay control unit <b>840</b>. In detail, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>; the first delay unit <b>810</b> may include a capacitor section <b>811</b>. The first delay unit <b>810</b> delays the signal loaded on the first node N<b>1</b> by the delay value determined by the total capacitance of the capacitor section <b>811</b> and outputs the delayed signal to a second node N<b>2</b>. The capacitor section <b>811</b> includes a plurality of capacitors CP<b>0</b> to CP<b>4</b> and a plurality of switches SW<b>1</b> to SW<b>4</b>. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates the case in which the capacitor section <b>811</b> includes five capacitors CP<b>0</b> to CP<b>4</b> and fourth switches SW<b>1</b> to SW<b>4</b>. The plurality of switches SW<b>1</b> to SW<b>4</b> are turned on and off in response to delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:4&#x3e;. The configuration and operation of the capacitor section <b>811</b> are similar to those of the capacitor section <b>220</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">The internal circuit <b>803</b> is configured to be inputted with the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b>, perform a specified operation using the inputted signal and subsequently transfers a resultant value to a third node N<b>3</b>. The internal circuit <b>803</b> means a circuit which constitutes the integrated circuit and performs the specified operation.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The second selection unit <b>802</b> is configured to select any one of the output signal of the internal circuit <b>803</b>, that is, the signal loaded on the third node N<b>3</b>, and the calibration signal CAL_SIG in response to the mode signal MODE and output the selected signal to the second delay unit <b>820</b>. In detail, the second selection unit <b>802</b> may be designed in such a way as to output the signal loaded on the third node N<b>3</b> to the second delay unit <b>820</b> in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) and output the calibration signal CAL_SIG to the second delay unit <b>820</b> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level).</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">The second delay unit <b>820</b> is configured to delay the output signal of the second selection unit <b>802</b>, that is, the signal loaded on a fourth node N<b>4</b>, by a one unit delay value. The signal delayed by the second delay unit <b>820</b> is transferred to another internal circuit (not shown) and the replica delay unit <b>830</b>. In detail, the second delay unit <b>820</b> may include a capacitor section as in the first delay unit <b>810</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, and delays the signal loaded on the fourth node N<b>4</b> by the delay value determined by the total capacitance of the capacitor section and outputs the delayed signal to a fifth node N<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The replica delay unit <b>830</b> is configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>820</b>, and the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>830</b> is the same as the one unit delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b>. The replica delay unit <b>830</b> is configured to delay the signal loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b> by the one unit delay value and transfers the delayed signal to the delay control unit <b>840</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">The delay control unit <b>840</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on a sixth node N<b>6</b> (that is, the signal transferred from the replica delay unit <b>830</b>) and control the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> using a comparison result. The delay control unit <b>840</b> controls the total capacitance of the capacitor section of the second delay unit <b>820</b> and controls the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b>. The configuration and operation of the delay control unit <b>840</b> are similar to those of the delay control unit <b>420</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In detail, the delay control unit <b>840</b> may include a phase comparing section <b>841</b> and a control section <b>842</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The phase comparing section <b>841</b> is configured to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> and output a calibrating up/down signal CUD. In detail, the phase comparing section <b>841</b> may be designed in such a way as to generate and output the calibrating up/down signal CUD of a high level when the phase of the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b>, and generate and output the calibrating up/down signal CUD of a low level when the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">The control section <b>842</b> is configured to generate delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; for controlling the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> and the replica delay unit <b>830</b>, in response to the calibrating up/down signal CUD, and transfer the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; to the second delay unit <b>820</b> and the replica delay unit <b>830</b>. In detail, the control section <b>842</b> may be designed in such a way as to increase the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the high level and decrease the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the low level.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Since the delay control unit <b>840</b> performs the operation for controlling, for example, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> only in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), the delay value controlling operation described above may be controlled so as not to be performed in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) to lock the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The operations of the integrated circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">First, operations of the integrated circuit in the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level) are as follows. In the normal mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the low level), the first selection unit <b>801</b> outputs the normal signal NML_SIG to the first delay unit <b>810</b>. The first delay unit <b>810</b> delays the inputted signal by the two units delay value and transfers the delayed signal to the internal circuit <b>803</b>. The internal circuit <b>803</b> performs the specified operation using the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and transfers the resultant value to the third node N<b>3</b>. The second selection unit <b>802</b> outputs the signal loaded on the third node N<b>3</b> to the second delay unit <b>820</b> in response to the mode signal MODE of the low level. The second delay unit <b>820</b> delays the signal loaded on the fourth node N<b>4</b> by the one unit delay value and transfers the delayed signal to another internal circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Operations of the integrated circuit in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level) will be described below with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. For illustration purposes, the following assumptions are made. {circle around (1)} It is assumed that the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is 20 ps and the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is changed from 10 ps to 8 ps due to a variation in PVT, and, since the replica delay unit <b>830</b> is configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>820</b> and a change in the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>830</b> due to the variation in PVT occurs in the same manner as in the second delay unit <b>820</b>, the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>830</b> is also changed from 10 ps to 8 ps due to the variation in PVT. {circle around (2)} It is assumed that the phase comparing section <b>841</b> generates the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the high level when the phase of the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and generates the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the low level in an opposite case. {circle around (3)} The control section <b>842</b> decreases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal CUD has the low level and increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal CUD has the high level, and {circle around (4)}, as the number of capacitors to be turned in response to the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; increases/decreases by one, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> increases/decreases by 1 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">First, the first selection unit <b>801</b> outputs the calibration signal CAL_SIG to the first delay unit <b>810</b> in response to the mode signal MODE of the high level.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">The signal transferred from the first selection unit <b>801</b>, that is, the signal loaded on the first node N<b>1</b>, is delayed by 20 ps through the first delay unit <b>810</b>, and is subsequently transferred to the phase comparing section <b>841</b> of the delay control unit <b>840</b> (STEP_A).</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The second selection unit <b>802</b> outputs the calibration signal CAL_SIG to the second delay unit <b>820</b> in response to the mode signal MODE of the high level.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">The signal transferred from the second selection unit <b>802</b>, that is, the signal loaded on the fourth node N<b>4</b>, is delayed by 8 ps through the second delay unit <b>820</b>, and is subsequently transferred to the replica delay unit <b>830</b> (STEP_B). The replica delay unit <b>830</b> delays the inputted signal, that is, the signal loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b>, again by 8 ps, and subsequently transfers the delayed signal to the phase comparing section <b>841</b> of the delay control unit <b>840</b> (STEP_C). Accordingly, the phase of the signal transferred from the replica delay unit <b>830</b> (that is, the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b>) is earlier by 4 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">The phase comparing section <b>841</b> of the delay control unit <b>840</b> compares the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b>, and since the phase of the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b>, generates the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the high level and transfers it to the control section <b>842</b>. The control section <b>842</b> performs an operation for controlling the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the mode signal MODE of the high level. In detail, the control section <b>842</b> increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; in response to the calibrating up/down signal CUD of the high level and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>820</b> and the replica delay unit <b>830</b>. The delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is increased by 1 ps through the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and is controlled to 9 ps. The delay value of the replica delay unit <b>830</b> is also increased by 1 ps through the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and is controlled to 9 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">Subsequently, the above-described operations are repeated. That is to say, the signal transferred from the second selection unit <b>802</b> (that is, the signal loaded on the fourth node N<b>4</b>) is delayed by 9 ps through the second delay unit <b>820</b> and is subsequently loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b> (STEP_D). Furthermore, the replica delay unit <b>830</b> delays the signal loaded on the fifth rode N<b>5</b> again by 9 ps and transfers the delayed signal to the sixth node N<b>6</b> (STEP_E). The delay control unit <b>840</b> compares the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b>, and, since the phase of the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> by 2 ps, increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>820</b> and the replica delay unit <b>830</b>. Due to this fact, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is increased to 10 ps, and the delay value of the replica delay unit <b>830</b> is also increased to 10 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">Thereupon, the above-described operations are repeated again. That is to say, the signal transferred from the second selection unit <b>802</b> (that is, the signal loaded on the fourth node N<b>4</b>) is delayed by 10 ps through the second delay unit <b>820</b> and is subsequently loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b> (STEP_F). Furthermore, the replica delay unit <b>830</b> delays the signal loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b> again by 10 ps and transfers the delayed signal to the sixth node N<b>6</b> (STEP_G).</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">During the calibration mode, that is, during a period in which the mode signal MODE is activated to the high level, the above-described operations are repeated, the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; is controlled, and thus, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is changed. The delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is finally determined by the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibration mode is ended, that is, when the mode signal MODE transitions from the high level to the low level. As a result, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is controlled to be half of the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b>, that is, 10 ps, so that the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> may maintain the ratio of 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">While the case in which the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is controlled in response to the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; was described as an example, it is to be noted that the delay circuit <b>3000</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention may be designed such that the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is controlled in response to the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;. In this case, the delay control unit <b>840</b> may be designed in such a way as to compare the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> and control the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> using a comparison result. For example, in the case where the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is 20 ps and the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is changed from 10 ps to 8.5 ps due to a variation in PVT, the delay control unit <b>840</b> decreases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and transfers it to the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is decreased in response to the inputted delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;. Furthermore, design may be made such that, in the case where the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is 10 ps and the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is changed from 20 ps to 18 ps due to a variation in PVT, the delay control unit <b>840</b> increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and transfers it to the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is increased in response to the inputted delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e;.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Here, the case in which the delay value ratio of the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the second delay unit <b>820</b> constituting the delay circuit is 2:1 has been described as an example. In the case where the delay value ratio of the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the second delay unit <b>820</b> is K:1 (K is an integer equal to or greater than 2), the delay value ratio of the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the second delay unit <b>820</b> is constantly maintained at K:1 by disposing K&#x2212;1 number of replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">A delay circuit <b>3000</b> may include a first delay unit <b>810</b> with a K units delay value, a second delay unit <b>820</b> with a one unit delay value, the K&#x2212;1 number of replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b> configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>820</b>, and a delay control unit <b>840</b>. For illustration purposes, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> illustrates that K is 3, that is, the delay circuit <b>3000</b> includes the first delay unit <b>810</b> with a three units delay value and two replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">The configuration and operating principle of the delay circuit <b>3000</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> are similar to those of the delay circuit <b>3000</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. Here, differences between the calibrating operations of the delay circuit <b>3000</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> and the calibrating operations of the delay circuit <b>3000</b> described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> in the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level) will be described. For illustration purposes, the following assumptions are made. {circle around (1)} It is assumed that the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> is 30 ps and the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is changed from 10 ps to 7 ps due to a variation in PVT, and, since the first and second replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b> are configured in the same way as the second delay unit <b>820</b>, the delay value of the each of the first and second replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b> is also changed from 10 ps to 7 ps due to the variation in PVT. {circle around (2)} It is assumed that a phase comparing section <b>841</b> generates a calibrating up/down signal CUD of a high level when the phase of the signal loaded on a seventh node N<b>7</b> is earlier than the phase of the signal loaded on a second node N<b>2</b> and generates the calibrating up/down signal CUD of a low level in an opposite case. {circle around (3)} A control section <b>842</b> decreases the value of delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal CUD has the low level and increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibrating up/down signal CUD has the high level, and {circle around (4)} as the number of capacitors to be turned in response to the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; increases/decreases by one, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> increases/decreases by 1 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">In the calibration mode (that is, when the mode signal MODE has the high level), the first delay unit <b>810</b> delays a calibration signal CAL_SIG by 30 ps and transfers the delayed signal to the second node N<b>2</b>. The second delay unit <b>820</b> delays the calibration signal CAL_SIG loaded on a fourth node N<b>4</b> by 7 ps and transfers the delayed signal to a fifth node N<b>5</b>. The first replica delay unit <b>831</b> delays the signal loaded on the fifth node N<b>5</b> again by 7 ps and transfers the delayed signal to a sixth node N<b>6</b>. The second replica delay unit <b>832</b> delays the signal loaded on the sixth node N<b>6</b> again by 7 ps and transfers the delayed signal to the seventh node N<b>7</b>. The delay control unit <b>840</b> compares the phases of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b> and the signal loaded on the seventh node N<b>7</b>, and, since the phase of the signal loaded on the seventh node N<b>7</b> is earlier by 9 ps than the phase of the signal loaded on the second node N<b>2</b>, increases the value of the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; and transfers it to the second delay unit <b>820</b> and the first and second replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b>. Due to this fact, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is increased by 1 ps and is controlled to 8 ps. The delay value of each of the first and second replica delay units <b>831</b> and <b>832</b> is increased by 1 ps and is controlled to 8 ps.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">The above-described operations are repeated during the calibration mode, that is, during a period in which the mode signal MODE is activated to the high level. The delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is finally determined by the delay codes NCTR&#x3c;1:M&#x3e; when the calibration mode is ended, that is, when the mode signal MODE transitions from the high level to the low level. As a result, the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> is controlled to the one thirds magnitude of the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b>, that is, 10 ps, so that the delay value of the first delay unit <b>810</b> and the delay value of the second delay unit <b>820</b> may maintain the ratio of 3:1.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">As is apparent from the above descriptions, in the phase difference quantization circuit according to the embodiments of the present invention, since the delay value ratios of delay units constituting the phase difference quantization circuit are kept constant, digital codes which precisely reflect a phase difference between two signals may be generated.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">Furthermore, in the delay circuit according to the embodiments of the present invention, a signal may be delayed while keeping the delay value ratios of delay units constant.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">While the present invention has been described with respect to the specific embodiments, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A delay value control circuit of a phase difference quantization circuit, wherein the phase difference quantization circuit has first to N<sup>th </sup>(N is an integer equal to or greater than 2) delay units with binary weights, the delay value control circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a replica delay unit replicating an A<sup>th </sup>(2&#x2266;A&#x2266;N) delay unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a first output signal generated from delaying an input signal with an A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit and a phase of a second output signal generated from delaying the input signal with the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and the replica delay unit and configured to control a delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit using a comparison result.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The delay value control circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit is configured to delay the input signal using a capacitor section and the delay control unit is configured to control a capacitance of the capacitor section of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The delay value control circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the delay control unit comprises:
<claim-text>a phase comparing section configured to compare the phase of the first output signal and the phase of the second output signal and output an up/down signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control section configured to generate delay codes for controlling the delay value of the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and the replica delay unit in response to the up/down signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A delay value control circuit of a phase difference quantization circuit, wherein the phase difference quantization circuit has first to N<sup>th </sup>(N is an integer equal to or greater than 2) delay units with binary weights, the delay value control circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a replica delay unit replicating an A<sup>th </sup>(2&#x2266;A&#x2266;N) delay unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay control unit configured to compare a phase of a first output signal generated from delaying an input signal with an A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit and a phase of a second output signal generated from delaying the input signal with the A<sup>th </sup>delay unit and the replica delay unit and configured to control a delay value of the A&#x2212;1<sup>th </sup>delay unit using a comparison result.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
