<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622664-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622664</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12462192</doc-number>
<date>20090731</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1191</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>47</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>408 92</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Hand held portable drill guide enabling single handed field setup and having releasable drill gripping securement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>641922</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Baumgardner</name>
<date>19000100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1184829</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Crist</name>
<date>19160500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2373785</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Seaboly</name>
<date>19450400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2667092</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shaffer</name>
<date>19540100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2695525</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Butenhoff</name>
<date>19541100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2827807</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Meyer</name>
<date>19580300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2947205</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wilson</name>
<date>19600800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3248973</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Meyer</name>
<date>19660500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3538794</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Grundmeyer</name>
<date>19701100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3698827</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Salfer</name>
<date>19721000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3741670</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wood</name>
<date>19730600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3834828</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kikuchi</name>
<date>19740900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3957387</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Evertz et al.</name>
<date>19760500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4235565</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Albano</name>
<date>19801100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4585376</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Davenport et al.</name>
<date>19860400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4823443</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Waters</name>
<date>19890400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5051044</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Allen</name>
<date>19910900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5890851</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hamilton</name>
<date>19990400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0202516</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lanser</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>408 92</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>408115 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>408  1 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110027029</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110203</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lanser</last-name>
<first-name>Jerry L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Longmont</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lanser</last-name>
<first-name>Jerry L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Longmont</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Burdick</last-name>
<first-name>Harold A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bryant</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<department>3726</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Wilensky</last-name>
<first-name>Moshe</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A portable drill guide and method are disclosed for use primarily with hand held power drills having a pistol-type hand grip. The drill guide includes a mounting assembly and an operational guide assembly, the mounting assembly having a tool support bracket with a clamping band and resilient gripping limbs. The operational guide assembly includes a support arm bracket having the tool support bracket connected therewith and a support arm extending therefrom at an angle normal to the mounting assembly, a pair of interface guide posts with retainers, and an interface tensioning mechanism including a slotted two level shaft. An interface, a sufficient length of durable webbing or strap for example, is engagable around a workpiece and the guide posts beneath the retainers, and is operably associable with the tensioning mechanism.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="165.69mm" wi="211.33mm" file="US08622664-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="227.75mm" wi="186.61mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622664-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.19mm" wi="159.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622664-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="205.99mm" wi="164.85mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622664-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="192.87mm" wi="144.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622664-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates to portable hand tool operation, and, more particularly, relates to portable guides and presses for hand held drill motors.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Hand held power drills are widely utilized in the field for various construction, repair and maintenance operations. The portability of such tools has made them an efficient and effective choice for site-based operations. Such tools, however, are inherently unstable, imprecise and difficult to employ for some operations.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">For example, hand held drill motors having pistol-type hand grips are difficult to use on slick or uneven surfaces, having a tendency to &#x201c;walk&#x201d; or slip from the desired drilling location upon initial motor start-up. Moreover, such drill motors tend toward binding of the bit in the workpiece, especially at difficult or awkward attack angles. Finally, at some drilling site locations, maintenance of sufficient working force (pressure applied at the drill bit to the workpiece) is difficult due to workpiece location.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In an effort to address these shortcomings, a number of apparatus have heretofore been suggested and/or utilized for stabilizing the tool and/or aiding in application of drilling pressure at the bit (see, for example, U.S. Patent Documents US2004/0202516, U.S. Pat. Nos. 641,922, 1,184,829, 2,667,092, 2,695,525, 2,827,807, 2,947,205, 3,248,973, 3,538,794, 3,698,827, 3,741,670, 3,834,828, 3,957,387, 4,168,926, 5051,044, and 5,890,851). Such heretofore known apparatus have, however, met with limited acceptance, due at least in part to lack of sufficient work site adaptability, for example the ability to operate independent of attitude of tool operation and/or simplification of operation of various attachments, guides and mounts not to mention the tool itself in the field. Operational stability, ease of use, and/or ability to operate mounts and attachments with one hand while operating the tool with the other should be attended to in further improving such apparatus.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">This invention provides a portable drill guide for stabilizing and applying continuing pressure during operation of a portable hand drill motor independent of attitude of application of the drill motor to the workpiece. The drill guide enables single handed field setup and has a readily releasable drill motor gripping securement, is adaptable to work site limitations, accommodates operation independent of attitude of drill operation, and simplifies operation of its various attachments, guides and mounts as well as drill manipulation during use in the field. The guide improves drill motor operational stability by limiting occurrences of drill bit slipping, walking and binding at the work piece during use.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The portable drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor includes a mounting assembly having a mounting bracket spaced resilient gripping limbs and a securing band maintained around the limbs. The band includes a tightness varying mechanism and may be readily replaceable/disposable in nature. An operational guide assembly is connected with the mounting assembly and includes a support arm bracket with first and second spaced guide posts connected with the support arm bracket. A tensioning mechanism is mounted at the support arm bracket with a slotted shaft thereof rotatable through the support arm bracket. The guide posts are located between the shaft of the tensioning mechanism and the limbs of the mounting assembly, the shaft and the limbs aligned centrally relative to the spaced guide posts. A workpiece engageble interface such as a strap is maintainable around the guide posts and at the slotted shaft of the tensioning mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Each of the guide posts includes a retainer adjacent thereto for receiving the interface therebeneath adjacent to the guideposts. The slotted shaft includes an extended shaft half for ease of interface insertion thereinto. The support arm bracket has a support arm extending therefrom, and the mounting bracket includes a rear wall attached to the support arm bracket and having the spaced resilient limbs thereat. Each of the first and second limbs includes an arcuate limb section, the limb sections contoured toward one another. The guide posts are preferably positioned at opposite sides of the rear wall of the drill motor support bracket. A ratchet assembly is mounted at the support arm bracket for tensioning the strap.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is therefore an object of this invention to provide a portable drill guide for stabilizing and applying continuing pressure during operation of a portable drill motor that enables single handed field setup and readily releasable drill motor securement.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">It is another object of this invention to provide a portable drill guide that simplifies operation of its various attachments, guides and mounts as well as drill manipulation during use in the field.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is another object of this invention to provide a drill guide for use with a portable hand drill that is useful in the field independent of work site limitations and/or attitude of application of the drill motor to the workpiece, is simple and stable to operate, and is configured to help limit occurrences of drill bit walking, slipping and binding at the work piece.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is still another object of this invention to provide an attitude independent portable drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor, the drill guide including a mounting assembly having spaced resilient gripping limbs and a securing band maintained around the limbs, an operational guide assembly connected with the mounting assembly and including a support arm bracket, first and second spaced guide posts connected with the support arm bracket, and a tensioning mechanism mounted at the support arm bracket with a slotted shaft thereof rotatably maintained therethrough, the guide posts located between the shaft of the tensioning mechanism and the limbs of the mounting assembly, the shaft and the limbs aligned centrally relative to the spaced guide posts, and a workpiece engageble interface maintainable around the guide posts and at the slotted shaft of the tensioning mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It is still another object of this invention to provide a hand held drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor with a pistol-type grip extending from a main body, the drill guide including a support arm bracket having a support arm extending therefrom, a drill motor support bracket including a rear wall attached to the support arm bracket and having first and second spaced resilient limbs configured to receive the drill motor main body thereat, the first and second limbs each including an arcuate limb section, the limb sections contoured toward one another, a band at the limbs including a tightness varying mechanism, first and second spaced guide posts connected with the support arm bracket and positioned thereat at opposite sides of the rear wall of the drill motor support bracket, a ratchet assembly mounted at the support arm bracket, and a workpiece engaging strap maintainable around the guide posts and operationally associable with the ratchet assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">With these and other objects in view, which will become apparent to one skilled in the art as the description proceeds, this invention resides in the novel construction, combination, and arrangement of parts substantially as hereinafter described, and more particularly defined by the appended claims, it being understood that changes in the precise embodiment of the herein disclosed invention are meant to be included as come within the scope of the claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The accompanying drawings illustrate a complete embodiment of the invention according to the best mode so far devised for the practical application of the principles thereof, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of the portable drill guide of this invention in use with a portable hand held power tool (a drill motor);</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is another perspective view of the drill guide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of the portable drill guide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a bottom plan view of the drill guide of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with ghosted sections.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates portable hand held drill guide <b>11</b> in use with a power tool <b>13</b>, a hand held drill (sometimes referred to as a drill motor), boring a hole in a workpiece (pipe <b>14</b>). Drill guide <b>11</b> is designed for use primarily with hand held power tools, and especially electric or pneumatic portable drill motors having a pistol-type hand grip <b>15</b> including an on/off switch (or trigger, not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 4</figref>, drill guide <b>11</b> includes mounting assembly <b>17</b> utilizing a flexible and disposable/replaceable band <b>18</b> and operational guide assembly <b>19</b>. Mounting assembly <b>17</b> includes power drill support bracket <b>21</b> and resilient support <b>25</b>. Operational guide assembly <b>19</b> includes support arm bracket <b>27</b> having drill support bracket <b>21</b> connected therewith and having support arm <b>29</b> extending therefrom at an angle normal to mounting assembly <b>17</b>, interface guide posts <b>31</b> and <b>33</b>, and interface tensioning mechanism <b>35</b>. Interface <b>36</b>, a sufficient length of durable webbing or strap for example, is engagable around a workpiece <b>14</b> and guides <b>31</b> and <b>33</b> and is operably associable with tensioning mechanism <b>35</b> as discussed hereinafter. Interface <b>36</b>, when a strap is used as shown herein, is preferably of nylon or other tear resistant and durable material. Strap retainers <b>37</b> and <b>39</b> extend from interface guide posts <b>31</b> and <b>33</b>, respectively, for receipt of interface <b>36</b> therebeneath between a respective retainer and its adjacent interface guide post. Strap retainer <b>37</b> extends only part of the length of post <b>31</b> defining a slot open at one end and thus accommodating one handed insertion of strap interface <b>36</b> therebeneath during field application. Retainer <b>39</b> extends the full length of post <b>33</b> (and may be secured at an opening through bracket <b>27</b>) defining a slot closed at both ends for retention of interface <b>36</b> through.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Converging securement limbs <b>51</b> and <b>53</b> of drill support bracket <b>21</b> are angled toward one another and include retainer bar or bars <b>54</b>. Either one or two bars <b>54</b> at the exterior of either or both limbs <b>51</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) or <b>53</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 4</figref>) can be utilized to retain band <b>18</b> adjacent to bracket <b>21</b>. Each of limbs <b>51</b> and <b>53</b> includes a drill motor contacting contoured sections <b>55</b> and <b>56</b>, respectively, these arcuate limb sections bulging toward one another to improve gripping securement of the drill motor and ready release thereof due to spring like operation of the thus configured limbs. Bracket <b>21</b>, and particularly limbs <b>51</b> and <b>53</b> thereof, is made of resilient material (metal or carbon plastic, for example).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, drill chuck <b>57</b> (releasably receiving drill bit <b>58</b>) of drill motor <b>13</b> is releasably secured with a selected orientation relative to workpiece <b>14</b> utilizing band <b>18</b> (by loosening and tightening tensioner screw mechanism <b>18</b>&#x2032; provided with a known variety of slotted band mechanism, for example&#x2014;other tensioning mechanisms being usable), and heel <b>59</b> at hand grip <b>15</b> of drill motor <b>13</b> is maneuvered into position at resilient support <b>25</b> (preferably made of a relatively hard, but yieldable rubber or the like secured to bracket rear wall <b>61</b> of drill support bracket <b>21</b>, for example by screws <b>63</b> or the like), with heel <b>59</b> resting in conforming surface <b>65</b> thereof. Drill motor <b>13</b> is clamped between band <b>18</b> (abutting side body <b>67</b> of drill motor housing <b>69</b>) and rear wall <b>61</b> of drill support bracket <b>21</b>, heel <b>59</b> of drill motor <b>13</b> being pressed into resilient support <b>25</b>. Limbs <b>51</b> and <b>53</b> are urged toward tight contact with motor body <b>67</b> by tightening of band <b>18</b>, particularly at contoured sections <b>55</b> and <b>56</b>. Thus motor <b>13</b> is securely gripped support <b>25</b> thereby holding the drill motor secure against movement in all dimensions (up, down, sided to side and forward and rearward).</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Tensioning mechanism <b>35</b> as shown herein is a ratchet assembly. While ratchet assembly <b>35</b> is shown, any other means for tensioning the strap known in the art may be utilized. Ratchet assembly <b>35</b> may be any common ratchet type assembly adaptable to the use indicated. As shown herein, the assembly includes ratchet handle <b>75</b> pivotable toward support arm <b>29</b> about pivot pin <b>77</b> held at mount <b>78</b> formed at support arm bracket/support arm <b>27</b>/<b>29</b> junction (support arm <b>29</b> preferably being a made of rigid hollow tubing). Ratchet handle end <b>79</b> is pivotably mounted at drive bar <b>81</b>, pawl <b>83</b> at the opposite end of drive bar <b>81</b> being engageable in the teeth of ratchet gear <b>85</b> rotatably held in journals (not shown) in support arm bracket <b>27</b>. As may be appreciated, this arrangement allows movement of ratchet gear <b>85</b> and thus slotted take-up shaft <b>87</b> connected therewith. Slotted shaft <b>87</b> includes extended shaft half <b>88</b> for ease of interface insertion into the slot (the ability to easily achieve one handed strap interface <b>86</b> manipulation in the field is needed).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Latch <b>89</b> is pivotably mounted at pin <b>91</b> to support arm bracket <b>21</b>. Pawl <b>93</b> of latch <b>89</b> engages teeth of gear <b>85</b> limiting gear rotation to a single direction when in the engaging position. Spring <b>95</b> is attached between a selected location at latch extension <b>97</b> and ear <b>98</b> of drive bar <b>81</b> to maintain bias of latch <b>89</b> toward gear <b>85</b> and bias drive bar <b>81</b> into engagement with gear <b>85</b>. Release <b>101</b> is attached to latch <b>89</b> for movement of latch <b>89</b> against its bias. When moved, release <b>101</b> brings latch pawl <b>93</b> out of engagement with the teeth of gear <b>85</b> and cam surface <b>103</b> of latch <b>89</b> into contact with cam guide surface <b>105</b> of drive bar <b>81</b> thus disengaging pawl <b>83</b> of bar <b>81</b> from the teeth of gear <b>85</b> and thereby allowing free rotation of gear <b>85</b> and shaft <b>87</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Interface strap storage reel <b>107</b> normally holds one end of interface strap <b>36</b> and is freely rotatable on its axle <b>109</b> through journal mount <b>111</b> at support arm <b>29</b>, maintained thereat by press fit retainer cap <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In use as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, after drill motor <b>13</b> is mounted in mounting assembly <b>17</b>, workpiece/drill motor interface strap <b>36</b> is inserted in the slot defined by retainer <b>39</b> and post <b>33</b> and bit <b>58</b> is located at the desired drilling location at workpiece <b>14</b>. Interface <b>36</b> is then wrapped around the workpiece (for example, the pipe <b>14</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and around the outside of guide post <b>31</b> beneath retainer <b>37</b>. Since guide posts <b>31</b>/<b>33</b> are located between the shaft <b>87</b> and limbs <b>51</b>/<b>53</b>, with shaft <b>87</b> and limbs <b>51</b>/<b>53</b> aligned centrally relative to guide posts <b>31</b>/<b>33</b>, rear support wall <b>61</b> of drill support bracket <b>21</b> is centered between posts <b>31</b>/<b>33</b> with shaft <b>87</b> centered thereat so that interface strap <b>36</b> is directly tensioned relative to the primary direction of drill motor <b>13</b> operation toward and away from the workpiece, with work force applied substantially evenly from both sides of the drill motor. Free end <b>121</b> and intermediate portion <b>123</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of strap <b>36</b> are then positioned in slot <b>125</b> of tensioning shaft <b>87</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The operator holds grip <b>15</b> of drill motor <b>13</b> with one hand to operate the drill, while holding support arm <b>29</b> and ratchet handle <b>75</b> of drill guide <b>11</b> with the other hand to operate tensioning mechanism <b>35</b>. When the operator squeezes handle <b>75</b> toward arm <b>29</b>, operation of ratchet assembly <b>35</b> and rotation of shaft <b>87</b> tensions strap <b>36</b> by wrapping strap <b>36</b> around shaft <b>87</b> decreasing the lengths (l) and (l&#x2032;) of strap <b>36</b> between guide posts <b>31</b> and <b>33</b>, respectively, and workpiece <b>14</b> equally (thereby maintaining substantially constant lateral pressure at each side of drill motor <b>13</b> at tensioning continues) and securing strap <b>36</b> in slot <b>125</b> of shaft <b>87</b> when taut.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As ratcheting continues, drill bit <b>57</b> in drill motor <b>24</b> is drawn into contact with workpiece <b>14</b> in a relatively constant directional orientation relative to the workpiece since mounting assembly <b>17</b> and operational guide assembly <b>19</b> are relatively aligned and operate together to apply work force substantially equally from opposite sides of drill motor <b>13</b>, and with drill motor <b>13</b> stabilized at both the front and rear of the drill motor in mounting assembly. The maintenance of such relatively constant directional orientation helps alleviate slipping and binding common to such operations.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The operator continues to operate ratchet handle <b>75</b> as necessary during drilling to maintain stability and substantially constant pressure between workpiece <b>14</b> and drill bit <b>57</b> as the bit enters the workpiece. When drilling is complete, the operator depresses latch release <b>101</b> at ratchet assembly <b>35</b> allowing ratchet gear <b>85</b> and thus shaft <b>87</b> to rotate in the opposite direction thereby releasing tension on interface <b>36</b> allowing it to be removed from around workpiece <b>14</b>. When not in use, band <b>18</b> is loosened so that resilient gripping limbs <b>51</b> and <b>53</b> readily release drill motor <b>13</b> due to spring like operation of support bracket <b>21</b> encouraged by contoured sections <b>55</b> and <b>56</b>. Drill motor <b>13</b> is thus readily made available for use or storage separately from portable hand held drill guide <b>11</b>. Interface strap <b>36</b> may be wound for storage at reel <b>107</b> when drill guide <b>11</b> is not in use.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An attitude independent portable drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor, said drill guide comprising:
<claim-text>a mounting assembly including spaced resilient gripping limbs and a securing band maintained around said limbs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operational guide assembly connected with said mounting assembly and including a support arm bracket, first and second spaced guide posts connected with said support arm bracket, and a tensioning mechanism mounted at said support arm bracket, said tensioning mechanism including a slotted shaft rotatably maintained therethrough, said slotted shaft having an extended shaft half, said guide posts located between said shaft of said tensioning mechanism and said limbs of said mounting assembly, said shaft and said limbs aligned centrally relative to said spaced guide posts; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a workpiece engageble interface maintainable around said guide posts and at said slotted shaft of said tensioning mechanism, whereby said extended shaft half is provided for ease of interface insertion at said slotted shaft.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The portable drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said guide posts each include a retainer adjacent thereto for receiving said interface therebeneath adjacent to said guide posts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The portable drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said retainer at said second guide post defines a slot closed at both ends and said retainer at said first guide post defines a slot open at one end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The portable drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein at least one of said limbs includes a retainer bar for receiving and retaining said securing band thereat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The portable drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said limbs of said mounting assembly each include arcuate limb sections contoured toward one another to improve gripping securement of the drill motor and ready release thereof due to spring like operation of said limbs thus configured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A hand held drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor with a pistol-type grip extending from a main body, said drill guide comprising:
<claim-text>a support arm bracket having a support arm extending therefrom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drill motor support bracket including a rear wall attached to said support arm bracket and having first and second spaced resilient limbs configured to receive the drill motor main body thereat, said first and second limbs each including an arcuate limb section, said limb sections contoured toward one another;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a band at said limbs including a tightness varying mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second spaced guide posts connected with said support arm bracket and positioned thereat at opposite sides of said rear wall of said drill motor support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ratchet assembly mounted at said support arm bracket, said ratchet assembly including a slotted shaft rotatably maintained through said support arm bracket and having an extended shaft half for ease of insertion thereinto, said shaft and said limbs aligned centrally relative to said spaced guide posts; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a workpiece engaging strap maintainable around said guide posts and insertable at said slotted shaft of said ratchet assembly.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising a rotatable storage reel holding one end of said strap and freely rotatable at a mount at one of said support arm bracket and said support arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said ratchet assembly includes a ratchet handle operative in association with said support arm by a user of the tool to tension said strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein said shaft is operable by manipulation of said ratchet handle, said shaft holding said strap at one end of said strap and at an intermediate location along said strap spaced from said one end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said drill motor support bracket includes a yieldable member maintained at said rear wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein said yieldable member has a conforming surface adapted to receive and be caused to grip a rear portion of the pistol-type grip of the drill motor positioned thereat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said guide posts each include a slot defining retainer adjacent thereto for receiving said strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An attitude independent portable drill guide for use with a hand held drill motor, said drill guide comprising:
<claim-text>a mounting assembly including spaced resilient gripping limbs and a securing band maintained around said limbs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operational guide assembly connected with said mounting assembly and including a support arm bracket, first and second spaced guide posts connected with said support arm bracket and each including a retainer adjacent thereto, wherein said retainer at said second guide post defines a slot closed at both ends and said retainer at said first guide post defines a slot open at one end, and a tensioning mechanism mounted at said support arm bracket with a slotted shaft thereof rotatably maintained therethrough, said guide posts located between said shaft of said tensioning mechanism and said limbs of said mounting assembly, said shaft and said limbs aligned centrally relative to said spaced guide posts; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a workpiece engageble interface receivable beneath said retainer adjacent to said guide posts so that said interface is maintainable around said guide posts and at said slotted shaft of said tensioning mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The portable drill guide of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said slotted shaft includes an extended shaft half for ease of interface insertion thereinto. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
