<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625563-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625563</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13686607</doc-number>
<date>20121127</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>4</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370338</main-classification>
<further-classification>370444</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e51">Conduit-sharing apparatus, systems, and methods</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6125110</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Proctor et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6560443</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Vaisanen et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6640239</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Gidwani</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6659947</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Carter et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7146133</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bahl et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0010689</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Awater et al.</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0028655</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rosener et al.</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0136233</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen et al.</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0141376</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kandala</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0050015</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kelly et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0108062</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Agrawal et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0192222</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Vaisanen et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370310</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370312-314</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>370328-339</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12637303</doc-number>
<date>20091214</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8320348</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13686607</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10742012</doc-number>
<date>20031217</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7633912</doc-number>
<date>20091215</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12637303</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Marvell International Ltd.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Hamilton</city>
<country>BM</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>BM</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fleming</last-name>
<first-name>Kristoffer D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Marvell International Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hamilton</city>
<country>BM</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Duong</last-name>
<first-name>Frank</first-name>
<department>2474</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus and a system, as well as a method and article, may operate to share an energy conduit, such as an antenna, between first data communicated according to a first formatting mechanism and second data communicated according to a second formatting mechanism according to a first priority assigned to the first data and a second priority assigned to the second data. The first formatting mechanism may be different from the second formatting mechanism.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.99mm" wi="192.53mm" file="US08625563-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="206.59mm" wi="162.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625563-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="201.34mm" wi="185.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625563-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="215.82mm" wi="173.99mm" file="US08625563-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="175.01mm" wi="132.50mm" file="US08625563-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">INCORPORATION BY REFERENCE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/637,303, filed Dec. 14, 2009, which is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/742,012, filed Dec. 17, 2003, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,633,912. The disclosures of the prior applications are incorporated herein by reference in their entireties.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Various embodiments described herein relate to communications generally, such as apparatus, systems, and methods used to transmit and receive information, including data packets.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Various protocols, media definitions, and other formatting mechanisms may operate to determine how data may be communicated. Examples of these mechanisms include spread-spectrum techniques, the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) 802.11 standards, and the Bluetooth Specification. Some communications devices, including wireless computing platforms, may use such mechanisms to communicate with other entities, using a single antenna or other wireless energy conduit.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Assuming an increasing consumer demand for multimedia communications, the need may arise to share a single energy conduit between two or more data streams, formatted according to a number of mechanisms (e.g., IEEE 802.11 and Bluetooth) as the data is communicated from one device to another. For more information regarding some of the formatting mechanisms mentioned above, please refer to &#x201c;IEEE Standards for Information Technology&#x2014;Telecommunications and Information Exchange between Systems&#x2014;Local and Metropolitan Area Network&#x2014;Specific Requirements&#x2014;Part 11: Wireless LAN Medium Access Control (MAC) and Physical Layer (PHY), ISO/IEC 8802-11: 1999&#x201d; and &#x201c;Bluetooth System Specification, Bluetooth Special Interest Group, Ver. 1.1, March 2001&#x201d;, and related amendments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a conceptual diagram of an apparatus and a system according to various embodiments;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of an apparatus and a system according to various embodiments;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart illustrating several methods according to various embodiments; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of an article according to various embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">During the process of communicating information, wireless devices may operate to optimize communications by sharing a single energy conduit, such as an antenna. For example, to support the communication of real time data in some embodiments of the invention, a single antenna may be shared via time division multiplexing between various formatting mechanisms, such as Bluetooth and IEEE 802.11. To determine how the antenna may be shared, priority information may be attached to data packets and used to evaluate the order of the data to be sent or received.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">For example, an IEEE 802.1Q priority tag may be used to identify the suggested priority of data contained in various packets, as assigned by an Operating System (OS) or networking application. The priority information can be used by routers and/or bridges in a network to order packets in their data queues. In some embodiments, packets with high-ranking IEEE 802.1Q priority tags can be placed at the beginning of transmission queues, perhaps operating to reduce the latency of intermediate nodes in the path of individual packets as they travel to their ultimate destination.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">For the purposes of this document, the term &#x201c;energy conduit&#x201d; includes any type of device or apparatus that has the capability to transmit and/or receive energy to and/or from space. Examples of such energy conduits include antennas, infra-red transmitters, infra-red receivers, photo-emitters (e.g., light emitting diodes), photo-receptors (e.g., a photocell), and charge-coupled devices, among others.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A &#x201c;formatting mechanism&#x201d; includes any rule or guide for formatting data as it is communicated, with respect to time, space, frequency, and/or some other organizing function. Examples of such formatting mechanisms include communications standards (e.g., IEEE 802.11, Bluetooth), communications protocols (e.g., transmission control protocol/Internet protocol), spread-spectrum communications techniques, multiple carrier communications techniques (e.g., orthogonal frequency division multiplexing), a data format (e.g., time division, multiple access), and various data types (e.g., binary, alphanumeric, audio, video).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A &#x201c;priority&#x201d; may mean any indication or information which permits determining the order of transmission and/or reception of data associated with one formatting mechanism over data associated with another formatting mechanism, so as to permit ranking, for example, a unit of data (e.g., a first packet) associated with a first priority against another unit of data (e.g., a second packet) associated with a second priority. Examples of a priority include a priority tag attached to data according to the IEEE 802.1Q standard.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The term &#x201c;transceiver&#x201d; (e.g., a device including a transmitter and a receiver) may be used in place of either &#x201c;transmitter&#x201d; or &#x201c;receiver&#x201d; throughout this document. For more specific information regarding the 802.1 Q standard, please refer to &#x201c;IEEE Standards for Local and Metropolitan Area Networks&#x2014;Virtual Bridged Local Area Networks&#x2014;IEEE Std. 802.1Q, 2003 Edition, and later versions.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a conceptual diagram of an apparatus <b>100</b> and a system <b>110</b> according to various embodiments. In this figure, a specific implementation of some embodiments is shown for simplicity, and it should not be used to limit the embodiments disclosed. Here it may be assumed that two formatting mechanisms are involved: IEEE 802.11 and Bluetooth. Of course, other formatting mechanisms can be used, and other numbers of formatting mechanisms can be used. In any case, the system <b>110</b> may include a software environment <b>112</b> having a module <b>114</b> operating according to the Microsoft&#xae; Network Driver Interface Specification (NDIS) to assign 802.1Q priority tags to data packets. For more information regarding the Microsoft&#xae; NDIS, please refer to the Microsoft Developer Network web site at http://msdn-microsoft-com/default-aspx (to avoid inadvertent hyperlinks the periods in the preceding URL have been replaced by dashes).</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The packets may be sent to NDIS drivers, for example, an 802.11 NDIS driver <b>116</b> and a Bluetooth NDIS driver <b>118</b>. The Bluetooth NDIS driver <b>118</b>, in turn, may send such packets on to a Bluetooth bus driver <b>122</b>, which may also receive packets having 802.1Q priority tags attached by other entities <b>126</b> and <b>127</b>. In some embodiments, priorities are assigned in a software environment <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Thus, each packet waiting to be sent may receive an IEEE 802.1Q priority tag, to be compared with other priority tags. Many methods are available to assign priorities, including hardware and software elements, such as networking applications. Priority tag information, such as data priority level and management priority level, may be shared and/or compared between formatting mechanisms using a hardware bus and/or software, such as registers and/or a memory.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The system <b>110</b> may include one or more of the apparatus <b>100</b>, which may in turn include a hardware environment <b>134</b> to receive packets from the software environment <b>112</b>. An entity representing each formatting mechanism (e.g., one or more hardware and/or software modules <b>135</b>-<b>138</b> located in hardware specific to particular formatting mechanisms) may compare priorities, perhaps using a bus <b>140</b>. The data associated with the greatest determined priority may be granted first access to the energy conduit <b>142</b>, such as an antenna.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the event that competing priorities are found to be substantially equal, then an arbitrator scheme, including a distributed arbitrator scheme, may be used to determine whether data associated with one formatting mechanism or the other will be communicated using the antenna. Such a scheme can vary in complexity from round-robin selection, to credit-based selection, to sliding window protocols, for example, as such arbitration schemes are known to those of skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Access to the energy conduit (e.g., an antenna) by data associated with each formatting mechanism may be limited in time, and signals may be used to indicate when use of the antenna is complete, perhaps restarting the process to gain control of the antenna. When access to the antenna has been granted to data associated with a particular formatting mechanism, the data may be transmitted at that time, and/or the time may be used to listen for traffic.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of an apparatus <b>200</b> and a system <b>210</b> according to various embodiments, each of which may operate in the manner described above. Thus, the apparatus <b>200</b> and the system <b>210</b> may be similar to or identical to the apparatus <b>100</b> and system <b>110</b> described previously (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">For example, an apparatus <b>200</b> may comprise a determination module <b>246</b> to determine whether a first priority P<b>1</b> assigned to first data <b>250</b> associated with a first formatting mechanism F<b>1</b> is greater than a second priority P<b>2</b> assigned to second data <b>254</b> associated with a second formatting mechanism F<b>2</b>. The first formatting mechanism F<b>1</b> may be different than the second formatting mechanism F<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The apparatus <b>200</b> may include an assignment module <b>258</b> to assign the first priority P<b>1</b> to the first data <b>250</b>, as well as to assign the second priority P<b>2</b> to the second data <b>254</b>. As noted previously, the first and second formatting mechanisms F<b>1</b>, F<b>2</b> may be selected from one or more of a communications standard, a communications protocol, a spread-spectrum communications technique, a data format, and a data type, among others.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Each of the priorities P<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b> may be indicated by or stored as a priority tag attached to the data <b>250</b>, <b>254</b> according to an IEEE 802.1Q standard. The apparatus <b>200</b> may also include a steering mechanism <b>262</b> to direct either the first data <b>250</b> or the second data <b>254</b> so as to be communicated through space via an energy conduit <b>242</b>. The steering mechanism <b>262</b> may include a hardware module (e.g., a physical switch) and/or a software module (e.g., one or more program branch instructions), or a combination of these, as desired. Other embodiments may be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">For example, a system <b>210</b> may include an apparatus <b>200</b>, similar to or identical to the apparatus <b>100</b> described above (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), as well as an energy conduit <b>242</b> to communicate either the first data or the second data through space for reception by some other device (not shown). The system <b>210</b> may include a hardware bus <b>240</b> to share the first priority P<b>1</b> and the second priority P<b>2</b>, as well as a memory <b>266</b> to store the first priority P<b>1</b> and the second priority P<b>2</b>. The memory <b>266</b> may also be used to store the first data <b>250</b> and the second data <b>254</b>. The system <b>210</b> may also include one or more receivers, transmitters, and/or transceivers X<b>1</b>, X<b>2</b> to selectively couple the first data <b>250</b> and the second data <b>254</b> to the energy conduit <b>242</b>, perhaps via the steering mechanism <b>262</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The apparatus <b>100</b>, <b>200</b>, systems <b>110</b>, <b>210</b>, modules <b>112</b>, <b>258</b>, NDIS drivers <b>114</b>, <b>118</b>, bus driver <b>122</b>, entities <b>126</b>-<b>127</b>, software environment <b>130</b>, hardware environment <b>134</b>, modules <b>135</b>-<b>138</b>, buses <b>140</b>, <b>240</b>, energy conduits <b>142</b>, <b>242</b>, determination module <b>246</b>, data <b>250</b>, <b>254</b>, formatting mechanisms F<b>1</b>, F<b>2</b>, priorities P<b>1</b>, P<b>2</b>, steering mechanism <b>262</b>, and memory <b>266</b> may all be characterized as &#x201c;modules&#x201d; herein. Such modules may include hardware circuitry, and/or one or more processors and/or memory circuits, software program modules, including objects and collections of objects, and/or firmware, and combinations thereof, as desired by the architect of the apparatus <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and the systems <b>110</b>, <b>210</b>, and as appropriate for particular implementations of various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It should also be understood that the apparatus and systems of various embodiments can be used in applications other than transmitters and receivers, and other than for wireless systems, and thus, various embodiments are not to be so limited. The illustrations of an apparatus <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> and systems <b>110</b>, <b>210</b> are intended to provide a general understanding of the structure of various embodiments, and they are not intended to serve as a complete description of all the elements and features of apparatus and systems that might make use of the structures described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Applications that may include the novel apparatus and systems of various embodiments include electronic circuitry used in high-speed computers, communication and signal processing circuitry, modems, processor modules, embedded processors, data switches, and application-specific modules, including multilayer, multi-chip modules. Such apparatus and systems may further be included as sub-components within a variety of electronic systems, such as televisions, cellular telephones, personal computers, personal digital assistants (PDAs), workstations, radios, video players, vehicles, and others.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart illustrating several methods according to various embodiments. In some embodiments of the invention, a method <b>311</b> may begin with assigning a first priority to first data associated with a first formatting mechanism, and assigning a second priority to second data associated with a second formatting mechanism at block <b>321</b>. For example, priority may be indicated by a priority tag attached to the first and/or second data according to the IEEE 802.1Q standard. The method <b>311</b> may continue at block <b>325</b> with sharing the first priority and the second priority using a hardware bus, or a memory, for example, to enable determining the greatest priority by various hardware and/or software elements.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The method <b>311</b> may include sharing an energy conduit between the first data communicated according to the first formatting mechanism and second data communicated according to the second formatting mechanism at block <b>331</b>. The energy conduit may be selected from a number of elements, and combinations of elements, including antennas, infra-red transmitters and/or receivers, photo-emitters and receptors, and charge-coupled devices, among others.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As noted above, the first formatting mechanism may be different from the second formatting mechanism, and either formatting mechanism may be selected from one or more of a communications standard, a communications protocol, a spread-spectrum communications technique, a data format, and a data type. For example, if the formatting mechanisms are selected from among communications standards, these may be selected to include an IEEE 802.11 standard and a Bluetooth System Specification. Sharing the conduit may be accomplished according to the first priority assigned to the first data and the second priority assigned to the second data.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">For example, sharing the energy conduit at block <b>331</b> may further include determining which of the priorities is greatest. Thus, the method <b>311</b> may include determining whether the first priority is greater than the second priority at block <b>335</b>. If so, the method <b>311</b> may include selecting the energy conduit to communicate the first data at block <b>341</b>, and then (optionally) continue with assigning new priorities at block <b>321</b>. The method <b>311</b> may also include determining whether the second priority is greater than the first priority at block <b>345</b>. If so, the method <b>311</b> may include selecting the energy conduit to communicate the second data at block <b>351</b>, and then (optionally) continue with assigning new priorities at block <b>321</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">If it is determined that the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal (e.g., the first priority is not greater than the second priority, and the second priority is not greater than the first priority, as determined at blocks <b>335</b> and <b>345</b>), then the method <b>311</b> may include activating an arbitration mechanism to determine whether the energy conduit will be selected for communicating the first data or the second data at block <b>355</b>, and then selecting the conduit to communicate the appropriate data at block <b>361</b>, as described above. The method <b>311</b> may (optionally) continue with assigning new priorities at block <b>321</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It should be noted that the methods described herein do not have to, be executed in the order described, or in any particular order. Moreover, various activities described with respect to the methods identified herein can be executed in serial or parallel fashion. For the purposes of this document, the terms &#x201c;information&#x201d; and &#x201c;data&#x201d; may be used interchangeably. Information, including parameters, commands, operands, and other data, can be sent and received in the form of one or more carrier waves.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Upon reading and comprehending the content of this disclosure, one of ordinary skill in the art will understand the manner in which a software program can be launched from a computer-readable medium in a computer-based system to execute the functions defined in the software program. One of ordinary skill in the art will further understand the various programming languages that may be employed to create one or more software programs designed to implement and perform the methods disclosed herein. The programs may be structured in an object-orientated format using an object-oriented language such as Java, Smalltalk, or C++. Alternatively, the programs can be structured in a procedure-orientated format using a procedural language, such as assembly or C. The software components may communicate using any of a number of mechanisms well-known to those skilled in the art, such as application program interfaces or inter-process communication techniques, including remote procedure calls. The teachings of various embodiments are not limited to any particular programming language or environment, including Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) and Extensible Markup Language (XML). Thus, other embodiments may be realized, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of an article <b>485</b> according to various embodiments, such as a computer, a memory system, a magnetic or optical disk, some other storage device, and/or any type of electronic device or system. The article <b>485</b> may comprise a processor <b>487</b> coupled to a machine-accessible medium such as a memory <b>489</b> (e.g., a memory including an electrical, optical, or electromagnetic conductor) having associated information <b>491</b> (e.g., computer program instructions, and/or other data), which when accessed, results in a machine (e.g., the processor <b>487</b>) performing such actions as sharing an energy conduit between first data communicated according to a first formatting mechanism and second data communicated according to a second formatting mechanism. The first and second formatting mechanisms may be different. The energy conduit may be shared according to a first priority assigned to the first data and a second priority assigned to the second data.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In some embodiments, the energy conduit may be selected from one of an antenna, an infra-red transmitter, an infra-red receiver, a photo-emitter, a photo-receptor, and a charge-coupled device. Either of the formatting mechanisms may be selected from one of a communications standard, a communications protocol, a spread-spectrum communications technique, a data format, and a data type.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Other activities may include determining that either the first or second priority is greater than the second or first priority, respectively, and then selecting the energy conduit to communicate the appropriate data, as described above. Further activities may include determining that the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal, and activating an arbitration mechanism to determine whether the energy conduit will be selected to communicate the first data or the second data.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Implementing the apparatus, systems, and methods described herein may result in using IEEE 802.1Q priority tags to improve communications without changes in existing software. Multiple formatting mechanisms may thus be more readily managed while using a single energy conduit to communicate data.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The accompanying drawings that form a part hereof show by way of illustration, and not of limitation, specific embodiments in which the subject matter may be practiced. The embodiments illustrated are described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the teachings disclosed herein. Other embodiments may be utilized and derived therefrom, such that structural and logical substitutions and changes may be made without departing from the scope of this disclosure. This Detailed Description, therefore, is not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of various embodiments is defined only by the appended claims, along with the full range of equivalents to which such claims are entitled.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Thus, although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, it should be appreciated that any arrangement calculated to achieve the same purpose may be substituted for the specific embodiments shown. This disclosure is intended to cover any and all adaptations or variations of various embodiments. Combinations of the above embodiments, and other embodiments not specifically described herein, will be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reviewing the above description.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The Abstract of the Disclosure is provided to comply with 37 C.F.R. &#xa7;1.72(b), requiring an abstract that will allow the reader to quickly ascertain the nature of the technical disclosure. It is submitted with the understanding that it will not be used to interpret or limit the scope or meaning of the claims. In addition, in the foregoing Detailed Description, it can be seen that various features are grouped together in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This method of disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an intention that the claimed embodiments require more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter lies in less than all features of a single disclosed embodiment. Thus the following claims are hereby incorporated into the Detailed Description, with each claim standing on its own as a separate embodiment.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for transmitting data packets, the method comprising:
<claim-text>formatting a first data ticket by a first formatting mechanism in accordance with a first communication protocol;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning a first priority to the first data packet formatted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>formatting a second data packet by a second formatting mechanism in accordance with a second communication protocol that is different from the first communication protocol;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning a second priority to the second data packet formatted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a priority tag to each of the first data packet and the second data packet, the priority tag including at least data priority level and management priority level that are shared and compared between the first formatting mechanism and the second formatting mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining one of the first priority and the second priority as having a higher priority than the other; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting by a transmitter one of the first data packet and the second data packet having the higher priority over a single energy conduit prior to transmitting the other of the first data packet and the second data packet over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the assigning the first priority to the first data packet and assigning the second priority to the second data packet comprises attaching a priority tag to each of the first data packet and the second data packet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the attaching the priority tag comprises attaching the priority tag including an IEEE 802.1Q priority tag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>formatting the first data packet in accordance with the first communication protocol that is an IEEE 802.11 protocol; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>formatting the second data packet in accordance with the second communication protocol that is a Bluetooth protocol.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transmitting over the single energy conduit comprises transmitting over the single energy conduit that is an antenna, an infrared transmitter, a photo emitter, or a charge coupled device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining that the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>activating an arbitration mechanism to select one of the first data packet and the second data packet when the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the selected one over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first formatting mechanism configured to format a first data packet in accordance with a first communication protocol:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second formatting mechanism configured to format a second data packet in accordance with a second communication protocol that is different from the first communication protocol:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assignment module configured to assign a first priority to the first data packet formatted, assign a second priority to the second data packet formatted, and attach a priority tag to each of the first data packet and the second data packet, the priority tag including at least data priority level and management priority level that are shared and compared between the first formatting mechanism and the second formatting mechanism:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a determination module configured to determine one of the first priority and the second priority as having a higher priority than the other; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmitter configured to transmit one of the first data packet and the second data packet having the higher priority over a single energy conduit prior to transmitting the other of the first data packet and the second data packet over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first communication protocol is an IEEE 802.11 protocol and the second communication protocol is a Bluetooth protocol.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a steering mechanism configured to steer the first data packet or the second data packet to the single energy conduit for transmission.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the steering mechanism comprises a switch.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the single energy conduit is an antenna, an infrared transmitter, a photo emitter, or a charge coupled device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the apparatus comprises a television, a cellular phone, a personal computer, a personal digital assistant, a workstation, a radio, a video player, or a vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the determination module is further configured to determine that the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal and activate an arbitration mechanism to select one of the first data packet and the second data packet when the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal, and the transmitter is further configured to transmit the selected one over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A computer program, tangibly stored on a computer readable non-transitory medium, the computer program being executable by a processor and comprising instructions for:
<claim-text>formatting a first data packet by a first formatting mechanism in accordance with a first communication protocol;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning a first priority to the first data packet formatted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>formatting a second data packet by a second formatting mechanism in accordance with a second communication protocol that is different from the first communication protocol;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning a second priority to the second data packet formatted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a priority tag to each of the first data packet and the second data packet, the priority tag including at least data priority level and management priority level that are shared and compared between the first formatting mechanism and the second formatting mechanism; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining one of the first priority and the second priority as having a higher priority than the other, and transmitting one of the first data packet and the second data packet having the higher priority over a single energy conduit prior to transmitting the other of the first data packet and the second data packet over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The computer program of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the instructions for assigning the first priority to the first data packet and the instructions for assigning the second priority to the second data packet comprise instructions for attaching a priority tag to each of the first data packet and the second data packet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The computer program of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the priority tag comprises an IEEE 802.1Q priority tag.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The computer program of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the first communication protocol is an IEEE 802.11 protocol and the second communication protocol is a Bluetooth protocol.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The computer program of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the single energy conduit is an antenna, an infrared transmitter, a photo emitter, or a charge coupled device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The computer program of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprises instructions for:
<claim-text>determining that the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>activating an arbitration mechanism to select one of the first data packet and the second data packet when the first priority and the second priority are substantially equal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the selected one over the single energy conduit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
