<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624378-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624378</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13223441</doc-number>
<date>20110901</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>165</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257691</main-classification>
<further-classification>257723</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Chip-housing module and a method for forming a chip-housing module</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5714801</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yano et al.</name>
<date>19980200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257691</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6967398</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Frech et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257691</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7378733</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hoang et al.</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257724</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257685</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257691</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257723</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257774</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E21499</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E23001</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130056877</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130307</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Otremba</last-name>
<first-name>Ralf</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaufbeuren</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Otremba</last-name>
<first-name>Ralf</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaufbeuren</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Infineon Technologies AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Neubiberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vu</last-name>
<first-name>Hung</first-name>
<department>2897</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A chip-housing module including a carrier configured to carry one or more chips; the carrier including: a first plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings is separated by a first pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip; a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a second pre-determined distance, and configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip; and wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance, is provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="79.42mm" wi="152.40mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="159.77mm" wi="162.73mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="237.74mm" wi="199.73mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="152.91mm" wi="145.97mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="185.25mm" wi="183.81mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="222.42mm" wi="207.69mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="246.63mm" wi="187.28mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="182.46mm" wi="189.91mm" file="US08624378-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Various embodiments relate generally to a chip-housing module and a method for forming a chip-housing module.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Traditionally, high-voltage power semiconductors have been arranged in discrete housing modules, e.g. TO220-3, e.g. TO247-3, as shown in illustration <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, so as to ensure that high-voltage components are well insulated from each other. As such housings are generally very large, such practice, results in massive board space limitations for the high-voltage power semiconductor housings.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">An embodiment provides a chip-housing module, including a carrier configured to carry one or more chips; the carrier including a first plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings is separated by a first pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip; the carrier including a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a second pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip; and wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the drawings, like reference characters generally refer to the same parts throughout the different views. The drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead generally being placed upon illustrating the principles of the invention. In the following description, various embodiments of the invention are described with reference to the following drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a housing for high-voltage chips;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows a high voltage application lamp ballast circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> shows a first high-voltage chip in electrical connection with a second high-voltage chip;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a chip-housing module for a single chip;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A to 4G</figref> show a chip-housing module according to various embodiments;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a method for forming a chip-housing module.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The following detailed description refers to the accompanying drawings that show, by way of illustration, specific details and embodiments in which the invention may be practiced.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A multi-chip module (MCM) for housing high-voltage power semiconductors is needed, to increase the integration density of power semiconductors in high-voltage applications. High-voltage applications may include high-voltage components e.g. AC/DC converters, motor drivers, power factor correction devices and switch mode power supplies SMPS.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Multi-chip modules may be used to house a plurality of discrete components, e.g. high-voltage chips. The high-voltage chips may be in electrical connection with each other, e.g. chips which may be connected in a half-bridge configuration, e.g. chips which may be connected in a full-bridge configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Illustration <b>200</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows according to an embodiment, a high voltage application such as a lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b> including a half-bridge architecture. Lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b> may include a plurality of chips, e.g. <b>204</b>, <b>224</b>, <b>244</b>. Each of the plurality of chips may include a high-voltage transistor, e.g. a CoolMOS&#x2122; 500V transistor, e.g. a LightMOS&#x2122; 600V transistor. Lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b> may include a plurality of chips, e.g. a first chip <b>204</b> and a second chip <b>224</b> electrically connected, e.g. electrically connected in a half-bridge configuration, e.g. electrically connected in a full-bridge configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">First chip <b>204</b> may include a first transistor <b>206</b> formed in first chip <b>204</b>, first transistor <b>206</b> including a first terminal <b>208</b>, e.g. a first source/drain terminal, a second terminal <b>212</b>, e.g. a second source/drain terminal, and a third terminal <b>214</b>, e.g. a gate terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Second chip <b>224</b> may include a second transistor <b>226</b> formed in second chip <b>224</b>, second transistor <b>226</b> including a first terminal <b>228</b>, e.g. a first source/drain terminal, a second terminal <b>232</b>, e.g. a second source/drain terminal, and a third terminal <b>234</b>, e.g. a gate terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b> may include a third chip <b>244</b>. Third chip <b>244</b> may include a third transistor <b>246</b> formed in third chip <b>244</b>, third transistor <b>246</b> including a first terminal <b>248</b>, e.g. a first source/drain terminal, a second terminal <b>252</b>, e.g. a second source/drain terminal, and a third terminal <b>254</b>, e.g. a gate terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">First chip <b>204</b> may be in connection with second chip <b>224</b>. First chip <b>204</b> may be in electrical connection with second chip <b>224</b>. First chip <b>204</b> may be in electrical connection with second chip <b>224</b> via an electrically conducting interface <b>238</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Second terminal <b>212</b>, e.g. second source/drain terminal <b>212</b> of transistor <b>206</b> formed in first chip <b>204</b>, may be in electrical connection with first terminal <b>228</b>, e.g. first source/drain terminal <b>228</b> of transistor <b>226</b> formed in second chip <b>224</b>. Second terminal <b>232</b>, e.g. second source/drain terminal <b>232</b> of transistor <b>226</b> formed in second chip <b>224</b> may be electrically connected to a first terminal of bulk capacitor <b>236</b>. First terminal <b>208</b>, e.g. first source/drain terminal <b>212</b> of transistor <b>206</b> formed in first chip <b>204</b>, may be electrically connected to a second terminal of bulk capacitor <b>236</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A power supply <b>216</b> may be configured to supply a voltage ranging from about 85 V to about 265V to lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b>. A first terminal of power supply <b>216</b> may be connected to a first terminal of a resistor <b>218</b>. A second terminal of the resistor <b>218</b> may be connected to a first terminal <b>248</b> of a transistor <b>246</b> formed in third chip <b>244</b>, and further connected to a first terminal of a diode <b>222</b>. First terminal <b>248</b> of a transistor <b>246</b> may be connected to the first terminal of diode <b>222</b>. Second terminal <b>252</b> of transistor <b>246</b> may be connected to a second terminal of power supply <b>216</b>. A second terminal of diode <b>222</b> may be connected to a first terminal of a bulk capacitor <b>236</b>. Second terminal <b>252</b> of transistor <b>246</b> may be connected to a second terminal of the bulk capacitor <b>236</b>. Therefore, bulk capacitor <b>236</b> may be connected in parallel with transistor <b>246</b> and diode <b>222</b>. The first terminal of diode <b>222</b> may include an input terminal of diode <b>222</b>. The second terminal of diode <b>222</b> may include an output terminal of diode <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The second terminal of diode <b>222</b> and the first terminal of bulk capacitor <b>236</b> may be connected to second terminal <b>232</b> of transistor <b>226</b>. Second terminal of bulk capacitor <b>236</b> and second terminal <b>252</b> of transistor <b>246</b> may be connected to first terminal <b>208</b> of transistor <b>206</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Electrically conducting interface <b>238</b> may be connected to a first terminal of further resistor <b>242</b> and a first terminal of capacitor <b>256</b>. Second terminal of capacitor <b>256</b> may be connected to first terminal <b>208</b> of transistor <b>206</b>. Second terminal of resistor <b>242</b> may be connected to a first terminal of further capacitor <b>258</b>. Second terminal of further capacitor <b>258</b> may be connected to a first terminal of lamp <b>262</b>. Second terminal of capacitor <b>256</b> may be connected to a second terminal of lamp <b>262</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Transistor <b>206</b> formed in first chip <b>204</b> may include a high-voltage transistor, e.g. a LightMOS&#x2122; 600V. Transistor <b>226</b> formed in first chip <b>224</b> may include a high-voltage transistor, e.g. a LightMOS&#x2122; 600V. Transistor <b>246</b> formed in third chip <b>244</b> may include a high-voltage transistor, e.g. a CoolMOS&#x2122; 500V.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A plurality of high-voltage transistors, e.g. high-voltage power transistors, e.g. transistors <b>206</b>, <b>226</b>, <b>246</b> could not be housed in a chip-housing module, such as the chip-module shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, which is only suitable for housing a single chip. Therefore, a chip-housing module, e.g. a multi-chip module, is needed to house a plurality of high-voltage chips. The chip-housing module, e.g. a multi-chip module, may be used to house at least part of a circuit including one or more high-voltage chips, e.g. power transistors, in electrical connection with each other. The chip-housing module may be used to house a plurality of transistors electrically connected to each other, e.g. electrically connected in a half-bridge configuration, e.g. electrically connected in a full-bridge configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A chip-housing module, e.g. multi-chip module may be used to house at least part of a circuit, e.g. at least part of a lamp ballast circuit <b>202</b>, the at least part of the circuit <b>202</b> including first chip <b>204</b> and second chip <b>224</b> electrically connected to each other, e.g. electrically connected in a half-bridge configuration, e.g. electrically connected in a full-bridge configuration, as shown in illustration <b>210</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>. A chip, e.g. first chip <b>204</b>, e.g. second chip <b>224</b>, may include a semiconductor chip. A chip, e.g. first chip <b>204</b>, e.g. second chip <b>224</b> may include at least part of a transistor, e.g. at least part of a high-voltage transistor, e.g. at least part of a power transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> shows a chip-housing module <b>400</b> according to an embodiment. Chip-housing module <b>400</b> may include a carrier <b>464</b> configured to carry one or more chips, e.g. chip <b>204</b> and chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Carrier <b>464</b> may include a first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may be separated by a first pre-determined distance x, and may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Carrier may include a second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c</i>, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be separated by a second pre-determined distance y, and may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Chip-housing module <b>400</b> as described according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> may include a first and second plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c</i>, <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>which may be configured to receive chip connections including at least part of a chip, e.g. chip <b>204</b>, e.g. chip <b>244</b>. A chip, e.g. chip <b>204</b>, e.g. chip <b>244</b> may include at least one chip connection. A chip connection may include an electrically conductive element, e.g. an electrically conductive wire, e.g. an electrically conductive pin, e.g. an electrically conductive chip pad.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">One or more of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may each be configured to receive a chip connection including at least one of an electrically conductive element, an electrically conductive wire, an electrically conductive wire, and an electrically conductive pin.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">One or more of the first and second plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c</i>, <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may each be configured to receive a chip connection including at least part of a semiconductor power transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">A pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be separated by a distance z different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The distance z separating a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be larger than at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y, and the voltage values in the second range of voltage values are larger than the voltage values in the first range of voltage values by a pre-determined voltage value.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The pair of openings may include a plurality of pairs of openings, each pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>separated by a distance z different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The voltage values in the first range of voltage values may represent voltage values in a first voltage class. Therefore, each opening, e.g. opening <b>466</b><i>a</i>, opening <b>466</b><i>b</i>, and opening <b>466</b><i>c</i>, of a first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip. The first range of voltage values may belong to a first voltage class with voltage values lying in the range from between about 0 V to less than about 100 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 25 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 30 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 40 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 60 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 75 V, e.g. from about 0 V to about 100 V. The separation distance between each opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>i.e. the first pre-determined distance, may be less than 1 mm if the voltages lying within the first range of voltage values differ by less than 100 V.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The voltage values in the second range of voltage values may represent voltage values in a second voltage class. Therefore, each opening, e.g. opening <b>468</b><i>a</i>, opening <b>468</b><i>b</i>, and opening <b>468</b><i>c</i>, of a second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip. The second range of voltage values may belong to a second voltage class with voltage values larger than 150 V. The second range of voltage values may belong to a second voltage class with voltage values lying in the range from between about 150 V to less than about 1700 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 200 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 250 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 300 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 600 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 650 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 1700 V. The separation distance between each opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c</i>, i.e. the second pre-determined distance, may be less than about 1 mm if the voltages lying within the second range of voltage values differ by less than 100 V.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y may be equal. According to an alternative embodiment, the first pre-determined distance x may be different from the second pre-determined distance y. At least one of the first pre-determined distance x and second pre-determined distance y may be less than about 1 mm. Both the first pre-determined distance x and second pre-determined distance y may be less than about 1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The pre-determined voltage may represent a voltage difference between the first voltage class and the second voltage class. The pre-determined voltage value may be larger than 100 V, e.g. may be in the range from about 100 V to about 200 V. The pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values, i.e. the first voltage class, and one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values, i.e. the second voltage class, may be separated by a distance greater than 2 mm, e.g. at a creepage distance of 2.7 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Chip-housing module <b>400</b> may include a surface mount device (SMD) package, e.g. a power quad flat no leads (PQFN) package. Chip-housing module <b>400</b> may have an aspect ratio greater than 3:2. Chip-housing module <b>400</b> may have an aspect ratio greater than 2:1.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The carrier may include at least one from the following group of materials, the group consisting of: Cu, Ni, Fe, NiFe, Sn, S, P, e.g. less than 5% Sn, e.g. less than 5% S, e.g. less than 5% P.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">According to an embodiment, illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>410</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, carrier <b>464</b> of chip-housing module <b>400</b> may be further configured to carry one or more components, <b>484</b> e.g. a driver integrated circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The basic functionalities of the features described with respect to chip-housing module <b>400</b> are applicable to chip-housing module <b>410</b>. Identical features as to those described with respect to chip-housing module <b>400</b> are denoted with the same reference signs.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">According to an embodiment illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>420</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4C</figref>, carrier <b>464</b> of any of chip-housing module <b>400</b> and <b>410</b> may further include a third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c</i>, wherein each opening of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may be separated by a third pre-determined distance q, and may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>and one opening of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may be separated by a distance r different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x, the second pre-determined distance y and the third pre-determined distance q.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The voltage values in the third range of voltage values may represent voltage values in a third voltage class. Therefore, each opening, e.g. opening <b>472</b><i>a</i>, opening <b>472</b><i>b</i>, and opening <b>472</b><i>c </i>of a third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip. The third range of voltage values may belong to a third voltage class with voltage values larger than 150 V. The third range of voltage values may belong to a third voltage class with voltage values lying in the range from between about 150 V to less than about 1700 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 200 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 250 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 300 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 600 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 650 V, e.g. from about 150 V to about 1700 V. The separation distance between each opening of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c</i>, i.e. the third pre-determined distance q, may be less than about 1 mm if the voltages lying within the third range of voltage values differ by less than 100 V.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The further pre-determined voltage may represent a voltage difference between the second voltage class and the third voltage class. The further pre-determined voltage value may be larger than 100 V, e.g. may be in the range from about 100 V to about 200 V. The pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values, i.e. the second voltage class, and one opening of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values, i.e. the third voltage class, may be separated by a distance greater than 2 mm, e.g. at a creepage distance of 2.7 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may include at least one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first chip <b>204</b>; and the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may include at least one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a first chip <b>204</b>, and at least one other opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may include at least one opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may include at least one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first source/drain terminal <b>208</b> of a transistor <b>206</b> formed in the first chip <b>204</b>, and at least one other opening <b>466</b><i>b </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a gate terminal <b>214</b> of the transistor <b>206</b> formed in the first chip <b>204</b>; and wherein the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may include at least one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal <b>212</b> of the transistor <b>206</b> formed in the first chip <b>204</b> and to a first source/drain terminal <b>228</b> of the transistor <b>226</b> formed in the second chip <b>224</b>, and at least one other opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a gate terminal <b>234</b> of a transistor <b>226</b> formed in the second chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The third plurality of openings may include at least one opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal <b>232</b> of the transistor <b>226</b> formed in the second chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Each opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>by a first pre-determined distance x. E.g. opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening <b>466</b><i>b </i>by a first pre-determined distance x, and opening <b>466</b><i>b </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening <b>466</b><i>c </i>by a first pre-determined distance x.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Each opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>by a second pre-determined distance y. E.g. opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>by a second pre-determined distance y, and opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>may be separated from an adjacent opening <b>468</b><i>c </i>by a second pre-determined distance y.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The pair of openings may include a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and one opening of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c</i>, and may be separated by a distance different z from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y. E.g. opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be adjacent and may be separated by a distance z different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y, e.g. opening <b>466</b><i>b </i>of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be adjacent and may be separated by a distance z different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The distance separating a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>and one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>may be larger than at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance, and the voltage values in the second range of voltage values are larger than the voltage values in the first range of voltage values by a pre-determined voltage value.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The distance r separating a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>and at least one opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may be different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x, the second pre-determined distance y and the third pre-determined distance q.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The distance r separating a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>468</b><i>a</i>, <b>468</b><i>b</i>, <b>468</b><i>c </i>and at least one opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>of the third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c </i>may be larger than at least one of the first pre-determined distance x, the second pre-determined distance y, and the third pre-determined distance q, when the voltage values in the third range of voltage values are larger than the voltage values in the first range of voltage values or second range of voltage values by the further pre-determined voltage value, e.g. the further pre-determined voltage value may be in the range from about 100 V to about 200 V. The further pre-determined voltage value may be different from the pre-determined voltage value. The further pre-determined voltage value may be equal to the pre-determined voltage value.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The basic functionalities of the features described with respect to chip-housing module <b>400</b>, <b>410</b>, and <b>420</b> are applicable to chip-housing module <b>430</b> described below. Identical features as to those described with respect to chip-housing module <b>400</b>, <b>410</b> and <b>420</b> are denoted with the same reference signs.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">According to an embodiment as illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>430</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4D</figref>, carrier <b>464</b> of any of chip-housing modules <b>400</b>, <b>410</b> and <b>420</b> may be further configured to carry one or more components <b>484</b>, e.g. a driver integrated circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">According to an embodiment as illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>440</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4E</figref>, any of chip-housing modules <b>400</b>, <b>410</b> <b>420</b> and <b>430</b> may include a single third opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>instead of third plurality of openings <b>472</b><i>a</i>, <b>472</b><i>b</i>, <b>472</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Third opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip; wherein a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings and the third opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>may be separated by a distance r different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y, e.g. wherein a pair of adjacent openings consisting of one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings and the third opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>may be separated by a distance r different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance x and the second pre-determined distance y. Third opening <b>472</b><i>a </i>may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to second chip <b>224</b>. The functionalities of the feature, opening <b>472</b><i>a</i>, and the basic functionalities of the other features described with respect to chip-housing module <b>400</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>420</b> and <b>430</b>, are applicable to chip-housing module <b>440</b>. Identical features as to those described with respect to chip-housing module <b>420</b> and <b>430</b>, are denoted with the same reference signs.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">According to an embodiment as illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>450</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4F</figref>, any of chip-housing modules <b>400</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>420</b>, and <b>430</b> may include a carrier <b>464</b> configured to carry one or more chips, e.g. chip <b>204</b> and chip <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Carrier <b>464</b> may include a first plurality of openings wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings may be separated by a first pre-determined distance (not shown), and may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The carrier may include a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings may be separated by a second pre-determined distance (not shown), and may be configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">A pair of openings consisting of one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings and one opening <b>468</b><i>b </i>of the second plurality of openings may be separated by a distance z, wherein z may be a distance equal to or larger than a creepage distance, e.g. a minimum distance between an electrical connection in one opening of the first plurality of openings and an electrical connection in one opening of the second plurality of openings, to prevent long term degradation of the surface of the carrier <b>464</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Carrier <b>464</b> may be further configured to carry one or more components, <b>474</b> e.g. a electrical connection for a supply voltage, components <b>476</b> and <b>478</b>, e.g. external terminals for providing a control voltage, e.g. an external ground terminal <b>482</b>. Carrier <b>464</b> may include at least one opening <b>488</b><i>a </i>to receive a electrical connection for providing a supply voltage <b>474</b>. Carrier <b>464</b> may include one or more openings <b>492</b><i>a</i>, <b>494</b><i>a </i>to each receive a electrical connection for providing a control voltage <b>476</b> and <b>478</b>. Carrier <b>464</b> may include at least one opening <b>496</b><i>a </i>to receive a electrical connection for providing an external ground voltage <b>482</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">A pair of openings consisting of one opening <b>488</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection configured to receive a electrical connection for providing a supply voltage <b>474</b> and an opening <b>492</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a electrical connection for providing a control voltage <b>476</b>, may be separated by the distance z.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">A pair of openings consisting of one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings and an opening <b>494</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a electrical connection for providing a control voltage <b>478</b>, may be separated by the distance z.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The opening <b>466</b><i>a</i>, i.e the at least one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may be configured to receive a electrical connection from a chip, e.g. a first chip <b>204</b>, wherein the electrical connection received by opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>may include the back side of the chip e.g. a drain region of a power transistor of a chip. Opening <b>468</b><i>b</i>, the at least one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings <b>466</b><i>a</i>, <b>466</b><i>b</i>, <b>466</b><i>c</i>, <b>466</b><i>c </i>may be configured to receive a electrical connection from a chip, e.g. a second chip <b>224</b>, wherein the electrical connection received by opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>may include the back side of the chip, e.g. a drain region of a power transistor of a chip. An electrically conductive connection, e.g. a terminal electrically connected to each of components <b>474</b>, <b>476</b> <b>478</b>, <b>482</b> received by openings <b>488</b><i>a</i>, <b>492</b><i>a</i>, <b>494</b><i>a</i>, <b>496</b><i>a </i>may include an electrically conductive element, e.g. an electrically conductive wire, e.g. an electrically conductive pin, e.g. an electrically conductive chip pad.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">According to an embodiment as illustrated in the chip-housing module <b>460</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4F</figref>, carrier <b>464</b> of any of chip-housing modules <b>400</b>, <b>410</b> <b>420</b>, <b>430</b>, <b>440</b> and <b>450</b> may be further configured to carry one or more components, <b>484</b> e.g. a driver integrated circuit. Carrier <b>464</b> may include one or more openings <b>486</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage to the one or more components, <b>484</b> e.g. a driver integrated circuit. A pair of openings consisting of one opening <b>486</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage to the one or more components, <b>484</b> and one opening <b>466</b><i>a </i>of the first plurality of openings may be separated by the distance z. A pair of openings consisting of one opening <b>486</b><i>a </i>configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage to the one or more components, <b>484</b> and one opening <b>468</b><i>a </i>of the second plurality of openings may be separated by the distance z (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">According to an embodiment, carrier <b>464</b> of any of chip-housing modules <b>400</b>, <b>410</b> <b>420</b>, <b>430</b>, <b>440</b>, <b>450</b> an <b>460</b> may be configured to carry a first chip <b>204</b>, a second chip <b>224</b>, one or more components <b>484</b>, <b>474</b>, <b>476</b>, <b>478</b>, <b>482</b> electrically connected to form a circuit. Carrier <b>464</b> may be configured to include a plurality of openings each configured to receive an electrical connection for providing a voltage to first chip <b>204</b>, second chip <b>224</b>, and the one or more components <b>484</b>, <b>474</b>, <b>476</b>, <b>478</b>, <b>482</b>. One or more adjacent openings are separated by the minimum distance z, such that when the difference in voltage provided by adjacent electrical connections to the circuit exceeds a pre-determined voltage, the electrical connections are separated by at least the minimum distance z. The plurality of openings may be of different sizes depending on the size of the voltage provided by each terminal received by the opening. Therefore, an opening receiving an electrical connection, e.g. an electrically conductive pin, an electrically conductive wire, an electrically conductive pin, providing a voltage lying within the range of a lower voltage class, may be smaller than an opening receiving a terminal, e.g. drain region at the back of a chip, providing a voltage lying within the range of a higher voltage class.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">According to an embodiment, carrier <b>464</b> may be formed from two thinpak 6&#xd7;5 chip-housing modules which remain connected at one package-edge during package-singulation with e.g. sawing.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">A method for forming a chip-housing module according to various embodiments is disclosed in illustration <b>500</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the method including (in 510):
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0073">forming a carrier for carrying one or more chips;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0074">the carrier including a first plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings is separated by a first pre-determined distance, and is capable of receiving a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0075">the carrier including a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by the second pre-determined distance, and is capable of receiving a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip; and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0076">wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0077">A chip-housing module according to various embodiments is disclosed, the chip-housing module, including a carrier configured to carry one or more chips; the carrier including a first plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings is separated by a first pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip; the carrier including a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a second pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip; and wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0078">According to an embodiment, the distance separating a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is larger than at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance, and the voltage values in the second range of voltage values are larger than the voltage values in the first range of voltage values by a pre-determined voltage value.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0079">According to an embodiment, the pre-determined voltage value may be in the range from about 100 V to about 200 V.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0080">According to an embodiment, the pair includes a plurality of pairs of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0081">According to an embodiment, the first plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first chip; and wherein the second plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a first chip, and at least one other opening for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0082">According to an embodiment, the carrier further includes a third opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip; wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings and the third opening is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance, the second pre-determined distance.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0083">According to an embodiment, the third opening is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0084">According to an embodiment, the carrier further includes a third plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the third plurality of openings is separated by a third pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip; wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings and one opening of the third plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance, the second pre-determined distance and the third pre-determined distance.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0085">According to an embodiment, the third plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0086">According to an embodiment, the first plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first source/drain terminal of a transistor formed in the first chip, and at least one other opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a gate terminal of the transistor formed in the first chip; and wherein the second plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the first chip and to a first source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip, and at least one other opening for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a gate terminal of a transistor formed in the second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0087">According to an embodiment, a third opening includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0088">According to an embodiment, a third plurality of openings includes at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0089">According to an embodiment, the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections including electrically conductive pins.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0090">According to an embodiment, the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections including at least part of a semiconductor chip.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0091">According to an embodiment, the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections including at least part of a semiconductor power transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0092">According to an embodiment, at least one of the first pre-determined distance and second pre-determined distance is about 1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0093">According to an embodiment, the pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance greater than 2 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0094">According to an embodiment, the voltage values of the first voltage range lie from between about 0 V to 100 V.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0095">According to an embodiment, the voltage values of the second voltage range are larger than 150 V.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0096">According to an embodiment, the voltage values of the third voltage range are larger than 150 V.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0097">According to an embodiment, the carrier includes at least one from the following group of materials, the group consisting of: Cu, Ni, Fe, NiFe, Sn, S, P.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0098">According to an embodiment, the carrier is further configured to carry a driver integrated circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0099">Various embodiments illustratively provide design rules for chip-housing modules for a plurality of high-voltage chips, e.g. surface mount devices, particularly for the distance separation between voltage terminals of high-voltage chips. The distance between an opening for providing a high voltage to a chip and an opening for providing a low voltage to a chip is larger than the distance between an opening for providing a low voltage to a chip and another opening for providing a low voltage to a chip.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0100">The chip-housing multichip-module, e.g. a multichip-module for HV-half-bridge, increases the integrations density of the circuit. Furthermore, as the optimal creepage distance of the contacts for the high-voltage multi-chip module has been provided for, creepage spacing, e.g minimal spacing between two conductive contacts, need no longer be considered.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0101">While the invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to specific embodiments, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and detail may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. The scope of the invention is thus indicated by the appended claims and all changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are therefore intended to be embraced.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A chip-housing module, comprising
<claim-text>a carrier configured to carry one or more chips;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the carrier comprising a first plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the first plurality of openings is separated by a first pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the carrier comprising a second plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a second pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a chip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the distance separating a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is larger than at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance, and the voltage values in the second range of voltage values are larger than the voltage values in the first range of voltage values by a pre-determined voltage value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the pre-determined voltage value may be in the range from about 100 V to about 200 V.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the pair comprises a plurality of pairs of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance and the second pre-determined distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first chip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a first chip, and at least one other opening for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the carrier further comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings and the third opening is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance, the second pre-determined distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the third opening is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the voltage values of the third voltage range are larger than 150 V.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the carrier further comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third plurality of openings, wherein each opening of the third plurality of openings is separated by a third pre-determined distance, and is configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a chip;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a pair of openings consisting of one opening of the second plurality of openings and one opening of the third plurality of openings is separated by a distance different from at least one of the first pre-determined distance, the second pre-determined distance and the third pre-determined distance.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the third plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a first source/drain terminal of a transistor formed in the first chip, and at least one other opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a first range of voltage values to a gate terminal of the transistor formed in the first chip; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the first chip and to a first source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip, and at least one other opening for providing a voltage lying within a second range of voltage values to a gate terminal of a transistor formed in the second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein a third opening comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein a third plurality of openings comprises at least one opening configured to receive a chip connection for providing a voltage lying within a third range of voltage values to a second source/drain terminal of the transistor formed in the second chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections comprising electrically conductive pins.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections comprising at least part of a semiconductor chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the first and second plurality of openings may be configured to receive chip connections comprising at least part of a semiconductor power transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein at least one of the first pre-determined distance and second pre-determined distance is about 1 mm.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the pair of openings consisting of one opening of the first plurality of openings and one opening of the second plurality of openings is separated by a distance greater than 2 mm.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the voltage values of the first voltage range lie from between about 0 V to 100 V.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the voltage values of the second voltage range are larger than 150 V.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the carrier comprises at least one from the following group of materials, the group consisting of: Cu, Ni, Fe, NiFe, Sn, S, P.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The chip-housing module of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the carrier is further configured to carry a driver integrated circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
