<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625059-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625059</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13456893</doc-number>
<date>20120426</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-110542</doc-number>
<date>20110517</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>71</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>1335</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>136</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349109</main-classification>
<further-classification>349 48</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Liquid crystal display device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7372525</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Liu</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7750998</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Tanno et al.</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>349106</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7936323</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mori et al.</name>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>345 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0033845</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tanno et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>200936795</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349 48</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>349109</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120293755</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121122</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagami</last-name>
<first-name>Takahiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mobara</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagami</last-name>
<first-name>Takahiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mobara</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ulmer &#x26; Berne LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hitachi Displays, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Mobara-shi, Chiba</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dudek</last-name>
<first-name>James</first-name>
<department>2871</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In a screen configuration in which pixels are in a delta arrangement, video signal lines are formed on every other pixel, and two scanning lines in one set are disposed, transmittance of the screen is improved. Pixels corresponding to a red pixel (R), a green pixel (G), and a blue pixel (B) are disposed in a delta arrangement in a TFT substrate. A red color filter, a green color filter, a blue color filter are formed, in a counter substrate, corresponding to the red pixel (R), the green pixel (G), and the blue pixel (B) of the TFT substrate. A black matrix is formed to a portion where the color filter is not present. Two blue color filters are formed continuously adjacent each other in the first direction, and a black matrix is not formed between the blue color filters adjacent each other.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="91.10mm" wi="267.21mm" file="US08625059-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="230.29mm" wi="144.27mm" file="US08625059-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="234.61mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08625059-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="215.82mm" wi="150.88mm" file="US08625059-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CLAIM OF PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority from Japanese Patent Application JP 2011-110542 filed on May 17, 2011, the content of which is hereby incorporated by reference into this application.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a liquid crystal display device, and particularly to a liquid crystal display device having a screen configuration at high definition in which pixels are in a delta arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Liquid crystal display devices include a TFT substrate, a counter substrate, and liquid crystals. In this case, the TFT substrate has pixel electrodes, thin film transistors (TFT), etc. formed in a matrix. The counter substrate is disposed in facing relation to the TFT substrate and has color filters, etc. formed at positions corresponding to the pixel electrodes of the TFT substrate. The liquid crystals put between the TFT substrate and the counter substrate. Images are formed by controlling the light transmittance of liquid crystal molecules of each pixel.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Since the liquid crystal display devices are flat and light in weight, their application use has been extended in various fields, for example, from large-sized display devices such as television sets to mobile phones and DSCs (Digital Still Cameras). Particularly, in DSC, etc., high screen definition is required. As the screen definition is higher, the size of the pixel is reduced. A TFT and a pixel electrode are present in each pixel and when the size of the pixel is reduced, the size of the pixel electrode is decreased relatively. Accordingly, transmittance of light from a backlight in the screen is lowered to decrease the luminance on the screen.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">On the other hand, a red filter (R), a green filter (G), and a blue filter (B) are present in a counter substrate to enable color display. A black matrix is filled between each of the filters. The black matrix serves to prevent interference between each of colors, and improve the screen contrast by using a black color for a portion not concerning display. The black matrix also serves to prevent external light from impinging on the TFT in a portion where the TFT is formed, thereby preventing a light current from flowing to the TFT. As the area of the black matrix is larger, the amount of the transmission light from the backlight decreases to lower the luminance on the screen.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">JP-A-2009-36795 describes that the area for the black matrix is decreased and the luminance on the screen is improved in a usual pixel arrangement by changing the order of disposing filters in the lateral direction for a specified color thereby disposing a filter having identical color between pixels adjacent to each other in the lateral direction and forming a region where a black matrix is not present. In this case, the usual pixel arrangement is a pixel arrangement in which filters having identical color are disposed in the longitudinal direction while different filters, for example, a red (R) filter, a green (G) filter, and a blue filter (B) are disposed in the lateral direction.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">DSCs are required to achieve an improvement in resolution. The resolution in the horizontal direction is more excellent in a structure where pixels are in a delta arrangement than in a pixel structure where identical colors are arranged in the vertical direction when the size of the pixel is identical. Accordingly, DSCs employ the configuration where pixels are in the delta arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Even when the delta arrangement is employed, it is identical with the existent structure in that the black matrix is necessary, and smaller area for the black matrix is advantageous for the luminance on the screen. Further, as the screen has a higher definition, the number of video signal lines increases and the transmittance is decreased by the video signal lines.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">To address the disadvantage, there is a method of decreasing the number of the video signal lines to one-half and changing a pixel arrangement, a scanning method, and a video signal input method correspondingly. However, the color filter structure in such a configuration is not simple as described in JP-A-2009-36795 and the pixel arrangement as described in the patent document cannot be applied.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention intends to improve the luminance on the screen in a liquid crystal display device having a pixel structure in a delta arrangement and a screen configuration where the number of the video signal lines is decreased to one-half, by disposing pixels of a specified color adjacent to each other and saving a black matrix between them.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The present invention intends to overcome the foregoing problem and provide a liquid crystal display device having liquid crystals put between a TFT substrate where pixels each having a pixel electrode and a TFT are formed and a counter substrate in which color filters are formed, wherein the TFT substrate includes pixels corresponding to a red pixel (R), a green pixel (G), and a blue pixel (B) disposed in a delta arrangement, the pixels disposed in the delta arrangement being disposed in a first direction, the TFT substrate includes a set of a first scanning line and a second scanning line extended in the first direction, the set of a first scanning line and a second scanning line being disposed in a second direction, video signal lines are extended in the second direction and disposed on every other pixel in the first direction, pixels corresponding to the blue pixel (B) are disposed adjacent to each other in the first direction, and the video signal line is not present between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other, the counter substrate includes a red color filter, a green color filter, and a blue color filter formed corresponding to the red pixel (R), the green pixel (G), and the blue pixel (B) of the TFT substrate, and a black matrix is formed to a portion where the color filter is not present, and the blue color filter is formed such that two blue color filters are formed continuously adjacent each other in the first direction, and a black matrix is not formed between the blue color filters adjacent each other.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to the present invention, in a liquid crystal display device having a pixel structure in a delta arrangement, the transmittance of the light from the backlight can be improved to improve the luminance on the screen by disposing pixels of a predetermined color adjacent to each other and saving the black matrix between them. Accordingly, for the identical luminance on the screen, the pixel area can be decreased and a high definition screen can be attained.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of a TFT substrate according to a first embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of a counter substrate according to a first embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view of a counter substrate according to a second embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross sectional view of an IPS liquid crystal display device.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a plan view of a TFT substrate in a liquid crystal display device of a delta arrangement according to an existent embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a plan view of a counter substrate in a liquid crystal display device of a delta arrangement according to the existent embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Liquid crystal display devices include various types such as a TN (Twisted Namatic) type, a VA (Vertical Alignment) type, and an IPS (In Plane Switching) type and the invention is applicable to liquid crystal display devices of any of the types.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Among various liquid crystal display devices, the IPS type is excellent in a so-called view angle characteristic and the demand therefor has been enlarged. A cross sectional configuration of a liquid crystal display device is to be described briefly with reference to the IPS type as an example. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross sectional view showing a structure in a display region of an IPS liquid crystal display device. Various electrode structures have been proposed and put to practical use for the IPS liquid crystal display device. The structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> has been used generally at present and, referring briefly, a comb-shaped pixel electrode <b>110</b> is formed over a counter electrode <b>108</b> formed in a solid plane with an insulating film put therebetween. Then, images are formed by rotating liquid crystal molecules <b>301</b> by a voltage between the pixel electrode <b>110</b> and the counter electrode <b>108</b> thereby controlling the transmittance of light in a liquid crystal layer <b>300</b> on every pixel. The structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is to be described.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a gate electrode <b>101</b> is formed over a TFT substrate <b>100</b> formed of glass. The gate electrode <b>101</b> is formed in a layer identical with that for the scanning line. A gate insulating film <b>102</b> is formed of SiN covering the gate electrode <b>101</b>, and a semiconductor layer <b>103</b> is formed over the gate insulating film <b>102</b> at a position opposing the gate electrode <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A source electrode <b>104</b> is used in common with a video signal line, and a drain electrode <b>105</b> is connected to the pixel electrode <b>110</b>. Both the source electrode <b>104</b> and the drain electrode <b>105</b> are formed simultaneously in one identical layer. An inorganic passivation film <b>106</b> is formed of SiN covering a TFT. The inorganic passivation film <b>106</b> protects the TFT, particularly, the channel portion thereof against an impurity <b>401</b>. An organic passivation film <b>107</b> is formed over the inorganic passivation film <b>106</b>. Since the organic passivation film <b>107</b> also serves to planarize the surface in addition to protecting the TFT, it is formed to a large thickness. The thickness is from 1 &#x3bc;m to 4 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A counter electrode <b>108</b> is formed over the organic passivation film <b>107</b>. The counter electrode <b>108</b> is formed by sputtering ITO (Indium Tin Oxide) as a transparent conductive film over the entire display region. An upper insulating film <b>109</b> is formed of SiN covering the counter electrode <b>108</b>. After the upper insulating film <b>109</b> is formed, a through hole <b>111</b> is formed by etching. Then, the ITO is formed by sputtering as a pixel electrode <b>110</b> covering the upper insulating film <b>109</b> and the through hole <b>111</b>. The sputtered ITO is patterned to form a comb-shaped pixel electrode <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, when a voltage is applied on the pixel electrode <b>110</b>, lines of electric force are generated to rotate the liquid crystal molecules <b>301</b> in the direction of the lines of electric force to control the transmittance of light from a backlight. Images are formed since the transmittance of light from the backlight is controlled on every pixel. An alignment film <b>113</b> for the alignment of the liquid crystal molecules <b>301</b> is formed over the pixel electrode <b>110</b>. Optical alignment process is applied to the alignment film <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a counter substrate <b>200</b> is disposed while putting the liquid crystal layer <b>300</b> between the substrates. Color filters <b>201</b> are formed at the inside of the counter substrate <b>200</b>. As the color filters <b>201</b>, color filters <b>201</b> of red, green, and blue colors are formed on every pixel to form color images. A black matrix <b>202</b> is formed between color filters <b>201</b>, <b>201</b> adjacent to each other to prevent interference between each of the colors and also improve the contrast of the images. The black matrix <b>202</b> also serves as a light shielding film for the TFT to prevent a light current from flowing to the TFT.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">An overcoat film <b>203</b> is formed by covering the color filter <b>201</b> and the black matrix <b>202</b>. Since the surface of the color filter <b>201</b> and the black matrix <b>202</b> is unevenned, the surface is planarized by the overcoat film <b>203</b>. An alignment film <b>113</b> for determining the initial alignment of the liquid crystals is formed over the overcoat film <b>203</b>. The optical alignment process is applied also to the alignment film <b>113</b>. A surface conductive film <b>210</b> for shutting external noises is formed to the outside of the counter substrate <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a plan view showing a pixel structure in the TFT substrate <b>100</b> according to an existent embodiment. As the screen definition becomes higher, the number of the video signal lines <b>30</b> increases particularly. When the number of the video signal lines <b>30</b> increases, the number of terminals also increases to result in problems in the probability of disconnection of the video signal lines <b>30</b>, connection reliability with the terminal portion, etc. On the other hand, while the number of scanning lines also increases, the number of the scanning lines is originally smaller than the number of the video signal lines.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a pixel arrangement in the TFT substrate <b>100</b>. An R pixel, a G pixel, and a B pixel are in a so-called delta arrangement. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a triangle with the R pixel being as an apex, and an inverted triangle with the R pixel being as an apex are arranged in a lateral direction, and a screen is formed by the two patterns repeated in the lateral direction.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the video signal lines <b>30</b> extending in the vertical direction are present on every other pixel. That is, the number of the video signal lines <b>30</b> is one-half of the number of the pixels in the lateral direction. On the other hand, scanning lines are present as a set of two lines, that is, a first scanning line <b>10</b> and a second scanning line <b>20</b>. That is, in the pixel configuration of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, video signals are written at a double frequency. That is, in one flame, video signals are at first written into every other pixel by supplying a gate signal to the first scanning line <b>10</b> thereby scanning the screen. Then, video signals are written to the remaining pixels by supplying gate signals to the second scanning line <b>20</b> thereby scanning the screen. In this pixel configuration, while the write time of the video signals is decreased to one-half, priority is given to the benefit of decreasing the number of the video signal lines <b>30</b> to one-half. While the number of the scanning lines is doubled in this case compared with that in the usual driving method, the entire number of wirings can be decreased by decreasing the number of the video signal lines into one-half.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a pixel configuration in the counter substrate <b>100</b> corresponding to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Color filters <b>201</b> are present at positions corresponding to the pixel electrodes <b>110</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. While the video signal lines <b>30</b> are not present in the counter substrate <b>200</b>, positions for the video signal lines <b>30</b> are described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> for ease of reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, each of portions between the color filters <b>201</b> and <b>201</b> adjacent each other is covered by a black matrix <b>202</b>. Since the transmittance of light from the backlight can be increased more as the area of the black matrix <b>202</b> is smaller, the luminance on the screen is improved. However, since the black matrix <b>202</b> serves to improve the contrast by covering the portion not concerning the image formation, to prevent interference between each of the colors, it is difficult to decrease the area of the black matrix <b>202</b> in the pixel configuration as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the embodiment of the invention to be shown below, the area of the black matrix <b>202</b> can be decreased by changing the arrangement of the color filters <b>201</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Embodiment 1</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing the pixel arrangement in the TFT substrate <b>100</b> of an Embodiment 1. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, video signal lines <b>30</b> are disposed in the vertical direction on every other pixel. That is, the number of the video signal lines <b>30</b> is one-half of the number of the pixels in the lateral direction. Scanning lines comprises sets each having a first scanning line <b>10</b> and a second scanning line <b>20</b>. Since the operation of the pixel configuration is identical with that described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, duplicate description is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, arrangement for each of colors is different from that in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. That is, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the screen comprises by repeating two sets of deltas in the lateral direction. On the contrary, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the screen comprises by repeating four sets of deltas in the lateral direction. P in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> represents the four sets of deltas.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">P in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> comprises four types of triangles, that is, a triangle with a red pixel (R) being as an apex, an inverted triangle with a blue pixel (B) being as an apex, a triangle with a blue pixel (B) being as an apex, and an inverted triangle with a red pixel (R) being as an apex. With such a pixel configuration, the blue pixels (B) can be disposed adjacent to each other. The video signal line is not present between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other. Since there is no color interference between pixels of an identical color to each other, the black matrix between them can be saved.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view showing a pixel arrangement in the counter substrate <b>200</b> in response to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. While the video signal lines <b>30</b> are not present in the counter substrate <b>200</b>, positions for the video signal lines <b>30</b> are described also in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> for ease of reference to the TFT substrate in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, color filters <b>201</b> are formed independently to a red pixel (R) and a green pixel (G). That is, the black matrix <b>202</b> is filled between the color filters <b>201</b> and <b>201</b> adjacent each other.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">On the other hand, since the blue pixels (B) are disposed adjacent to each other and there is no interference of colors to each other, the color filters <b>201</b> are formed continuously. Further, also the video signal line <b>30</b> is not present between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other, reflection from the video signal line <b>30</b> formed of a metal is not also present. Accordingly, the black matrix <b>201</b> between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other can be saved and the blue filters can be formed continuously. Accordingly, transmittance of light from the backlight can be improved in the blue pixel (B) and the luminance on the screen can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Since the transmittance of the blue color filter <b>201</b> is smaller than that of the color filter of other color, improvement in the transmittance by enlarging the color filter <b>201</b> for the blue pixel (B) is also advantageous in view of easy color balance.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Embodiment 2</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">A pixel arrangement in the TFT substrate <b>100</b> of an Embodiment 2 is identical with that of the Embodiment 1 shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view showing the pixel arrangement in the counter substrate <b>200</b> of the Embodiment 2. The arrangement of the color filters <b>201</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is identical with that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> in the Embodiment 1. That is, P in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> comprises four kinds of triangles, that is, a triangle with a red pixel (R) being as an apex, an inverted triangle with a blue pixel (B) being as an apex, a triangle with a blue pixel (B) being as an apex, and an inverted triangle with a red pixel (R) being as an apex from the left. Accordingly, transmittance can be improved by saving the black matrix <b>202</b> between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other also in the Embodiment 2.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The Embodiment 2 is different from the Embodiment 1 in that a color filter <b>201</b> is formed continuously also for the red pixels (R) and (R) adjacent each other and the black matrix <b>202</b> is not formed between them. Accordingly, the transmittance of light from the backlight can be improved in the red pixel (R) by so much as the black matrix <b>202</b> is not present between the red pixels (R) and (R) adjacent each other and the luminance on the screen can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Different from the case of the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other, the video signal line <b>30</b> is present between the red pixels (R) and (R) adjacent each other in the TFT substrate <b>100</b>. Since the video signal line <b>30</b> is formed of the metal, when the light from the outside is reflected on the metal, contrast may sometimes be lowered. However, since the light from the outside is incident through the color filter <b>201</b> to the video signal line <b>30</b>, the contrast is not lowered greatly.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Accordingly, the luminance on the screen can be improved by forming the color filter <b>201</b> continuously to the two red pixels (R) without forming the black matrix <b>202</b> between the red pixels (R) and (R) adjacent each other. Whether the color filter <b>201</b> is formed continuously to the two red pixels (R) on both sides of the video signal line <b>30</b> or not as in this embodiment may be determined depending on both of the trade off relations of the luminance on the screen and the contrast.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A liquid crystal display device having liquid crystals put between a TFT substrate where pixels each having a pixel electrode and a TFT are formed and a counter substrate in which color filters are formed, wherein
<claim-text>the TFT substrate includes pixels corresponding to a red pixel (R), a green pixel (G), and a blue pixel (B) disposed in a delta arrangement, the pixels disposed in the delta arrangement being disposed in a first direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the TFT substrate includes a set of a first scanning line and a second scanning line extended in the first direction, the set of a first scanning line and a second scanning line being disposed in a second direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>video signal lines are extended in the second direction and disposed on every other pixel in the first direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>pixels corresponding to the blue pixel (B) are disposed adjacent to each other in the first direction, and the video signal line is not present between the blue pixels (B) and (B) adjacent each other,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the counter substrate includes a red color filter, a green color filter, and a blue color filter formed corresponding to the red pixel (R), the green pixel (G), and the blue pixel (B) of the TFT substrate, and a black matrix is formed to a portion where the color filter is not present, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the blue color filter is formed such that two blue color filters are formed continuously adjacent each other in the first direction, and a black matrix is not formed between the blue color filters adjacent each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The liquid crystal display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the red pixel (R) in the TFT substrate is formed such that two red pixels (R) are formed continuously adjacent each other in the first direction, and the black matrix is not formed between the red color filter and another red color filter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The liquid crystal display device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>four kinds of triangles, that is, a triangle with the red pixel (R) being as an apex, an inverted triangle with the blue pixel (B) being as an apex, a triangle with the blue pixel (B) being as an apex, and an inverted triangle with the red pixel (R) being as an apex comprise a set of the pixels, and the set of the pixels are disposed in the first direction in the TFT substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
