<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624673-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624673</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13348397</doc-number>
<date>20120111</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>26</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330267</main-classification>
<further-classification>330264</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Self-biasing radio frequency circuitry</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3887878</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Schade, Jr.</name>
<date>19750600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330267</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4087760</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yokoyama</name>
<date>19780500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330265</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5900783</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dasgupta</name>
<date>19990500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6097253</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hissen</name>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330277</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7936217</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Deng et al.</name>
<date>20110500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330264</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0273442</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bajdechi et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0133839</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Brekelmans</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330267</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>201233053</doc-number>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO-2006013543</doc-number>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>&#x201c;PCT Search Report and Written Opinion&#x201d;, Application No. PCT/US2012/021032, (Mar. 30, 2012), 14 pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Molnar, Alyosha et al., &#x201c;An Ultra-low Power 900 MHz RF Transceiver for Wireless Sensor Networks&#x201d;, <i>In Proceedings of Custom Integrated Circuits Conference 2004</i>, (Oct. 3, 2004), 4 pages.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>11</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330267</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330264</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330265</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61433470</doc-number>
<date>20110117</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120182072</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120719</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Park</last-name>
<first-name>Jinho</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lu</last-name>
<first-name>Yuan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Li</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saratoga</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Park</last-name>
<first-name>Jinho</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lu</last-name>
<first-name>Yuan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Li</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saratoga</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Marvell World Trade Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hamilton</city>
<country>BM</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Choe</last-name>
<first-name>Henry</first-name>
<department>2817</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present disclosure describes self-biasing radio frequency circuitry. In some aspects a radio frequency (RF) signal is amplified via a circuit having a first transistor configured to source current to an output of the circuit and a second transistor configured to sink current from the output of the circuit, and another signal is provided, without active circuitry, from the output of the circuit to a gate of the first transistor effective to bias a voltage at the output of the circuit. By so doing, the output of the circuit can be biased without active circuitry which can reduce design complexity of and substrate area consumed by the circuit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="188.55mm" wi="160.19mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="244.09mm" wi="181.02mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.91mm" wi="135.04mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="244.60mm" wi="159.09mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.06mm" wi="153.33mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.63mm" wi="147.40mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="219.88mm" wi="135.04mm" file="US08624673-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This present disclosure claims priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 61/433,470 filed Jan. 17, 2011, the disclosure of which is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The background description provided herein is for the purpose of generally presenting the context of the disclosure. Unless otherwise indicated herein, the approaches described in this section are not prior art to the claims in this disclosure and are not admitted to be prior art by inclusion in this section.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Wireless communications between computing devices are often transmitted as radio frequency (RF) signals. Communications (e.g., data or medium control information) of a transmitting device are modulated to a radio frequency and amplified before being broadcast as RF signals via an antenna. These RF signals, often because they have a degraded signal strength due to antenna efficiencies or propagation, are typically amplified by a receiving device to enable demodulation of the RF signals and recovery of the communications. Circuitry associated with the amplification of RF signals, however, may have stability issues due to high-impedance nodes within the circuitry. While these stability issues can be resolved with negative feedback, circuitry capable of providing negative feedback is typically active circuitry (e.g., operational amplifiers). Adding active feedback circuitry to an amplifier circuit, however, increases design complexity and an amount of substrate area consumed by the amplifier circuit, which may result in increased design costs, fabrication costs, and/or amplifier power consumption.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">This summary is provided to introduce subject matter that is further described below in the Detailed Description and Drawings. Accordingly, this Summary should not be considered to describe essential features nor used to limit the scope of the claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A method is described for amplifying a radio frequency (RF) signal via a circuit having a first transistor configured to source current from a power source to an output of the circuit based on the RF signal and a second transistor configured to sink current from the output of the circuit to a current sink based on the RF signal, and providing, without active circuitry, another signal from the output of the circuit to a gate of the first transistor effective to bias a voltage at the output of the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another method is described for applying an RF signal to respective gates of a first and a second metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET) that are operatively connected in series between a power source and a current sink by their respective drains, sourcing current via the first MOSFET to an output formed at the drains, sinking current via the second MOSFET from the output formed at the drains, and biasing a voltage at the output without active circuitry operably connected between a gate of the first MOSFET and the output formed at the drains of the first and the second MOSFETs.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A circuit is described that includes two p-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (pMOSFETs) operably connected in series and configured to source current from a current source to an output of the circuit, two n-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (nMOSFETs) operably connected in series and configured to sink current from the output of the circuit to a current sink, and non-active biasing circuitry operably connected between the output of the circuit and a gate of one of the pMOSFETs configured to bias a voltage of the output of the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The details of one or more implementations are set forth in the accompanying drawings and the description below. Other features and advantages will be apparent from the description and drawings, and from the claims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The details of one or more implementations are set forth in the accompanying figures and the detailed description below. In the figures, the left-most digit of a reference number identifies the figure in which the reference number first appears. The use of the same reference numbers in different instances in the description and the figures indicate like elements.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an operating environment having wireless devices in accordance with one or more aspects.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a detailed aspect of an example of the wireless interface shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a detailed aspect of an example of the push-pull circuitry shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates a method of providing a signal from an output of a circuit to a gate of a transistor of the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a method of biasing a voltage of an output formed by gates of two transistors.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a System-on-Chip (SoC) environment for implementing aspects of the techniques described herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Conventional amplification circuits use active circuitry to maintain stability when amplifying radio frequency (RF) signals. This active circuitry (e.g., transistors, diodes, operational amplifiers) increases design complexity and an amount of substrate area consumed by the amplification circuit. This disclosure describes apparatuses and techniques for self-biasing that enable an amplification circuit to be implemented without active feedback circuitry. A signal can be provided from the output of an amplification circuit to a gain cell of the amplification circuit in such a way as to preserve stability during operation, thereby precluding a need to add active circuitry to the amplification circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The following discussion describes an operating environment, techniques that may be employed in the operating environment, and a System-on-Chip (SoC) in which components of the operating environment can be embodied. In the discussion below, reference is made to the operating environment by way of example only.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Operating Environment</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example of an operating environment <b>100</b> having wireless computing devices <b>102</b> (wireless devices <b>102</b>) and a base station <b>104</b>, each of which are capable of communicating data, packets, and/or frames over a wireless connection <b>106</b>, such as a cellular, local-area, or short-range wireless network. The wireless network may operate in accordance with various standards, such as high-speed packet access (HSPA) or long-term evolution (LTE) cellular standards, or an Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) standard such as 802.11, 802.15, or 802.16. Wireless computing devices <b>102</b> include smart-phone <b>108</b>, tablet computer <b>110</b>, and laptop computer <b>112</b>. Although not shown, other configurations of wireless computing devices <b>102</b> are also contemplated, such as a desktop computer, a server, personal navigation device (PND), mobile-internet device (MID), network-attached-storage (NAS) drive, mobile gaming console, and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Base station <b>104</b> provides connectivity to Internet <b>114</b> or other networks via backhaul link <b>116</b>, which may be either wired or wireless (e.g., a T1 line, a fiber optic link, a wireless data relay). Although not shown, other configurations of base station <b>104</b> are also contemplated, such as an access point or cellular modem. Backhaul link <b>116</b> may include or connect with data networks operated by an internet service provider, such as a digital subscriber line (DSL) or broadband cable and may interface with base station <b>104</b> via an appropriately configured modem (not shown). While in communication with base station <b>104</b>, smart-phone <b>108</b>, tablet computer <b>110</b>, or laptop computer <b>112</b> has internet access and/or connectivity with other networks and services for which base station <b>104</b> acts as a gateway.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Each of wireless devices <b>102</b> include processor(s) <b>118</b> and computer-readable storage media <b>120</b>. Processor <b>118</b> can be any suitable type of processor, either single-core or multi-core, for executing instructions or code associated with applications and/or an operating system of the wireless device <b>102</b>. Processor <b>118</b> may be constructed with or fabricated from any suitable material such as silicon or other semiconductors. Computer-readable storage media <b>120</b> may include any type and/or combination of suitable storage media, such as electronic, magnetic, or optical media embodied as memory devices <b>122</b> and storage drive(s) <b>124</b>. Memory devices <b>122</b> may include memory components or modules such as random-access memory (RAM), non-volatile RAM (NVRAM), read-only memory (ROM), or Flash memory useful to store data of applications and/or an operating system of the wireless device <b>102</b> (not shown). Storage drive(s) <b>124</b> may include hard disk drives and/or solid-state drives (not shown) and are useful to store code or instructions associated with the applications and the operating system of wireless device <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Wireless devices <b>102</b> may also each include I/O ports <b>126</b>, graphics engine <b>128</b>, and wireless interface <b>130</b>. I/O ports <b>126</b> allow a wireless device <b>102</b> to interact with other devices and/or users. Graphics engine <b>128</b> processes and renders graphics for wireless device <b>102</b>, including user interface elements of an operating system, applications, and the like. Wireless interface <b>130</b> provides one or more wireless connections, such as wireless connection <b>106</b> with base station <b>104</b>, and is described in greater detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Base station <b>104</b> includes base station processor <b>132</b> (BS processor <b>132</b>) and base station computer-readable storage media <b>134</b> (BS computer-readable storage media <b>134</b>). BS computer-readable storage media <b>134</b> includes any suitable type and/or combination of storage media, such as electronic media embodied as ROM <b>136</b>, Flash <b>138</b>, or other memory devices (not shown). ROM <b>136</b> may store firmware (e.g., boot code) for base station <b>104</b> and Flash <b>138</b> may be useful to store code or instructions associated with an operating system of base station <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Base station <b>104</b> also includes network interface <b>140</b> and base station wireless interface <b>142</b> (BS wireless interface <b>142</b>). Network interface <b>140</b> enables base station <b>104</b> to communicate via backhaul link <b>116</b> with the Internet or other networks. BS wireless <b>142</b> enables communication with wireless devices <b>102</b> or other wirelessly-enabled clients. BS wireless interface <b>142</b> may be similar in configuration to wireless interface <b>130</b>, having the same circuits or components, while featuring increased power output and/or robust routing abilities for communication with a number of wireless clients over greater distances.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a detailed example of wireless interface <b>130</b>, which is capable of communicating over various wireless networks, such as cellular, local-area, or short-range wireless networks. Wireless interface <b>130</b> includes medium access control (MAC) controller <b>202</b>, which facilitates communication of data between wireless interface <b>130</b> and wireless device <b>102</b> via a suitable internal bus (not shown), such as a serial bus, universal serial bus (USB), peripheral component interconnect (PCI) express bus, and the like. Wireless interface <b>130</b> also includes baseband processing block <b>204</b> and radio frequency block <b>206</b> (RF block <b>206</b>) for processing and communicating wireless data.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Baseband processing block <b>204</b> manages communication functions of wireless interface <b>130</b> and processes (e.g., encodes/decodes) un-modulated data communicated by wireless interface <b>130</b>. RF Block <b>206</b> includes RF mixer <b>208</b> for modulating data for transmission or demodulating received data. RF block <b>206</b> also includes low-noise amplifier <b>210</b> that amplifies received RF signals with push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>, which is described below in greater detail. Power amplifier <b>214</b> amplifies signals of wireless interface <b>130</b> prior to transmission to base station <b>104</b> or other wireless devices. Although not shown, power amplifier <b>214</b> may also implement push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> to amplify RF signals. RF Block <b>206</b> may also include filter <b>216</b> to isolate particular frequency bands of RF signals communicated by wireless interface <b>130</b> and antenna port(s) <b>218</b> that enable connections to one or more antennas configured for diversity or multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) communication. Functionalities or portions of RF block <b>206</b> may be implemented separately as transmitter and receiver components (not shown) or combined as a transceiver (shown).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a detailed example of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>, which is capable of amplifying RF signals for transmission or signal recover. Push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> includes input <b>302</b> at which a signal (e.g. RF signal) is received, and output <b>304</b> that provides an amplified signal (e.g. an amplified RF signal). Power can be supplied to push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> via voltage drain <b>306</b> (V<sub>DD </sub><b>306</b>) or another suitable power source. Current from push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> can be sank to ground <b>308</b> (GND <b>308</b>) or another node having a potential lower than V<sub>DD </sub><b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> may also include Direct Current (DC) blocking capacitors <b>310</b> and <b>312</b>, which block DC or low frequency components of signals received at input <b>302</b>. Transistors <b>314</b> and <b>316</b> are configured to source current from V<sub>DD </sub><b>306</b> to output <b>304</b>. Transistors <b>318</b> and <b>320</b> are configured to sink current from output <b>304</b> to GND <b>308</b>. Transistors <b>316</b> and <b>318</b>, functioning as additional gain cells, increase a gain of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> or enable a similar gain at lower power supply potentials.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In this example, transistors <b>314</b> and <b>316</b> are illustrated as p-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (pMOSFETs or pMOS) and transistors <b>318</b> and <b>320</b> are illustrated as n-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (nMOSFETs or nMOS). Although shown as a single-ended or common-mode circuit, push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> may be implemented as a differential circuit by essentially mirroring the design shown. It should also be noted, that the push and pull sections of push-pull circuitry may be implemented with any suitable combination of transistors, such as with fewer transistors (e.g., without transistors <b>316</b> and <b>318</b>) or with transistors of a different type or structure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> also includes self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b>, which biases DC and/or low frequency voltages at output <b>304</b>. Although current is sourced to and sank from output <b>304</b> at RF frequencies, biasing or setting a DC voltage at output <b>304</b> can enable proper circuit function. Self-biasing circuitry includes bias resistor <b>324</b>, which provides a feedback signal from output <b>304</b> to a gate of transistor <b>314</b>. By so doing, a DC voltage at output <b>304</b> can be biased or set based on bias resistor <b>324</b> and an amount of current flowing through transistor <b>314</b>. Self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> may also include compensation capacitor <b>326</b> for stability, such as when an impedance of input <b>302</b> and output <b>304</b> are similar. Depending on a value of compensation capacitor <b>326</b>, self-biasing circuitry may include isolation resistor <b>328</b> to prevent compensation capacitor <b>326</b> from conducting RF signals.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As described above, wireless interface <b>130</b> and BS wireless interface <b>142</b> may be configured in a similar fashion, with BS wireless interface <b>142</b> having one or more of the components described above (e.g., push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>). As such, apparatuses or techniques described herein may equally apply to a BS wireless interface <b>142</b>. Additionally, although described with respect to a wireless networks, these techniques may be implemented in association with any wired or wireless communication system (e.g., microwave, optical) that implement push-pull amplification circuitry.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Techniques of Self-Biasing RF Circuitry</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The following discussion describes techniques of self-biasing RF circuitry. These techniques can be implemented using the previously described environments, such as self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> embodied on a wireless interface <b>130</b> of wireless device <b>102</b> and/or BS wireless interface <b>142</b> of base station <b>104</b>. These techniques include methods illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, each of which is shown as a set of operations performed by one or more entities. These methods are not necessarily limited to the orders shown for performing the operations. Further, these methods may be used in conjunction with one another, in whole or in part, whether performed by the same entity, separate entities, or any combination thereof In portions of the following discussion, reference will be made to operating environment <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and entities of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and/or <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> by way of example. Such reference is not to be taken as limited to operating environment <b>100</b> but rather as illustrative of one of a variety of examples.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts a method <b>400</b> for self-biasing RF circuitry, including operations performed by self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">At <b>402</b>, an RF signal is received. The RF signal may range in frequency from about 3 kHz to about 300 Ghz and may include encoded and/or modulated data. The RF signal may be received from any suitable source, such as a component in an RF circuit including a filter, switch, multiplexor, mixer, and the like. In some cases, the RF signal is a signal received via an antenna or an RF signal to be transmitted via an antenna.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">As an example, consider smart-phone <b>108</b> in the context of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, which shows smart-phone <b>108</b> communicating with base station <b>104</b> over wireless connection <b>106</b>. Assume here that wireless interface <b>130</b> of smart-phone <b>108</b> is communicating over an LTE cellular network and is receiving RF signals from base station <b>104</b>. Here, low-noise amplifier receives an RF signal from filter <b>216</b> for amplification.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">At <b>404</b>, the RF signal is amplified via a circuit having transistors configured to source current to or sink current from an output of the circuit. The circuit may be configured with a push-pull topology, such as push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. The transistors of the circuit may be any suitable type of transistors, such as single or stacked pMOSFETs or nMOSFETs, configured to source or sink current respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the context of the present example, the RF signal is amplified by push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>, which sources current from V<sub>DD </sub><b>306</b> with transistors <b>314</b> and <b>316</b> to output <b>304</b> and sinks current from output <b>304</b> to GND <b>308</b> with transistors <b>318</b> and <b>320</b>. This current sourced to and sank from output <b>304</b> forms an amplified RF signal at output <b>304</b> suitable for transmission to another stage of RF block <b>206</b>, such as RF mixer <b>208</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At <b>406</b>, another signal is provided from the output of the circuit to the gate of one of the transistors without active circuitry. This active circuitry may include any active circuit component or structure such as diodes, triodes, transistors, or operational amplifiers. The other signal may be provided via a resistor connected between the output of the circuit to the gate of one of the transistors. This other signal is effective to bias or set a voltage (DC or low frequency) at the output of the circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Additionally, this signal may be compensated and/or isolated with additional passive circuitry, such as a capacitor and an additional resistor. In some cases, a compensation capacitor may be connected in parallel with the resistor conducting the other signal for compensation or stabilization purposes. In such a case, a resistor may be connected in series with this capacitor to prevent the capacitor from conducting or leaking an RF signal or noise.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Concluding the present example, a feedback signal is provided by bias resistor <b>324</b> or self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b>. Assume here that impedances of input <b>302</b> and output <b>304</b> of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> are similar and may cause stability issues. Compensation capacitor <b>326</b> provides compensation for these stability issues and isolation resistor <b>328</b> prevents compensation capacitor <b>326</b> from conducting an RF signal from output <b>304</b> to the gate of transistor <b>314</b>. Note that this is but one example of self-biasing, and that a feedback signal may be provided using any suitable passive circuitry without departing from the spirit of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> depicts a method <b>500</b> of biasing a voltage of an output formed by gates of two transistors, including operations performed by self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">At <b>502</b>, an RF signal is received. The RF signal may range in frequency from about 3 kHz to about 300 Ghz and may include encoded and/or modulated data. The RF signal may be received from any suitable source, such as a component in an RF circuit including a filter, switch, multiplexor, mixer, and the like. In some cases, the RF signal is a signal received via an antenna or an RF signal to be transmitted via an antenna.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As an example, consider RF block <b>206</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, which shows RF mixer <b>208</b>, low-noise amplifier <b>210</b>, power amplifier <b>214</b>, filter <b>216</b>, and antenna ports <b>218</b>. Assume here that wireless interface <b>130</b> is receiving an RF signal from BS wireless interface <b>142</b> via wireless connection <b>106</b>. Here antenna ports <b>218</b> receive the signal from antennas (not shown) and filter <b>216</b> mitigates signals of various undesirable frequency bands.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At <b>504</b>, the RF signal is applied to respective gates of a first and a second metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET). The respective MOSFETs may be configured as single or stacked gain cells (cascode configurations), such as p-type MOSFETs and n-type MOSFETs connected by their respective gates (e.g., push-pull topology). Configuring MOSFETs as stacked gain cells can increase an effective gain of the gain cells or enable a similar gain to be obtained from the gain cells with reduced power consumption. In the context of the present example, the RF signal from filter <b>216</b> is applied to gates of transistors <b>314</b> and <b>320</b> of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">At <b>506</b>, current is sourced via the first transistor to an output formed by the drains of the first and the second transistor. The current may be sourced from a higher potential node, such as a power supply or rail to which the first transistor is connected. An amount and/or frequency of the current sourced to the output may be based on the RF signal applied to the gates of the first transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">At <b>508</b>, current is sank via the second transistor from the output formed by the drains of the first and the second transistor. The current may be sank from the output to a node of lower potential, such as a power or digital ground to which the second transistor is connected. An amount and/or frequency of the current sank from the output may be based on the RF signal applied to the gates of the second transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In the context of the ongoing example and with reference to operations <b>506</b> and <b>508</b>, transistors <b>314</b> and <b>316</b> source current from V<sub>DD </sub><b>306</b> to output <b>304</b>, which is formed by the drains of transistors <b>316</b> and <b>318</b>. Transistors <b>318</b> and <b>320</b> sink to GND <b>308</b> from output <b>304</b>, which is formed by the drains of transistors <b>316</b> and <b>318</b>. The current sourced to or sank from output <b>304</b> forms an amplified RF signal based on the RF signal applied to the gates of transistors <b>314</b> and <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">At <b>510</b>, a voltage at the output formed by drains of the transistors is biased without active circuitry. The voltage may be a DC or low frequency voltage at the output. Biasing the voltage may implement a passive component, such as a resistor connected between the output formed by the drains of the transistors and a gate of the first transistor. Additionally, the output may be stabilized with additional passive components, such as a capacitor connected in parallel with the resistor. In such a case, another resistor may be connected in series with the capacitor to prevent the capacitor from conducting other RF signals or noise from the output to the gate of the first transistor.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Continuing the ongoing example, a DC voltage at output <b>304</b> is biased with bias resistor <b>324</b>, which provides a feedback signal to a gate of transistor <b>314</b>. Assume here that impedances of input <b>302</b> and output <b>304</b> of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> are similar and may cause stability issues. Compensation capacitor <b>326</b> provides compensation for these stability issues and has a capacitance value that sufficiently prevents other RF signals or noise from conducting from output <b>304</b> to the gate of transistor <b>314</b>. Thus, in this case, an additional isolation resistor is not needed for stability or operation of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>. Note that this is but one example of self-biasing, and that a feedback signal may be provided using any suitable passive circuitry without departing from the spirit or intent of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">At <b>512</b>, an amplified RF signal formed by the current sourced and sank by the transistors is transmitted. The amplified signal may be transmitted to any suitable component, such as an RF mixer, filter, switch, multiplexor, and the like. In some cases, the amplified RF signal may be transmitted to another amplification stage for further amplification.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Concluding the present example, low-noise amplifier <b>210</b> transmits an amplified signal of push-pull circuitry <b>212</b> to RF mixer <b>208</b> for further processing, such as demodulation. It should be noted that by implementing self-biasing circuitry, design of push-pull circuitry can be simplified which may result in design cost savings and a reduced amount of substrate consumed by the push-pull circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">System-on-Chip</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a System-on-Chip (SoC) <b>600</b>, which can implement various embodiments described above. An SoC can be implemented in any suitable device, such as a smart-phone, cellular phone, video game console, IP enabled television, desktop computer, laptop computer, tablet computer, server, base station, wireless router, network-enabled printer, set-top box, printer, scanner, camera, picture frame, and/or any other type of device that may implement wireless connective technology.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">SoC <b>600</b> can be integrated with electronic circuitry, a microprocessor, memory, input-output (I/O) logic control, communication interfaces and components, other hardware, firmware, and/or software needed to provide communicative coupling for a device, such as any of the above-listed devices or as an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC) for integration within any of the above-listed devices. SoC <b>600</b> can also include an integrated data bus (not shown) that couples the various components of the SoC for data communication between the components. A wireless communication device that includes SoC <b>600</b> can also be implemented with many combinations of differing components. In some cases, these differing components may be configured to implement concepts described herein over a wireless connection or interface.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In this example, SoC <b>600</b> includes various components such as an input-output (I/O) logic control <b>602</b> (e.g., to include electronic circuitry) and a microprocessor <b>604</b> (e.g., any of a microcontroller, application processor, or digital signal processor). SoC <b>600</b> also includes a memory <b>606</b>, which can be any type of RAM, low-latency nonvolatile memory (e.g., flash memory), ROM, and/or other suitable electronic data storage. SoC <b>600</b> can also include various firmware and/or software, such as an operating system <b>608</b>, which can be computer-executable instructions maintained by memory <b>606</b> and executed by microprocessor <b>604</b>. SoC <b>600</b> can also include other various communication interfaces and components, communication components, other hardware, firmware, and/or software.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">SoC <b>600</b> includes MAC Controller <b>202</b>, baseband processing block <b>204</b>, RF mixer <b>208</b>, low-noise amplifier <b>210</b>, push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>, and self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b>, which may be embodied as disparate or combined components, as described in relation to various aspects presented herein. Examples of these various components, functions, and/or entities, and their corresponding functionality, are described with reference to the respective components of the environment <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b>, either independently or in combination with other entities, can be implemented with any suitable combination of passive components to implement various embodiments and/or features described herein. Self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> may also be provided integral with other entities of the SoC, such as integrated with one or both of low-noise amplifier <b>210</b>, push-pull circuitry <b>212</b>, or any RF section within SoC <b>600</b>. Alternately or additionally, self-biasing circuitry <b>322</b> and the other components can be implemented as hardware, firmware, fixed logic circuitry, or any combination thereof that is implemented in connection with the I/O logic control <b>602</b> and/or other signal processing and control circuits of SoC <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Although the subject matter has been described in language specific to structural features and/or methodological operations, it is to be understood that the subject matter defined in the appended claims is not necessarily limited to the specific features or operations described above, including orders in which they are performed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method comprising:
<claim-text>amplifying a radio frequency (RF) signal via a circuit having a first transistor configured to source current from a power source to an output of the circuit based on the RF signal and a second transistor configured to sink current from the output of the circuit to a current sink based on the RF signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing, without active circuitry and via a resistor, another signal from the output of the circuit to a gate of the first transistor effective to bias a voltage at the output of the circuit, the resistor connected between the output of the circuit and the gate of the first transistor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>compensating, via a capacitor connected in parallel with the resistor, the other signal that is provided from the output of the circuit to the gate of the first transistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising preventing the capacitor from conducting RF energy with another resistor connected in series with the capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transistors are metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (MOSFETs), the first transistor being a p-type MOSFET (pMOSFET), and the second transistor being an n-type MOSFET (nMOSFET).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the circuit includes a third transistor that is a pMOSFET configured in series with the first transistor and to source current to the output of the circuit, and a fourth transistor that is an nMOSFET configured in series with the second transistor and to sink current from the output of the circuit effective to increase a gain or an efficiency of the circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the circuit is configured as a RF low-noise amplifier or an RF power amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A method comprising:
<claim-text>applying a radio frequency (RF) signal to respective gates of a first and a second metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET) that are operatively connected in series between a power source and a current sink by their respective drains;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sourcing, based on the RF signal, current via the first MOSFET to an output formed at the drains of the first and the second MOSFETs effective to amplify the RF signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sinking, based on the RF signal, current via the second MOSFET from the output formed at the drains of the first and the second MOSFETs effective to amplify the RF signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>biasing, via a first resistor and without active circuitry, a voltage at the output formed at the drains of the first and the second MOSFETs, the first resistor operably connected between a gate of the first MOSFET and the output; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>stabilizing the output via a capacitor and a second resistor connected in series between the gate of the first MOSFET and the output formed at the drains of the first and the second MOSFETs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first MOSFET is a p-type MOSFET (pMOSFET) and the second MOSFET is an n-type MOSFET (nMOSFET).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein an additional pMOSFET is connected between the first MOSFET and the output, and an additional nMOSFET is connected between the second MOSFET and the output effective to increase a gain or an efficiency associated with the sourcing of the current or the sinking of the current.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving the RF signal from a filter, multiplexor, or switch operably coupled with an antenna.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising transmitting, to an RF mixer, an amplified RF signal formed by the current sourced and the current sink.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A circuit comprising:
<claim-text>two p-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (pMOSFETs) operably connected in series and configured to source current from a current source to an output of the circuit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two n-type metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors (nMOSFETs) operably connected in series and configured to sink current from the output of the circuit to a current sink;</claim-text>
<claim-text>non-active biasing circuitry operably connected between the output of the circuit and a gate of one of the pMOSFETs effective to bias a voltage of the output of the circuit, the non-active biasing circuitry including a resistor operably connected between the output of the circuit and the gate of one of the pMOSFETs; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>non-active compensating circuitry effective to compensate the output of the circuit, the non-active compensating circuitry including a capacitor connected in parallel with the resistor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising non-active blocking circuitry connected between an input of the circuit and the gate of the pMOSFET, the non-active blocking circuitry configured to block low-frequency components of a signal received at the input of the circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the non-active compensating circuitry includes an additional resistor connected in series with the capacitor to prevent the capacitor from conducting RF energy.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the circuit is embodied as a common-mode or differential push-pull amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the circuit is embodied as a radio frequency (RF) low-noise amplifier or an RF power amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the circuit is embodied in a System-on-Chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the circuit is configured as a common-mode or differential push-pull amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising receiving the RF signal from a filter, multiplexor, or switch operably coupled with an antenna.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising preventing the capacitor from conducting RF energy with another resistor connected in series with the capacitor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising additional non-active blocking circuitry connected between the input of the circuit and a gate of one of the nMOSFETs, the additional non-active blocking circuitry configured to block the low-frequency components of the signal received at the input of the circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
