<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624176-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624176</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12981721</doc-number>
<date>20101230</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>366</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>40</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>250239</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Detector assembly comprising a cap assembly including a radially expandable member</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5742057</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Frederick et al.</name>
<date>19980400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6222192</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Sekela et al.</name>
<date>20010400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6359282</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Sekela</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6781134</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Murray et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>250239</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>250361 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25036305</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25036309</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25037011</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61291783</doc-number>
<date>20091231</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110155896</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110630</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bush</last-name>
<first-name>Michael L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ravenna</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bush</last-name>
<first-name>Michael L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ravenna</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Abel Law Group, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Young</last-name>
<first-name>Robert N.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Saint-Gobain Ceramics &#x26; Plastics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Worcester</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Luu</last-name>
<first-name>Thanh</first-name>
<department>2878</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Naphas</last-name>
<first-name>Renee</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A detector assembly includes a cap assembly configured to close an end of a detector housing that is configured to contain a sensor therein, the cap assembly has a radially expandable member configured to expand radially within the detector housing and lock the position of the cap assembly relative to the detector housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="229.87mm" wi="156.72mm" file="US08624176-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="244.18mm" wi="183.22mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624176-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="247.48mm" wi="175.60mm" file="US08624176-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="252.05mm" wi="214.12mm" file="US08624176-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="234.95mm" wi="204.30mm" file="US08624176-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION(S)</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 61/291,783, filed Dec. 31, 2009, entitled &#x201c;Detector Assembly for a Scintillation Article,&#x201d; naming inventor Michael L. Bush, which application is incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The following disclosure is directed to detector assemblies, and more particularly, a releasable cap assembly for a detector assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Radiation detector devices are used in a variety of industrial applications, for example, well logging in the oil and gas industry. Typically, the detectors have scintillator crystals made of an activated sodium iodide or other material effective for detecting certain types of radiation. Because the scintillator crystals are sensitive components, they are generally enclosed in casings or sleeves. The casings can include a window to permit radiation-induced scintillation light to pass out of the crystal package to a light-sensing device such as a photomultiplier tube (PMT). The photomultiplier tube converts the light photons emitted from the scintillator crystal into electrical pulses, which are shaped and digitized by associated electronics and may be registered as counts that are transmitted to analyzing equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In certain applications, such as the well logging industry, scintillation detectors are useful for measuring gamma rays and neutrons emitted from surrounding rock strata. In fact, scintillation detectors can be used in drilling apparatuses themselves, giving rise to the common practice of measurement while drilling (MWD) (or logging while drilling). Nonetheless, MWD applications often take place in severe environments characterized by large amounts of heat, vibration and shock. Vibration and shock can cause the detector and/or the sensor to malfunction or fail.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, the industry continues to need improvements in scintillation articles and PMT assemblies.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a first aspect, a detector assembly includes a cap assembly configured to close an end of a detector housing configured to contain a sensor therein, the cap assembly includes a radially expandable member configured to expand radially within the detector housing and lock the position of the cap assembly relative to the detector housing.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to another aspect, a detector assembly includes a detector housing, and a cap assembly configured to close an end of the detector housing, wherein the cap assembly has a first component configured to directly connect to an interior surface of the detector housing and lock at an axial position within an interior of the detector housing, and a second component configured to directly connect to the first component and indirectly connect to the detector housing.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In yet another aspect, a detector assembly includes a detector housing having an outer diameter (OD) and an inner diameter (ID) defining a cavity within the detector housing, wherein the detector housing is a thin-walled structure and the ID has a dimension of at least about 90% and not greater than about 99% of the dimension of the OD. The detector assembly further includes a cap assembly releasably coupled to an end of the detector housing.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to still another aspect, a detector assembly including a thin-walled detector housing includes a sensor disposed within the detector housing, wherein the detector housing having an average side wall thickness of not greater than about 3.0 mm, and a cap assembly releasably coupled to an end of the detector housing opposite an end of the detector housing abutting the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In another aspect, a detector assembly including a thin-walled housing includes a sensor disposed within the detector housing, wherein the detector housing has an outer diameter (OD), and an inner diameter (ID) defining a cavity within the detector housing. The ID has a dimension of at least about 90% and not greater than about 99% of the dimension of the OD, and a cap assembly is releasably coupled to an end of the detector housing via a fastener.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In accordance with still another aspect, a detector assembly includes a sensor disposed within a detector housing and a cap assembly releasably connected to the detector housing. The cap assembly includes a radially expandable member, wherein the cap assembly is moveable between an open position and a closed position, and wherein in the closed position the detector assembly is sealed by the cap assembly and the radially expandable member is in an expanded position.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Another aspect includes a detector assembly having a sensor disposed within a detector housing and a cap assembly including a shield cap, a push plate, and a lock disk disposed between the shield cap and the push plate. In an open position, the shield cap is disengaged from the detector housing, and in changing the cap assembly from the open position to the closed position the shield cap engages the push plate.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present disclosure may be better understood, and its numerous features and advantages made apparent to those skilled in the art by referencing the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> includes a cross-sectional illustration of a scintillation article in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> includes an exploded view of a detector assembly including a cap assembly in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> includes a cross-sectional view of a portion of a detector assembly including the cap assembly in an open position in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> includes a cross-sectional view of a portion of a detector assembly including the cap assembly in a closed position in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> includes a cross-sectional illustration of a portion of a detector housing and a radially expandable member in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> includes a top view of a lock disk in an unexpanded state in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> includes an illustration of an actuator for use with the lock disk in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> includes a top view of a lock disk in an expanded state in accordance with an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The use of the same reference symbols in different drawings indicates similar or identical items.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The following is directed to a detector assembly, which can include a sensor, such as a photomultiplier tube (PMT) or other light sensor, which can be contained within the detector housing and optically coupled to a radiation detector, such as a scintillator. Accordingly, the embodiments of detector assemblies herein may be particularly suited for use with scintillation articles, and be used in conjunction with scintillator crystals. Such embodiments may be used in various industrial environments, including MWD applications, and thus can be ruggedized housing designs. Moreover, such embodiments can use releasably coupled components, making the detector assemblies field-serviceable.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> includes a cross-sectional illustration of a scintillation article in accordance with an embodiment. In particular, the scintillation article <b>100</b> includes a radiation detector <b>101</b>, which may be suitable for detecting particular types of radiation by virtue of a scintillator material. Various types of scintillator materials can be used, including inorganic materials, organic materials, and a combination thereof. In certain instances, the scintillator material can be a liquid material, or solid material (e.g., a crystalline material) or a combination thereof. According to one embodiment, the scintillator material can be a crystalline material, and may be a crystalline material including a halide material. Some such suitable scintillator crystals can include activated halide-containing materials, such as rare-earth halide materials and/or alkali halide materials. According to one embodiment, the scintillator crystal can be an activated halide crystal, for example, activated LaBr<sub>3</sub>, LaCl<sub>3</sub>, GdI<sub>3</sub>, GdBr<sub>3</sub>, and LuI<sub>3</sub>. Still, in other embodiments, the scintillator crystal can be an activated iodide crystal, such as a thallium-activated sodium iodide crystal. Various activating elements can be provided as dopants within particular scintillator materials, including for example, cerium, thallium, europium, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The scintillation article <b>100</b> can further include a detector housing <b>103</b> for incorporation of a sensor <b>105</b> therein. The detector housing <b>103</b> can have a first end <b>107</b> that houses a cap assembly <b>112</b> for sealing the detector housing <b>103</b>, and a second end <b>108</b> that is coupled to the radiation detector <b>101</b>. The detector housing <b>103</b> can be a casing having a particular shape, and generally has a cavity as defined by an interior surface that is suitable for securing a sensor <b>105</b> therein.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The detector housing <b>103</b> can be made of a metal material, such as a refractory metal or metal alloy suitable for use in industrial environments. For example, suitable metals can include titanium, cobalt, chrome, molybdenum, aluminum, steel, nickel, and a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The sensor <b>105</b> disposed within the cavity of the detector housing <b>103</b> can be a radiation sensing device, and more particularly may be a device suitable for detection fluoresced radiation given off by the scintillator material. That is, when a particular type of radiation (e.g., gamma ray radiation) interacts with the scintillator, the scintillator fluoresces a particular type of radiation (e.g., light of a particular wavelength), which can be detected by the sensor <b>105</b>. In one embodiment, the sensor <b>105</b> can be a photomultiplier tube (PMT). In other embodiments, the sensor <b>105</b> can include a hybrid PMT or a silicon photomultiplier (SiPM) device with associated electronics.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The sensor <b>105</b> can include electronics suitable for converting the fluoresced radiation emitted from the scintillator material into electrical pulses that may be registered as counts for analysis. Such electronics may include, among other things, a photocathode, an electron detector, an amplifier, a pre-amplifier, a discriminator, an analog-to-digital signal converter, or the like. Additionally, the sensor <b>105</b> can be a hybrid PMT.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As further illustrated, proximate to the end <b>108</b> within the detector housing <b>103</b>, an optical coupling pad <b>109</b> can be provided for suitable optical coupling between the sensor <b>105</b> and the radiation detector <b>101</b>. In one embodiment, the optical coupling pad <b>109</b> can be a UV-transparent silicone gel pad.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The detector housing <b>103</b> can be sealed via a cap assembly <b>112</b> coupled to the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>, such that the sensor <b>105</b> is secured within the interior of the detector housing <b>103</b>. The cap assembly <b>112</b> can include multiple parts, including for example, a shield cap <b>113</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can further include an opening <b>190</b>, extending axially and facilitating the passage of wires <b>115</b> therethrough and out of the detector housing <b>103</b>. The wires <b>115</b> can be electrically coupled to the electronics within the PMT and can be used to transmit signals to analyzing equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> includes an exploded view of a detector assembly including a cap assembly in accordance with an embodiment. As illustrated, the detector assembly can include the detector housing <b>103</b> as described in accordance with embodiments herein. Moreover, the detector assembly can include the sensor <b>105</b> having a shape and size configured to be contained within the detector housing <b>103</b>, and particularly contained within a cavity <b>251</b> within the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> and particularly the manner in which the components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> may be combined to facilitate closing the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. In particular, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can include a spacer <b>201</b> that may be configured to engage an upper surface of the sensor <b>105</b> when the cap assembly <b>112</b> is assembled and in a closed position. The spacer <b>201</b> may provide a suitable surface for engaging other components of the cap assembly <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The spacer <b>201</b> can be made of a suitable material, such as an inorganic material, an organic material, and a combination thereof. In one instance, the spacer <b>201</b> can be made of a metal or metal alloy. In particular instances, the spacer <b>201</b> can be made of steel, including for example, stainless steel. The spacer <b>201</b> may be used to evenly distribute the load of a biasing member <b>203</b> on adjacent components.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Additionally, while not illustrated, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can include a pad that may be disposed between the spacer <b>201</b> and the sensor <b>105</b>, such that the pad is configured to directly engage an end of the sensor <b>105</b>. The pad can be made of a soft material suitable for absorbing shocks and limiting physical strain on the sensor <b>105</b>. For instance, the pad can include a polymer material, such as an elastomer.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As further illustrated, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can include a biasing member <b>203</b> that is configured to be disposed over the spacer <b>201</b> and engage an upper major surface of the spacer <b>201</b>. The biasing member <b>203</b>, as illustrated, can be in the form of a spring member, and may be used to facilitate biasing of other components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> against the sensor <b>105</b>, thus urging the components in an axial direction away from the sensor <b>105</b>. Moreover, the biasing member <b>203</b> may be used to facilitate proper operation between open and closed positions of the detector assembly, and more particularly, may be suitable for removal of particular components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> thus facilitating the field-serviceable design. That is, because the biasing member <b>203</b> is disposed between the cap assembly <b>112</b> and the sensor <b>105</b>, the cap assembly <b>112</b> and the sensor <b>105</b> are biased against each other and urged in opposite directions, and thus once the cap assembly <b>112</b> is disengaged from the detector housing <b>103</b>, the cap assembly <b>112</b> is urged axially from the detector housing <b>103</b>, thus opening the end of the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The biasing member <b>203</b> can be formed of a particular material, including for example, an inorganic material, such as a metal or metal alloy material. Alternatively, the biasing member <b>203</b> may be formed of an organic material, such as a polymer. In accordance with a particular embodiment, the biasing member <b>211</b> is made of a refractory metal or metal alloy, including for example, stainless steel, titanium, nickel, cobalt, chrome, aluminum or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The cap assembly <b>112</b> can include a push plate <b>205</b>, which can be configured to be seated over the biasing member <b>203</b>, and more particularly, between the biasing member <b>203</b> and a radially expandable member as will be described herein. As illustrated, the push plate <b>205</b> can be formed such that it has a flange <b>208</b> having an upper surface <b>206</b> configured to engage components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> thereon. Additionally, the push plate <b>205</b> can include a hub <b>207</b> extending axially from the flange <b>208</b> along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>, which may be configured to engage other components of the cap assembly as will be described in more detain herein. Notably, the hub <b>207</b> can be formed such that it has a length suitable to engage and extend through other components of the cap assembly <b>112</b>. Additionally, the push plate <b>205</b>, and particularly the hub <b>207</b> can have a central opening extending axially through the entire height of the body configured to allow passage of the wires <b>115</b> therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The push plate <b>205</b> may be made of an inorganic material, organic material, or a combination thereof. Particularly suitable inorganic materials may include a metal or metal alloy material. Such metal or metal alloy materials may incorporate one or more transition metal elements. In one particular instance, the push plate <b>205</b> can consist essentially of stainless steel. Alternatively, the push plate <b>205</b> may be formed of an organic material, such as a polymer, and more particularly, a thermoset, thermoplastic, or elastomer.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can further include a lock disk <b>210</b>. The lock disk <b>210</b> can be sized and shaped such that it may engage the push plate <b>205</b>. For example, in certain positions (e.g., an open position), the lock disk <b>210</b> may be seated on the upper surface <b>206</b> of the flange <b>208</b> of the push plate <b>205</b>. Additionally, the lock disk <b>210</b> may be formed such that it has a central opening <b>218</b> that is configured to engage at least a portion of the hub <b>207</b> therein. For example, the hub <b>207</b> can extend axially along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> through the central opening <b>218</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b>. Additionally, the central opening <b>218</b> may permit passage of other components, such as the wires <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As illustrated, in accordance with one embodiment, the lock disk <b>210</b> may include a groove region <b>212</b> that may be sized and shaped to engage a component of the cap assembly <b>112</b> as will be described in more detail herein. In particular, the groove region <b>212</b> can be a region at the external, peripheral surface of the lock disk <b>210</b> that has a different dimension as compared to other regions along the external, peripheral surface of the lock disk <b>210</b>. In particular, the groove region <b>212</b> can have a ledge surface <b>213</b> extending radially inward, in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> and defining a step between a lower perimeter surface <b>216</b> and an upper perimeter surface <b>214</b>. As illustrated, the upper perimeter surface <b>214</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b> and particularly of the groove region <b>212</b> can define an exterior surface having a smaller dimension (i.e., circumference) as compared to the lower surface <b>216</b>. The difference in external dimensions between the lower perimeter surface <b>216</b> and upper perimeter surface <b>214</b> facilitates the formation of the groove region <b>212</b> and accommodation of a component of the cap assembly <b>112</b> therein.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Moreover, the lock disk <b>210</b> can include openings <b>217</b> spaced apart from the central opening <b>218</b> and situated at regular intervals throughout a circumference of the lock disk <b>210</b>. In particular, the openings <b>217</b> can extend axially through the full of the height of the lock disk <b>210</b> along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>. The openings <b>217</b> may be formed to facilitate engagement of the fasteners <b>231</b> therein and thereby facilitate coupling between one or more components of the cap assembly <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The lock disk <b>210</b> may be formed of an inorganic material, an organic material, or a combination thereof. In particular embodiments, the lock disk <b>210</b> may be formed of the same material as the push plate <b>205</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">As further illustrated, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can include a radially expandable member <b>215</b>. The radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be an annular-shaped member configured to engage the lock disk <b>210</b> within the groove region <b>212</b>. In particular, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be formed such that is configured to be seated on the ledged surface <b>213</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b> in a closed position of the detector assembly. As will be appreciated, the radially expandable member can change diameters, expanding radially, such that upon placement of particular components (e.g., the lock disk <b>210</b> and the radially expandable member <b>215</b>) of the cap assembly <b>112</b> at certain positions within the cavity <b>251</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> may change dimensions (e.g., expand in a radial direction) and fix the components of the cap assembly <b>112</b> at an axial position within the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In certain instances, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be a lock ring, having a generally annular shape and a central opening configured to engage a portion of the lock disk <b>210</b> therein. As illustrated, and in accordance with an embodiment, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be a split ring having a split <b>219</b> extending axially along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>. One particular embodiment may utilize a Hoopster&#x2122; retaining ring, available from Smalley Steel Ring Company.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The radially expandable member can be formed of an inorganic material, such as a metal or metal alloy. In particular instances, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be formed of a metal alloy comprising a transition metal element. For example, in one embodiment, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be made of steel such as stainless steel. In one particular embodiment, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> consists essentially of steel.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The cap assembly <b>112</b> can further include a shield cap <b>113</b> that may be sized such that it is configured to fit over the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> and facilitate closing of the detector housing <b>103</b>. As illustrated, the shield cap <b>113</b> may include a bottom surface <b>223</b> that is configured to engage the upper surface of the lock disk <b>210</b> in certain positions, such as in an open position. Moreover, the shield cap <b>113</b> can include a central opening <b>229</b> extending along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>, which may extend through the entire body of the shield cap <b>113</b>. In particular, the central opening <b>229</b> may facilitate extension of the wires <b>115</b> therethrough, such that the wires <b>115</b> can extend outside the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The shield cap <b>113</b> can include a protrusion <b>227</b> extending axially from the body along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>, which may facilitate user manipulation of the shield cap <b>113</b> during assembly and disassembly of the cap assembly <b>112</b>. As further illustrated, the protrusion <b>227</b> can include a flange <b>228</b> which may further facilitate user manipulation of the shield cap <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As further illustrated, the shield cap <b>113</b> can include openings <b>225</b> formed to facilitate engagement of the fasteners <b>231</b> therein. As such, the openings <b>225</b> may align with openings <b>217</b> within the lock disk <b>210</b>, such that fasteners <b>231</b> may be directly engaged with the shield cap <b>113</b> and extend into the lock disk <b>210</b>, thereby directly coupling the lock disk <b>210</b> and shield cap <b>113</b> to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The shield cap <b>113</b> may be formed of an inorganic material, such as a metal or metal alloy. In particular, the shield cap <b>113</b> may be formed of a metal alloy incorporating transition metal elements. In certain instances, the shield cap <b>113</b> can be made of stainless steel, such that it consists essentially of stainless steel. In other designs, the shield cap <b>113</b> can be made of a titanium-containing metal alloy, including, for example, Ti-6Al-4V metal alloy.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> include cross-sectional illustrations of portions of the detector assembly demonstrating the operation of the cap assembly <b>112</b>. In particular, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> demonstrate aspects of the releasable coupling mechanism utilized by the cap assembly to facilitate formation of a field-serviceable detector assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> includes a cross-sectional image of a portion of a detector assembly and cap assembly in accordance with an embodiment. In particular, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a cap assembly <b>112</b> as provided in an open position, and particularly a partially open position, with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>. In the open position, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can be positioned with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>, such that the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> is not closed, and more particularly a flange surface <b>421</b> of the shield cap <b>113</b> is disengaged and axially spaced apart from an end surface <b>395</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As illustrated, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can be assembled such that the spacer <b>201</b> is disposed between the sensor <b>105</b> and the biasing member <b>203</b>. The biasing member <b>203</b> can be disposed between the sensor <b>105</b> and the radially expandable member <b>215</b> of the cap assembly <b>112</b>, and more particularly, between the sensor <b>105</b> and lower surface of the flange <b>208</b> of the push plate <b>205</b> to facilitate biasing of the push plate <b>205</b>, lock disk <b>210</b>, radially expandable member <b>215</b>, and shield cap <b>113</b>. In particular instances, particularly in a partially open position and a closed position, the push plate <b>205</b>, lock disk <b>210</b>, radially expandable member <b>215</b>, and shield cap <b>113</b> have an axial force applied by the biasing member <b>203</b> such that the components are urged in a direction toward the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. As such, when moving the cap assembly <b>112</b> between an open position and a closed position, the biasing member may change position, and more particularly, change dimensions of height as measured axially along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>, which facilitates coupling and decoupling of the cap assembly <b>112</b> from the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The push plate <b>205</b>, and particularly the flange <b>208</b>, may be formed to fit within the cavity <b>251</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> and be in direct contact with a lower surface of the lock disk <b>210</b> when the cap assembly <b>112</b> is in the open position based on the pressure exerted by the biasing member <b>203</b> on the rear surface of the flange <b>208</b>. As further illustrated, the hub <b>207</b> of the push plate <b>205</b> can extend axially along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> and through the central opening <b>218</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b>. In particular embodiments, the hub <b>207</b> can be formed to have a sufficient length such that it extends through the entire height of the lock disk <b>210</b> and protrudes beyond an upper surface <b>331</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b>, such that it is configured to engage a portion of the shield cap <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As further illustrated, the lock disk <b>210</b> can include the radially expandable member <b>215</b>, which may be configured to radially expand at a particular position within the interior of the detector housing <b>103</b>, thereby locking the axial position of the radially expandable member <b>215</b> and the lock disk <b>210</b> along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> within the detector housing <b>103</b>. While such features will be described in more detail herein, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates that the radially expandable member <b>215</b> may be engaged within surface feature <b>305</b>, such as a groove, formed within the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>, thereby facilitating locking of the axial position of the radially expandable member <b>215</b> and lock disk <b>210</b> with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It will be appreciated, that upon initial insertion of the lock disk <b>210</b> and the radially expandable member <b>215</b> into the cavity of the detector housing <b>103</b>, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> may be in a compressed state within the groove region <b>212</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b>. Upon insertion of the lock disk <b>210</b> to a suitable axial distance, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> may be aligned with certain surface features (e.g. a groove) within the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>, allowing the radially expandable member <b>215</b> to expand and thereby engage the detector housing <b>103</b>. As such, the lock disk <b>210</b> and the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be directly coupled to the detector housing <b>103</b> and the axial position of the lock disk <b>210</b> and radially expandable member <b>215</b> are fixed with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As further illustrated, the shield cap <b>113</b> can include a central opening <b>229</b>, which may be aligned axially with the central opening <b>218</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b> to facilitate passage of the wires <b>115</b> through the cap assembly <b>112</b> and external to the detector housing <b>103</b>. As further illustrated, the hub <b>207</b> of the push plate <b>205</b> can be configured to extend axially along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> and have an upper surface configured to engage a surface <b>301</b> of the shield cap <b>113</b>, such that upon movement of the shield cap <b>113</b> from one axial position to a different axial position along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>, the push plate <b>205</b> can be actuated by the shield cap <b>113</b> and moved correspondingly between the axial positions. Moreover, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, fasteners <b>231</b> can extend through the openings <b>225</b> of the shield cap <b>113</b> and further engage the lock disk <b>210</b> within the openings <b>217</b>, facilitating direct connection between the lock disk <b>210</b> and shield cap <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> includes a cross-sectional illustration of a detector assembly and cap assembly in a closed position in accordance with an embodiment. Notably, in the closed position, the shield cap <b>113</b> has been moved along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> in the direction <b>401</b> such that the flange surface <b>421</b> of the shield cap <b>113</b> is abutting and directly contacting the end surface <b>395</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. In particular, closing the end of the detector housing <b>103</b> can be facilitated by the movement of the fasteners <b>231</b> into the openings <b>217</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b> such that the shield cap <b>113</b> is fastened to the lock disk <b>210</b> and thereby directly connected to the lock disk <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Moreover, the closure of the cap assembly <b>112</b> in the direction <b>401</b> further facilitates axial movement of the push plate <b>205</b> in the direction <b>401</b> as the surface <b>301</b> of the shield cap <b>113</b> is engaged with the hub <b>207</b> of the push plate <b>205</b>. As such, a gap <b>405</b> can be formed between the upper surface <b>206</b> of the flange <b>208</b> of the push plate <b>205</b> and a lower surface <b>407</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b>. The gap <b>405</b> may be referred to as a working height, which is a measure of a suitable distance along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> between the lower surface <b>407</b> of the lock disk <b>210</b> and the upper surface <b>206</b> of the push plate that facilitates proper coupling between the shield cap <b>113</b> and the lock plate <b>210</b> as well as proper biasing of the biasing member <b>203</b>. That is, as further illustrated, in a change between the open position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and the closed position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the shield cap <b>113</b> is moved in the direction <b>401</b>, which in turn moves the push plate <b>205</b> in the direction <b>401</b> and the biasing member <b>203</b> is compressed such that the push plate <b>205</b>, lock disk <b>210</b> and shield cap <b>113</b> of the cap assembly <b>112</b> are suitably biased away from the sensor <b>105</b> contained within the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In accordance with an embodiment, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can be formed such that it includes components that are directly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b> and components that are indirectly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b> to facilitate closing the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. In particular, the cap assembly <b>112</b> can include components such as the lock disk <b>210</b> and radially expandable member <b>215</b> that are configured to be directly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b>. The lock disk <b>210</b> can be directly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b> via the radially expandable member <b>215</b>, which locks the axial position of the lock disk <b>210</b> with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>. The shield cap <b>113</b> can be configured to be directly connected to the lock disk <b>210</b> via fasteners <b>231</b>. Notably, the shield cap <b>113</b> can be configured to be indirectly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b>, since without the positioning of the lock disk <b>210</b> within the detector housing <b>103</b>, the axial position of the shield cap <b>113</b> could not be fixed with respect to the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In particular, the fasteners <b>231</b> can be spaced apart from the surfaces of the detector housing <b>103</b>. As such, the fasteners <b>231</b> are configured to directly connect the shield cap <b>113</b> and lock disk <b>210</b> to each other and may be completely disengaged from the detector housing <b>103</b>. In short, the fasteners <b>231</b> may be oriented such that they extend along the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> between the shield cap <b>113</b> and push plate <b>205</b> and may be disengaged from direct connection with the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The cap assembly <b>112</b> may further include a gap <b>409</b> formed between a surface <b>421</b> of the shield cap and an interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. The gap <b>409</b> may facilitate engagement of a sealing member therein. Particularly suitable sealing members may include an o-ring or the like, such that the end <b>107</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> is suitably sealed against the shield cap <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> includes a cross-sectional illustration of a portion of the detector housing and radially expandable member in accordance with an embodiment. It will be appreciated that certain other components have been removed from the figure for simplicity's sake. In accordance with embodiments herein, the detector housing <b>103</b> can be a thin-walled structure, wherein the inner diameter <b>515</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> is a particular percentage of the value of the outer diameter <b>517</b>. Notably, the industry continues to seek detector housings capable of holding the largest possible sensors, and accordingly, detector housings utilizing thinner wall thickness to accommodate larger sensors. In accordance with an embodiment, the detector housing <b>103</b> can have an outer diameter <b>517</b> within a range between about 15 mm and about 60 mm, such as between about 18 mm and about 60 mm, or even between about 20 mm and about 60 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As noted herein, the detector housing <b>103</b> can be a thin-walled structure, such that the inner diameter <b>515</b> may be within a range between about 15 mm and about 60 mm, such as between about 16 mm and about 59 mm, or even between about 17 mm and about 58 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The thin-walled structure of the detector housing <b>103</b> can be defined such that the inner diameter <b>515</b> has a dimension of at least about 90% and not greater than about 99% of the dimension of the outer diameter <b>517</b>. In fact, embodiments herein may utilize a detector <b>103</b> wherein the inner diameter <b>515</b> has a dimension of at least 92% and not greater than about 99%, such as on the order of at least about 93% and not greater than about 99%, at least about 94% and not greater than about 99%, or even at least about 96% and not greater than about 99% of the dimension of the outer diameter <b>517</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In more particular terms, the detector housing <b>103</b> may have an average side wall thickness <b>501</b> as measured between the interior surface <b>303</b> and exterior surface <b>551</b> in a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axis <b>299</b> that is not greater than about 3.0 mm. In other instances, average side wall thickness <b>501</b> can be not greater than about 2.5 mm, not greater than about 2.0 mm, not greater than about 1.5 mm, not greater than about 1.25 mm, not greater than about 1.0 mm, not greater than about 0.9 mm, or even greater than about 0.8 mm. Still, in particular embodiments, the average side wall thickness <b>501</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> can be within a range between about 0.2 mm and about 3.0 mm, between about 0.2 mm and about 2.5 mm, such as between about 0.3 mm and about 2.0 mm, or between about 0.3 mm and 1.5 mm, between about 0.3 mm and about 1 mm, or even between about 0.3 mm and 0.8 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">As further illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the radially expandable member <b>215</b>, which is a component configured to be directly connected to the detector housing <b>103</b>, can be connected to the detector housing <b>103</b> via a complimentary engagement structure <b>530</b>. In accordance with an embodiment, the complimentary engagement structure <b>530</b> can be formed via interlocking surfaces between two components, for example, the radially expandable member <b>215</b> and the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>. In particular, the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> can be formed to include a surface feature <b>305</b>, which can be a groove in particular designs, that extends radially outward into the side wall of the detector housing <b>103</b>. The surface feature <b>305</b> can be sized and shaped, such that it is configured to engage at least a portion of the radially expanding member <b>215</b> therein.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">As will be appreciated, the surface feature <b>305</b> may extend for a fraction of the perimeter (i.e., circumference) of the interior surface <b>303</b> about the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>. Alternatively, the surface feature <b>305</b> can extend around the entire perimeter (i.e., circumference) of the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> about the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>. It will be appreciated that the radially expandable member <b>215</b> can be engaged within the surface feature <b>305</b> through substantially the entire perimeter of the inner surface <b>303</b> with the exception of a small radial gap that may exist.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">In certain designs, the detector housing <b>103</b> can be formed such that the surface feature <b>305</b> (e.g., the groove) has a depth <b>503</b> that can be measured between the interior surface <b>303</b> and a bottom surface <b>511</b> of the groove <b>305</b>, which may be a particular fraction of the average side wall thickness <b>501</b>. As illustrated, the depth <b>503</b> can be measured in a direction that is substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis <b>299</b>. In accordance with an embodiment, the depth <b>503</b> of the surface feature <b>305</b> can be at least about 5% of the sidewall thickness <b>501</b>. In other instances, the surface feature <b>305</b> can have a greater depth <b>503</b>, such as on the order of at least about 10%, at least about 12%, at least about 15%, or even at least about 18% of the average side wall thickness <b>501</b>. Still, in particular instances, the surface feature <b>305</b> can have a depth <b>503</b> that is within a range between about 5% and 60%, such as between about 10% and about 60%, between about 15% and about 60%, between about 20% and about 60%, between about 30% and about 60%, between about 40% and 60%, between about 45% and about 60%, or even between about 50% and about 60% of the average side wall thickness <b>501</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">In certain designs, the detector housing <b>103</b> can be formed such that the surface feature <b>305</b> (e.g., the groove) has a depth <b>503</b> that can be at least about 0.15 mm, such as at least about 0.18 mm, at least about 0.2 mm, at least about 0.25 mm, or even at least about 0.3 mm. In particular instances, surface feature <b>305</b> can have a depth <b>503</b> that can be within a range between about 0.15 mm and about 2 mm, such as between about 0.15 mm and about 1.5 mm, between about 0.18 mm and about 1 mm, or even between about 0.2 mm and about 0.5 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6-8</figref> include illustrations of certain components in accordance with an alternative design of the cap assembly. In accordance with at least one alternative design, the cap assembly <b>112</b> may utilize a different radially expandable member as compared to the previously described lock ring. For example, the cap assembly <b>112</b> may utilize a lock disk that has radially expandable capabilities. That is, the lock disk may be actuated to facilitate radial expansion of at least a portion of the body of the lock disk to fix the axial position of the lock disk within the detector housing <b>103</b> and facilitate a direct connection between the lock disk and detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> includes a top view of a lock disk in accordance with an embodiment. In particular, the lock disk <b>610</b> can include a central opening <b>218</b> and openings <b>217</b> configured to engage fasteners therein as described in accordance with embodiments herein. Notably, the lock disk <b>610</b> can include a groove <b>603</b> extending radially between an outer surface <b>611</b> defining the outer diameter of the lock disk <b>610</b> and an inner surface <b>612</b> defining the central opening <b>218</b> of the lock disk <b>610</b>. Moreover, the lock disk <b>610</b> can include an opening <b>605</b> connected to and intersecting the groove <b>603</b> that may facilitate engagement of an actuator therein.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> includes a side view illustration of an actuator in accordance with an embodiment. In particular, the actuator <b>701</b> can include an upper end <b>707</b> and a lower end <b>706</b>, wherein the upper end can include a head portion <b>703</b> which is connected to a shaft <b>705</b> having a tapered shape. In certain designs, the width of the actuator <b>701</b> can be narrower at the end <b>706</b> than the width of the actuator <b>701</b> at the end <b>707</b>. It will be appreciated, that the actuator can be a pin, bolt, screw, or the like having a particular shape which may be engaged within the opening <b>605</b> of the lock disk <b>610</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> includes a top view illustration of a lock disk in accordance with an embodiment. In particular, the lock disk <b>610</b> is illustrated in a different position as compared to the position of the lock disk <b>610</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. Notably, the actuator <b>701</b> is disposed within the opening <b>605</b>, which facilitates opening and separation of the gap <b>603</b>. As such, incorporation of the actuator <b>701</b> within the opening <b>605</b> can facilitate changing (i.e., increasing) the diameter <b>851</b> of the lock disk <b>610</b> as compared to the diameter <b>651</b> of the lock disk <b>610</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> without the actuator <b>701</b> disposed within the opening <b>605</b>. That is, the actuator <b>701</b> can be used to change the diameter of the lock disk <b>610</b> such that the diameter <b>851</b> can be greater than the diameter <b>651</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In one particular embodiment, the actuator <b>701</b> can be a threaded fastener that can be threaded into the opening <b>605</b> of the lock disk <b>610</b>, which can facilitate radial expansion of the lock disk <b>610</b> and an increase in the diameter of the body of the lock disk <b>610</b>. During assembly, the lock disk <b>610</b> may be disposed within the cavity <b>251</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>, and upon proper placement of the lock disk <b>610</b> within the cavity <b>251</b>, the actuator <b>701</b> may be placed within the opening <b>605</b>. Upon sufficient engagement of the actuator <b>701</b> within the opening <b>605</b>, the gap <b>603</b> can be urged to widen thus causing radial expansion of the lock disk <b>610</b>. Radial expansion of the lock disk <b>610</b> can facilitate direct connection between the interior surface <b>303</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b> and the lock disk <b>610</b>, thus fixing the axial position of the lock disk <b>610</b> within the cavity <b>251</b> of the detector housing <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The components and methods disclosed herein represent a departure from the state-of-the-art. Generally, conventional scintillation articles include a sensor having wires extending from the end of the detector housing through a unitary shield cap. Such designs typically closed the detector housing in a permanent manner, via welding or epoxies. Alternatively, some conventional detector housings may have utilized fasteners, but generally fasteners could only be used with detector housings having substantial wall thicknesses. In the past, servicing of detector assemblies was not generally conducted, but if servicing was needed, extraction of the sensor from the housing included destructively removing the shield cap and extracting the internal components from the housing. As can be appreciated, such a process may results in additional costs and potential damage to sensitive components, such as the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">By contrast, the detector assembly disclosed herein includes a unique design including a combination of components allowing for operation of the article in industrial environments while further providing a field-serviceable design that utilizes a releasable coupling arrangement between a cap assembly and detector housing that can be used in large sensor and thin-walled detector housing designs. Releasable coupling attachments herein are field-serviceable designs allowing for opening and closing of the detector assembly using common hand tools. Notably, the embodiments described herein include a multi-component cap assembly, including a shield cap, lock disk, push plate, biasing member, and a radially expandable member configured for use with each other, and engagement with particular surface features of the detector housing to form a releasably coupling assembly. Moreover, the components described herein also facilitate operations in industrial environments, providing shock absorption capabilities and integrity in environments having varying temperatures.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The above-disclosed subject matter is to be considered illustrative, and not restrictive, and the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications, enhancements, and other embodiments, which fall within the true scope of the present invention. Thus, to the maximum extent allowed by law, the scope of the present invention is to be determined by the broadest permissible interpretation of the following claims and their equivalents, and shall not be restricted or limited by the foregoing detailed description.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The foregoing disclosure does not limit the scope or meaning of the claims and should not be interpreted as such. In addition, in the foregoing description, various features may be grouped together or described in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an intention that the claimed embodiments require more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter may be directed to less than all features of any of the disclosed embodiments. Thus, the following claims are incorporated into the description and figures, with each claim standing on its own as defining separately claimed subject matter.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A detector assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a sensor disposed within a detector housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap assembly releasably connected to the detector housing and comprising a radially expandable member, wherein the cap assembly is moveable between an open position and a closed position, and wherein in the closed position the detector assembly is sealed by the cap assembly and the radially expandable member is in an expanded position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the radially expandable member is configured to expand radially into a groove within an interior surface of the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the detector housing has an average side wall thickness and the groove has a depth of at least about 5% of the average side wall thickness.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the groove extends around an entire circumference of the interior surface of the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the detector housing has an outer diameter (OD) and an inner diameter (ID) defining a cavity within the detector housing, wherein the ID has a dimension of at least about 90% and not greater than about 99% of the dimension of the OD.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cap assembly further comprises:
<claim-text>a shield cap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a push plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lock disk disposed between the shield cap and the push plate, wherein:
<claim-text>in an open position the shield cap is disengaged from the detector housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in changing the cap assembly from the open position to the closed position the shield cap engages the push plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sensor comprises a wire extending axially through the cap assembly external to the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a lock disk, wherein the lock disk is configured to be moved between the open and closed positions via an actuator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the actuator has a tapered shape configured to separate portions of the lock disk from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cap assembly comprises a lock disk configured to lock an axial position of a portion of the cap assembly within an interior of the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the radially expandable member comprises a lock ring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the cap assembly comprises a lock disk configured to lock an axial position of a portion of the cap assembly within an interior of the detector housing, and the lock ring is configured to engage an exterior surface of the lock disk.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the lock ring is a split ring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the cap assembly further comprises a lock disk configured to lock an axial position of a portion of the cap assembly within an interior of the detector housing, and a shield cap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the lock disk is a first component directly connected to the detector housing, and the shield cap is a second component indirectly connected to the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the cap assembly further comprises a push plate, and the lock disk is disposed between the push plate and the shield cap in the closed position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the shield cap is connected to the lock disk.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The detector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the radially expandable member is configured to engage a surface feature at an interior surface of the detector housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
