<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624140-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624140</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11822840</doc-number>
<date>20070710</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-189726</doc-number>
<date>20060710</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-189804</doc-number>
<date>20060710</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="03" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-189825</doc-number>
<date>20060710</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>154</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2003022</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e108">Key switch and keyboard</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5283407</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pohl</name>
<date>19940200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200332</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5642950</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hochgesang et al.</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2003022</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6376789</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Maruyama et al.</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200344</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>09-306271</doc-number>
<date>19971100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-063394</doc-number>
<date>19980300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-231090</doc-number>
<date>20020800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-251937</doc-number>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-334627</doc-number>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-031067</doc-number>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2003022</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200344</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2003021</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200341</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>16</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080006516</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nishino</last-name>
<first-name>Takeshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maruyama</last-name>
<first-name>Junichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Shuji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nishino</last-name>
<first-name>Takeshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maruyama</last-name>
<first-name>Junichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Shuji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shinagawa</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Staas &#x26; Halsey LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fujitsu Component Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Figueroa</last-name>
<first-name>Felix O</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A key switch preferably used for a keyboard as an input device in electronic equipment. The key switch includes a base section; a key top disposed above the base section; a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top in a vertical direction relative to the base section; a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to a vertical movement of the key top; and a biasing member capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction to the key top. The key switch further includes a protection member disposed and inserted between the base section and the key top at a position where the protection member surrounds the pair of link members, the contact section and the biasing member. The protection member is elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top, and protects the pair of link members, the contact section and the biasing member from penetration of foreign matter.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="75.10mm" wi="161.12mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.23mm" wi="172.64mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="209.80mm" wi="174.07mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="205.74mm" wi="168.83mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="183.81mm" wi="145.46mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="186.94mm" wi="140.89mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="177.12mm" wi="133.10mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="199.31mm" wi="176.87mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="219.29mm" wi="167.89mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="213.19mm" wi="179.66mm" file="US08624140-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to a switch configuration for a keying operation, and more particularly to a key-entry switch device (hereinafter referred to as a key switch) preferably used for a keyboard incorporated as an input device in electronic equipment. The present invention also relates to a keyboard provided with a plurality of key switches.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In a thinner or low-profile type keyboard, equipped for a portable electronic apparatus such as a notebook or palm-top personal computer, it is required to reduce the height of a key switch for a keying operation as well as to improve the operability and structural reliability of the key switch. The key switch usable in the low-profile keyboard typically includes a base section, a key top disposed above the base section, a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top in an upward-and-downward direction (or a substantially vertical direction), a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to the vertical or upward-and-downward movement of the key top, and a biasing member capable of applying an elastic biasing force (i.e., an initial-position recovering force) in a vertically upward direction to the key top. The key top is movable substantially in the vertical direction relative to the base section, through an interlocking action of the link members, while keeping a predetermined posture of the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Conventionally, in the above key switch, several types of link-member pairs have been used. For example, the first type pair of link members, which may be referred to as a gear-link type, are assembled together into a reverse V-shape as seen from a lateral direction (or in a side view) and meshed at toothed end regions thereof with each other (see, e.g., Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication (Kokai) No. 2003-031067 (JP-A-2003-031067)). The second type pair of link members, which may be referred to as a pantograph type, are assembled together into an X-shape as seen from a lateral direction (or in a side view) and rotatably or slidably joined at intersections thereof with each other (see, e.g., Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication (Kokai) Nos. 2002-231090 (JP-A-2002-231090), 2002-334627 (JP-A-2002-334627), and 2002-251937 (JP-A-2002-251937)). Also, a switch member which is widely used, is configured from a sheet-like switch including a pair of flexible circuit boards respectively carrying contacts in a mutually facing arrangement (referred to as a membrane switch sheet, in this application), the pair of contacts constituting a contact section capable of opening and closing.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The key switch further includes an actuating member making the contact section of the switch member open or close in response to the vertical movement of the key top. For example, the key switch disclosed in JP-A-2003-031067 uses a dome-shaped actuating member made of a rubber, which is disposed between the key top and the membrane switch sheet. When the key top reaches a lower limit position of the vertical movement, the actuating member acts to press, at the inner side of the dome top thereof, the membrane switch sheet, and thus makes the contact section close. On the other hand, the dome-shaped actuating member also acts as the above-described biasing member that is elastically deformed in response to the vertical downward movement of the key top, so as to apply the initial-position recovering force to the key top. In this key switch, during a keying operation of the key top, the actuating member (or the biasing member) is elastically deformed in a buckling manner due to the dome shape thereof, so that the elastic biasing force, non-linearly corresponding to the amount of depression of the key top, is applied to the key top, whereby ensuring unique keying operation properties involving a so-called click feeling.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The first pending technical situation relevant to the conventional key switches is described below. Due to a diversified environment for using a keyboard as an input device of an electronic apparatus, it is required that the keyboard be equipped with a protection structure for protecting an internal structure (e.g., an electrical contact section, a vertically guiding section, etc.) of each of the plurality of key switches installed in the keyboard from the penetration of foreign matter such as dust, liquid and the like. It is known that a separate cover member is provided, as the above-described protection structure, which is additionally or optionally fitted to the keyboard so as to entirely cover the key-arranging surface of the keyboard. However, due to the existence of the cover member, the keying operability for each key switch or the touch feeling of a finger may be deteriorated. Therefore, it is conventionally proposed that a protection function against the penetration of foreign matter is incorporated into the key switch.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">For example, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication (Kokai) No. 10-063394 (JP-A-10-063394) discloses a key switch including a key top slidably guided in a vertical direction relative to a base section, wherein a protection member (or a cup rubber) for preventing dust or liquid from penetrating an electric circuit inside the base section through a gap defined in a slide guide structure of the key top (which includes a tubular guide provided in the base section and a slider provided in the key top) is disposed between the base section and the key top. In this key switch, the cup rubber is a tubular element elastically deformable in response to the vertical downward movement of the key top, and acts to surround the slide guide structure, during vertical movement of the key top, so as to inhibit the penetration of dust or liquid into the base section. The cup rubber also acts, due to the elastic restoring force thereof, as a biasing member for applying an initial-position recovering force in an upward direction to the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The key switch described in JP-A-10-063394 includes the slide-guide type key top frequently used in a keyboard having a normal size, i.e., not a low-profile type. The built-in cup rubber is configured to surround the columnar slide-guide structure formed by the tubular guide of the base section and the slider of the key top, while acting as the biasing member for returning the key top to the initial position. In this configuration, in which the region to be protected against the penetration of foreign matter has relatively narrow gap between the tubular guide and the slider, the protection function required to the cup rubber is not strict, and therefore, the cup rubber can also be used as the biasing member.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">However, in the key switch used for a low-profile keyboard, as described in, e.g., JP-A-2003-031067 or JP-A-2002-231090, in which a supporting and directing structure for the key top is formed by a pair of link members interlocked with each other in an openable and closable manner about a mutually joining point, the movable sections of the supporting and directing structure exist in a relatively large area between the base section and the key top, and also a gap permitting an access to the contact section of the switch member (defined at, e.g., an engaging portion between the base section and the link member, an interacting portion between the contact section and the actuating member, etc.) is formed in a relatively large area of the base section. If foreign matter, such as dust, liquid, etc., penetrates the movable sections of the link members or the engaging portions between the base section and the link members, the keying operation properties of the key top may be affected, and, if foreign matter penetrates the interacting portion between the contact section of the switch member and the actuating member, the accuracy of the opening or closing action of the contact may be deteriorated. Therefore, it is required that a key switch used for a low-profile keyboard includes a more strict protection function against the penetration of the foreign matter into the internal structure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The second pending technical situation relevant to the conventional key switches is described below. In conventional key switches, as described in JP-A-2003-031067 or JP-A-2002-334627, a pair of link members are assembled in an interlockable manner with each other and movably attached to both the base section and the key top. For example, in the key switch disclosed in JP-A-2003-031067, each link member is provided at a first end region thereof with a sliding axle slidably engaged with the base section and at a second end region thereof, opposite to the first end region, with a pivoting axle pivotably joined to the key top and a tooth meshable with a tooth of a counterpart link member in a gearing manner. Correspondingly, the base section is provided with slide support sections having guide grooves for respectively receiving the sliding axles of the link members, and the key top is provided with pivot support sections having bearing holes for respectively receiving the pivoting axles of the link members.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">When assembling the key switch of JP-A-2003-031067, the pair of link members are laid on the base section in a flat state (i.e., in a state where the link members do not show the reverse V-shape, but show an opened shape along one plane), with their teeth being meshed with each other, and with their sliding axles being inserted into the respective guide grooves of the slide support sections of the base section. In this state, the key top is pressed onto the link members laid in the flat state, so as to fit the pivoting axles of the link members into the corresponding bearing holes of the pivot support sections of the key top. In order to enable this attachment procedure, the pivot support sections of the key top are provided with notches extending from their outer edges to the bearing holes. When attaching the key top, the pivoting axles of the link members are received in the notches of the pivot support sections and thereby the pivot support sections are elastically expanded, and then, the key top is further pressed on the link members, so as to fit the pivoting axles into the bearing holes in a snap-fit manner.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">On the other hand, in the key switch disclosed in JP-A-2002-334627, a pair of link members are mutually joined at their central region in a relatively rotatable manner, and include a first link member that is provided at a first end region thereof with a sliding axle slidably engaged with the base section and at a second end region thereof, opposite to the first end region, with a pivoting axle pivotably joined to the key top, and a second link member that is provided at a first end region thereof with a pivoting axle pivotably joined to the base section and at a second end region thereof, opposite to the first end region, with a sliding axle slidably engaged with the key top. Correspondingly, the base section is provided with a slide support section having a guide groove for receiving the sliding axle of the first link member and a pivot support section having a bearing groove for receiving the pivoting axle of the second link member, while the key top is provided with a pivot support section having a bearing groove for receiving the pivoting axle of the first link member.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Further, the key switch of CP-A-2002-334627 includes an actuator attached to the inner surface of the key top. The actuator includes a pivot support section having a bearing groove for receiving the pivoting axle of the first link member in an auxiliary manner, and a slide support section having a guide groove for receiving the sliding axle of the second link member. According to this configuration, when a force is applied to the key top in a direction detaching the key top from the first and second link members, the force is dispersed so as to reduce damage that may otherwise occur in the respective pivot and slide support sections.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the key switch of JP-A-2003-031067, in order to improve operability for attaching the key top to the pair of link members, the pivot support sections of the key top are provided respectively with notches extending from the outer edges to the bearing holes. These notches act to allow the pivoting axles of the link members to be easily fitted into the bearing holes in a snap-fit manner, but may allow the key top to be easily detached from the link members.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In particular, when external force is applied to the outer periphery of the key top in a direction pulling-up the key top apart from the base section, the key switch having the link members of the gear-link type shows geometrical properties such that, with regard to a force point (i.e., the outer periphery of the key top), a fulcrum (i.e., one pivot support section farther from the force point) and an application point (i.e., another pivot support section closer to the force point), a ratio of a distance between the fulcrum and the application point to a distance between the force point and the fulcrum is relatively small, and therefore, a force generated at the application point (i.e., a force acting to detach the pivot support section closer to the force point from the pivoting axle of the link member) becomes relatively large. As a result, the pivoting axle may be disengaged from the bearing hole while expanding the notch, and the key top thus may be detached from the link members. Further, a relatively large amount of application force may damage the pivot support section.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In contrast to this, in the key switch of JP-A-2002-334627, due to the provision of the actuator attached to the inner surface of the key top, when force is applied to the key top in a direction detaching the key top from the first and second link members, it is possible to stop damage that may occur in the pivot and slide support sections. However, in the link members of the pantograph type in JP-A-2002-334627, a distance between the support sections (i.e., the pivot support section and the slide support section) on the key top for movably supporting the pair of link members is considerably larger than a distance between the support sections (i.e., the pivot support sections) on the key top for the link members of the gear-link type in JP-A-2003-031067, and therefore, when the external force is applied to the outer periphery of the key top to pull-up the key top apart from the base section as described above, a disengaging force generated at an application point (i.e., the pivot support section or the slide support section) is considerably smaller than a disengaging force that may be assumed in the case of the link members of the gear-link type.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As a result, in the key switch in JP-A-2002-334627, the pivot support section formed in the key top is provided with the bearing groove for directly receiving, in a temporarily retaining manner, the pivoting axle of the first link member, and the pivot support section of the actuator is also provided with the bearing groove for assisting the temporarily retaining function of the direct pivot support section of the key top. In this configuration, if a large disengaging force occurs, which is assumed in the link members of the gear-link type, the key top may be detached from the link member.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The third pending technical situation relevant to the conventional key switches is described below. Due to a diversified environment for using a keyboard as an input device of an electronic apparatus, in the provision of a plurality of key switches in the keyboard, a key switch having a so-called backlight configuration is known, as disclosed in JP-A-2002-251937, in which a marked region defined by, e.g., a character, a symbol, etc., formed in the key top is illuminated from the interior of the key switch, so as to improve the operability of the keyboard in a dark environment. In the key switch of JP-A-2002-251937, a light-emitting section having a LED (light-emitting diode) or EL (electro-luminescence) element is disposed on or below a membrane switch sheet constituting a switch member.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In association with the key switch having the backlight configuration, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication (Kokai) No. 9-306271 (JP-A-9-306271) discloses a switch for operating a cursor, which has a basic structure different from that of the key switch subject to the keying operation, and which includes a rubber cap for preventing light emitted from the light-emitting section disposed beneath the key top from escaping laterally through a gap between the key top and the base section. The cursor-operating switch of JP-A-9-306271 includes a switch body having a manipulating shaft operable in a pivoting manner into an inclined posture, a key top joined to the manipulating shaft of the switch body, a light-emitting element attached to the switch body, and a cap disposed between the key top and a front plate covering the switch body so as to surround the manipulating shaft. Even when the key top is operated in an inclined manner, the cap closes the gap between the key top and the front plate, thereby preventing light emitted from the light-emitting device from escaping laterally.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the key switch having the backlight configuration as described in JP-A-2002-251937, it is important to permit the light emitted from the light-emitting section to efficiently reach the marked region of the key top. In this connection, the cursor-operating switch of JP-A-9-306271 includes the cap for preventing the lateral escape of the light emitted from the light-emitting section, but this cap is intended to be installed in the key top of the inclinational type, and it is not considered to apply the cap to the key switch subject to the keying operation.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In particular, in the key switch used for the low-profile keyboard, which includes a pair of link members interlocked with each other in an openable and closable manner so as to act as a support and direct structure for the key top, an opening region formed in the base section is defined in a relatively large area of the base section (e.g., an engaging portion between the base section and the link member, an interacting portion between the contact section and the actuating member, etc.), so that it is necessary to reliably prevent light emitted from the light-emitting section from diffusing through the opening region. Therefore, it is required for the key switch used in the low-profile keyboard to ensure a high-level internal light-shielding function making it possible to more reliably prevent light emitted from the light-emitting section from escaping out from the key switch and permitting the emitted light to efficiently reach the marked region of the key top.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It is an object of the present invention to provide a key switch including a pair of link members for supporting and directing a key top in a vertical direction relative to a base section, and possessing a protection function making it possible to reliably and stably prevent foreign matter from penetrating an internal structure of the key switch.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">It is another object of the present invention to provide a key switch including a pair of link members having a gear-link configuration for supporting and directing a key top in a vertical direction relative to a base section, and capable of properly maintaining a mutually joined configuration of the key top and the link members against a force acting to detach the key top from the link members, and preventing a pivot support section formed on the key top from being damaged due to the detaching force.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is a further object of the present invention to provide a key switch having a backlight configuration, including a pair of link members for supporting and directing a key top in a vertical direction relative to a base section, and possessing a high-level internal light-shielding function making it possible to reliably prevent light emitted from a light-emitting section from escaping, and permitting the emitted light to efficiently reach a marked region of the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is a yet further object of the present invention to provide a keyboard including a plurality of key switches and having a low-profile configuration, which also has excellent operability and structural reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">To accomplish the above object, the present invention provides a key switch comprising a base section; a key top disposed above the base section; a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top in a vertical direction relative to the base section; a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to a vertical movement of the key top; a biasing member capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction to the key top; and a protection member disposed and inserted between the base section and the key top at a position where the protection member surrounds the pair of link members, the contact section and the biasing member; the protection member being elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top and protecting the pair of link members, the contact section and the biasing member from penetration of foreign matter.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the above-described key switch, the protection member may have properties such as to be deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top without affecting a keying operation feeling given by the elastic biasing force of the biasing member.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The present invention also provides a key switch comprising a base section; a key top disposed above the base section; a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top in a vertical direction relative to the base section; a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to a vertical movement of the key top; and a link support member attached to the key top and pivotably supporting the pair of link members; the pair of link members being provided at respective one-end regions thereof with teeth meshable with each other in a gearing manner and pairs of pivoting axles pivotably joined to the link support member; the link support member including two pairs of bearing holes respectively receiving the pairs of pivoting axles of the pair of link members, each of the bearing holes being formed as a through hole with no notch in a periphery thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the above-described key switch, the link support member may include a major plate portion and a pair of opposing wall portions provided along a pair of edges of the major plate portion and generally parallel with each other, each of the opposing wall portions being provided with two of the bearing holes, and the major plate portion having elasticity permitting a pair of pivoting axles of each of the pair of link members to be received correspondingly in the bearing holes provided in the pair of opposing wall portions.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The present invention further provides a key switch comprising a base section; a key top disposed above the base section and including an optically transparent marked region; a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top in a vertical direction relative to the base section; a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to a vertical movement of the key top; a light-emitting section provided in the base section and generating light transmitted through the marked region of the key top; and a light-shielding member disposed and inserted between the base section and the key top at a position where the light-shielding member does not interfere with a propagation of the light from the light-emitting section to the marked region; the light-shielding member being deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top and preventing the light from escaping through a gap between the base section and the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the above-described key switch, further comprising a biasing member capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction to the key top, the light-shielding member may have properties, such as to be deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top without affecting a keying operation feeling given by the elastic biasing force of the biasing member.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The present invention yet further provides a keyboard comprising a plurality of key switches in an array, each of the key switches being described above.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The above and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following description of preferred embodiments in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing a key switch according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view showing the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an assembled state wherein a key top is not operated;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged perspective bottom-side view showing a link support member used in the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged perspective bottom-side view showing a pair of link members used in the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view showing the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an assembled state wherein a key top is operated;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> is an illustration for describing a function of the link support member in the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and schematically showing a configuration before the link members are joined to the link support member;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> is an illustration for describing a function of the link support member in the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and schematically showing a configuration during an act for joining the link members to the link support member;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an exploded perspective bottom-side view showing a modification of the link support member in the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> together with a key top and the link members;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> is a perspective bottom-side view showing a first modification of the key top of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> is a perspective bottom-side view showing a second modification of the key top of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sectional view showing a key switch according to another embodiment of the present invention, in an assembled state wherein a key top is not operated;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a sectional view showing the key switch of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, in an assembled state wherein the key top is operated;</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an exploded perspective partial view showing main components of a keyboard according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a sectional view showing a protection/light-shielding member used in the keyboard of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref> is a sectional view showing a modification of the protection/light-shielding member in a state before being assembled; and</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</figref> is a sectional view showing the modification of the protection/light-shielding member in a state after being assembled.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The embodiments of the present invention are described below in detail, with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings, the same or similar components are denoted by common reference numerals.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing a key switch <b>10</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention; <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view showing the key switch <b>10</b> in an assembled and non-operated state; <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are enlarged views of various components of the key switch <b>10</b>; and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view showing the key switch <b>10</b> in an assembled and operated state. The key switch <b>10</b> can be preferably used for a thin or low-profile keyboard provided in a portable electronic apparatus such as a notebook or palmtop personal computer and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the key switch <b>10</b> includes a base section <b>12</b>; a key top <b>14</b> disposed above the base section <b>12</b>; a pair of link members <b>16</b> interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top <b>14</b> in an upward-and-downward direction (i.e., a substantially vertical direction) relative to the base section <b>12</b>; a switch member <b>20</b> including a contact section <b>18</b> of an electric circuit, capable of opening and closing in response to an upward-and-downward movement (i.e., a vertical movement) of the key top <b>14</b>; and a biasing member <b>22</b> capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction (i.e., an initial-position recovering force) to the key top <b>14</b>. The key top <b>14</b> is movable in the vertical direction relative to the base section <b>12</b>, through an interlocking action of the link members <b>16</b>, while keeping a predetermined posture of the key top <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The base section <b>12</b> includes a rigid and flat first support plate <b>24</b> functioning as a structural base of the key switch <b>10</b>, such as a separate metallic shin-plate made of a sheet metal material or a resinous bottom panel of a keyboard into which the key switch <b>10</b> is incorporated, and a frame-like second support plate <b>26</b> disposed on the first support plate <b>24</b> and formed as, e.g., an integrally molded unitary piece made of a resinous material. The second support plate <b>26</b> includes a generally rectangular opening <b>28</b> adapted to be substantially covered or shaded by the key top <b>14</b>. Along a pair of opposed inner edges defining the opening <b>28</b>, a pair of slide support sections <b>30</b> are provided to be apart from each other in a link sliding direction (in a leftward-and-rightward direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Each slide support section <b>30</b> includes a wall portion <b>30</b><i>a </i>extending from an upper surface <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the second support plate <b>26</b> to overhang the opening <b>28</b>. A pair of guide grooves <b>32</b> are formed inside each wall portion <b>30</b><i>a </i>at opposite longitudinal ends thereof, to extend generally parallel to the upper surface <b>26</b>. The guide grooves <b>32</b> provided in each slide support section <b>30</b> act to slidably receive the first end (i.e., bottom end) region of each link member <b>16</b> as described later.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Alternatively, the base section <b>12</b> may also be configured, without using the second support plate <b>26</b>, so that the first support plate <b>24</b> acts to directly guide and support the link members <b>16</b>. In this arrangement, the first support plate <b>24</b> is provided on the upper surfaces <b>24</b><i>a </i>thereof with slide support sections (not shown) having guiding holes for slidably guiding the first end (bottom end) regions of the respective link members <b>16</b>, in place of the slide support sections <b>30</b> described above. Further, as described later, the base section <b>12</b> may be provided with a light-emitting structure for illuminating a marked region, such as a character, a symbol, etc., provided on the key top <b>14</b>, from the interior of the key switch.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The key top <b>14</b> is a dish-like member having a generally rectangular shape as seen in a plan view and, e.g., integrally molded into a unitary member from a resinous material, and includes an operating surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>subjected to a keying operation by an operator and an inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>opposite to the operating surface <b>14</b><i>a</i>. A link support member <b>34</b> is attached to the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b>, for pivotably supporting the second end (i.e., top end) regions of the respective link members <b>16</b> as described later. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the link support member <b>34</b> is provided with two pairs of bearing holes (i.e., pivot support sections) <b>36</b> for respectively receiving axles (described later) provided at the second end regions of the respective link members <b>16</b>. The link support member <b>34</b> is securely mounted on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b> in an orientation such that the two pairs of bearing holes <b>36</b> are apart from each other in the link sliding direction (in the leftward-and-rightward direction in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The configuration of the link support member <b>34</b> will be described in more detail later.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Alternatively, the key top <b>14</b> may also be configured, without using the link support member <b>34</b>, so that the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>is directly joined to the link members <b>16</b>. In this arrangement, the key top <b>14</b> is provided on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>thereof with pivot support sections (not shown) for pivotably receiving the second end (top end) regions of the respective link members <b>16</b>, in place of the bearing holes <b>36</b> described above.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">A pair of link members <b>16</b> have shapes and dimensions identical to each other, and are assembled together into a reverse V-shape as seen in a lateral direction or a side view, and meshed at one end regions thereof with each other in a gearing manner. Each link member <b>16</b> is formed as, e.g., an integrally molded unitary piece made of a resinous material. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the link member <b>16</b> includes integrally a pair of arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> extending generally parallel to each other and a trunk <b>42</b> interconnecting the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> with each other. In the illustrated embodiment, in each of the link members <b>16</b>, the end regions of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> adjoining the trunk <b>42</b> are defined as a first end (or bottom end) region of the link member <b>16</b>, and the distal end regions of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> extending from the trunk <b>42</b> are defined as a second end (or top end) region of the link member <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In the first end region of each link member <b>16</b>, a pair of sliding axles <b>44</b> are provided to project coaxially with each other from the mutually facing-away outer sides of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> and oppositely to the trunk <b>42</b>. In the second end region of each link member <b>16</b>, a pair of pivoting axles <b>46</b> are provided to project coaxially with each other from the outer sides of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> in the same direction as the sliding axles <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Each of the sliding axles <b>44</b> and pivoting axles <b>46</b> has a cylindrical shape. Further, on one arm <b>38</b> of each link member <b>16</b>, one tooth <b>48</b> is provided on the distal end surface of the second end region proximal to the pivoting axle <b>46</b>, and on the other arm <b>40</b>, two teeth <b>50</b> are provided on the distal end surface of the second end region proximal to the pivoting axle <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Each link member <b>16</b> is disposed between the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b> so that the pair of sliding axles <b>44</b> in the first end region are slidably fitted into the corresponding guide grooves <b>32</b> of the slide support section <b>30</b> provided on the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>12</b> and the pair of pivoting axles <b>46</b> in the second end region are pivotably fitted into the corresponding bearing holes <b>36</b> provided in the link support member <b>34</b> of the key top <b>14</b>. The pair of link members <b>16</b> are configured to form an interlocking structure in which one tooth <b>48</b> of the respective one arm <b>38</b> is meshed with two teeth <b>50</b> of the respective other arm <b>40</b>, thereby rotatable in a mutually interlocking manner about respective pivot axes <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) defined by the pivoting axles <b>46</b> of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Thus, when the link members <b>16</b> synchronously rotate in opposite directions about respective pivot axes <b>52</b> (i.e., about the respective rotatable engagement points between the pivoting axles <b>46</b> and the bearing holes <b>36</b>) and the respective first end regions slide in a generally horizontal direction under the guiding action of the corresponding slide support sections <b>30</b> of the base section <b>12</b> (i.e., under the sliding engagement between the sliding axles <b>44</b> and the guide grooves <b>32</b>), the key top <b>14</b> is subjected to a parallel displacement in a generally vertical direction relative to the base section <b>12</b>, while maintaining a predetermined, generally horizontal posture of the key top <b>14</b> in which the operating surface <b>14</b><i>a </i>is substantially parallel with the upper surface <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the base section <b>12</b> (or the second support plate <b>26</b>). The upper limit position of the keying stroke (i.e., the stroke of the vertical movement) of the key top <b>14</b> is determined when the sliding movement of the first end regions of the link members <b>16</b> toward each other is stopped by the surrounding walls of the guide grooves <b>32</b> of the corresponding slide support sections <b>30</b> of the base section <b>12</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). As the key top <b>14</b> descends from this upper limit position, the first end regions of the link members <b>16</b> slide, under the guiding action of the guide grooves <b>32</b> for the sliding axles <b>44</b>, away from each other in a direction generally orthogonal to the direction of vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>. When the key top <b>14</b> reaches the lower limit position of the keying stroke, the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b> is closed (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The switch member <b>20</b> includes a membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> disposed adjacent to the base section <b>12</b> and carrying the contact section <b>18</b> at a position beneath the key top <b>14</b>. The membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> includes a pair of flexible circuit boards respectively carrying a pair of contacts to face to each other (not shown), and a sheet-like spacer supporting these circuit boards with a predetermined gap defined therebetween to maintain the contacts in an opened state. The contacts are patterned on the surfaces of film substrates of the circuit boards and constitute the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b>. The membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> is inserted and supported between the first support plate <b>24</b> and the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>12</b>, and the contact section <b>18</b> is positioned generally at the center of the opening <b>28</b> of the second support plate <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The biasing member <b>22</b> is a dome-shaped member integrally molded into a unitary piece from a rubber material, and is disposed between the key top <b>14</b> and the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> with the dome top <b>22</b><i>a </i>facing toward the key top <b>14</b>. The biasing member <b>22</b> is disposed in the opening <b>28</b> of the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>12</b> and fixed to the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>, at the bottom dome-open end <b>22</b><i>b </i>of the biasing member. When no load is applied to the biasing member <b>22</b>, the dome top <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the biasing member <b>22</b> is upwardly spaced from the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>. On the inner surface of the dome top <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the biasing member <b>22</b>, a projection <b>22</b><i>c </i>is formed to be aligned with the contact section <b>18</b> of the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>, for pressing and closing the contact section <b>18</b> when the key top <b>14</b> is depressed.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In the key switch <b>10</b>, when no external force is applied to the key top <b>14</b>, the biasing member <b>22</b> biases the key top <b>14</b> toward and supports it, by the dome top <b>22</b><i>a</i>, at the upper limit position of the stroke vertically above and apart from the base section <b>12</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). At this time, the contact section <b>18</b> of the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> is in an opened state. When the key top <b>14</b> is depressed by a keying operation, the biasing member <b>22</b> is elastically deformed in response to the downward movement of the key top <b>14</b>, while exerting an elastic biasing force (or an initial-position recovering force) to the key top <b>14</b> in an upward direction, and presses by the inside projection <b>22</b><i>c </i>the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> from the outside thereof, at the instant when the key top <b>14</b> reaches the lower limit position of the stroke, so as to close the contact section <b>18</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). When the depressing force to the key top <b>14</b> is released, the biasing member <b>22</b> is elastically restored so as to return the key top <b>14</b> to the upper limit position, and thereby the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> is restored to open the contact section <b>18</b>. As will be understood from the above, the biasing member <b>22</b> also functions as an actuating member for making the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b> open or close in response to the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">When the key top <b>14</b> is depressed by a keying operation, the biasing member <b>22</b> is elastically deformed in a buckling mode due to the dome shape thereof, so that an elastic biasing force is exerted to the key top <b>14</b>, which assumes non-linear relationship with a displacement of the key top <b>14</b>. As a result, the key switch <b>10</b> can establish unique keying operation properties, accompanied by a so-called click feeling, such that when the amount of depression of the key top <b>14</b> exceeds a predetermined value, the biasing force in a return direction, which has been gradually increased until that time, is abruptly reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The key switch <b>10</b> is provided in itself with a protection function making it possible to reliably and stably prevent foreign matter, such as dust, liquid, etc., from penetrating the internal structure of the key switch (i.e., the link members <b>16</b>, the switch member <b>20</b>, etc.). More specifically, the key switch <b>10</b> includes a protection member <b>56</b> inserted and disposed between the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b> at a position where the protection member <b>56</b> surrounds the pair of link members <b>16</b>, the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b>, and the biasing member <b>22</b>. The protection member <b>56</b> is an annular rubber element capable of being elastically deformed in response to the downward movement of the key top <b>14</b>. Between the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b>, the protection member <b>56</b> is elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>, and maintains the posture thereof to continuously surround the pair of link members <b>16</b>, the contact section <b>18</b> and the biasing member <b>22</b>. As a result, during the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>, the protection member <b>56</b> reliably and stably protects the link members <b>16</b>, the contact section <b>18</b> and the biasing member <b>22</b> from the penetration of the foreign matter (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 5</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The protection member <b>56</b> includes a tubular part <b>58</b> having a generally rectangular shape as seen in a plan view and exhibiting a major protection function against the foreign matter, and a sheeting part <b>60</b> connected with one end (a bottom end, in the drawing) of the tubular part <b>58</b>. The tubular part <b>58</b> is provided, at an intermediate point in a height direction thereof, with a stepped area <b>58</b><i>a </i>through which a radial dimension changes locally. The sheeting part <b>60</b> is provided with an opening <b>60</b><i>a </i>formed to communicate with an internal space of the tubular part <b>58</b>. In this connection, the tubular part <b>58</b> and the sheeting part <b>60</b>, of the protection member <b>56</b>, may be formed integrally or unitarily with each other, or alternatively, may be formed as separate members adapted to be securely attached to each other by, e.g., an adhesive (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 5</figref> show the protection member <b>56</b> in which the tubular part <b>58</b> and the sheeting part <b>60</b> are unitarily formed).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In the key switch <b>10</b> configured as described above, the protection member <b>56</b> is provided separately from the biasing member <b>22</b>, both being similar rubber elements adapted to be elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>, and solely for the purpose of protecting the internal structure of the key switch from the penetration of foreign matter, so that it is possible to prepare the protection member <b>56</b> having optimal properties capable of exhibiting the function for preventing the penetration of foreign matter at a required level. Therefore, in the key switch <b>10</b> adapted to be preferably used for a low-profile keyboard and including, as a directing structure for the key top <b>14</b>, the pair of link members <b>16</b> interlocked with each other in an openable and closable manner about a mutually joined point (or the teeth <b>48</b>, <b>50</b>, in the illustrated embodiment), it is possible to ensure a more stricter protection function capable of reliably and stably preventing the foreign matter from penetrating the internal structure. As a result, it is possible to provide the key switch <b>10</b> having excellent operability and structural reliability, which can effectively prevent the keying operation properties of the key top <b>14</b> from being affected, or the accuracy of the opening or closing action of the contact section <b>18</b> from being deteriorated, by the existence of foreign matter. Further, the key switch <b>10</b> according to the present invention can be configured only by adding the protection member <b>56</b> to a conventional key switch having a low-profile structure, so that it is possible to inhibit an increase in manufacturing costs.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">It is extremely advantageous that the protection member <b>56</b> has properties such as to be readily deformed to accurately follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b> without substantially affecting a keying operation feeling given by the elastic biasing force of the biasing member <b>22</b> applied to the key top <b>14</b>. In this arrangement, the movement of the key top <b>14</b> to return to the initial position is determined substantially only by the elastic restoring force generated in the biasing member <b>22</b>. These properties of the protection member <b>56</b> are obtained mainly depending on the attributes of the tubular part <b>58</b>, such as the shape, dimensions, material, etc. According to this configuration, in spite of the provision of the protection member <b>56</b> interposed between the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b>, it is possible to ensure the high-level protection function against the foreign matter, while eliminating the influence on the keying operation properties of the key switch <b>10</b> (i.e., without causing an uncomfortable feeling to the operator during the keying operation).</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The protection member <b>56</b> is arranged so that the bottom end of the tubular part <b>58</b> and the sheeting part <b>60</b> contact the upper surface <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the second support plate <b>26</b>, at a location outside the pair of slide support sections <b>30</b> provided on the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>12</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Thus, the protection member <b>56</b> continuously surrounds the opening <b>28</b> of the base section <b>12</b>, provided for allowing the biasing member <b>22</b> to be disposed adjacent to the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b>, as well as the slide support sections <b>30</b> (in particular, the guide grooves <b>32</b>) of the base section <b>12</b>, provided for slidably supporting the link members <b>16</b>, during the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>, so as to reliably protect them from the penetration of foreign matter. As a result, it is possible to effectively prevent the keying operation properties of the key top <b>14</b> from being affected, or the accuracy of the opening or closing action of the contact section <b>18</b> from being deteriorated, by the existence of foreign matter.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Also, the protection member <b>56</b> is arranged so that the top end <b>58</b><i>b </i>of the tubular part <b>58</b> contacts the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b>, at a location outside the link support member <b>34</b> provided on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Thus, the protection member <b>56</b> continuously surrounds the link support member <b>34</b> (in particular, the bearing holes or pivot support sections <b>36</b>) of the key top <b>14</b> for pivotably joining the link members <b>16</b>, during the vertical movement of the key top <b>14</b>, so as to reliably protect it from the penetration of foreign matter. As a result, it is possible to effectively prevent the keying operation properties of the key top <b>14</b> from being affected by the existence of foreign matter.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Further, it is advantageous that, when the key top <b>14</b> is located at the above-described upper limit position of the vertical movement, the protection member <b>56</b> receives initial pressure from the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b>. In this configuration, even when the key switch <b>10</b> is not used, the protection member <b>56</b> is stably retained between the base section <b>12</b> and the key top <b>14</b> in a slightly and elastically deformed state, and therefore, it is possible, in particular, to prevent the sheeting part <b>60</b> from being floated or turned up over the base section <b>12</b> and thus to eliminate an undesirable situation in which foreign matter can penetrate between the sheeting part <b>60</b> and the base section <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">In this connection, the protection member <b>56</b> described above can preferably be applied not only to the illustrated key switch <b>10</b>, but also to, e.g., a conventional key switch including link members of a so-called pantograph type. Also in this arrangement, it is possible to provide a key switch having excellent operability and structural reliability, and which provides protection for reliably and stably preventing foreign matter from penetrating the internal structure.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In the key switch <b>10</b>, the link support member <b>34</b> provided on the key top <b>14</b> includes a flat major plate portion <b>62</b> having a generally rectangular shape as seen in a plan view, and a pair of opposing wall portions <b>64</b> provided uprightly along a pair of edges of the major plate portion <b>62</b> and generally parallel with each other, each of the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> being provided with two bearing holes <b>36</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The opposing wall portions <b>64</b> are spaced apart from each other by a distance permitting the second end region (including the pivoting axles <b>46</b>) of each link member <b>16</b> to be stably inserted between the wall portions <b>64</b> without substantial wobbling (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>). Further, each bearing hole <b>36</b> is formed as a through hole with no notch, in a periphery of the hole, extending up to the outer edge of the opposing wall portion <b>64</b>, and smoothly and rotatably receives the cylindrical pivoting axle <b>46</b> of the corresponding link member <b>16</b>. In this connection, the bearing hole <b>36</b> is desirably formed as a circular hole as illustrated, but may be formed as a polygonal hole, on the condition that the bearing holes <b>36</b> do not interfere with the smooth rotation of the pivoting axles <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">According to the provision of the link support member <b>34</b> configured as described above, in the key switch <b>10</b>, the pivoting axles <b>46</b> of the link members <b>16</b> can be supported more stably in the bearing holes <b>36</b> of the link support member <b>34</b> while reliably preventing the disengagement of the pivoting axles <b>46</b>, in comparison with a conventional key switch in which a pivotable support section of the key top, to which a link member is pivotably joined, is provided with a through hole having a notch. Thus, even when external force is applied to an outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>14</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) in a direction pulling-up the key top <b>14</b> apart from the base section <b>12</b>, it is possible to reliably prevent the pivoting axles <b>46</b> of the link members <b>16</b> from being disengaged from the bearing holes <b>36</b> of the link support member <b>34</b>. If the external force is excessively large, the link support member <b>34</b> can be detached from the key top <b>14</b> so as to prevent the link support member <b>34</b> from being damaged. As a result, it is possible to provide the key switch <b>10</b> having excellent operability and structural reliability, which can effectively prevent the key top <b>14</b> from being unexpectedly detached.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In order to surely prevent external force from being unintentionally applied to the outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>14</b> in the direction pulling-up the key top <b>14</b> from the base section <b>12</b>, the sheeting part <b>60</b> of the protection member <b>56</b> may be provided, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, with an annular projection <b>66</b> spaced apart from the outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>14</b>. In this arrangement, the projection <b>66</b> and the sheeting part <b>60</b> may be formed integrally or unitarily as illustrated, or alternatively, a projection <b>66</b> as a separate member may be securely attached to the sheeting part <b>60</b> by an adhesive, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In order to allow the key switch <b>10</b> to be safely and easily assembled, the link support member <b>34</b> has, at least in the major plate portion <b>62</b> thereof, an elasticity permitting the pair of pivoting axles <b>46</b> of each link member <b>16</b> to be received in the corresponding bearing holes <b>36</b> provided in the pair of opposing wall portions <b>64</b>. An operation for attaching the link members <b>16</b> to the link support member <b>34</b>, performed in an assembling process of the key switch <b>10</b>, will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In a normal state, the link support member <b>34</b> is dimensioned so that a space between the pair of opposing wall portions <b>64</b> is substantially equal to a distance between the outer surfaces of the arms <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> of each link member <b>16</b>, to an extent not to interfere with a smooth sliding between the link members <b>16</b> and the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>). In the assembling process of the key switch <b>10</b>, the link support member <b>34</b> as a separate piece is attached to the second end regions of the pair of link members <b>16</b>. At this time, while the outer edges of the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> of the link support member <b>34</b> are pressed against the pair of pivoting axles <b>46</b> of each link member <b>16</b>, pressing force F is further applied to the major plate portion <b>62</b> of the link support member <b>34</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>). As a result, the major plate portion <b>62</b> is inwardly convexly curved, and thus the space between the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> is expanded in a dovetail manner, so that, by continuously applying the pressing force F, the pivoting axles <b>46</b> are fitted into the corresponding bearing holes <b>36</b>. Thereafter, when pressing force F is released, the major plate portion <b>62</b> is elastically restored to its original flat shape, and the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> return to the normal positions ensuring a mutually parallel arrangement, so that the pivoting axles <b>46</b> of each link member <b>16</b> are stably supported in the bearing holes <b>36</b> of the link support member <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In the above-described attaching operation, the link members <b>16</b> may be attached to the link support member <b>34</b> sequentially one by one, or alternatively, both of the link members <b>16</b> may be simultaneously attached to the link support member <b>34</b>. In the latter case, the pair of link members <b>16</b> with the respective tooth <b>48</b> being meshed with the respective teeth <b>50</b> are laid on, e.g., the base section <b>12</b> in a flat state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), and the link support member <b>34</b> is pressed on these link members <b>16</b> so as to be attached to the link members <b>16</b>. It is advantageous that the link support member <b>34</b> has guide channels <b>68</b> on mutually opposing inner surfaces of the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, so that the pair of pivoting axles <b>46</b> of each link member <b>16</b> can be smoothly inserted between the opposing wall portions <b>64</b> and accurately fitted into the corresponding bearing holes <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">After the link support member <b>34</b> is attached to the pair of link members <b>16</b> as described above, the key top <b>14</b> is attached to the link support member <b>34</b>. To this end, the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b> is provided with a plurality of hooks <b>70</b> for securely retaining the link support member <b>34</b> at a predetermined position on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). The hooks <b>70</b> uprightly project from the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b>, and are detachably engaged, at respective hooking-ends <b>70</b><i>a </i>formed at the distal ends thereof, with an outer periphery of the major plate portion <b>62</b> of the link support member <b>34</b>. In the assembling process of the key switch <b>10</b>, the key top <b>14</b> is disposed over and pressed on the link support member <b>34</b> attached to the pair of link members <b>16</b> laid in the flat state, so that it is possible to bring the major plate portion <b>62</b> of the link support member <b>34</b> into engagement with the hooks <b>70</b> in a snap-fit manner while slightly and elastically deforming the major plate portion <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In this connection, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, in order to ensure areas used for an engagement with the hooks <b>70</b>, the major plate portion <b>62</b> of the link support member <b>34</b> may be provided with extensions <b>72</b> horizontally extending outward from edges other than the edges having the opposing wall portions <b>64</b>. This configuration, in which the hooks <b>70</b> are engaged with the extended portions <b>72</b>, shows geometrical properties, when the external force is applied to, e.g., the outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>14</b> in a direction pulling-up the key top <b>14</b> from the base section <b>12</b>, such that a ratio of a distance between a fulcrum P<b>2</b> and an application point P<b>3</b> to a distance between a force point P<b>1</b> and the fulcrum P<b>2</b>, with regard to the force point P<b>1</b> (i.e., the outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c</i>), the fulcrum P<b>2</b> (i.e., the bearing holes <b>36</b> farther from the force point P<b>1</b>) and the application point P<b>3</b> (i.e., the hooks <b>70</b> closer to the force point P<b>1</b>), is greater than a ratio of a distance between a fulcrum and an application point to a distance between a force point and the fulcrum, with regard to the force point (i.e., the outer periphery of the key top), the fulcrum (i.e., one pivot support section farther from the force point) and the application point (i.e., another pivot support section closer to the force point) defined in the conventional key switch. As a result, in the key switch <b>10</b>, force generated at the application point P<b>3</b> (i.e., force acting to disengage the hooks <b>70</b> closer to the force point P<b>1</b> from the major plate portion <b>62</b>) is reduced in comparison with a force generating in the conventional key switch if external force of identical magnitude is applied, and therefore, it is possible to more effectively prevent the key top <b>14</b> from being detached from the link support member <b>34</b> or the hooks <b>70</b> from being damaged due to the detachment of the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the plurality of hooks <b>70</b> provided on the inner surface <b>14</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>14</b> may be configured as a set of hooks <b>70</b> cooperating with each other to securely retain the link support member <b>34</b> and located so as to face to each other in a direction orthogonal to the pivoting axis <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of each link member <b>16</b> (two pairs of hooks <b>70</b> are provided, in the drawing). Alternatively, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, the plurality of hooks <b>70</b> may be configured as a set of hooks <b>70</b> cooperating with each other to securely retain the link support member <b>34</b> and located so as to face to each other in a direction parallel to the pivoting axis <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of each link member <b>16</b> (two pairs of hooks <b>70</b> are provided, in the drawing). Also, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref>, four pairs of hooks <b>70</b> may be provided to be located so as to face to each other in both directions orthogonal and parallel to the pivoting axis <b>52</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of each link member <b>16</b>. The disposition and number of the hooks <b>70</b> may be optimized in consideration of, e.g., a size of the key top <b>14</b>, a position along the outer periphery <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>14</b> that are likely to be the above-described force point during use, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The above-described configuration of the link support member <b>34</b> and the corresponding configuration of the hooks <b>70</b> of the key top <b>14</b> can preferably be applied not only to the illustrated key switch <b>10</b> but also to, e.g., a conventional key switch that does not have the protection member <b>56</b>. Also in this arrangement, it is possible to provide a key switch having excellent operability and structural reliability, which can prevent the key top from being unexpectedly detached.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> show a key switch <b>80</b> according to another embodiment of the present invention. The key switch <b>80</b> includes several components substantially identical to those of the key switch <b>10</b> according to the first embodiment, and therefore, the corresponding components are denoted by common reference numerals and the descriptions thereof are not repeated.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The key switch <b>80</b> includes a base section <b>82</b>, a key top <b>86</b> disposed above the base section <b>82</b> and including an optically transparent marked region <b>84</b>; a pair of link members <b>16</b> interlocked to each other to support and direct the key top <b>86</b> in an upward-and-downward direction (i.e., a substantially vertical direction) relative to the base section <b>82</b>; a switch member <b>20</b> including a contact section <b>18</b> capable of opening and closing in response to an upward-and-downward movement (or a vertical movement) of the key top <b>86</b>; and a light-emitting section <b>88</b> provided in the base section <b>82</b> and that generating light L transmitted through the marked region <b>84</b> of the key top <b>86</b>. The key switch <b>80</b> also includes a biasing member <b>22</b> capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction (i.e., an initial-position recovering force) to the key top <b>86</b>, and capable of making the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b> open or close in response to the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b>. The key top <b>86</b> is movable in the vertical direction relative to the base section <b>82</b>, through an interlocking action of the link members <b>16</b>, while keeping a predetermined posture of the key top <b>86</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The base section <b>82</b> has a laminated structure that includes, in addition to the first and second support plates <b>24</b>, <b>26</b> of the base section <b>12</b> in the key switch <b>10</b>, a circuit board <b>90</b> placed on the upper surfaces <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the first support plates <b>24</b>, a third support plate <b>92</b> placed on the upper surface <b>90</b><i>a </i>of the circuit board <b>90</b>, and a fourth support plate <b>94</b> placed on the upper surface <b>92</b><i>a </i>of the third support plate <b>92</b>. The circuit board <b>90</b> is configured as, e.g., a flexible circuit board, and a LED (light-emitting diode, not shown) acting as a light source of the light-emitting section <b>88</b> is mounted at a desired position (a center position, in the drawing) of the circuit board <b>90</b>. As the light source of the light-emitting section <b>88</b>, various light emitting elements, such as an organic EL (electroluminescence) element, may be used in place of the LED.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The third support plate <b>92</b> is a shin plate made of metal or resin, and the light-emitting section <b>88</b> is formed therein at a position beneath the key top <b>14</b>. For example, in the case where the LED mounted on the circuit board <b>90</b> is located at a position of the light-emitting section <b>88</b>, the light-emitting section <b>88</b> formed in the third support plate <b>92</b> is structured as a through hole, a mesh structure, a transparent region, etc., capable of transmitting the light emitted from the LED with substantially no obstruction. On the other hand, in the case where the LED mounted on the circuit board <b>90</b> as the light source is located at a position remote from the key switch <b>10</b>, the third support plate <b>92</b> is configured as a light-guiding plate made of a resinous material having desired light-guiding properties. In this case, the light-emitting section <b>88</b> is provided with a reflecting structure having a dotted pattern and capable of directing (or changing the traveling direction of) the light propagating through the third support plate <b>92</b> as the light-guiding plate from the LED as the light source toward the key top <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The fourth support plate <b>94</b>, placed on the third support plate <b>92</b>, cooperates with the second support plate <b>26</b> so as to hold therebetween the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> constituting the switch member <b>20</b>. The fourth support plate <b>94</b> is provided with an opening <b>96</b> formed at a position superimposed on the light-emitting section <b>88</b>, so as not to interfere with the propagation of the light emitted from the light-emitting section B<b>8</b> provided in the third support plate <b>92</b>. The opening <b>96</b> is disposed at a position superimposed on the contact section <b>18</b> formed in the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>, and thus may actually include a plurality of beams or columns to provide a backside support for the contact section <b>18</b>, effectively acting when the key top <b>14</b> is depressed. Further, the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> is formed transparently or translucently at least at a portion thereof superimposed on the opening <b>96</b> of the fourth support plate <b>94</b>, so as not to interfere with the propagation of the light emitted from the light-emitting section <b>88</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Similarly to the key top <b>14</b> in the key switch <b>10</b>, the key top <b>86</b> includes an operating surface <b>86</b><i>a </i>and an inner surface <b>86</b><i>b</i>. The key top <b>86</b> does not use the link support member <b>34</b> and, at a predetermined position on the inner surface <b>86</b><i>b</i>, pivot support sections <b>98</b> are formed for pivotably receiving the second end (or top end) regions of the respective link members <b>16</b>. Each pivot support section <b>98</b> has, for example, a bearing hole formed as a through hole with a notch (not shown). In place of this configuration, the link support member <b>34</b> may be attached to the inner surface <b>86</b><i>b </i>of the key top <b>86</b> in a manner similar to the key switch <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The key top <b>86</b> is preferably formed as an integral or unitary piece, which is made of a transparent or translucent resinous material having light transmittance. A primary coating with a desired color is applied to the surface of the key top, and a finish coating with a dark color, such as black, is applied over the primary coating. Through, e.g., a marking process using laser, a desired part of the finish coating is locally removed, so as to form the desired marked region <b>84</b> such as a character, symbol, etc. The marked region <b>84</b> thus obtained can transmit light L, emitted from the light-emitting section <b>88</b>, from the inner surface <b>86</b><i>b </i>to the operating surface <b>86</b><i>a </i>of the key top <b>86</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Similarly to the biasing member <b>22</b> in the key switch <b>10</b>, the biasing member <b>22</b> is disposed between the key top <b>86</b> and the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>. In other words, the biasing member <b>22</b> is disposed midway in the propagation path of the light L from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> to the marked region <b>84</b>. Therefore, the biasing member <b>22</b> is made of a transparent or translucent material capable of transmitting light L. As a result, light L emitted from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> is transmitted through the biasing member <b>22</b> and reliably reaches the marked region <b>84</b> of the key top <b>86</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">In the key switch <b>80</b>, similarly to the key switch <b>10</b>, when no external force is applied to the key top <b>86</b>, the biasing member <b>22</b> biases the key top <b>86</b> toward and supports it, by the dome top <b>22</b><i>a</i>, at the upper limit position of the stroke vertically above and apart from the base section <b>86</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). At this time, the contact section <b>18</b> of the membrane sheet <b>54</b> is in an opened state. When the key top <b>86</b> is depressed by a keying operation, the biasing member <b>22</b> is elastically deformed in response the downward movement of the key top <b>86</b>, while exerting an elastic biasing force (or an initial-position recovering force) to the key top <b>86</b> in an upward direction, and presses by the inside projection <b>22</b><i>c </i>the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> from the outside thereof, when the key top <b>86</b> reaches the lower limit position of the stroke, so as to close the contact section <b>18</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">When the depressing force to the key top <b>86</b> is released, the biasing member <b>22</b> is elastically restored so as to return the key top <b>86</b> to the upper limit position, and thereby the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> is restored to open the contact section <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The key switch <b>80</b> possesses an internal light-shielding function permitting the light L emitted from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> to efficiently reach the marked region <b>84</b>, in the configuration such that the marked region <b>84</b>, such as a character, symbol, etc., of the key top <b>86</b> is illuminated from the inside of the key switch (so-called a backlight configuration). More specifically, the key switch <b>80</b> includes a light-shielding member <b>100</b> disposed and inserted between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b> at a position where the light-shielding member <b>100</b> does not interfere with the propagation of the light L from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> to the marked region <b>84</b>. The light-shielding member <b>100</b> is an annular rubber element capable of being elastically deformed in response to the downward movement of the key top <b>86</b>. Between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b>. The light-shielding member <b>100</b> is elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b>, and maintains the posture thereof to continuously surround the pair of link members <b>16</b>, the contact section <b>18</b> of the switch member <b>20</b>, and the biasing member <b>22</b>. As a result, during the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b>, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> reliably and stably prevents the light L from escaping through a gap between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b> to the outside of the key switch (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">The light-shielding member <b>100</b> is configured similarly to the protection member <b>56</b> in the key switch <b>10</b>. More specifically the light-shielding member <b>100</b> includes a tubular part <b>102</b> having a generally rectangular shape as seen in a plan view and exhibiting a major light-shielding function against the light L, and a sheeting part <b>104</b> connected with one end (a bottom end, in the drawing) of the tubular part <b>102</b>. The tubular part <b>102</b> is provided, at an intermediate point in a height direction thereof, with a stepped area <b>102</b><i>a </i>through which a radial dimension changes locally. The sheeting part <b>104</b> is provided with an opening <b>104</b><i>a </i>formed to communicate with an internal space of the tubular part <b>102</b>. In order to reliably prevent the escape of the light L, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> or at least the tubular part <b>102</b> thereof is formed to have an opaque or light-intransmittable color.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In this connection, the tubular part <b>102</b> and the sheeting part <b>104</b>, of the light-shielding member <b>100</b>, may be formed integrally or unitarily with each other, or alternatively, may be formed as separate members adapted to be securely attached to each other by, e.g., an adhesive (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> show the light-shielding member <b>100</b> in which the tubular part <b>102</b> and the sheeting part <b>104</b> as the separate members are securely attached to each other). Further, the sheeting part <b>104</b> of the light-shielding member <b>100</b> may be provided with an annular projection <b>106</b> spaced apart from the outer periphery <b>86</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>86</b>, so as to surely prevent external force from being unintentionally applied to the outer periphery <b>86</b><i>c </i>of the key top <b>86</b> in a direction pulling-up the key top <b>66</b> from the base section <b>82</b>. Also in this arrangement, the projection <b>106</b> as a separate member may be securely attached to the sheeting part <b>104</b> by an adhesive, etc., as illustrated, or alternatively, the projection <b>106</b> and the sheeting part <b>104</b> may be formed integrally or unitarily.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In the key switch <b>80</b> configured as described above, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> is provided separately from the biasing member <b>22</b>, both being similar rubber elements adapted to be elastically deformed to follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b>, and solely for the purpose of preventing light L from escaping from the inside of the switch, so that it is possible to prepare the light-shielding member <b>100</b> having optimal properties capable of exhibiting the function for preventing the escape of the light at a required level. Therefore, in the key switch <b>80</b> adapted to be preferably used for a low-profile keyboard and including, as a directing structure for the key top <b>86</b>, the pair of link members <b>16</b> interlocked with each other in an openable and closable manner about a mutually joined point (or the teeth <b>48</b>, <b>50</b>, in the illustrated embodiment), it is possible to ensure a high-level internal light-shielding function capable of reliably and stably preventing light L as a backlight from escaping through the gap between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b>. As a result, it is possible to provide the key switch <b>80</b> having excellent operability and structural reliability, which can permit light L emitted from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> to efficiently reach the marked region <b>84</b> so as to improve visibility of the marked region <b>84</b>. Further, the key switch <b>80</b> according to the present invention can be configured only by adding the light-shielding member <b>100</b> to a conventional key switch having a low-profile structure, so that it is possible to decrease manufacturing costs.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">It is extremely advantageous that the light-shielding member <b>100</b> has properties such as to be readily deformed to accurately follow the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b> without substantially affecting a keying operation feeling given by the elastic biasing force of the biasing member <b>22</b> applied to the key top <b>86</b>. In this arrangement, the movement of the key top <b>86</b> to return to the initial position is determined substantially only by the elastic restoring force generated by the biasing member <b>22</b>. These properties of the light-shielding member <b>100</b> are obtained mainly depending on attributes of the tubular part <b>102</b>, such as the shape, dimensions, material, etc. According to this configuration, in spite of the provision of the light-shielding member <b>100</b> interposed between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b>, it is possible to ensure the high-level light-shielding function against the light as a backlight, while eliminating the influence on the keying operation properties of the key switch <b>80</b> (i.e., without causing an uncomfortable feeling to the operator during the keying operation).</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The protection member <b>100</b> is arranged so that the bottom end of the tubular part <b>102</b> and the sheeting part <b>104</b> contact the upper surface <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the second support plate <b>26</b>, at a location outside the pair of slide support sections <b>30</b> provided on the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>82</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). Thus, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> continuously surrounds the opening <b>28</b> of the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>82</b>, provided for allowing the biasing member <b>22</b> to be disposed adjacent to the switch member <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), as well as the slide support sections <b>30</b> (in particular, the guide grooves <b>32</b>) of the second support plate <b>26</b> of the base section <b>82</b>, provided for slidably supporting the link members <b>16</b>, during the vertical movement of the key top <b>86</b>, so as to reliably prevent the light L diffusing through these components from escaping to the outside of the key switch.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Also, it is advantageous that, when the key top <b>86</b> is located at the above-described upper limit position of the vertical movement, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> receives initial pressure from the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b>. In this configuration, even when the key switch <b>80</b> is not used, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> is stably retained between the base section <b>82</b> and the key top <b>86</b> in a slightly and elastically deformed state, and therefore, it is possible, in particular, to prevent the sheeting part <b>104</b> from being floated or turned up over the base section <b>82</b> and thus eliminate an undesirable situation in which the light L from the light-emitting section <b>88</b> escapes through a gap between the sheeting part <b>104</b> and the base section <b>82</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In this connection, the light-shielding member <b>100</b> described above can preferably be applied not only to the illustrated key switch <b>80</b>, but also to, e.g., a conventional key switch including link members of a so-called pantograph type. Also in this arrangement, it is possible to provide a key switch having excellent operability and structural reliability, which can possess an internal light-shielding function permitting light as a backlight to efficiently reach the marked region of the key top.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows, by a schematic exploded view, a keyboard <b>110</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention, which includes a plurality of key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) arranged in a predetermined array. The keyboard <b>110</b> has a low-profile configuration capable of being used as an input device of a portable electronic apparatus, such as a notebook or palmtop personal computer, etc. In the keyboard <b>110</b>, the base section <b>12</b> (or <b>82</b>) and the membrane switch sheet <b>54</b> of the switch member <b>20</b> in each key switch <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) are formed as a large-sized base section <b>12</b>&#x2032; (or <b>82</b>&#x2032;) and a large-sized membrane switch sheet <b>54</b>&#x2032;, respectively, which are shared by all of the key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) incorporated into the keyboard <b>110</b>. Further, the sheeting part <b>60</b> (or <b>104</b>) of the protection member <b>56</b> (or the light-shielding member <b>100</b>) in the key switch <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) is formed as a large-sized sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;) shared by all of the key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>). Still further, each key switch <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) includes the link support member <b>34</b> attached to the key top <b>14</b> (or <b>86</b>). The keyboard <b>110</b> configured as described above has a low-profile configuration, which also has excellent operability and structural reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the keyboard <b>110</b> may be configured so that the tubular parts <b>58</b> (or <b>102</b>) of the protection members <b>56</b> (or the light-shielding members <b>100</b>) of the respective key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) are previously formed integrally or unitarily with the large-sized sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;). Thus, in this case, each of the protection members <b>56</b> (or the light-shielding members <b>100</b>) of the key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) is provided unitarily with the sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;) extending over a range covering these key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Alternatively, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the tubular parts <b>58</b> (or <b>102</b>) of the protection members <b>56</b> (or the light-shielding members <b>100</b>) of the respective key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) may be previously formed separately from the large-sized sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;) (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13A</figref>), and in a subsequent process, the tubular parts <b>58</b> (or <b>102</b>) may be securely attached to the sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;) by an adhesive, etc. (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13B</figref>). Thus, in this case, each of the protection members <b>56</b> (or the light-shielding members <b>100</b>) of the key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>) is securely attached to the separate sheet member <b>60</b>&#x2032; (or <b>104</b>&#x2032;) extending over a range covering these key switches <b>10</b> (or <b>80</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">While the invention has been described with reference to specific preferred embodiments, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made thereto without departing from the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A key switch comprising:
<claim-text>a base section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a key top disposed above said base section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of link members interlocked to each other to support and direct said key top in a vertical direction relative to said base section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch member including a contact section capable of opening and closing in response to a vertical movement of said key top;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a biasing member capable of applying an elastic biasing force in a vertically upward direction to said key top; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an annular protection member including a tubular part having an open top end, the annular protection member being disposed and inserted between said base section and said key top at a position where said protection member surrounds said pair of link members, said contact section and said biasing member, the tubular part being disposed on a sheeting part of the annular protection member, the sheeting part further including an annular projection spaced apart from an outer periphery of the key top in an outward direction generally parallel to an operating surface of the key top,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said key top including pivot support sections pivotably supporting said pair of link members, the open top end of said tubular part of said annular protection member contacting an inner surface of said key top at a location outside said pivot support sections, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said protection member being elastically deformed to follow said vertical movement of said key top and protecting said pair of link members, said pivot support sections, said contact section and said biasing member from penetration of foreign matter.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A key switch as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said protection member has properties such as to be deformed to follow said vertical movement of said key top without affecting a keying operation feeling given by said elastic biasing force of said biasing member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A key switch as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said base section includes a slide support section slidably supporting each of said pair of link members; and wherein said protection member contacts at a bottom end thereof with an upper surface of said base section and protects said slide support section from said penetration of said foreign matter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A key switch as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said switch member comprises a membrane switch sheet disposed adjacent to said base section and carrying said contact section at a position beneath said key top; and wherein said biasing member is disposed between said key top and said membrane switch sheet, is elastically deformed in response to a vertical downward movement of said key top to generate said elastic biasing force, and presses said membrane switch sheet, when said key top reaches a lower limit position of said vertical movement, to close said contact section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A key switch as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said pair of link members are provided at respective one-end regions thereof with teeth meshable with each other in a gearing manner and pivoting axles pivotably joined to said key top, and at respective other-end regions of the link members with sliding axles slidably engaged with said base section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A keyboard comprising a plurality of key switches in an array, each of said key switches being described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said protection member of each key switch is provided unitarily with a sheet member extending over a range covering said plurality of key switches.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A keyboard comprising a plurality of key switches in an array, each of said key switches being described in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said protection member of each key switch is securely attached to a separate sheet member extending over a range covering said plurality of key switches. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
