<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624689-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624689</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12899150</doc-number>
<date>20101006</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>98133794 A</doc-number>
<date>20091006</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>519</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>01</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>66</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>01</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333185</main-classification>
<further-classification>43962021</further-classification>
<further-classification>363 39</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Power line filter</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5206779</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sato et al.</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361111</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5292257</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Milan</name>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439214</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5340944</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wang</name>
<date>19940800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>174350</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5475347</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kwak</name>
<date>19951200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>333185</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5760591</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Matsuda et al.</name>
<date>19980600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>324524</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7259975</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Holme Pedersen et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>363146</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>S. Wang, F.C. Lee, D.Y. Chen, W. G. Odendaal, Effects of Parasitic Parameters on EMI Filter Performance, Power Electronics Specialist Conference, PESC '03, Jun. 15-19, 2003, pp. 73-78.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>43962021</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>337194-199</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>337257</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363146</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>363 39- 48</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>333185</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110080231</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110407</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsieh</last-name>
<first-name>Shin-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Po-Jen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsieh</last-name>
<first-name>Shin-Chih</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Po-Jen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Muncy, Geissler, Olds &#x26; Lowe, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delta Electronics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taoyuan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Benny</first-name>
<department>2817</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Rakesh</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A power line filter including a socket, a housing, a plurality of filter elements and a ground inductor is disclosed. The socket includes at least one power pin and a ground pin. The housing is assembled with the socket, and includes a first receptacle and a second receptacle. The opening direction of the first receptacle is opposite to the opening direction of the second receptacle. The plurality of filter elements is disposed in the first receptacle. At least one of the filter elements is electrically connected to the power pin. The ground inductor is disposed in the second receptacle and electrically connected to the ground pin.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="198.97mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US08624689-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="217.76mm" wi="170.69mm" file="US08624689-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.99mm" wi="182.88mm" file="US08624689-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="234.95mm" wi="168.66mm" file="US08624689-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.26mm" wi="172.64mm" file="US08624689-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Non-provisional application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119(a) on Patent Application No. 098133794 filed in Taiwan, Republic of China on Oct. 6, 2009 the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a power line filter, and, in particular, to a size-reduced, material-saving, labor-saving and high-yield power line filter.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The basic structure of a conventional power line filter is composed of a socket and a housing disposed at one side of the socket. The electronic elements such as an X capacitor, a Y capacitor, a filter inductor and a ground inductor are disposed in the receptacle of the housing. However, because the filter inductor and the ground inductor are both disposed in the receptacle of the housing, the distance between them is quite short. Furthermore, the ground inductor is generally wrapped by an insulating tape only. Thus, the filter inductor, the ground inductor or other inductor elements are vulnerable to be interfered by each other so as to influence the filtering results. Additionally, the insulating tape wrapping the outside of the ground inductor is easily detached and cracked, and its insulating efficacy is quite limited as well. It results in generating sparks due to a high voltage difference, which is occasionally induced between the filter inductor and the ground inductor by a significant variation of magnetic fields at the moment of being powered on or off. This severely endangers the safety of use.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention is to provide a power line filter, especially a size-reduced, material-saving, labor-saving and high-yield power line filter.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">To achieve the above, the power line filter includes a socket, a housing, a plurality of filter elements and a ground inductor. The socket includes at least one power pin and a ground pin. The housing is assembled with the socket, and has a first receptacle and a second receptacle. The opening direction of the first receptacle is opposite to the opening direction of the second receptacle. The plurality of filter elements is disposed in the first receptacle, and at least one of the filter elements is electrically connected to the power pin. The ground inductor is disposed in the second receptacle and electrically connected to the ground pin.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The power line filter further includes a connecting element disposed between the socket and the housing to connect the ground pin to the ground inductor. The connecting element includes a protruding portion extending out from the opening of the second receptacle to connect the ground inductor. Preferably, the connecting element includes a groove to engage with the ground pin.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The housing further includes a division plate and a side plate. The division plate divides the housing into the first receptacle and the second receptacle. A first bottom plate used as a bottom portion of the first receptacle is extended from one of two corresponding ends of the division plate, and a second bottom plate used as a bottom portion of the second receptacle is extended from the other one of the two corresponding ends of the division plate. Preferably, the second bottom plate has a through hole to hold the ground inductor. The side plate is disposed between the first receptacle and the socket to insulate the ground pin from the plurality of filter elements. Preferably, the housing, the division plate and the side plate are formed as one piece with an insulating material.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The filter elements include an X capacitor, two Y capacitors and a filter inductor. The filter inductor is preferably disposed at the bottom of the first receptacle, and the X capacitor is disposed above the filter inductor. The two Y capacitors are disposed at one side of the X capacitor and the filter inductor, and located at one side in the first receptacle opposite to the socket. Preferably, the X capacitor and the filter inductor are electrically connected to the power pin.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The power line filter further includes at least one power terminal and a ground terminal. The at least one power terminal extends out from the housing. The filter inductor and the two Y capacitors are electrically connected to the power terminal. The ground terminal has two end portions extending out from the opening of the first receptacle and the second opening of the second receptacle, respectively. Preferably, one of the two end portions of the ground terminal is connected to the ground inductor, and the other one of the two end portions is connected to the Y capacitor. The housing has a groove, and the ground terminal is engaged within the groove. Preferably, the at least one power terminal and the ground terminal are disposed at one side of the housing opposite to the socket.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The power line filter further includes an insulating cover disposed on the opening of the first receptacle to cover the filter elements. The power line filter further includes a metal case and a first locking element. The metal case is mounted on the surfaces of the socket and the housing. The first locking element is used to assemble the metal case with the socket. The power line filter further includes a second locking element used to assemble the socket with the housing. Preferably, the power pins are a line wire pin and a neutral wire pin, and the power terminals are a line wire terminal and a neutral wire terminal.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The invention will become more fully understood from the detailed description and accompanying drawings, which are given for illustration only, and thus are not limitative of the present invention, and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded view of a power line filter in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2F</figref> are schematic figures showing the assembling steps of the power line filter shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present invention will be apparent from the following detailed description, which proceeds with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein the same references relate to the same elements.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a power line filter in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention includes a socket <b>11</b>, a housing <b>12</b>, a plurality of filter elements <b>14</b> and a ground inductor <b>16</b>. The socket <b>11</b> includes a first power pin <b>111</b>, a second power pin <b>112</b> and a ground pin <b>113</b>. The housing <b>12</b> is assembled with the socket <b>11</b>, and has a first receptacle <b>121</b> and a second receptacle <b>122</b>. The opening direction of the first receptacle <b>121</b> is opposite to the opening direction of the second receptacle <b>122</b>. In more detailed, the opening of the first receptacle <b>121</b> is upward, but the opening of the second receptacle <b>122</b> is downward. The plurality of filter elements <b>14</b> is disposed in the first receptacle <b>121</b>, and at least one of the filter elements <b>14</b> is electrically connected to the first power pin <b>111</b> and the second power pin <b>112</b>. The ground inductor <b>16</b> is disposed in the second receptacle <b>122</b> and electrically connected to the ground pin <b>113</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The power line filter further includes a connecting element <b>13</b> disposed between the socket <b>11</b> and the housing <b>12</b> to connect the ground pin <b>113</b> to the ground inductor <b>16</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the connecting element <b>13</b> includes a protruding portion <b>132</b> extending out from the opening of the second receptacle <b>122</b> to connect the ground inductor <b>16</b>. Preferably, the connecting element <b>13</b> has a groove <b>131</b> to engage with the ground pin <b>113</b>, and then the connecting element <b>13</b> and the ground pin <b>113</b> are fixed together with a solder s.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, the housing includes a division plate <b>125</b>, and the division plate <b>125</b> divides the housing into the first receptacle <b>121</b> and the second receptacle <b>122</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref>, a first bottom plate <b>1211</b> used as a bottom portion of the first receptacle <b>121</b> is extended from one of two corresponding ends of the division plate <b>125</b>, and a second bottom plate <b>1221</b> used as a bottom portion of the second receptacle <b>122</b> is extended from the other one of the two corresponding ends of the division plate <b>125</b>. Preferably, the second bottom plate <b>1221</b> has a through hole h to hold the ground inductor <b>16</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the housing also includes a side plate <b>124</b> disposed between the first receptacle <b>121</b> and the socket <b>11</b> to insulate the ground pin <b>113</b> from the plurality of filter elements <b>14</b>. Preferably, the housing <b>12</b>, the division plate <b>125</b> and the side plate <b>124</b> are formed as one piece with an insulating material.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2D and 2E</figref>, the plurality of filter elements includes an X capacitor <b>142</b>, two Y capacitors <b>141</b> and a filter inductor <b>143</b>. The filter inductor <b>143</b> is preferably disposed at the bottom of the first receptacle <b>121</b>, and the X capacitor <b>142</b> is disposed above the filter inductor <b>143</b>. The two Y capacitors <b>141</b> are disposed at one side of the X capacitor <b>142</b> and the filter inductor <b>143</b>, and located at one side in the first receptacle <b>121</b> opposite to the socket <b>11</b>. Preferably, the X capacitor <b>142</b> and the filter inductor <b>143</b> are electrically connected to the first power pin <b>111</b> and the second power pin <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The power line filter further comprises a first power terminal <b>151</b>, a second power terminal <b>152</b> and a ground terminal <b>153</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2B and 2C</figref>, the first power terminal <b>151</b> and the second power terminal <b>152</b> extend out from the housing <b>12</b>. The filter inductor <b>143</b> and the two Y capacitors <b>141</b> are electrically connected to the first power terminal <b>151</b> and the second power terminal <b>152</b>. The ground terminal <b>153</b> is disposed outside the housing <b>12</b>. One end of the ground inductor <b>16</b> is connected to the ground terminal <b>153</b>, and the other end of the ground inductor <b>16</b> is electrically connected to the ground pin <b>113</b> by the protruding portion <b>132</b> of the connecting element <b>13</b>. The ground terminal <b>153</b> has two end portions <b>1531</b> and <b>1532</b> extending out from the opening of the first receptacle <b>121</b> and the second opening of the second receptacle <b>122</b>, respectively. Preferably, the end portion <b>1532</b> of the two end portions of the ground terminal <b>153</b> is connected to the ground inductor <b>16</b>, and the other end portion <b>1531</b> of the two end portions is connected to the two Y capacitor <b>141</b>. The housing <b>12</b> has a groove <b>123</b>, and the ground terminal <b>153</b> is engaged within the groove <b>123</b>. Preferably, the first power terminal <b>151</b>, the second power terminal <b>152</b> and the ground terminal <b>153</b> are disposed at one side of the housing <b>12</b> opposite to the socket <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2F</figref>, the power line filter further includes an insulating cover <b>18</b> disposed on the opening of the first receptacle <b>121</b> to cover the plurality of filter elements <b>14</b>. The power line filter further includes a metal case <b>17</b> and a first locking element <b>21</b>. The metal case <b>17</b> is mounted on the surfaces of the socket <b>11</b> and the housing <b>12</b>. The first locking element <b>21</b> is used to assemble the metal case <b>17</b> with the socket <b>11</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, the power line filter further includes a second locking element <b>22</b> used to assemble the socket <b>11</b> with the housing <b>12</b>. The plurality of filter elements <b>14</b>, the ground inductor <b>16</b>, the first power terminal <b>151</b>, the second power terminal <b>152</b>, the ground terminal <b>153</b>, the first power pin <b>111</b>, the second power pin <b>112</b> and the ground pin <b>113</b> are fixed together with the solders s. The first power pin <b>111</b> and the second power pin <b>112</b> are preferably a line wire pin and a neutral wire pin. The first power terminal <b>151</b> and the second power terminal <b>152</b> are preferably a line wire terminal and a neutral wire terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In summary, the power line filter of the present invention contains a plurality of filter elements and a ground inductor in two receptacles of a housing, respectively, among others the opening directions of the two receptacles are opposite with respect to each other. Thus, the ground inductor can be disposed upright at one side of a filter inductor so that it can shorten the length of the power line filter by improving the interior design and the element arrangement. Otherwise, taking advantage of the double-receptacle design, the present invention can omit the material and the process that use the insulating tape, and avoid the safety issue resulted from the detachment or the crack of the insulating tape during the manufacturing or executing processes thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Although the invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments, this description is not meant to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications of the disclosed embodiments, as well as alternative embodiments, will be apparent to persons skilled in the art. It is, therefore, contemplated that the appended claims will cover all modifications that fall within the true scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A power line filter, comprising:
<claim-text>a socket comprising at least one power pin and a ground pin;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing assembled with the socket and comprising a first receptacle and a second receptacle, wherein the opening direction of the first receptacle is opposite to the opening direction of the second receptacle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of filter elements disposed in the first receptacle, wherein at least one of the plurality of filter elements is electrically connected to the at least one power pin, wherein the plurality of filter elements comprise an X capacitor, two Y capacitors and a filter inductor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground inductor disposed in the second receptacle and electrically connected to the ground pin; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground terminal disposed outside the housing, wherein two ends of the ground inductor are electrically connected to the ground terminal and the ground pin, respectively, wherein the housing comprises a groove, and the ground terminal is engaged within the groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a connecting element disposed between the socket and the housing to c he ground pin to the ground inductor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting element comprises a protruding portion extending out from an opening of the second receptacle to connect the ground inductor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting element comprises a connecting groove to engage with the ground pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing further comprises a division plate to divide the housing into the first receptacle and the second receptacle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein a first bottom plate used as a bottom portion of the first receptacle is extended from one of two corresponding ends of the division plate, and a second bottom plate used as a bottom portion of the second receptacle is extended from the other one of the two corresponding ends of the division plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the second bottom plate comprises a through hole to hold the ground inductor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the housing further comprises a side plate disposed between the first receptacle and the socket to insulate the ground pin from the plurality of filter elements.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the housing, the division plate and the side plate are formed as one piece with an insulating material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one power pin comprises a line wire pin and a neutral wire pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the filter inductor is disposed at the bottom of the first receptacle, and the X capacitor is disposed above the filter inductor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the two Y capacitors are disposed at one side of the X capacitor and the filter inductor, and located at one side in the first receptacle opposite to the socket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the X capacitor and the filter inductor are electrically connected to the at least one power pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>at least one power terminal extending out from the housing, wherein the filter inductor and the two Y capacitors are electrically connected to the at least one power terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one power terminal comprises a line wire terminal and a neutral wire terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ground terminal comprises two end portions extending out from an opening of the first receptacle and an opening of the second receptacle, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein one of the two end portions of the ground terminal is connected to the ground inductor and the other one of the two end, portions is connected to both of the two Y capacitors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second locking element for assembling the socket with the housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one power terminal and the ground terminal are disposed at one side of the housing opposite to the socket.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>an insulating cover disposed on the opening of the first receptacle to cover the plurality of filter elements.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a metal case mounted on the surfaces of the socket and the housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The power line filter of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first locking element for assembling the metal case with the socket.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
