<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624187-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624187</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11466347</doc-number>
<date>20060822</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2503383</main-classification>
<further-classification>250340</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Imaging detector array with optical readout</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4019015</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hassan et al.</name>
<date>19770400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>21912131</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4883926</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Baldwin</name>
<date>19891100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>178 1901</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6080988</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ishizuya et al.</name>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2503381</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6392233</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Channin et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2503381</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6469301</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Suzuki et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2503381</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6552344</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Sone et al.</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2503381</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0130728</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Degertekin et al.</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>356505</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2503383</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>250340</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60709791</doc-number>
<date>20050822</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070045541</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070301</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Urey</last-name>
<first-name>Hakan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Istanbul</city>
<country>TR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Torun</last-name>
<first-name>Hamdi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Istanbul</city>
<country>TR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Urey</last-name>
<first-name>Hakan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Istanbul</city>
<country>TR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Torun</last-name>
<first-name>Hamdi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Istanbul</city>
<country>TR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Venable, Campillo, Logan &#x26; Meaney PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Porta</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<department>2884</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Igyarto</last-name>
<first-name>Carolyn</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention relates to thermal detectors and the application of such to devices and methods of detecting the infrared images using thermal detectors. For example, by using optical measuring systems in combination with at least one light source to measure changes position of a movable anchored surface coupled to an absorption surface such that the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption of infrared radiation by the absorption surface. In another example, by combining a detector pixel (infrared radiation sensitive) with an optical measuring device such as an interferometer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.34mm" wi="207.52mm" file="US08624187-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.75mm" wi="133.27mm" file="US08624187-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="265.09mm" wi="205.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624187-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="238.25mm" wi="152.65mm" file="US08624187-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="274.40mm" wi="196.60mm" file="US08624187-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="273.39mm" wi="213.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624187-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="192.62mm" wi="215.90mm" file="US08624187-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This Application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 60/709,791, filed on Aug. 22, 2005, which is entirely incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to the field of imaging technology. Particularly, it involves the field of infrared (IR) imaging device using a light source, diffraction grating and a detector array having at least two detector pixels. More particularly, the invention may be used by an uncooled opto-mechanical IR detector with optical readout.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It is well known that Infrared (IR) imaging technology has found many important application areas such as military, automobile heads-up-displays (HUD), medical diagnostics, surveillance for security, victim search for rescue teams, non-destructive testing for industrial applications, and geo-thermal event detection for environmental control. The devices used to generate the thermal map of the targets are passive devices that collect the optical signal radiated from the targets according to Planck's radiation law assuming that the targets behave as black bodies. According to the well known Planck's radiation law, the energy emitted per unit volume per unit wavelength from a blackbody (EA) is proportional to the temperature of the blackbody.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Therefore, it is possible to generate the thermal map of the target by detecting the radiated energy since the only parameters that determine the amount of energy are the temperature and the radiation wavelength. The interested spectrum of the radiation is classified as infrared (IR) band and IR band is further divided into bands as a function of wavelength as follows:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0005">Near IR (NIR): 0.78-1 micron</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0006">Short wavelength IR (SWIR): 1-3 micron</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0007">Mid-wavelength IR (MWIR): 3-5 micron</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0008">Long-wavelength IR (LWIR): 8-14 micron</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0009">Very long-wavelength IR (VLWIR): 14-100 micron</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0010">Each of these specific bands has their own properties, and specific detector technologies have been developed for these bands. For infrared imaging applications, MWIR and LWIR bands, where the transmittance of the atmosphere is high, are especially important. Transmittance through air is reduced by several factors as a result of scattering and absorption processes. The bands of operation should be selected specifically to each application. For instance, MWIR band is favorable if the target is relatively hot and the weather is clear, on the other hand LWIR band offers high sensitivity in hazy weather conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0011">Infrared imaging devices can basically be classified into two main groups according to the detection mechanism. Photon detectors deal directly with the interaction of the incoming photons with the electrons in the detector material. On the other hand, thermal detectors are the devices whose properties can be modulated by its temperature. Therefore, the detection mechanism of thermal detectors is indirect in the sense that the incoming radiation is first converted into heat energy and the generated heat energy is used to change an appropriate material property of the detector.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0012">Information relevant to this invention can also be found in United States Patent and Parent Publication U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,576,572, 6,643,025, 6,753,969, 20040130728, 20060138347, and 20060181712 issued to Degertekin, et al.; each of the foregoing in United States Patent and Patent Publication Nos. is hereby incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0013">Each one of the above descriptions or references, however, suffers from disadvantages including; for example, one or more of the following, the invention is not directed at thermal detectors, or if directed at thermal detectors, the thermal detector has poor sensitivity, poor response time and noise. Other disadvantages of known thermal detectors include that they are not easily scalable and that they do not integrate a diffraction grating into each detector pixel to be combined with an optical readout to decrease the noise and improve the sensitivity.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0014">It is an object of the present invention to provide a thermal detector and related method comprising an absorption surface coupled to a movable anchored surface wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface; at least one light source; and an optical measuring system to measure the movable anchored surface changes using the at least one light source. In a preferred embodiment, the movable anchored surface is a movable leg or a flexible membrane, and more preferably is made of at least two materials having sufficient differences in the coefficient of expansion to cause measurable mechanical movement (displacement) in response to thermal changes (absorption). Preferably, the optical measuring system also includes at least one detector and an interferometer comprising a reflector surface and an interference means forming a gap between the reflector surface and the interference means wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface and the movable anchored surface is coupled to the interferometer to make the gap variable wherein the at least one detector detects variations in the gap and produces a detector signal related thereto. In another preferred embodiment the at least one light source is selected from the group consisting of light emitting diodes, laser diodes, vertical cavity surface emitting lasers, lasers and combinations thereof. The absorption surface is a thermal absorption surface. Also preferably, the interference means is selected from a diffraction grating or a Fabry-Perot surface. It is also preferable that the movable anchored surface is coupled to the group consisting of either an interference means or a reflector surface, and more preferably that the movable anchored surface is at least two materials having different coefficients of thermal expansion to cause measurable mechanical movement in response to thermal changes; for example, a bimaterial comprising silicon nitride and aluminum (or gold) or silicon dioxide and aluminum (or gold) and combinations thereof. Also, in a preferred embodiment, the absorption surface comprises silicon nitride, infrared absorbing thin metal films and combinations thereof, and more preferably the reflector surface comprises polysilicon, light reflecting thin metal films and combinations thereof. In yet another preferred embodiment, the invention includes at least one more thermal detector to form an infrared imaging system when coupled with an infrared lens (collimating or focusing means). In a further preferred embodiment of the invention, the optical imaging system further comprises a read-out imaging system, and more preferably the read-out imaging system is selected from the group consisting of one dimensional detectors, two dimensional detectors, and CCD cameras. Also preferably, the read-out imaging system further comprises a processing device to control the light source and process the detector signal.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0015">The novel features that are considered characteristic of the invention are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention itself, however, both as to its structure and its operation together with the additional object and advantages thereof will best be understood from the following description of the preferred embodiment of the present invention when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. Unless specifically noted, it is intended that the words and phrases in the specification and claims be given the ordinary and accustomed meaning to those of ordinary skill in the applicable art or arts. If any other meaning is intended, the specification will specifically state that a special meaning is being applied to a word or phrase. Likewise, the use of the words &#x201c;function&#x201d; or &#x201c;means&#x201d; in the Description of Preferred Embodiments is not intended to indicate a desire to invoke the special provision of 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;112, paragraph 6 to define the invention. To the contrary, if the provisions of 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;112, paragraph 6, are sought to be invoked to define the invention(s), the claims will specifically state the phrases &#x201c;means for&#x201d; or &#x201c;step for&#x201d; and a function, without also reciting in such phrases any structure, material, or act in support of the function. Even when the claims recite a &#x201c;means for&#x201d; or &#x201c;step for&#x201d; performing a function, if they also recite any structure, material or acts in support of that means of step, then the intention is not to invoke the provisions of 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;112, paragraph 6. Moreover, even if the provisions of 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;112, paragraph 6, are invoked to define the inventions, it is intended that the inventions not be limited only to the specific structure, material or acts that are described in the preferred embodiments, but in addition, include any and all structures, materials or acts that perform the claimed function, along with any and all known or later-developed equivalent structures, materials or acts for performing the claimed function.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of one preferred embodiment of one of a thermal detector.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of one preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2-A</figref> is a perspective view of a preferred embodiment of the invention represented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagrammatic view of a preferred embodiment of a light source for the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic view of a preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagrammatic view of another preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side diagrammatic view of another preferred embodiment of one of a thermal detector.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of another preferred embodiment of the invention</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view of another preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0025">The infrared imaging device of this invention is a thermal detector in which the incoming radiation is first converted into heat energy and then the heat energy is converted into mechanical energy that deflects the detector pixels of the detector array. To achieve mechanical deflection, the working principle of thermostats is employed. Additionally, one embodiment of the current invention measures the deflection using an interferometer having a diffraction grating and a light source. In a preferred embodiment the pixels in the detector array have structures that are connected to a movable anchored surface (preferably suitable bimaterial layers) as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is depicted a preferred embodiment of the one detector pixel <b>100</b> having an absorption surface <b>110</b>, a reflector surface <b>120</b> and a movable anchored surface <b>130</b> (specifically a movable leg in this preferred embodiment). The absorption surface <b>110</b> can be chosen from light absorptive material such as silicon nitride (SiN) or thin metal films such as aluminum (Al) or gold (Au) and the reflector surface <b>120</b> can be chosen from any reflective material such as polysilicon or thin metals films such as aluminum (Al) or gold (Au) or polysilicon. In a preferred embodiment, the thickness of the absorption surface <b>110</b> of SiN would be 300 nanometers and for thin metals would range from 10 to 30 nanometers. In a preferred embodiment, the thickness of the reflector surface <b>120</b> for thin metals would be at least 70 nanometers. Additionally, the detector pixel <b>100</b> may have anchors <b>140</b> and thermal isolation legs <b>150</b>. In the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the absorption surface <b>110</b> is a thermal absorption surface such that it absorbs heat energy (infrared radiation). The movable leg <b>130</b> of the preferred embodiment is composed of any two compatible materials that have different thermal expansion rates; for example, SiN and Al or silicon dioxide (SiO<sub>2</sub>) and Al.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a preferred embodiment of a thermal detector <b>160</b> having a detector pixel <b>100</b> coupled to an optical measuring system comprising a detector <b>400</b>; a light source <b>300</b> and an interferometer having an interference means <b>200</b> (such as a diffraction grating) and a reflector surface (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, but <b>120</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) that form a gap <b>70</b> there between; for example, the optical measuring system may comprise in one preferred embodiment a diffraction grating, the reflector surface, a light source and a detector. In this preferred embodiment, the diffraction grating <b>200</b> is preferably coupled to a transparent substrate <b>220</b> while the reflector surface <b>120</b> contained in the pixel detector <b>100</b> is coupled to the a movable anchored surface <b>130</b> contained in the pixel detector <b>100</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>). More preferably, the movable anchored surface <b>130</b> is a movable leg. Preferably, the transparent substrate <b>220</b> can be chosen from quartz or other transparent materials. In this preferred embodiment, the detector pixel <b>100</b> is separated from the diffraction grating <b>200</b> creating a gap <b>70</b>. Preferably, the distance of the gap <b>70</b> is chosen to be one-quarter of the center of the wavelength range to be measured. The reflector surface <b>120</b> is illuminated by a light source <b>300</b>. Preferably, the light source <b>300</b> can be chosen from light emitting diodes, lasers, laser diodes, lasers and vertical cavity surface emitting diodes. As shown in the preferred embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, detectors <b>400</b> can be set next to an entrance for the light source <b>300</b>, or in an alternative embodiment set next to the light source <b>300</b> itself In the preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the light reflected by the reflector surface <b>120</b> of the detector pixel <b>100</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>) is diffracted to form reflected light orders; for example the zero order reflection <b>350</b> (I<sub>0</sub>) is directly reflected and higher order reflections (1<sup>st</sup>) <b>351</b>, (3<sup>rd</sup>) <b>353</b>, etc. are reflected at greater angles and with lessening intensity. Additionally, a voltage (V) <b>235</b> may be applied for tuning and calibration purposes. In an alternative embodiment (not shown), the reflector surface <b>120</b> would be fixed and the movable anchored surface <b>130</b> would be coupled to the interference means <b>200</b>; for example, a silicon substrate (infrared transmissive but not visible light transmissive) can be used as the reflector surface <b>120</b> while the interference means <b>200</b> could be coupled to the movable anchored surface <b>130</b> such that infrared light would pass through a first side of the silicon substrate to heat the absorption surface but visible light from the light source directed towards a second side (opposite the first side) of the silicon substrate and through the interference means <b>200</b> would be reflected.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-A</figref> and <b>8</b> show another view of preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0029">In a preferred embodiment of the invention shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the light source <b>300</b> may be split into many beams so that it may illuminate multiple thermal detectors having detector pixels <b>100</b> such as one thousand detector pixels or more using a micro-optical element <b>500</b> such as a fan out diffraction grating and a lens <b>510</b>. In an alternative embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the light source <b>300</b>, may be scanned across an array <b>180</b> of at least two thermal detectors <b>160</b>; for example, using a microelectromechanical scanner <b>600</b>, a mirror <b>610</b>, and a first lens <b>620</b> such as a convex lens. In this preferred embodiment, the reflector surface <b>120</b> of the detector pixels <b>100</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> also) reflects light through an interference means <b>200</b> which in this preferred embodiment is a focal plan array comprising one or more diffraction grating to create reflected light orders, and in this preferred embodiment, the first order reflection <b>351</b> is focused by the first lens <b>620</b> on a optical component <b>650</b> (a second lens) to focus it on the detector <b>400</b>. The optical measuring system, in a preferred embodiment, includes a read-out imaging system to image the focal plane image of the at least two detector pixels. In a preferred embodiment, the light source <b>300</b> is controlled by a processing device <b>700</b> such as a special or general-purpose computer or a microprocessor. The light source <b>300</b> may be controlled by a microprocessor <b>700</b> such that the light may be modulated by frequency, wavelength and/or intensity; and more preferably, the modulation of the light source <b>300</b> may then be multiplexed with the information received from the detector <b>400</b> such that an image of the thermal emission of the black body may be constructed (<b>800</b>). In a more preferred embodiment of the invention, some of the thermal detectors <b>160</b> may be designated for reference so that their reflected order signals may be used to cancel noise from the thermal detectors <b>160</b> that are active.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0030">In yet another preferred embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a light source <b>300</b> is scanned across a detector array <b>180</b> through a lens <b>620</b> using a light source directing device <b>605</b> (for example a lens) and a two dimensional scanner <b>615</b> such as a rotating stage. Preferably, the light source <b>300</b> can be modulated; for example, using a laser combined with an acousto-optic modulator (AOM) or a laser diode and more preferably the modulated light source <b>300</b> may be controlled using either frequency, wavelength, amplitude (intensity) or combinations thereof by a processing device <b>700</b> such as a general or specific purpose computer or microprocessor. In this preferred embodiment, the detector array <b>180</b> comprising an interference means (in a focal plane array) and the detector pixels are placed in a controlled environment <b>662</b>; for example, a temperature stabilized vacuum is used for thermal detectors. In this preferred embodiment, infrared radiation <b>50</b> is directed through an infrared lens <b>60</b> and through a silicon substrate <b>65</b> (transmissive to infrared light but not visible light) which is used as the reflector surface <b>120</b> while the interference means <b>200</b> is coupled to the movable anchored surface <b>130</b> (preferably, a movable leg) such that infrared light would pass through a first side of the silicon substrate <b>65</b> to heat the absorption surface <b>110</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) but visible light from the light source <b>300</b> is directed towards a second side (opposite the first side) of the silicon substrate and reflected from the silicon substrate <b>65</b> through the interference means <b>200</b>. The reflected order light (zero order reflected order light <b>350</b> and first order reflected order light <b>351</b>) is then reflected through at least one optical component <b>650</b>. In this preferred embodiment, the first order reflected order light <b>351</b> is directed through a polarizing beam splitter <b>655</b>, a quarter wave plate <b>667</b>, a spatial filter <b>674</b>, and a second lens <b>676</b> to a two dimensional detector <b>900</b>; for example, a CCD camera. In this preferred embodiment, the quarter wave plate rotates the light polarization by 90 degrees (by the light passing through it twice) such that it increases the light reflected to the detectors and minimizes any light that would be reflected to the light source <b>300</b>. The zero order reflected order light <b>350</b> is directed by the polarizing beam splitter <b>655</b> to a mirror <b>675</b> and through a third lens <b>688</b> to focus on a zero order detector <b>685</b>; for example a photo diode or array of photo diodes. The processing device <b>700</b> can use the signal received from the two dimensional detector <b>900</b> to modulate the light source <b>300</b> so that the dynamic range can be expanded. For example, the light source illumination (intensity or amplitude) can be modulated using feedback from the CCD camera corresponding to each detector pixel <b>100</b> to increase the optical detection dynamic range. Likewise, the frequency and wavelength could be modulated in real time with feedback from the two dimensional detector <b>900</b>. In this preferred embodiment, the zero order reflected order light may be detected for noise cancellation and signal equalization.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an alternate preferred embodiment of a thermal detector <b>160</b> comprising an optical measuring system using a Fabry-Perot (FP) interferometer. As shown in the alternative preferred embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the thermal detector <b>160</b> comprises an absorption surface <b>110</b> coupled to a reflector surface <b>120</b> and a movable anchored surface <b>130</b> (preferably a flexible membrane) coupled to an anchor <b>140</b> coupled to a Fabry-Perot surface <b>195</b> (also known as a distributed Bragg reflector (DBR) surface for Fabry-Perot interferometer (FP) in this preferred embodiment) thereby forming a gap <b>70</b>; and more preferably the Fabry-Perot surface <b>195</b> is coupled to a transparent substrate <b>220</b>. The incoming infrared radiation <b>50</b> is absorbed by an absorption surface <b>110</b> having a reflector surface <b>120</b> such that the absorbed heat causes movable anchored surface <b>130</b> (preferably in this embodiment a bimaterial cantilever or a flexible membrane device) to deflect and change the gap <b>70</b> which changes the FP interferometer. If the gap is biased to a sensitive region (such as the mid-point of the infrared wavelength range of interest) the measurement of the reflected light will give information about the deflection in the bimaterial cantilever proportional to infrared radiation <b>50</b>. More preferably, the gap is chosen to be one-quarter of the center of the wavelength range to be measured to enhance the absorption. In this read-out configuration, no diffraction grating is needed and the absorption surface <b>110</b> and read-out cavity of the Fabry-Perot interferometer can be biased to the optimum points independent of each other.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows another preferred embodiment with cantilever like structures. In another preferred embodiment, the pixel overview of the detector design is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-A</figref> and <b>8</b> where the membrane hangs from the mid portions by the cantilever like structures. Due to the symmetry in the design the membrane motion is parallel to the substrate on which there are the fingers of diffraction gratings. As the membrane moves up and down relative to the gratings as a result of absorbed IR radiation, the light intensity at the diffraction orders is modulated. For thermal detectors, such as those in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, resonant frequency for a first mode analysis is almost 40 kHz while there is good separation between the resonant frequency first mode and the resonant frequency second mode is around 120 kHz; in a preferred embodiment, the movable leg is composed of 500 nm Al on top of 500 nm SiN<sub>x</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0033">In the preferred embodiments of this invention the interferometer may be of any known type; for example reflecting surface, diffraction grating, Fabry-Perot, etc. Further, the interference means of the preferred embodiments of the invention may include one or more elements such as a single diffraction grating, two diffraction gratings, multiple diffraction gratings; a single Fabry-Perot surface or multiple Fabry-Perot surface; more preferably when two or more gratings are employed the gratings are oriented at different angles or have different grating periods to provide enhanced deflection measurement range due to varying amounts of deflection at different parts of the detector pixel. In a preferred embodiment of the invention the light source may comprise one or more narrow spectrum sources, and more preferrably coherent light sources; for example, the light source can use multiple wavelenghts to enhance the dynamic range of detection such as the preferred use of two coherent (laser) radiation have wavelengths of 620 nm and 670 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0034">The preferred embodiment of the invention is described above in the Drawings and Description of Preferred Embodiments. While these descriptions directly describe the above embodiments, it is understood that those skilled in the art may conceive modifications and/or variations to the specific embodiments shown and described herein. Any such modifications or variations that fall within the purview of this description are intended to be included therein as well. Unless specifically noted, it is the intention of the inventor that the words and phrases in the specification and claims be given the ordinary and accustomed meanings to those of ordinary skill in the applicable art(s). The foregoing description of a preferred embodiment and best mode of the invention known to the applicant at the time of filing the application has been presented and is intended for the purposes of illustration and description. It is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise form disclosed, and many modifications and variations are possible in the light of the above teachings. The embodiment was chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and its practical application and to enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the invention in various embodiments and with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A thermal detector comprising:
<claim-text>an absorption surface coupled to a movable anchored surface having at least one thermal isolation leg and at least one anchor wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light source; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical measuring system to measure the movable anchored surface changes using the at least one light source</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical measuring system comprises at least one detector and an interferometer comprising a reflector surface and at least one diffraction grating forming a gap between the reflector surface and the at least one diffraction grating wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface and the movable anchored surface is coupled to the interferometer to make the gap variable wherein the at least one detector detects variations in the gap to produce a detector signal and wherein the reflector surface changes position, with a piston motion, parallel to the at least one diffraction grating.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the gap is chosen to be one-quarter of a center of a wavelength range to be measured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the at least one light source is selected from the group consisting of light emitting diodes, laser diodes, vertical cavity surface emitting lasers, lasers and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the movable anchored surface comprises at least two materials having different coefficients of thermal expansion to cause measurable mechanical movement in response to thermal changes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the absorption surface comprises silicon nitride, infrared absorbing thin metal films and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising at least one more thermal detector to form an infrared imaging system when coupled with an infrared lens.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising a read-out imaging system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The thermal detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the read-out imaging system is selected from the group consisting of at least one detector, one dimensional detectors, two dimensional detectors, CCD cameras and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The detector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the read-out imaging system further comprises a processing device to control the light source and process the detector signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method to produce an image from infrared radiation comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>creating an array of thermal detectors using at least two thermal detectors wherein each of the at least two thermal detectors comprises at least one thermal isolation leg, least one anchor, at least one reflector surface, and at least one absorption surface for absorbing infrared radiation coupled to a movable anchored surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>focusing infrared radiation, using an infrared imaging system, on the array of thermal detectors wherein absorbing infrared radiation causes the movable anchored surface to move;</claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling the at least one reflector surface to the movable anchored surface and to an interferometer comprising at least one diffraction grating and wherein the reflector surface position, with a piston motion, parallel to the at least one diffraction grating;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting changes in the movable anchored surface using at least one light source coupled to the interferometer and at least one detector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>producing an image using a processing device to process the detected changes in the movable anchored surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein the step of coupling an interferometer to the movable anchored surface comprises forming a gap by placing the at least one diffraction grating between the at least one reflector surface and the at least one light source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the step of forming the gap further comprises spacing the at least one diffraction grating from the at least one reflector by one-quarter of a center wavelength of a wavelength range to be measured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein the step of detecting changes in the movable anchored surface using at least one light source coupled to the interferometer and at least one detector comprises detectors selected from the group consisting of at least one one-dimensional detectors, at least one two-dimensional detectors, photodiodes, photodetectors and CCD cameras and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of placing at least one optical component between the at least one two-dimensional detector and the at least one diffraction grating.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> wherein the step of placing at least one optical component between the at least one two-dimensional detector and the at least one diffraction grating comprises using at least one optical component selected from the group consisting of polarizing beam splitters; lenses; spatial filters, mirrors, quarter waveplates and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> further comprising the step of scanning the at least one light source across the at least two thermal detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> further comprising the step of scanning the at least one light source across the at least two thermal detectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> further comprising a step of modulating of the at least one light source is selected from the group consisting of frequency modulation, intensity modulation, wavelength modulation and combinations thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> wherein the step of creating the thermal array further comprises creating at least one reference thermal detector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of detecting the infrared image in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> further comprising the step of monitoring at least two zero order reflections using a zero order detector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A thermal detector comprising:
<claim-text>an absorption surface coupled to a movable anchored surface having at least one thermal isolation leg and at least one anchor wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light source; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical measuring system to measure the movable anchored surface changes using the at least one light source</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical measuring system comprises at least one detector and an interferometer comprising a reflector surface and at least one diffraction grating forming a gap between the reflector surface and the at least one diffraction grating wherein the movable anchored surface changes position due to absorption by the absorption surface and the movable anchored surface is coupled to the interferometer to make the gap variable wherein the at least one detector detects variations in the gap to produce a detector signal and wherein the at least one anchor is two anchors and wherein the thermal detector has a first mode resonant frequency and a second mode resonant frequency having a separation of around 120 kHz.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
