<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622532-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622532</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13103468</doc-number>
<date>20110509</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>175</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 88</main-classification>
<further-classification>347 99</further-classification>
<further-classification>347100</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method and system for clog detection and mitigation in delivering solid-ink pellets to an imaging apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4943818</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hotomi</name>
<date>19900700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>401171905</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19890700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>264142</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  6</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347  9</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 14</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 19</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 17</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 84- 85</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 88</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 99</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347100</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120287210</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121115</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wayman</last-name>
<first-name>William H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ontario</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brundige</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Playfair</last-name>
<first-name>David B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Penfield</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wayman</last-name>
<first-name>William H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ontario</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Brundige</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Playfair</last-name>
<first-name>David B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Penfield</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Root</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Xerox Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Norwalk</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Jackson</last-name>
<first-name>Juanita D</first-name>
<department>2853</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Apparatus and methods for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets when delivering solid-ink pellets from a container to an image-forming apparatus. The apparatus includes an extraction tube inserted into the container and connected to a vacuum source. Suction from the vacuum source impels pellets into the extraction tube through an extraction inlet, but pellet agglomerations may clog the system. Such a clog produces an immediate pressure spike within the extraction tube, an event detected by the clog detector. An actuator, responsive to the clog detector, drives an agitating structure that breaks up agglomerations and restores smooth pellet flow. Alternative embodiments can include devices having only the clog detector or the agitating structure. Alternative implementations of the agitating structure provide means for accomplishing pellet break up. The accompanying method detects the occurrence of a clog and responds by operating the agitating structure to break up agglomerations.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="144.95mm" wi="282.02mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="159.00mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="147.83mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="152.40mm" wi="127.42mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="156.04mm" wi="136.91mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="258.83mm" wi="105.58mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="254.08mm" wi="102.87mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="126.49mm" wi="110.07mm" file="US08622532-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The presently disclosed embodiments relate to delivery of solid-ink pellets to an image-forming apparatus, and more particularly to devices that maintain flowability of solid-ink pellets during delivery.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">An image-forming apparatus employing solid-ink pellets, such as a printer, a fax machine, or a photocopier, includes a system for extracting pellets from a container for delivery to the image-forming apparatus. Conventionally, the solid ink pellets are placed in a container, and a feeding mechanism extracts the pellets and transports them to a heater assembly. There, the heater melts the pellets and a feeding mechanism applies the resulting liquid to media to form images.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In general, solid-ink pellets are stored in a container, from which pellets are extracted for print production as required. Typically, an extraction tube is inserted into the container, suction is applied to the extraction tube, and the resulting airflow entrains the solid-ink pellets from an extraction inlet in the extraction tube.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A flow problem can arise, however, when pellets bridge or clump together. This process, known as agglomeration, can occur when the pellets are stored in the container, as adjacent particles tend to fuse together under the combined action of temperature and pressure. Also, static charges on individual particles can cause attraction between adjacent particles, leading to agglomerations. Further, the prilling process employed to manufacture the solid-ink pellets can result in the pellets being brought into close proximity before they have cooled, likewise leading to agglomerations. The resulting clumps or agglomerations may exceed the size of the extraction inlet, clogging the flow of the solid-ink pellets.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Known approaches to this problem aim to break up the bridges and clumps, employing a variety of mechanical means. Generally, these solutions adapt the extraction tube to provide a device that manually agitates the solid-ink pellets to break up the agglomerations. This manual agitation must be performed sufficiently often to maintain the desired flow of solid-ink pellets. Where a number of agglomerations have formed, significant operator intervention may be required. Moreover, the agitation process itself interrupts pellet movement, and it often fails to produce the pellet movement once clumps have clogged the system.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In general, containers store considerable volumes of solid-ink pellets, and manually agitating the container may be cumbersome. In another alternative solution, mixers or grinders are coupled to the container to break obstructions. Current solutions, however, limit the breakage of agglomerates to positions near the extraction tube, thereby reducing both the efficiency of the breakage mechanism as well as the flowability of the solid-ink pellets.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It would be highly desirable to have a simple and cost-effective system that identifies an appropriate time for agitating pellet agglomerations, and further maintains flowability of solid ink-pellets from a container, breaking up clumps and agglomerates.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">One embodiment of the present disclosure provides an apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device. The apparatus employs an extraction tube attached to a vacuum source, with an end of the extraction tube being inserted into the container for receiving pellets. Further, the apparatus includes a clog detector for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging. Based on the identification of the pellet agglomerations, an agitating structure breaks up pellet agglomerations</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Another embodiment of the present disclosure provides an apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, employing a clog detector. The apparatus employs an extraction tube attached to a vacuum source, with an end of the extraction tube being inserted into the container for receiving pellets. Further, the apparatus includes a clog detector for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A further embodiment of the present disclosure provides an apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, incorporating apparatus to break up pellet agglomerations. The apparatus employs an extraction tube attached to a vacuum source, with an end of the extraction tube being inserted into the container for receiving pellets. Further, the apparatus includes an agitating structure to break up pellet agglomerations</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another embodiment discloses a method for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during flow from a container to an image-forming device. The method involves inducing a suction force through an extraction tube for pellet extraction. The method further involves transporting the pellets from the container to an assist tube, through inlet holes of the assist tube, the assist tube being inside the container. In addition, the method includes detection of clogging, followed by agitation of the pellet agglomerations to undergo breakage. Pellets are transferred from the assist tube to the image-forming device through the extraction tube.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conventional solution for providing solid-ink pellet delivery to an image-forming device.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary system for delivering a continuous flow solid-ink pellets to an image-forming device.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows an embodiment of an agitating system including a spring, according to the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary embodiment of an agitating system employing a brush.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A</figref>, <b>5</b>B, and <b>5</b>C show an embodiment of the present disclosure employing a set of wires.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</figref>, <b>6</b>B, and <b>6</b>C show another embodiment implementing a pair of substantially perpendicular wires.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart of an exemplary method for detecting clogging and breaking pellet agglomerations for delivering solid-ink pellets to an image-forming device.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The following detailed description is made with reference to the figures. Preferred embodiments are described to illustrate the disclosure, not to limit its scope, which is defined by the claims. Those of ordinary skill in the art will recognize a number of equivalent variations in the description that follows.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As used herein, the term &#x201c;tube&#x201d; includes any generally elongated device enclosing a lengthwise passage, suitable for conveying fluid or particulates. As thus defined, a tube may be formed of any suitable material and in any suitable cross-section.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">Overview</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The present disclosure describes various embodiments of a system and a method for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during delivery to an image-forming device. The solid-ink pellets are stored in a container, and an extraction tube extends into the container for receiving the pellets. One end of the tube extends to the vicinity of the container bottom and the other end extends at least above the top, or lid, of the container. A vacuum source applies suction to the end of the vacuum tube to produce an airflow through the tube, entraining pellets in the airflow and moving them to the image-forming device. In the event that obstructions interfere with the smooth flow of pellets, a clog detector connected to the extraction tube senses a pressure spike. The system then activates an agitating structure, which can take any of a number of alternative constructions. The resulting agitation breaks up the pellet agglomerations to eliminate clogging, and airflow resumes, restoring a smooth extraction of pellets from the container.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">Conventional Delivery System</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conventional delivery system <b>100</b> for supplying solid-ink pellets to an image-forming device <b>101</b>. Delivery system <b>100</b> includes a container <b>102</b>, an extraction assembly <b>105</b>, and a delivery assembly <b>117</b>. Container <b>102</b> is adapted to receive and store solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>. Container <b>102</b> is generally cylindrical and is typically sized to store 50-60 gallons of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>. The top of container <b>102</b> can remain open, or it can be either closed, by a lid or by a special top adapted as explained below (neither type of lid shown). Both container <b>102</b> and the lid, if any, can be formed from convenient materials, such as plastic. It should be noted that in the interest of clarity, image-forming device <b>101</b> will not be shown below but will be understood to be present.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Extraction assembly <b>105</b> provides a path by which solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> can flow from container <b>102</b>, and it includes an assist tube <b>106</b> and an extraction tube <b>112</b>. Assist tube <b>106</b> is generally rigid and tubular, having an open end <b>106</b><i>a</i>, a closed end <b>106</b><i>b</i>, and a number of inlet holes <b>108</b> passing through the sides of assist tube <b>106</b> near closed end <b>106</b><i>b</i>. This structure stands vertically in container <b>102</b>, supported either by a convenient structure (not shown), such as struts, extending to the sides of container <b>102</b>, or by an opening formed in a lid or cover (not shown) provided atop container <b>102</b>. As shown, assist tube <b>106</b> extends to the vicinity of container <b>102</b> bottom. Extraction tube <b>112</b> is carried within assist tube <b>106</b>, with an extraction inlet <b>116</b> at the tip of extraction tube <b>112</b>, extending to the vicinity of closed end <b>106</b><i>b</i>. The portion of this tube lying within assist tube <b>106</b> is generally rigid, and it is carried within assist tube <b>106</b>, supported by convenient means (not shown). The sizing of assist tube <b>106</b>, extraction tube <b>112</b>, and inlet holes <b>108</b> is based on the sizing of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>, as discussed below. It should be noted that the extraction inlet <b>116</b> of the illustrated embodiment is defined by the tip of the extraction tube, but that inlet can be formed as desired in the extraction tube, based on the need to provide a convenient and effective entrance for the pellets to enter the extraction tube.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Delivery assembly <b>117</b> provides both the motive means and the destination for the flow of solid-ink pellets. Components of delivery assembly <b>117</b> include a vacuum source <b>114</b> and a melter <b>118</b>. Vacuum source <b>114</b> is a source of suction, such as an air pump, connected to a downstream end <b>109</b> of extraction tube <b>112</b>. A similar tube <b>119</b> extends from vacuum source <b>114</b> to melter <b>118</b>, the latter being a conventional component of imaging devices employing solid-ink pellets.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In operation, vacuum source <b>114</b> applies suction to extraction tube <b>112</b>, inducing a longitudinal airflow <b>120</b> in assist tube <b>106</b>. This flow produces suction at inlet holes <b>108</b>, impelling individual pellets <b>104</b> to become entrained in airflow <b>120</b> within extraction tube <b>112</b>. Pellets <b>104</b> proceed to vacuum source <b>114</b> and on to melter <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">For purposes of description, the present disclosure is described in connection with solid-ink pellets. Those skilled in the art, however, will appreciate that other environments may similarly require delivery of solid-ink pellets for printing or other purposes, from a storage container or similar device. The technology set out here can also be employed to promote flowability of solid particulates and pellets in a variety of other environments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">That delivery system encounters difficulties when solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> have agglomerated, as described above. Then, the agglomerations (also referred to as clumps, arches, or bridges) either cannot pass through inlet holes <b>108</b> or they cannot enter extraction inlet <b>116</b>, depending on the size of the agglomerations. Experience has shown that the most likely clogging point is extraction inlet <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">Exemplary Embodiments</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> schematically illustrates an exemplary system <b>200</b> for delivering an uninterrupted flow of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> to an image-forming device (not shown). System <b>200</b> employs a number of components identical to those discussed in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, such as assist tube <b>106</b>, extraction tube <b>112</b>, and vacuum source <b>114</b>. Those components are similar in structure and operation to those shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In addition, system <b>200</b> includes a clog detector <b>202</b> for identifying clogs.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In adapting the structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, however, it should be noted that particular care is exercised to design a structure that minimizes the possibility of clogs. For example, components are sized to maximize pellet flow. Solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> are generally between about 1 mm in 3 mm in diameter, most often about 2 mm, and system components are sized to accommodate those pellets. Thus, inlet holes <b>108</b> are generally larger than the individual pellets <b>104</b>, so that some agglomerates will pass through those holes. The diameter of assist tube <b>106</b>, and the size of the gap between assist tube <b>106</b> and extraction tube <b>112</b>, as well as the diameter of extraction inlet <b>116</b>, are all planned with a view to maximize pellet flow and minimize the possibility of clogging. For example, the inside diameter of associated fittings of extraction tube <b>112</b>, as well as associated fittings and flexible tubing, at a constant or increasing diameter, never decreasing. That measure minimizes or eliminates pinch points.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Clog detector <b>202</b> identifies clogging within extraction tube <b>112</b> by sensing pressure changes. Thus, input to clog detector <b>202</b> is a pressure line <b>205</b> connected to extraction tube <b>112</b> at some point above assist tube <b>106</b>, but upstream of vacuum source <b>114</b>. The output of clog detector <b>202</b> is some indication that a clog exists, which can be provided by any known means, such as an indicator light <b>203</b> or the automated means discussed below. Those of skill in the art will appreciate that a wide range of conventional and readily available devices can be employed to provide clog detector <b>202</b>. Primarily, the device must be able to sense changes in pressure and indicate that fact. Thus, suitable devices would include a pressure switch or a vacuum switch, all well within the knowledge of those in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Clog detector <b>202</b> operates by sensing the pressure spike that normally accompanies a blockage. During normal operation, vacuum pressure within extraction tube <b>112</b> remains relatively constant. Solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> flow smoothly into assist tube <b>106</b>, where they become entrained in airflow <b>120</b> and proceed through extraction tube <b>112</b>. If agglomerate forms near extraction inlet <b>116</b>, however, vacuum pressure within extraction tube <b>112</b> immediately spikes, in a manner directly analogous to blocking the entry nozzle of a home vacuum cleaner. Clog detector <b>202</b> senses that condition and communicates it to the operator by illuminating indicator light <b>203</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As will be appreciated by those in the art, clog detector <b>202</b> can be any device that responds to events that accompany a clog. As noted, a pressure sensor or vacuum switch performs these functions and are clear choices for this component. Devices that sense airflow would also suffice, given that a decreasing airflow occurs following a clog. The latter class of devices is generally more expensive than simple pressure sensors, but airflow monitors may be preferred in certain situations. Of the devices, now known or hereafter developed, as known to those in the art can be substituted as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Alternatives and variations of the disclosed structure will be apparent to those of skill in the art. On the macro scale, it will be recognized that the principles of the present disclosure apply generally to systems in which pelletized solids or particulates must be delivered from one point to another. Similarly, the material, construction, and sizing of disclosed components may be varied as desired to suit particular applications.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">System <b>200</b> improves upon the operation of the conventional device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> by providing a capability to identify clogs. By itself, however, clog detector <b>202</b> cannot remove the agglomerates clogging the system. To accomplish that result, an agitating structure is required. Clogs generally form in two places&#x2014;at extraction inlet <b>116</b> or in the vicinity of inlet holes <b>108</b>, and thus an effective agitating structure must be positioned to break up agglomerates in both areas. As disclosed below, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-6</figref> set out specific embodiments of agitating structures aimed at both locations.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an agitating structure <b>300</b> designed to break up agglomerations near extraction inlet <b>116</b>. This embodiment adds to the structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> by providing a spring-loaded agitating mechanism <b>312</b> mounted on extraction tube <b>112</b> and operated by an actuator <b>304</b>. In terms of operation through the point of detecting a clog interrupting flow within extraction tube <b>112</b>, components illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, operate generally identically to system <b>200</b>, as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the embodiments described above, both assist tube <b>106</b> and extraction tube <b>112</b> were generally stationary within container <b>102</b>. Here, however, extraction tube <b>112</b> is mounted on spring mechanism <b>312</b>, and an upstream tube <b>313</b> extends from spring mechanism <b>312</b> to vacuum source <b>114</b> (not shown). Spring mechanism <b>312</b> is widely known in the art, consisting of a lower portion attached to extraction tube <b>112</b> and an upper portion attached to upstream tube <b>313</b>. The lower and upper portions of spring mechanism <b>312</b> can slide longitudinally with respect to each other, lengthening or shortening the distance between them. A coil spring <b>302</b> separates the two portions, biasing them in a relatively open position. By adding spring mechanism <b>312</b>, extraction tube <b>112</b> can move vertically within assist tube <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Movement of spring mechanism <b>312</b> is accomplished by actuator <b>304</b>, operating through a linkage <b>306</b>. Actuator <b>304</b> applies force to the upper portion of spring mechanism <b>312</b> to move it downward, together with extraction tube <b>112</b>, and it releases that pressure to allow coil spring <b>302</b> to return extraction tube <b>112</b> to its starting position. Those of skill in the art will recognize a number of well-known devices can embody actuator <b>304</b>. One embodiment may employ a stepper motor for this purpose, for example. Likewise, linkage <b>306</b> can employ a suitable mechanical construction to convert rotary output of actuator <b>304</b> to a reciprocal vertical motion. An embodiment for accomplishing that result may employ a cam connected to a pivoted arm to accomplish that result. Numerous variations on these particular components will be apparent to those in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Agitating structure <b>300</b> operates in a generally automatic manner, requiring notification from clog detector <b>202</b> to actuator <b>304</b> that agitation is required. That result can be accomplished through a number of means, most readily by a signal connection <b>305</b>. As desired for various applications, clog detector <b>202</b> may directly provide an operating signal to actuator <b>304</b>, or suitable control means may be provided. Those devices lie within the skill of those in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Agitating structure <b>300</b> begins operation with the detection of a clog, typically an agglomeration <b>315</b> lodged at extraction inlet <b>116</b>. As discussed above, that situation produces a pressure spike within extraction tube <b>112</b> and upstream tube <b>313</b>, triggering a detection event at clog detector <b>202</b>. Here, clog detector <b>202</b> reacts to the detection event by signaling actuator <b>304</b> via signal connection <b>305</b>. In turn, actuator <b>304</b> operates through linkage <b>306</b> to apply a downward force to the upper portion of spring mechanism <b>312</b>, driving extraction tube <b>112</b> toward closed end <b>106</b><i>b</i>. That action results in extraction tube <b>112</b> pressing against agglomeration <b>315</b>, breaking it into individual solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>. Continued operation of actuator <b>304</b> produces a release of pressure on the upper portion of spring mechanism <b>312</b>, so that the restoring force of coil spring <b>302</b> returns that mechanism to its fully open position, retracting extraction tube <b>112</b> as well. In the illustrated embodiment, clog detector <b>202</b> continues to signal actuator <b>304</b> as long as a clog remains, and during that time, actuator <b>304</b> and linkage <b>306</b> impart a reciprocal vertical motion to spring mechanism <b>312</b>. When the clog is cleared, clog detector <b>202</b> stops signaling and actuator <b>304</b> ceases operation.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">It should be clear to those in the art that a number of variations and alternative embodiments can be introduced into agitating structure <b>300</b> to cope with a varied assortment of particular situations. For example, depending upon the exact consistency of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>, the distance between the low cycle point of extraction tube <b>112</b> and closed end <b>106</b><i>b </i>can be varied so that extraction tube <b>112</b> impresses more or less pressure on agglomeration <b>315</b>. Similarly, both the speed and operating force applied by actuator <b>304</b> can be varied as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As shown, agitating structure <b>300</b> operates automatically, but manual operation can be provided if desired. For a manual system, a suitable device for signaling an operator, such as indicator light <b>203</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, would replace signal connection <b>305</b>. For a full manual operation, a simple handle could substitute for actuator <b>304</b> and linkage <b>306</b>, allowing the operator to move spring mechanism <b>312</b> up and down as desired. For a semi-manual operation, actuator <b>304</b> and linkage <b>306</b> could remain in position, operated by a simple on-off switch or button (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts an agitating structure <b>400</b> that employs a brush <b>402</b> to break up clumps close to inlet holes <b>108</b>. As with previous embodiments, agitating structure <b>400</b> builds on previous embodiments, incorporating clog detector <b>202</b>, an actuator <b>404</b>, and extraction tube <b>112</b>. Here, clog detector <b>202</b> operates exactly as discussed above, and actuator <b>404</b> responds to clog indications by signaling through a line <b>405</b>. Here, however, extraction tube <b>112</b> is adapted for circular motion relative to an upstream tube <b>413</b> through the action of a rotating fitting <b>412</b>, which permits the free rotation of extraction tube <b>112</b>. As shown, actuator <b>404</b>, through a linkage <b>406</b>, drives extraction tube <b>112</b>. As desired, actuator <b>404</b> and linkage <b>406</b> can be configured to provide a continuous or reciprocal rotating movement.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Agitating structure <b>400</b> operates to clear clogs through the actions of brush <b>402</b> mounted at the tip of extraction tube <b>112</b>, near extraction inlet <b>116</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, brush <b>402</b> consists of a number of bristles extending generally perpendicular to extraction tube <b>112</b>, of sufficient length to engage the inner sidewalls of assist tube <b>106</b>. Brush <b>402</b> lies generally level with inlet holes <b>108</b>, so that the bristles engage inlet holes <b>108</b>. Only one set of bristles appears in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, but a designer could provide as many sets of bristles as desired. It has been found that three or four sets of bristles seem to provide an optimal solution. Additionally, it appears desirable to size bristle length slightly longer than the exact distance from extraction tube <b>112</b> to assist tube <b>106</b> inner sidewall, so that bristles extend at least slightly into inlet holes <b>108</b>. That sizing allows the bristles to clear inlet holes <b>108</b> of any agglomerations while also providing for extended bristle life. Brush <b>402</b> may be constructed of any suitable material, with bristles formed of a resilient material having sufficient stiffness to engage and break up agglomerations. Nylon, plastics, and similar materials have been found effective materials from which to construct brush <b>402</b>. Likewise, mounting brush <b>402</b> on extraction tube <b>112</b> lies well within the skill of the art.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Agitating structure <b>400</b> operates in a manner similar to structures discussed above. Upon clog identification, clog detector <b>202</b> signals actuator <b>404</b> via line <b>405</b> to initiate agitation of pellet agglomerations blocking inlet holes <b>108</b>. Actuator <b>404</b> , acting through linkage <b>406</b>, starts rotation of extraction tube <b>112</b>, which in turn causes brush <b>402</b> to rotate within assist tube <b>106</b>. Brush <b>402</b> wipes the inner surface of assist tube <b>106</b> including inlet holes <b>108</b>, breaking any pellet agglomerations blocking inlet holes <b>108</b>. It should be understood that at any instant during the circular motion, sets of bristles of brush <b>402</b> may only block one inlet hole, leaving remaining holes open. Alternatively, if brush <b>402</b> is substantially narrower than the width of inlet holes <b>108</b>, all four inlet holes may be open at any instant to receive stored pellets. Actuator <b>404</b> may rotate extraction tube <b>112</b> continuously, at a predetermined time interval, or on agglomerate identification. In addition, actuator <b>404</b> and linkage <b>406</b> may be configured to provide reciprocal rotary movement, restricted in extent so that the bristles of brush <b>402</b> remain inserted into inlet holes <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The embodiments discussed in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> illustrate agitating structures that remove obstructions near extraction inlet <b>116</b> and adjacent to inlet holes <b>108</b>, respectively. The present disclosure may also remove obstructions simultaneously from both locations, by combining the reciprocal vertical movement of spring mechanism <b>312</b> and the rotation of brush <b>402</b>, in an embodiment. In such an embodiment, an actuator may act through appropriate linkages to initiate vertical and rotary motion simultaneously. Alternatively, clog detector <b>202</b> may visually indicate the presence of a clog, allowing an operator to manually rotate or vertically move extraction tube <b>112</b>, either continuously or periodically. These and other modifications of agitating structure <b>400</b> will be apparent to those in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A</figref>, <b>5</b>B, and <b>5</b>C illustrate an alternative embodiment, in which an agitating structure <b>500</b> employs a set of wires <b>502</b> and an actuator <b>503</b> for breaking up agglomerations blocking inlet holes <b>108</b>. Agitating structure <b>500</b> operates in a manner similar to that discussed previously, with clog detector <b>202</b> detecting and signaling a pressure spike within extractor tube <b>112</b> and an upstream tube <b>513</b>. Likewise, actuator <b>503</b> receives the clog detection signal through a line <b>507</b>. Similarly, extraction tube <b>112</b> is adapted for rotary motion by connecting it to a rotating fitting <b>512</b>. Actuator <b>503</b> acts through a linkage <b>509</b> to drive extraction tube <b>112</b> in continuous or reciprocal rotary motion.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Agitating structure <b>500</b> employs a set of wires to break up agglomerations near inlet holes <b>108</b> and extraction inlet <b>116</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, wires <b>502</b> are mounted at the bottom of extraction tube <b>112</b> and extend perpendicularly outward for a distance sufficient to protrude through inlet holes <b>108</b>. The illustrated embodiment provides one wire for each inlet hole; fewer wires may be provided, but such a design would forgo clog clearance where no wire was present. In general, wires <b>502</b> are sufficiently thin to avoid restricting pellet flow through inlet holes <b>108</b>. Further, wires <b>502</b> are sufficiently resilient to bend without deforming, preventing damage if actuator <b>503</b> over rotates extraction tube <b>112</b> so that individual wires may contact with the end of inlet holes <b>108</b>. In one embodiment of the wires, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, wires <b>502</b> are formed from a single stamped metal part, which employs a material sufficiently rigid to break up the agglomerates.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">It can be noted from inspection of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> that inlet holes <b>108</b> provided in agitating structure <b>500</b> may be formed as elongated slots, permitting wires <b>502</b> to move in reciprocal rotation within the openings. Additionally, inlet holes <b>108</b> may be provided with sufficient vertical dimension that extraction tube <b>112</b> can move in vertical reciprocal motion, as discussed in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Wires <b>502</b> can be attached to extraction tube <b>112</b> using a number of conventional devices, such as a span fit attachment, a friction joint, or other suitable attachment means. For a span fit attachment, wires <b>502</b> are connected to a ring-shaped structure <b>505</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, whose diameter is sized to slide over and span extraction tube <b>112</b>. In another implementation, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, wires <b>502</b> may be connected to extraction tube <b>112</b> using a spring (not shown) or a wave washer <b>506</b> that provides a friction fit. Wires <b>502</b> and wave washer <b>506</b> may be retained at a desired position using a set of clamp rings <b>504</b> surrounding the wire attachment. Moreover, torque produced by actuator <b>503</b> during the activation of extraction tube <b>112</b> may be limited by wave washer <b>506</b>, avoiding wire breakage.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The extent of both vertical and rotary movement provided by actuator <b>503</b> and linkage <b>509</b> is carefully regulated in this embodiment to avoid damaging wires <b>502</b>. Those in the art will understand suitable methods for controlling actuator <b>503</b> to accomplish that result. Alternatively, mechanisms such as wave washer <b>506</b>, discussed above, may be employed to prevent damage to wires <b>502</b> in the event of over rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Operation of agitating structure <b>500</b> proceeds in a fashion similar to that previously discussed. Upon identifying a clog, clog detector <b>202</b> signals actuator <b>503</b> via line <b>507</b> to initiate motion of extraction tube <b>112</b>. Based on the exact type and extent of motion desired, as reflected in configuration of the embodiment, actuator <b>503</b> and linkage <b>509</b> cooperate to produce a desired degree and tempo of reciprocal rotary or vertical motion, or a combination of the two. This motion is restricted to an extent that precludes wires <b>502</b> from making contact with the sides of inlet holes <b>108</b>. The reciprocating motion causes wires <b>502</b> to move across inlet holes <b>108</b>, breaking up agglomerations and clearing any flow barriers.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6A</figref>, <b>6</b>B, and <b>6</b>C illustrate an agitating structure <b>600</b>, an embodiment that adds a pair of substantially perpendicular wires <b>602</b> to extraction tube <b>112</b>. Here, contrary to previous embodiments, extraction tube <b>112</b> remains stationary while assist tube <b>106</b> rotates. Agitating structure <b>600</b> once clog detector <b>202</b> detects and signals a pressure spike within extractor tube <b>112</b> and an upstream tube <b>613</b>. Rotation is accomplished by the action of an actuator <b>601</b>, acting through a linkage <b>609</b> to rotate assist tube <b>106</b> in either reciprocal or continuous movement.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Agitating structure <b>600</b> breaks up agglomerations in the vicinity of inlet holes <b>108</b> through the action of a set of wires <b>602</b>. As shown, the two wires <b>602</b> are mounted at the bottom of extraction tube <b>112</b> and extend outward through inlet holes <b>108</b>. The two wires <b>602</b> meet at a crossover point <b>606</b>, with no rigid connection between the two. In general, wires <b>602</b> are substantially thin wires such that they do not restrict the flow of pellets <b>104</b> from inlet holes <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">To prevent wires <b>602</b> from slipping out of assist tube <b>106</b>, a retention mechanism may be employed. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, each wire <b>602</b> includes a retention mechanism in the form of a kink <b>604</b> formed in each wire just outside inlet holes <b>108</b>. Each kink is angled such that kinks <b>604</b> remains outside assist tube <b>106</b>, preventing the wires from slipping out of assist tube <b>106</b>. In addition, wires <b>602</b> are sized to permit a smooth flow of pellets <b>104</b> through inlet holes <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Agitating structure <b>600</b> operates in a manner similar to the embodiments previously discussed. Once a clog is identified, clog detector <b>202</b> directs actuator <b>601</b>, through a signal line <b>605</b>, to initiate rotation of assist tube <b>106</b>. Rotation proceeds through the action of actuator <b>601</b> through linkage <b>609</b>, which reciprocally rotates assist tube <b>106</b> about a pivot point <b>603</b>. That movement causes wires <b>602</b> to move back and forth within inlet holes <b>108</b>, breaking up any agglomerations near inlet holes <b>108</b>. Breaking up clogs allows smooth passage of pellets <b>104</b> entering through inlet holes <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref> illustrates an alternative of the retention mechanism, in which the pair of wires <b>602</b> are connected at crossover point <b>606</b>. Crossover point <b>606</b> may substantially coincide with the longitudinal axis and center of extraction tube <b>112</b>, preventing wires <b>602</b> from slipping out of assist tube <b>106</b> through inlet holes <b>108</b>. As already discussed, the ends of wires <b>602</b> extend out from assist tube <b>106</b> through inlet holes <b>108</b>. Wires <b>602</b> may be manufactured from stainless steel with a thickness sufficient to provide a stirring action in the midst of the pellets. Other suitable materials may be employed without departing from the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In the illustrated embodiments of system <b>200</b>, the width of inlet holes <b>108</b> depends on the size of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>, which is typically about 2 mm. In general, inlet holes <b>108</b> are structured with a clearance greater than the size of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> in order to allow transportation of pellets <b>104</b>. Thus, the slots of the illustrated embodiment have a width of about 8 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As can be seen, the agitating structures or systems described in various embodiments (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-6</figref>) and implementations are arranged to encounter minimal resistance from solid-ink pellets <b>104</b>, minimizing torque requirements from the respective actuators. Alternatively, the various agitating structures may include other suitable structural geometries, such as blades, sheet metal, or pins, that may dislodge solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> with minimum torque required.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The geometry and the movement of the agitating structures may depend on the properties of the particular solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> employed in a given implementation. Relevant parameters can include bulk density, size range, melting point, static charge, flowability and so on. Further, assist tube <b>106</b> and extraction tube <b>112</b> can be tailored to these properties; for example, the diameter of extraction tube <b>112</b> may be based on the size range of solid-ink pellets <b>104</b> being extracted.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It will be apparent to those of skill in the art that a number of structural variations can be introduced to agitate and break up agglomerations. For example, the actuator (described in various embodiments) may be operatively coupled to the agitating structure (such as wires, brushes, or the like) but not to extraction tube <b>112</b>, so that the actuator only rotates the agitating structure. Alternatively, multiple agitating structures may be introduced in container <b>102</b>, all driven by an actuator. Further, the agitating structure may only include a brush or wires to break up pellet agglomerations.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In addition, actuators <b>304</b>, <b>404</b>, and <b>503</b> are disclosed as being individually connected to extraction tube <b>112</b>; it should be apparent, however, that these actuators may be a part of the image-forming device or container <b>102</b> and may be detachably connected to extraction tube <b>112</b>. The actuators may include a drive motor or an air cylinder. The process of introducing vertical and/or rotary movement in a structure, such as extraction tube <b>112</b>, using an actuator is known to those skilled in the art and is not explained in detail. In the illustrated embodiments, the actuators may substantially move the actuator arm about the longitudinal axis and/or about the circumference of extraction tube <b>112</b>, breaking up the flow barriers with minimum torque. A torque value of 5 N-m generated by the actuators may be sufficient to break up the pellet agglomerations.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Additionally, those in the art will understand that embodiments of the present disclosure will be suitable for performing agitation and clog detection functions in implementations that deal with any manner of pelletized, pellet-like, or particulate matter. The particular details of clog detection and mitigation will differ for each environment, but those of skill in the art will understand the specific variations required in each situation.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart of an exemplary method <b>700</b> for detecting clogging and breaking pellet agglomerations in an image-forming device. The process begins when vacuum source <b>114</b> applies a suction force to extraction tube <b>112</b>. That suction induces an airflow <b>120</b> flowing from inlet holes <b>108</b> of assist tube <b>106</b>, into extraction tube <b>112</b>, and on to vacuum source <b>114</b>. In the vicinity of the tip of extraction tube <b>112</b>, extraction inlet <b>116</b>, airflow <b>120</b> passes by inlet holes <b>108</b>, where the low pressure within assist tube <b>106</b> impels pellets <b>104</b> through inlet holes <b>108</b>, where they become entrained in airflow <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Pellets <b>104</b> in the vicinity of inlet holes <b>108</b> may have agglomerated into clumps or agglomerations, owing to the processes discussed above. Where, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, agglomeration <b>315</b> exceeds the size of the opening end of extraction tube <b>112</b>, near extraction inlet <b>116</b>, the agglomeration will lodge in the opening, producing a clog. That blockage impedes or stops airflow, producing an immediate pressure spike within extraction tube <b>112</b>. Pressure spikes are quickly detected by clog detector <b>202</b>, as shown in step <b>704</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">After detecting a clog, the system proceeds to step <b>706</b>, where it begins to employ an agitating structure to break up the agglomerations. Specific examples of agitating structures are described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-6</figref>. Various combinations of such structures are useful for breaking agglomerates.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">As explained above, a variety of devices can embody the processes of detecting clogs and mitigating their effects. Moreover, the specific steps employed in such processes may vary in order of timing, or exact manner of implementation. Those of skill in the art will understand effective techniques adapted to particular situations.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">It should be noted that the description below does not set out specific details of manufacture or design of the various components. Those of skill in the art are familiar with such details, and unless departures from those techniques are set out, techniques, designs and materials known in the art should be employed. Those in the art are capable of choosing suitable manufacturing and design details.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The terminology used herein describes particular embodiments only; considerable variation is anticipated in implementation. It will be appreciated that several of the disclosed and other features and functions, or alternatives thereof, may be desirably combined into many other different systems or applications. Various presently unforeseen or unanticipated alternatives, modifications, variations, or improvements therein may be subsequently made by those skilled in the art which are also intended to be encompassed by the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube inserted into the container, the extraction tube being in fluid communication with a vacuum source;
<claim-text>mounted for reciprocal vertical motion within the container;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and further including
<claim-text>a spring mechanism mounted on the extraction tube to bias the extraction tube at the top end in the extraction tube's range of vertical motion; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extraction inlet, sized for receiving the pellets;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clog detector connected to the extraction tube for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, responsive to the clog detector, for breaking up pellet agglomerations.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>an actuator, operatively connected to the clog detector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart reciprocal vertical force on the spring mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube inserted into, and mounted for rotary motion within, the container, the extraction tube being in fluid communication with a vacuum source and the extraction tube further including an extraction inlet, sized for receiving the pellets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clog detector connected to the extraction tube for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assist tube encompassing the extraction tube, the assist tube having inlet holes formed therein, sized for receiving pellets and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, responsive to the clog detector, for breaking up pellet agglomerations and wherein the agitating structure includes a brush perpendicularly mounted on the extraction tube near the extraction inlet, the brush including one or more sets of bristles extending at least between the extraction tube and the inner wall of the assist tube, the bristles being positioned to extend into the inlet holes;
<claim-text>the extraction tube is mounted for rotary motion within the container; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the agitating structure includes a brush perpendicularly mounted on the extraction tube near the extraction inlet, the brush including one or more sets of bristles extending at least between the extraction tube and the inner wall of the assist tube, the bristles being positioned to extend into the inlet holes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further including
<claim-text>an actuator, operatively connected to the clog detector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart rotary motion to the extraction tube.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the imparted rotary motion is reciprocal and the extraction tube is configured to rotate an angular distance sufficient to cause the brush to traverse the inlet holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube inserted into, and mounted for rotary motion within, the container, the extraction tube being in fluid communication with a vacuum source and the extraction tube further including an extraction inlet, sized for receiving the pellets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clog detector connected to the extraction tube for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assist tube encompassing the extraction tube, the assist tube having inlet holes formed therein, sized for receiving pellets and
<claim-text>an agitating structure, responsive to the clog detector, for breaking up pellet agglomerations and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the agitating structure includes a plurality of wires mounted on the extraction tube and extending perpendicularly outward for a distance sufficient to protrude through the inlet holes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further including
<claim-text>an actuator, operatively connected to the clog detector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart rotary motion to the extraction tube.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the imparted rotary motion is reciprocal and is configured to rotate an angular distance sufficient to cause each wire to traverse an inlet hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube inserted into the container, the extraction tube being in fluid communication with a vacuum source and the extraction tube further including an extraction inlet, sized for receiving the pellets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clog detector connected to the extraction tube for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, responsive to the clog detector, for breaking up pellet agglomerations;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the agitating structure includes a plurality of perpendicular wires placed along the diametrically opposite inlet holes, wires having projections on either end such that the projections extend outward from the inlet holes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube mounted for reciprocal vertical motion within the container and in fluid communication with a vacuum source and the extraction tube, wherein the extraction tube further includes
<claim-text>an extraction inlet, sized for receiving pellets; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a spring mechanism mounted on the extraction tube to bias the extraction tube at the top end in the extraction tube's range of vertical motion;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, for breaking up pellet agglomerations, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assist tube encompassing the extraction tube, the assist tube having inlet holes formed therein, sized for receiving pellets.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further including
<claim-text>an actuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart reciprocal vertical force on the spring mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube mounted for rotary motion within the container and in fluid communication with a vacuum source, wherein the extraction tube further includes
<claim-text>an extraction inlet, sized for receiving pellets;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, for breaking up pellet agglomerations, the agitating structure including a brush perpendicularly mounted on the extraction tube near the extraction inlet, the brush including one or more sets of bristles extending at least between the extraction tube and the inner wall of the assist tube, the bristles being positioned to extend into the inlet holes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assist tube encompassing the extraction tube, the assist tube having inlet holes formed therein, sized for receiving pellets.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further including
<claim-text>an actuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart rotary motion to the extraction tube.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the imparted rotary motion is reciprocal and the extraction tube is configured to rotate an angular distance sufficient to cause the brush to traverse the inlet holes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube, mounted for rotary within the container and in fluid communication with a vacuum source, the extraction tube further including an extraction inlet, sized for receiving pellets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, for breaking up pellet agglomerations the agitating structure including a plurality of wires mounted on the extraction tube and extending perpendicularly outward for a distance sufficient to protrude through the inlet holes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an assist tube encompassing the extraction tube, the assist tube having inlet holes formed therein, sized for receiving pellets.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further including
<claim-text>an actuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a linkage, operatively joining the actuator and the spring mechanism,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the actuator and the linkage are configured to impart rotary motion to the extraction tube.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the imparted rotary motion is reciprocal and the extraction tube is configured to rotate an angular distance sufficient to cause each wire to traverse an inlet hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. An apparatus for maintaining flowability of solid-ink pellets during suction-induced flow from a container to an image-forming device, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an extraction tube inserted into the container, the extraction tube being in fluid communication with a vacuum source and the extraction tube further including an extraction inlet, sized for receiving the pellets;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clog detector connected to the extraction tube for sensing changes in vacuum level within the extraction tube to identify clogging; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitating structure, responsive to the clog detector, for breaking up pellet agglomerations;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the agitating structure includes a plurality of perpendicular wires placed along the diametrically opposite inlet holes, wires having projections on either end such that the projections extend outward from the inlet holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
