<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624273-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624273</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13118575</doc-number>
<date>20110531</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>97144960 A</doc-number>
<date>20081120</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>234</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>205</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 89</main-classification>
<further-classification>257E33002</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e73">Circuit structure of package carrier and multi-chip package</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4600970</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bauer</name>
<date>19860700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0006734</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Harun et al.</name>
<date>20050100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0220200</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0257341</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0001908</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wen et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0191222</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20080800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>WO 2007055457</doc-number>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 2007055457</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 89</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E27121</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257E33002</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12621529</doc-number>
<date>20091119</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8071989</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13118575</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110254024</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111020</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chao</last-name>
<first-name>Tzu-Hao</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chao</last-name>
<first-name>Tzu-Hao</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Han IP Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Everlight Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dickey</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas L</first-name>
<department>2826</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A multi-chip package comprises a plurality of chip pads and a plurality of LED chips. The chip pads are arranged in an M&#xd7;N array, M and N each a positive integer greater than 1. A peripheral area of each chip pad comprises a respective first bonding pad, a respective second bonding pad, and a respective third bonding pad arranged in sequence in a clockwise direction. A first orientation of the respective first to third bonding pads in a first row of the N rows differs from a second orientation of the respective first to third bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees. Each of the LED chips is disposed on a respective one of the chip pads and electrically connected to two of the respective first to third bonding pads on a same side of the respective LED chip.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="113.28mm" wi="146.56mm" file="US08624273-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="165.61mm" wi="120.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624273-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="195.75mm" wi="111.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624273-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="168.74mm" wi="112.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624273-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED PATENT APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/621,529, filed Nov. 19, 2009, which claims the priority benefit of Taiwan Patent Application Number 097144960, filed Nov. 20, 2008, which applications are herein incorporated in their entirety by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present disclosure relates to a circuit structure of a package carrier and a multi-chip package having the circuit structure, and more particularly, to a circuit structure suitable for carrying a plurality of wire bonding light emitting diode (LED) chips and a multi-chip package having the circuit structure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The advanced countries in the world are all currently devoting time and effort to the development of opto-electronic material industry. The LED has longevity and low power consumption and thus application thereof is becoming popular. The LED can be used in applications such as large electronic billboard, traffic lights, turn signals of vehicles, and illumination. The current LED industry is advancing toward the goal of high brightness and low light loss so that the LED is able to replace conventional illumination means.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, to increase the brightness of the LED and to decrease the light loss thereof, the package method of the LED is a key factor influencing the brightness, uniformity of illumination, and element lifespan of the LED in addition to improving the structure of the LED itself. In the conventional technology, a plurality of LED chips is packaged on a same substrate by means of a multi-chip packaging method to form a multi-chip package. Therefore, the multi-chip package including a plurality of LED chips has more diversified brightness and color. The plurality of LED chips in the multi-chip package may be electrically connected in parallel, in series, or in series-parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the conventional technology, a plurality of chip pads in the multi-chip package are arranged in arrays and a plurality of bonding pads respectively connected to different electrodes are disposed in a peripheral area of each of the LED chips. The orientations of the bonding pads in the peripheral area of each chip pad are the same. Each of the LED chips is disposed on each of the chip pads and is respectively electrically connected to the different bonding pads in the peripheral area of each of the chip pads through a first conductive line and a second conductive line so that the LED chips are connected to each other in parallel, in series, or in series-parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">When the LED chips in the multi-chip package are electrically connected in series or in series-parallel, one of the LED chips may be respectively electrically connected to a first bonding pad and a second bonding pad in the peripheral area of the LED chip through the first conductive line and the second conductive line. Another LED chip may be respectively electrically connected to the second bonding pad and a third bonding pad in the peripheral area of the LED chip through the first conductive line and the second conductive line. Therefore, the wire bonding directions of the mentioned two LED chips are different.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">However, in the manufacturing process of wire bonding, changing the wire bonding direction decreases the speed and yield of wire bonding and thereby causes low productivity and high costs. Hence, how to enable LED chips to be electrically connected in series or in series-parallel without changing wire bonding direction is currently an issue to be resolved.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present disclosure provides a circuit structure of a package carrier in which wire bonding direction does not need to be changed in a subsequent wire bonding process.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present disclosure further provides a multi-chip package for which wire bonding direction does not need to be changed in the manufacturing process so that the speed and yield of the wire bonding process are increased.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one aspect, a circuit structure of a package carrier that carries a plurality of wire bonding LED chips is provided. The circuit structure may comprise a plurality of chip pads, and a first electrode, a second electrode, and a third electrode. The chip pads may be arranged in an array of M columns and N rows to dispose the LED chips, M and N each being a positive integer greater than 1. For each of the chip pads, the circuit structure may also comprise a respective first bonding pad, a respective second bonding pad, and a respective third bonding pad that are electrically insulated from each other and sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the respective chip pad. A first orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a first row of the N rows may differ from a second orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees. The first electrode may comprise a plurality of first branch lines connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows. The second electrode may comprise a plurality of second branch lines connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows. The third electrode may comprise a plurality of third branch lines connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one embodiment, the second orientation may differ from the first orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise. Additionally, a third orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a third row of the N rows may differ from the second orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise, the second row being between the first row and the third row.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In one embodiment, the first electrode may have a first main body portion, the second electrode may have a second main body portion, and the third electrode may have a third main body portion. The first, second, and third main body portions may be sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the array of the chip pads.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one embodiment, the first main body portion may be connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows via the first branch lines.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one embodiment, the second main body portion may be connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows via the second branch lines.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one embodiment, the third main body portion may be connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows via the third branch lines.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one embodiment, the first branch lines and the second branch lines may be alternately arranged.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one embodiment, for each of the chip pads, the circuit structure may further comprise a respective fourth bonding pad that is electrically insulated from the respective first, second, and third bonding pads. A fourth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a first row of the N rows may differ from a fifth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees. The circuit structure may additionally comprise a fourth electrode that comprises a plurality of fourth branch lines connected to the respective M fourth bonding pads in each of the N rows.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In another aspect, a multi-chip package may comprise a plurality of chip pads and a plurality of LED chips. The plurality of chip pads may be arranged in an M&#xd7;N array, M and N each being a positive integer greater than 1. A peripheral area of each of the chip pads may comprise a respective first bonding pad, a respective second bonding pad, and a respective third bonding pad arranged in sequence in a clockwise direction. A first orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a first row of the N rows may differ from a second orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees. Each LED chip may be disposed on a respective one of the chip pads and electrically connected to two of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads on a same side of the respective LED chip.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one embodiment, the multi-chip package may further comprise a first electrode, a second electrode, and a third electrode. The first electrode may comprise a plurality of first branch lines connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows. The second electrode may comprise a plurality of second branch lines connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows. The third electrode may comprise a plurality of third branch lines connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows. The first electrode may have a first main body portion, the second electrode may have a second main body portion, and the third electrode may have a third main body portion. The first, second, and third main body portions may be sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the array of the chip pads.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, the multi-chip package may further comprise a substrate on which the chip pads are disposed. The substrate may include an insulation layer. The first electrode, the second electrode, and the first to fourth bonding pads may be disposed on the insulation layer. The third electrode may be disposed under the insulation layer and may pass through the insulation layer to connect to the third bonding pad.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Additionally, the multi-chip package may comprise a plurality of first conductive lines and a plurality of second conductive lines. Each of the first conductive lines and each of the second conductive lines may be electrically connected to a respective one of the LED chips and two of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads on a same side of the respective one of the LED chips. The first conductive lines in each pair and the second conductive lines in each pair may be respectively electrically connected to the respective one of the LED chips and two of the bonding pads on a same side of each LED chip.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Additionally, the multi-chip package may further comprise a coating layer disposed on the insulation layer and covering the first, second, and third bonding pads. The coating layer may have a plurality of openings that expose the LED chips and portions of the first, second, and third bonding pads in the peripheral area of each LED chip. The portions of the first, second, and third bonding pads may be adjacent to each LED chip. The coating layer may comprise resin.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the second orientation may differ from the first orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise. A third orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a third row of the N rows may differ from the second orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise, where the second row is between the first row and the third row.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In one embodiment, the multi-chip package may further comprise a fourth electrode that comprises a plurality of fourth branch lines connected to the respective M fourth bonding pads in each of the N rows. Additionally, the peripheral area of each of the chip pads may further comprise a respective fourth bonding pad that is electrically insulated from the respective first, second, and third bonding pads. A fourth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a first row of the N rows may differ from a fifth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In light of the above illustration, the orientations of each of the first to third bonding pads in the Sth row are different from the orientations of each of the first to third bonding pads in the (S&#x2212;1)th row by a quadrant (90 degrees). Therefore, the first conductive line and the second conductive line may respectively be electrically connected to two bonding pads on a same side of each LED chip. As such, in the present disclosure, the direction of wire bonding does not need to be changed when fabricating the first and second conductive lines.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In order to make the above and other objects, features and advantages of the present disclosure more comprehensible, several embodiments accompanied with figures are described in detail below.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The accompanying drawings are included to provide a further understanding of the disclosure, and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification. The drawings illustrate embodiments of the disclosure and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a circuit structure of a package carrier according to one embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is an exploded view illustrating the circuit structure of the package carrier of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a multi-chip package according to one embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a circuit structure of a package carrier according to one embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is an exploded view illustrating the circuit structure of the package carrier of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> simultaneously, a circuit structure <b>100</b> of a package carrier S of the present embodiment is suitable for carrying a plurality of wire bonding LED chips (not shown). The circuit structure <b>100</b> includes a plurality of chip pads C, a first bonding pad P<b>1</b>, a second bonding pad P<b>2</b>, a third bonding pad P<b>3</b>, a fourth bonding pad P<b>4</b>, a first electrode <b>110</b>, a second electrode <b>120</b>, a third electrode <b>130</b>, and a fourth electrode <b>140</b>. The chip pads C are arranged in an M&#xd7;N array for disposing the LED chips, the M and N are positive integers greater than 1. For convenience of illustration, a 3&#xd7;3 array formed by nine chip pads C is used for the purpose of illustration in the present embodiment, which, however, is not intended to limit the number of chip pads C and the values of M and N of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The first bonding pad P<b>1</b>, the second bonding pad P<b>2</b>, the third bonding pad P<b>3</b>, and the fourth bonding pad P<b>4</b> are sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of each chip pad C. Orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads in the Sth row are different respectively from the first to fourth bonding pads in the (S&#x2212;1)th and the (S+1)th row by a quadrant (90 degrees), wherein S is a positive integer in the range of 2&#x2dc;N. In the present embodiment, the orientation of each bonding pad P is, for example, the orientation of each bonding pad P in relation to a center of the chip pad C corresponding to the bonding pad P.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the present embodiment, when S is 2, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row are different respectively from the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S&#x2212;1)th row by a quadrant (90 degrees). For example, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row are different respectively from the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S&#x2212;1)th row by 90 degrees in the counterclockwise direction. The orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S+1)th row are different respectively from the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the S row by 90 degrees in the counterclockwise direction. In other words, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S&#x2212;1)th row rotated by 90 degrees in the counterclockwise direction are equal to the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row. The orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row rotated by 90 degrees in the counterclockwise direction are equal to the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S+1)th row. Certainly, in other embodiments, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row and the (S+1)th row may be different respectively from the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S&#x2212;1)th row and the Sth row by 90 degrees in the clockwise direction.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> again, in order for the M first bonding pads P<b>1</b> in the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows to connect to the first electrode <b>110</b>, the first electrode <b>110</b> may have a plurality of first branch lines <b>112</b> through which the first electrode <b>110</b> is respectively connected to the M first bonding pads P<b>1</b> in the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. Similarly, the second electrode <b>120</b> has a plurality of second branch lines <b>122</b> through which the second electrode <b>120</b> is respectively connected to the M second bonding pads P<b>2</b> in the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. The third electrode <b>130</b> has a plurality of third branch lines <b>132</b> through which the third electrode <b>130</b> is respectively connected to the M third bonding pads P<b>3</b> in the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. The fourth electrode <b>140</b> has a plurality of fourth branch lines <b>142</b> through which the fourth electrode <b>140</b> is respectively connected to the M fourth bonding pads P<b>4</b> in the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In addition, in the present embodiment, the first electrode <b>110</b> has a first main body portion <b>114</b>, the second electrode <b>120</b> has a second main body portion <b>124</b>, the third electrode <b>130</b> has a third main body portion <b>134</b>, and the fourth electrode <b>140</b> has a fourth main body portion <b>144</b>. Moreover, the first main body portion <b>114</b>, the second main body portion <b>124</b>, the third main body portion <b>134</b>, and the fourth main body portion <b>144</b> are, for example, sequentially arranged in a clockwise direction in the peripheral area of the M&#xd7;N array formed by the plurality of chip pads C.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In one embodiment of the present disclosure, the first branch lines <b>112</b> may extend from the first main body portion <b>114</b> to the right and are connected sequentially to the M first bonding pads P<b>1</b> of the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. In one embodiment of the present disclosure, the second branch lines <b>122</b> may extend from the second main body portion <b>124</b> to the left and are connected sequentially to the M second bonding pads P<b>2</b> of the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. From the above illustration, the first branch lines <b>112</b> and the second branch lines <b>122</b> are alternately arranged but are not connected.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In one embodiment of the present disclosure, the third branch lines <b>132</b> may extend from the third main body portion <b>134</b> to the left and are connected sequentially to the M third bonding pads P<b>3</b> of the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. The fourth branch lines <b>142</b> may extend from the fourth main body portion <b>144</b> to the right and are connected sequentially to the M fourth bonding pads P<b>4</b> of the 1st&#x2dc;Nth rows. From the above illustration, the third branch lines <b>132</b> and the fourth branch lines <b>142</b> are alternately arranged but are not connected. It should be noted that the afore-mentioned arrangement of the first to fourth branch lines <b>112</b>, <b>122</b>, <b>132</b>, and <b>142</b> is one embodiment of the present disclosure and is not intended to limit the scope of the present disclosure. Persons skilled in the art may make modification and variation thereto without departing from the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A detailed illustration on a multi-chip package having the circuit structure <b>100</b> is given below.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a multi-chip package according to one embodiment of the present disclosure. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a multi-chip package <b>200</b> of the present embodiment includes a substrate <b>210</b>, a plurality of chip pads C, a plurality of LED chips <b>220</b>, a first electrode <b>110</b>, a second electrode <b>120</b>, a third electrode <b>130</b>, and a fourth electrode <b>140</b>, wherein the chip pads C and the first to fourth electrodes <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and <b>140</b> form the circuit structure <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Simultaneously referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in the present embodiment, to insulate among the first electrode <b>110</b>, the second electrode <b>120</b>, the third electrode <b>130</b>, and the fourth electrode <b>140</b>, the substrate <b>210</b> has an insulation layer <b>212</b>, and the first electrode <b>110</b>, the second electrode <b>120</b>, and the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> are all disposed on the insulation layer <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The third electrode <b>130</b> and the fourth electrode <b>140</b> are both disposed under the insulation layer <b>212</b> and pass through the insulation layer <b>212</b> to respectively connect to the third bonding pad P<b>3</b> and the fourth bonding pad P<b>4</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, since the third electrode <b>130</b> and the fourth electrode <b>140</b> are both disposed under the insulation layer <b>212</b>, the third electrode <b>130</b> and the fourth electrode <b>140</b> are illustrated with dotted lines. The third electrode <b>130</b> and the fourth electrode <b>140</b> respectively connect to the third bonding pad P<b>3</b> and the fourth bonding pad P<b>4</b> via a plurality of through holes (not shown) passing through the insulation layer <b>212</b>. Certainly, in other embodiments, the first electrode <b>110</b>, the second electrode <b>120</b>, the third electrode <b>130</b>, and the fourth electrode <b>140</b>, and the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> may all be disposed on a same plane via other circuit layouts.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Each of the LED chips <b>220</b> is disposed on one of the chip pads C. Each LED chip <b>220</b> is electrically connected to two of the bonding pads P on a same side of each LED chip <b>220</b>, wherein the two bonding pads P are selected from the first bonding pad P<b>1</b>, the second bonding pad P<b>2</b>, the third bonding pad P<b>3</b>, and the fourth bonding pad P<b>4</b>. For example, the multi-chip package <b>200</b> may include a plurality of first conductive lines <b>230</b> and a plurality of second conductive lines <b>240</b>, wherein each of the first conductive lines <b>230</b> and each of the second conductive lines <b>240</b> are respectively electrically connected to each LED chip <b>220</b> and two of the bonding pads P on a same side of each LED chip <b>220</b>. As such, the LED chips <b>220</b> are electrically connected in series-parallel, wherein the LED chips <b>220</b> in a same row are connected in parallel and the LED chips <b>220</b> in adjacent rows are connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the present embodiment, each LED chip <b>220</b> has the first conductive lines <b>230</b> and the second conductive lines <b>240</b> in pairs. It is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> that the first conductive lines <b>230</b> in each pair and the second conductive lines <b>240</b> in each pair are respectively electrically connected to each LED chip <b>220</b> and two of the bonding pads P on a same side <b>222</b> of each LED chip <b>220</b>. In other words, the first conductive lines <b>230</b> in pair are electrically connected to the LED chip <b>220</b> and one of the bonding pads P on the side <b>222</b> of the LED chip <b>220</b> and the second conductive lines <b>240</b> in pair are electrically connected to the LED chip <b>220</b> and the other of the bonding pads P on the same side <b>222</b> of the LED chip <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It should be noted that in the present embodiment, each of the LED chips <b>220</b> has four sides <b>222</b>, <b>224</b>, <b>226</b>, and <b>228</b>. The first conductive lines <b>230</b> in each pair and the second conductive lines <b>240</b> in each pair may respectively be electrically connected to two bonding pads P on any side of each LED chip <b>220</b>. Each pair of the first conducive lines <b>230</b> and each pair of the second conductive lines <b>240</b> are respectively electrically connected to two bonding pads P on a same side of each LED chip <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Compared to the conventional technology, in the present embodiment, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the Sth row of the circuit structure <b>100</b> differ respectively with the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the (S&#x2212;1)th row by 90 degrees. Therefore, the first conductive line <b>230</b> and the second conductive line <b>240</b> may respectively be electrically connected to two of the bonding pads P on a same side of each LED chip <b>220</b>. As such, in the present disclosure, the direction of wire bonding does not need to be changed when fabricating the first conductive lines <b>230</b> and the second conductive lines <b>240</b>. In light of the above, when fabricating the multi-chip package <b>200</b> of the present embodiment, the speed and yield of the wire bonding process are improved and thus productivity is promoted and cost is decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In addition, in the present embodiment, the multi-chip package <b>200</b> further includes a coating layer <b>250</b> disposed on the insulation layer <b>212</b> and covering the first to fourth electrodes <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and <b>140</b> and the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> to protect the first to fourth electrodes <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and <b>140</b> and the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b>. The coating layer <b>250</b> has a plurality of openings OP to expose the LED chips <b>220</b> and portions of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> in the peripheral area of each LED chip <b>220</b>, wherein the portions of the first to fourth bonding pads P<b>1</b>&#x2dc;P<b>4</b> are adjacent to each LED chip <b>220</b>. A material of the coating layer <b>250</b> includes insulating materials such as resin.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In summary, the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads in the Sth row of the circuit structure of the present disclosure are different from the orientations of each of the first to fourth bonding pads in the (S&#x2212;1)th row by 90 degrees. Therefore, the first conductive line and the second conductive line may respectively be electrically connected to two bonding pads on a same side of each LED chip. As such, in the present disclosure, the direction of wire bonding does not need to be changed when fabricating the first or second conductive lines. In light of the above, when fabricating the multi-chip package of the present disclosure, the speed and yield of the wire bonding process are improved and thus productivity is promoted and cost is decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made to the structure of the present disclosure without departing from the scope or spirit of the disclosure. In view of the foregoing, it is intended that the present disclosure cover modifications and variations of this disclosure provided they fall within the scope of the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circuit structure of a package carrier that carries a plurality of wire bonding light emitting diode (LED) chips, the circuit structure comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of chip pads arranged in an array of M columns and N rows to dispose the LED chips, M and N each being a positive integer greater than 1;</claim-text>
<claim-text>for each of the chip pads:
<claim-text>a respective first bonding pad, a respective second bonding pad, and a respective third bonding pad that are electrically insulated from each other and sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the respective chip pad, a first orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a first row of the N rows differing from a second orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees, the respective first, second, and third bonding pads being different from each other; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first electrode, a second electrode, and a third electrode:
<claim-text>the first electrode comprising a plurality of first branch lines connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second electrode comprising a plurality of second branch lines connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third electrode comprising a plurality of third branch lines connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first branch lines and the second branch lines are alternately arranged.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>for each of the chip pads:
<claim-text>a respective fourth bonding pad that is electrically insulated from the respective first, second, and third bonding pads, a fourth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a first row of the N rows differing from a fifth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth electrode comprising a plurality of fourth branch lines connected to the respective M fourth bonding pads in each of the N rows.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second orientation differs from the first orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a third orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a third row of the N rows differs from the second orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise, the second row being between the first row and the third row.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first electrode has a first main body portion, the second electrode has a second main body portion, and the third electrode has a third main body portion, and wherein the first, second, and third main body portions are sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the array of the chip pads.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first main body portion is connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows via the first branch lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the second main body portion is connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows via the second branch lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The circuit structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the third main body portion is connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows via the third branch lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A multi-chip package, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of chip pads arranged in an M&#xd7;N array, M and N each being a positive integer greater than 1, a peripheral area of each of the chip pads comprising a respective first bonding pad, a respective second bonding pad, and a respective third bonding pad arranged in sequence in a clockwise direction, a first orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a first row of the N rows differing from a second orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of light emitting diode (LED) chips, each LED chip disposed on a respective one of the chip pads and electrically connected to two of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads on a same side of the respective LED chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first electrode comprising a plurality of first branch lines connected to the respective M first bonding pads in each of the N rows;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electrode comprising a plurality of second branch lines connected to the respective M second bonding pads in each of the N rows; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third electrode comprising a plurality of third branch lines connected to the respective M third bonding pads in each of the N rows.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the first electrode has a first main body portion, the second electrode has a second main body portion, and the third electrode has a third main body portion, and wherein the first, second, and third main body portions are sequentially arranged in a peripheral area of the array of the chip pads.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate on which the chip pads are disposed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the substrate includes an insulation layer, wherein the first electrode, the second electrode, and the first, second, and third bonding pads are disposed on the insulation layer, and wherein the third electrode is disposed under the insulation layer and passes through the insulation layer to connect to the third bonding pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of first conductive lines and a plurality of second conductive lines, each of the first conductive lines and each of the second conductive lines electrically connected to a respective one of the LED chips and two of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads on a same side of the respective one of the LED chips.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the first conductive lines in each pair and the second conductive lines in each pair are respectively electrically connected to the respective one of the LED chips and two of the bonding pads on a same side of each LED chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a coating layer disposed on the insulation layer and covering the first, second, and third bonding pads, the coating layer having a plurality of openings that expose the LED chips and portions of the first, second, and third bonding pads in the peripheral area of each LED chip, the portions of the first, second, and third bonding pads being adjacent to each LED chip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the coating layer comprises resin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the second orientation differs from the first orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise, and wherein a third orientation of the respective first, second, and third bonding pads in a third row of the N rows differs from the second orientation by 90 degrees counterclockwise, the second row being between the first row and the third row.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The multi-chip package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a fourth electrode comprising a plurality of fourth branch lines connected to the respective M fourth bonding pads in each of the N rows, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the peripheral area of each of the chip pads further comprises:
<claim-text>a respective fourth bonding pad that is electrically insulated from the respective first, second, and third bonding pads, a fourth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a first row of the N rows differing from a fifth orientation of the respective first, second, third, and fourth bonding pads in a second row of the N rows by 90 degrees. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
