<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622583-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622583</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13609735</doc-number>
<date>20120911</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362294</main-classification>
<further-classification>36231102</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">LED lamp scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0165632</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Liang</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362294</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2013/0128589</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20130500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362294</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224902</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362294</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36231102</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Chi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Hua-Zheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Chi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Li</last-name>
<first-name>Hua-Zheng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rosenberg, Klein &#x26; Lee</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Jiawei Photovoltaic Lighting Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Light-Core Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bruce</last-name>
<first-name>David V</first-name>
<department>2875</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An LED lamp scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents mainly constructs multiple channels interleaved in heat scattering areas among fin units of a cooling device. At least one first hole is defined on a wall of each channel for assisting the channels in communicating with the heat scattering areas. Accordingly, the exterior air is introduced from the channels into an accommodating chamber of a seat body of the LED lamp. Thence, a fan installed in the LED lamp further blows the exterior air and the wasted heat of the LED unit to cause a current exchanging effect. Whereby, the wasted heat is efficiently expelled from the LED lamp, which increases the heat radiating efficiency and the using life of the LED lamp and remedies restrictions on installations of the LED lamp for expanding the lamp application.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="132.93mm" wi="172.80mm" file="US08622583-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="156.80mm" wi="148.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="193.04mm" wi="148.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="178.22mm" wi="155.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="139.70mm" wi="161.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="171.62mm" wi="157.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="201.34mm" wi="153.25mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622583-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="183.56mm" wi="148.25mm" file="US08622583-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a design of an LED lamp, particularly to an LED lamp preferably scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a conventional LED lamp <b>1</b> comprises a seat body <b>11</b> including an accommodating chamber <b>111</b>, a protective cover <b>10</b> connected to a rim of the seat body <b>11</b>, a light module <b>12</b> installed within the accommodating chamber <b>111</b>, and a cooling device <b>13</b>. Wherein, the light module <b>12</b> has an electrically-connected circuit board <b>121</b>, an optical reflector <b>122</b> disposed on the circuit board <b>121</b>, and at least one LED unit <b>123</b> disposed on the circuit board <b>121</b>. Moreover, the cooling device <b>13</b> has a fin set <b>131</b> disposed around the optical reflector <b>122</b>, and a fan <b>132</b> disposed under the circuit board <b>121</b>. In using, the LED unit <b>123</b> and the circuit board <b>121</b> are electrified for emitting light through the optical reflector <b>122</b>, and heat generated by the LED unit <b>123</b> is released via the cooperation of the fan <b>132</b> and the fin set <b>131</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In practice, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the heat in the LED lamp <b>1</b> generated during lighting may be released via the fan <b>132</b> and the fin set <b>131</b>. However, the effect of heat dispersion depends on materials adopted on the fin set <b>131</b>. Namely, if the fin set <b>131</b> is made of materials that possess the higher radiating coefficient, the effect of heat dispersion in the LED lamp <b>1</b> favorably advances. Oppositely, if the fin set <b>131</b> is made of materials that possess the lower radiating coefficient, the heat in the LED lamp <b>1</b> can not be timely released, which adversely incurs an overheated LED lamp <b>1</b>. As a result, either the lighting effect or the using life of the LED lamp <b>1</b> is influenced.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In fact, where the LED lamp <b>1</b> is placed is also one of the factors that influence the effect of heat dispersion. Namely, if the seat body <b>11</b> of the LED lamp <b>1</b> is uncovered and attached to ceilings, plywood, or any other decorative rails, a favorable effect of heat dispersion could be provided. Oppositely, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the seat body <b>11</b> of the LED lamp <b>1</b> may be also embedded in a ground G. A large quantity of wasted heat is similarly generated after the LED unit <b>123</b> and the optical reflector <b>122</b> continuingly provide light. Herein, since the seat body <b>11</b> of the LED lamp <b>1</b> is wrapped in the compact ground material G, and the protective cover <b>10</b> is designed solid, there is only the narrow and small accommodating chamber <b>111</b> left between the fin set <b>131</b> and the seat body <b>11</b> for wasted heat to be removed out (as shown by dotted-line arrows in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Herein, cooling air out of the LED lamp <b>1</b> can not get into the seat body <b>11</b>. Thus, the wasted heat generated in time of lighting is difficultly to be dispersed out of the accommodating chamber <b>111</b> of the LED lamp <b>1</b>. Obviously, the LED lamp <b>1</b> is thence overheated. Therefore, the lighting effect and the using life of the LED lamp <b>1</b> are both affected.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is therefore the purpose of this invention to provide an LED lamp scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents. Namely, when the currents are exchanged by means of a fin set providing a plurality of channels for communicating with an accommodating chamber in the LED lamp, circulation of air is constructed for promoting the heat dispersion of the LED lamp and expanding the application of the LED lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The LED lamp scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents in accordance with the present invention comprises a seat body including an accommodating chamber, a light module installed within the accommodating chamber, and a cooling device correspondingly disposed to the light module. Wherein, the light module has an electrically-connected circuit board, an optical reflector disposed on the circuit board, and at least one LED unit disposed on the circuit board. The cooling device has a fan installed under the circuit board, and a fin set enveloping the circuit board and the optical reflector. A room is formed within the fin set for holding the circuit board and the optical reflector. A plurality of fin units are extended outward from the fin set. Wherein, the fin set comprises a plurality of heat scattering areas defined among the fin units at intervals and a plurality of channels disposed between the heat scattering areas. Each of the heat scattering areas is communicated with the accommodating chamber and disposed corresponding to the fan. A side of each channel toward the seat body is formed into a closed stated. At least one first hole is defined on a periphery wall of each channel and disposed corresponding to the adjacent fin unit for assisting the channels in communicating with the heat scattering areas, thereby introducing exterior air into the seat body through the channels and allowing the fan to guide the exterior air into the heat scattering areas for resulting in a current exchanging effect between the exterior air and wasted heat from the LED lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably, a protective cover with a plurality of openings defined thereon is connected to a rim of the seat body.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, the cooling device further includes a lodging set connecting to the fin set, and the lodging set has a plurality of lodging units disposed at intervals for corresponding to part of the fin units so that each of the channels is enclosed by combining each lodging unit with each corresponding fin unit and each of the heat scatting areas is formed between a remainder of the fin units which do not cooperate with the lodging units.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Accordingly, exterior air is introduced into the seat body through the channels. Thence, the fan guides the exterior air traveling around the heat scattering area for forming current circulation in the accommodating chamber to effectively cool the heat generated from the light module in the eat body of the LED lamp. As a result, currents of the wasted heat and the exterior air are circularly exchanged in the LED lamp and expelled therefrom. Thereby, the heat can be favorably scattered, so the using life of the LED lamp is prolonged. Moreover, installing location of the LED lamp is unlimited since the wasted heat can be scattered efficiently. Accordingly, the LED lamp can be more expansively installed and used.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view showing a conventional LED lamp;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the conventional LED lamp;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view showing a first preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of the first preferred embodiment of the present invention in operation;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of part a-a in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic view showing a second preferred embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic view of partial elements in the second preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Wherever possible, the same reference numbers are used in the drawings and the description to refer to the same or like parts.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a first preferred embodiment of the present invention is shown. An LED lamp <b>2</b> scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents comprises a seat body <b>21</b> including an accommodating chamber <b>211</b>, a light module <b>22</b> installed within the accommodating chamber <b>211</b>, and a cooling device <b>23</b> correspondingly disposed to the light module <b>22</b>. Further, the light module <b>22</b> has an electrically-connected circuit board <b>221</b>, an optical reflector <b>222</b> disposed on the circuit board <b>221</b>, and at least one LED unit <b>223</b> disposed on the circuit board <b>221</b>. Herein, the LED unit <b>223</b> provides light and emits light out of the LED lamp <b>2</b> through the optical reflector <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Moreover, the cooling device <b>23</b> has a fan <b>231</b> installed under the circuit board <b>221</b>, and a fin set <b>232</b> disposed between the circuit board <b>221</b> and the fan <b>231</b> for enveloping the optical reflector <b>222</b>. There is a room <b>233</b> formed in the fin set <b>232</b> for receiving the circuit board <b>221</b> and the optical reflector <b>222</b>. Especially, the fin set <b>232</b> comprises a plurality of heat scattering areas <b>2323</b> defined among the fin units <b>2321</b> at intervals and a plurality of channels <b>2322</b> disposed between the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b>. Each of the heat scattering areas <b>232</b> is communicated with the accommodating chamber <b>211</b> and disposed corresponding to the fan <b>231</b>. A side of each channel <b>2322</b> toward the seat body <b>21</b> is formed into a closed stated. At least one first hole <b>23222</b> defined on a periphery wall <b>23221</b> of each channel <b>2322</b> and disposed corresponding to the adjacent fin unit <b>2321</b>. The first hole <b>23222</b> assists the channels <b>2322</b> in communicating with the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b>, corresponding to the fan <b>231</b>. Thereby introducing exterior air into the seat body <b>21</b> through the channels <b>2322</b> and allowing the fan <b>231</b> to guide the exterior air into the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b> for resulting in a current exchanging effect between the exterior air and wasted heat of the LED unit <b>223</b> within accommodating chamber <b>211</b> of the seat body <b>21</b> of the LED lamp <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Additionally, a protective cover <b>20</b> connected to a rim of the seat body <b>21</b> can be freely adopted in this embodiment for preferably preventing objects from intruding into the seat body <b>21</b>, and the protective cover <b>20</b> also defines a plurality of openings <b>201</b> that further communicate with both the channels <b>2322</b> and the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b>. Herein, the protective cover <b>20</b> is adopted depending on practical situation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 to 5</figref>, in using, the LED unit <b>223</b> and the circuit board <b>221</b> are electrified to emit light. Namely, the light goes through the optical reflector <b>222</b> and then illuminates any desired places. Concurrently, the fan <b>231</b> under the circuit board <b>221</b> is driven during the illumination. When the LED unit <b>223</b> keeps lighting and creating heat energy, the seat body <b>21</b> is full of wasted heat. Herein, one side of the channel <b>2322</b> near the seat body <b>21</b> is formed closed. Accordingly, when the exterior air enters the LED lamp <b>2</b>, the exterior air firstly goes through the first hole <b>23222</b> on each channel <b>2322</b> and then travels in the accommodating chamber <b>211</b> of the seat body <b>21</b>. In the meantime, the fin units <b>2321</b> are cooled by the exterior air, and the fan <b>231</b> guides the wasted heat around the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b> out of the protective cover <b>20</b>, so that current circulation by exchanging the currents of the wasted heat and the exterior air is executed in the seat body <b>21</b>. Preferably, the wasted heat is efficiently expelled, which concurrently enhances the heat dispersing effect of the LED lamp <b>2</b> and prolongs the using life of the same.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Whereby, no matter the LED lamp <b>2</b> is placed in an exposed manner or a hidden manner, the channels <b>2322</b> guides the exterior air to go around the heat scattering area <b>2323</b> of the fin set <b>232</b> via the first hole <b>23222</b> so as to cool accordingly. Concurrently, the fan <b>231</b> pushes and blows the exterior air that is mixed with the wasted heat for introducing the circulation of currents to enhance the heat dispersing effect. As a result, when the wasted heat is guided out of the openings <b>201</b> of the protective cover <b>20</b>, the LED lamp <b>2</b> can be cooled easily. Therefore, the using life of the LED lamp <b>2</b> can be prolonged and the installing location of the LED lamp <b>2</b> becomes free and more expansive now since the heat dispersing problem is resolved.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, a second preferred embodiment of the present invention is shown. In order to clearly show features of the present invention in this embodiment, the LED lamp <b>2</b> is basically shown by a structure derived from the first preferred embodiment. Differently, the cooling device <b>23</b> further includes a lodging set <b>234</b> connecting to the fin set <b>232</b>, and the lodging set <b>234</b> has a plurality of lodging units <b>2341</b> disposed at intervals for corresponding to part of the fin units <b>2321</b> so that each of the channels <b>2322</b> is enclosed by combining each lodging unit <b>2341</b> with each corresponding fin unit <b>2321</b> and each of the heat scatting areas <b>2323</b> is formed between a remainder of the fin units <b>2321</b> which do not cooperate with the lodging units <b>2341</b>. Accordingly, the channels <b>2322</b> is used to guide exterior air into the LED lamp <b>2</b> for attaining the effect of current circulation around the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b> and the fin units <b>2321</b>. When the fan <b>231</b> is driven, the wasted heat and the exterior air are exchanged and the exchanged current is expelled from the heat scattering areas <b>2323</b> efficiently. Preferably, the using life of the present invention is enhanced, and the installing location of the LED lamp <b>2</b> is unlimited, which expands the application of the LED lamp <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">To sum up, the present invention particularly constructs multiple heat scattering areas among the fin units of the cooling device at intervals and channels disposed between the fin units. When the heat scattering areas are communicated with the accommodating chambers via the first holes, the channels introduce the exterior air to go around the heat scattering areas via the first holes, and the fan brings the exterior air and the wasted heat in the seat body to exchange for causing circulation of currents. Thereby, the heat scattering areas thence disperse heat in the seat body. Preferably, a favorable radiating effect of the present invention is easily achieved and enhanced. Additionally, the using life of the LED lamp is further extended. Further, when the installing location of the LED lamp is unlimited, the LED lamp of the present invention can be more expansively applied.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">While we have shown and described the embodiment in accordance with the present invention, it should be clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An LED lamp scattering heat swiftly by exchanging currents comprising a seat body including an accommodating chamber, a light module installed within said accommodating chamber, and a cooling device correspondingly disposed to said light module; wherein, said light module has an electrically-connected circuit board, an optical reflector disposed on said circuit board, and at least one LED unit disposed on said circuit board; said cooling device having a fan installed under said circuit board, and a fin set enveloping said circuit board and said optical reflector; a room being formed within said fin set for holding said circuit board and said optical reflector; a plurality of fin units being extended outward from said fin set;
<claim-text>wherein, said fin set comprises a plurality of heat scattering areas defined among said fin units at intervals and a plurality of channels disposed between said heat scattering areas; each of said heat scattering areas being communicated with said accommodating chamber and disposed corresponding to said fan; a side of each channel toward said seat body being formed into a closed stated; at least one first hole being defined on a periphery wall of each channel and disposed corresponding to said adjacent fin unit for assisting said channels in communicating with said heat scattering areas, thereby introducing exterior air into said seat body through said channels and allowing said fan to guide said exterior air into said heat scattering areas for resulting in a current exchanging effect between said exterior air and wasted heat from said LED lamp.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The LED lamp as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, a protective cover with a plurality of openings defined thereon is connected to a rim of said seat body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The LED lamp as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, said cooling device further includes a lodging set connecting to said fin set, and said lodging set has a plurality of lodging units disposed at intervals for corresponding to part of said fin units so that each of said channels is enclosed by combining each lodging unit with each corresponding fin unit and each of said heat scatting areas is formed between a remainder of said fin units which do not cooperate with said lodging units.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The LED lamp as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein, said cooling device further includes a lodging set connecting to said fin set, and said lodging set has a plurality of lodging units disposed at intervals for corresponding to part of said fin units so that each of said channels is enclosed by combining each lodging unit with each corresponding fin unit and each of said heat scatting areas is formed between a remainder of said fin units which do not cooperate with said lodging units.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
