<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622574-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622574</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13108993</doc-number>
<date>20110517</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0299052</doc-number>
<date>20101007</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>306</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>005</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362241</main-classification>
<further-classification>36224902</further-classification>
<further-classification>36224906</further-classification>
<further-classification>362294</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">LED lamp having light emitting diodes with reduced number of lenses covered thereon</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6598994</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tait et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362 11</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7922372</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li</name>
<date>20110400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362373</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7959327</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lai et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362294</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8220971</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Harbers et al.</name>
<date>20120700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362294</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8419224</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wan-Chih et al.</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362294</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0202007</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yagi et al.</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362545</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0244894</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhou et al.</name>
<date>20091000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36224902</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0194285</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Harbers et al.</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>36224902</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224902</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3622491</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>36224911</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362800</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362294</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362373</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362241</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120087125</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120412</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>You-Xue</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>You-Xue</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fu Zhun Precision Industry (Shen Zhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Foxconn Technology Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ton</last-name>
<first-name>Anabel</first-name>
<department>2875</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A light emitting diode (LED) lamp includes a light emitting module; a power module for driving the light emitting module; and a housing having an optical part for receiving the light emitting module, an electrical part for receiving the power module. The light emitting module includes a plurality of circuit boards sequentially arranged parallel to each other, a plurality of first LED chips which has lenses covered thereon being mounted on the circuit boards, and a plurality of second LED chips which has no lens covered thereon being mounted also on the circuit boards. The first and the second LED chips are arranged in columns and rows. The second LED chips are located symmetrically in respect to the first LED chips.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="234.19mm" wi="164.08mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="257.47mm" wi="168.91mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.14mm" wi="185.25mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="196.85mm" wi="175.09mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="228.85mm" wi="164.85mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="232.33mm" wi="164.17mm" file="US08622574-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a light emitting diode (LED) lamp, and more particularly, to an LED lamp having a plurality of LED chips wherein some of the LED chips are without lens covered thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The LED lamps have been more and more widely used around the world recently. A typical LED lamp includes a plurality of LED chips and a plurality of lenses correspondingly covering each light emitting diode to obtain a special light distribution curve. However, the lenses covering the light emitting diodes block the light transmission to some degree thereby lowering the efficiency of use of light generated by LED chips of the LED lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, a new LED lamp is desired to overcome the above-described shortcomings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of at least one embodiment. In the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the various views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic, isometric view of an LED lamp according to a first embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic, enlarged, exploded, partial view of the LED lamp of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic, isometric assembly of the LED lamp of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic, isometric view of an LED lamp according to a second embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic, isometric view of an LED lamp according to a third embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Reference will now be made to the drawings to describe various inventive embodiments of the present disclosure in detail, wherein like numerals refer to like units throughout.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, an LED lamp <b>1</b> according to a first embodiment of the present invention includes a housing <b>10</b>, a light emitting module <b>11</b>, a power supply module <b>12</b> for driving the light emitting module <b>11</b>, a plurality of reflectors <b>114</b>, a transparent cap <b>14</b>, a cover <b>15</b>, a heat sink <b>16</b>, and a plurality of ring-shaped sealants <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The power supply module <b>12</b> includes a transformer <b>120</b>, a first wire <b>122</b>, a second wire <b>124</b>, and a connector <b>126</b> connected to the transformer <b>120</b> via the first wire <b>122</b>. The transformer <b>120</b> is configured for receiving an external power supply via the connector <b>126</b> and configured for converting an alternating current (AC) power into a direct current (DC) power with a required operation voltage for driving the light emitting module <b>11</b> to generate light.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The housing <b>10</b> includes an optical part <b>101</b>, an electric part <b>102</b>, and a lamp head <b>103</b>. The optical part <b>101</b> includes a frame <b>104</b> which defines a space <b>105</b> for receiving the light emitting module <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The electric part <b>102</b> is located adjacent to the optical part <b>101</b> and the lamp head <b>103</b> and sandwiched therebetween. The electric part <b>102</b> is configured for receiving the transformer <b>120</b>. The lamp head <b>103</b> is configured for receiving the first wire <b>122</b> and the connector <b>126</b>. In this embodiment, the lamp head <b>103</b> is hollow column. One terminal of the lamp head <b>103</b> communicates with the electric part <b>102</b> and the other terminal of the lamp head <b>103</b> connects to a mounting device, such as a pole of a street lamp (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The second wire <b>124</b> is extended from the transformer <b>120</b> and arranged along the frame <b>104</b> to surround the space <b>105</b> for providing the operation voltage to the light emitting module <b>11</b>. The second wire <b>124</b> is electrically connected with the light emitting module <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The light emitting module <b>11</b> includes a plurality of circuit boards <b>111</b> sequentially arranged parallel to each other, a plurality of LED chips <b>112</b>, a plurality of lens <b>113</b>, and the plurality of reflectors <b>114</b>. In this embodiment, the circuit boards <b>111</b> are rectangular and received in the space <b>105</b>. Two ends of each circuit board <b>111</b> are fixed to opposite sides of the frame <b>104</b> and electrically connected to the transformer <b>120</b> via the second wire <b>124</b> for receiving the operation voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The LED chips <b>112</b> are mounted on the circuit boards <b>111</b> in columns and rows. Some of the LED chips <b>112</b> have lenses <b>113</b> covered thereon while some of the other LED chips <b>112</b> have no lens covered thereon. That is, the lenses <b>113</b> cover only a part of the LED chips <b>112</b> to generate a predetermined light distribution curve for the LED lamp <b>1</b>. For convenience of description, the LED chips <b>112</b> with lenses <b>113</b> covered thereon are defined as first LED chips and the LED chips <b>112</b> without lens covered thereon are defined as second LED chips. In one embodiment, each circuit board <b>111</b> includes two rows of LED chips <b>112</b>. Each row of LED chips <b>112</b> includes ten LED chips <b>112</b>. Six middle ones of the ten LED chips <b>112</b> function as the first LED chips and four LED chips <b>112</b> located beside the six middle ones function as the second LED chips. More specifically, two second LED chips are located at one side of the six first LED chips and the other two second LED chips are located at an opposite side of the six first LED chips. That is, the second LED chips are arranged symmetrically at two opposite sides of the first LED chips.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Each reflector <b>114</b> covers one corresponding circuit board <b>111</b> and includes a plurality of through holes <b>115</b> for exposing the LEDs <b>112</b> and the corresponding lenses <b>113</b> covering the first LEDs. In other words, the through holes <b>115</b> of the reflectors <b>114</b> are configured for exposing both the first LED chips and the second LED chips.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The transparent cap <b>14</b> is arc-shaped and covers one side of the optical part <b>101</b> for protecting the light emitting module <b>11</b>. In this embodiment, a fixing ring <b>108</b> is further provided between the transparent cap <b>14</b> and the frame <b>104</b> for more securely and hermetically connecting the cap <b>14</b> to the frame <b>104</b>. One sealant <b>17</b> is sandwiched between the transparent cap <b>14</b> and the fixing ring <b>108</b> and another sealant <b>17</b> is sandwiched between the frame <b>104</b> and the fixing ring <b>108</b>, whereby the space <b>105</b> and the light emitting module <b>11</b> received in the space is protected from moisture and dust.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In an alternative embodiment, the fixing ring <b>108</b> can be omitted and the transparent cap <b>14</b> is mounted to the optical part <b>101</b> with a sealant <b>17</b> sandwiched therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The cover <b>15</b> covers the electric part <b>102</b> with another sealant <b>17</b> sandwiched therebetween, whereby the transformer <b>20</b> received in the electric part <b>102</b> is protected from moisture and dust.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The heat sink <b>16</b> is attached to the other side of the optical part <b>101</b> and in thermal and mechanical connection with the light emitting module <b>11</b>. The heat sink <b>16</b> includes a heat dissipating substrate <b>161</b> and a plurality of fins <b>162</b> formed on a bottom surface of the dissipating substrate <b>161</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In this embodiment, edge of the dissipating substrate <b>161</b> is fixed to the frame <b>104</b>, and the circuit boards <b>111</b> are secured on a top surface of the dissipating substrate <b>161</b> via a plurality of screws (not shown) whereby heat generated by the LED chips <b>112</b> can be effectively transferred to the heat sink <b>16</b> and dissipated to surrounding air by the fins <b>162</b>. In this embodiment, the fins <b>162</b> are spaced from each other and perpendicularly extended from a bottom surface of the dissipating substrate <b>161</b>. In one embodiment, a heat conductive material such as silicone grease is smashed on the top surface of the dissipating substrate <b>161</b> to improve a heat transfer from the LED chips <b>112</b> to the heat sink <b>16</b>. An assembly of the LED lamp <b>1</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Because only a part of the LED chips <b>112</b> is covered with the lenses <b>113</b> and the other part of LED chips <b>112</b> without lens covered thereon is symmetrically arranged in respect to the part, both brightness and light distribution curve of the LED lamp <b>1</b> are improved.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an LED lamp <b>2</b> according to a second embodiment of the present disclosure is similar to the LED lamp <b>1</b> of the first embodiment. The LED lamp <b>2</b> is only different from the LED lamp <b>1</b> in that the light emitting module <b>11</b> includes a plurality of circuit boards <b>111</b> sequentially arranged parallel to each other as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. All of the LED chips <b>112</b> on the circuit board <b>111</b> have lenses <b>113</b> covered thereon except the LED chips <b>112</b> on the two outermost circuit boards <b>111</b>. In other words, the second LED chips are only on the two outermost circuit boards <b>111</b> while the first LED chips are on the other circuit boards <b>111</b> that are sandwiched between the two outermost circuit boards <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an LED lamp <b>3</b> according to a third embodiment of the present disclosure is similar to the LED lamp <b>1</b> of the first embodiment. The LED lamp <b>3</b> is only different from the LED lamp <b>1</b> in that the light emitting module <b>11</b> includes a plurality of circuit boards <b>111</b> sequentially arranged parallel to each other as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and the second LED chips are cross-shaped. In this embodiment, a central circuit board <b>111</b> includes two rows of LED chips <b>112</b> without lenses <b>113</b> covered thereon. Each of the other circuit boards <b>112</b> includes two rows of LED chips <b>112</b> in which middle fours of the LED chips <b>112</b> are without lens covered thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In alternative embodiment, the LED chips <b>112</b> of the LED lamp <b>3</b> without lens covered thereon can be arranged in other patterns, i.e., capital letters or symbols, such as such as H<img id="CUSTOM-CHARACTER-00001" he="2.46mm" wi="1.02mm" file="US08622574-20140107-P00001.TIF" alt="custom character" img-content="character" img-format="tif"/>I<img id="CUSTOM-CHARACTER-00002" he="2.46mm" wi="1.02mm" file="US08622574-20140107-P00001.TIF" alt="custom character" img-content="character" img-format="tif"/>O<img id="CUSTOM-CHARACTER-00003" he="2.46mm" wi="1.02mm" file="US08622574-20140107-P00001.TIF" alt="custom character" img-content="character" img-format="tif"/>X<img id="CUSTOM-CHARACTER-00004" he="2.46mm" wi="1.02mm" file="US08622574-20140107-P00001.TIF" alt="custom character" img-content="character" img-format="tif"/>&#x3b8;, according to the actual requirement.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of certain inventive embodiments have been set out in the foregoing description, together with details of the structures and functions of the embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only; and that changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of arrangement of parts within the principles of present invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A light emitting diode (LED) lamp comprising:
<claim-text>a light emitting module comprising
<claim-text>a plurality of circuit boards sequentially arranged parallel to each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of first LED chips on the circuit boards which are cover by lenses; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of second LED chips on the circuit boards which are without lens covered thereon;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power module for providing a driving power to the light emitting module; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing comprising an optical part for receiving the light emitting module therein, and an electrical part for receiving the power module therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and the second LED chips are arranged in columns and rows, and the second LED chips are arranged symmetrically in respect to the first LED chips.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second LED chips are arranged at opposite sides of the first LED chips.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first LED chips are formed on each circuit board in two rows, and the second LED chips are positioned at two opposite sides of the first LED chips on each circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the second LED chips are only on two outermost circuit boards and the first LED chips are only on the other circuit board that are sandwiched between the two outermost circuit boards.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second LED chips are cross-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second LED chips are symmetrically arranged in a pattern of a capital letter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a transparent cap fixed to the housing and covering the optical part for protecting the light emitting module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a ring-shaped sealant sandwiched between the transparent cap and the optical part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat sink fixed to the housing at a position opposite to the transparent cap, wherein the heat sink comprises a heat dissipating substrate and a plurality of fins spaced from each other formed on a bottom surface of the heat dissipating substrate, and a top surface of the heat dissipating substrate is in thermal and mechanical connection with the circuit boards.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising conductive silicon grease smashed on the top surface of the dissipating substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of reflectors each covering one circuit board and comprising a plurality of through holes to expose the first and the second LED chips.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical part comprises a frame defining a space therein for receiving the light emitting module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the power supply module comprises a transformer, a first wire, and a connector connected to the transformer via the first wire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the housing further comprise a lamp head configured for receiving the first wire and the connector therein, wherein one terminal of the lamp head communicates with the electric part and the other terminal of the lamp head connects to a mounting device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the connector and the first wire are adapted for electrically connecting with an external power source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the power supply module further comprises a second wire extending from the transformer and arranged around the frame for providing an operation voltage to the light emitting module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein each of the circuit boards is rectangular and electrically connected to the transformer via the second wire for receiving the operation voltage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The LED lamp of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a fixing ring sandwiched between the optical part of the housing and the transparent cap for securely mounting transparent cap to the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
