<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626458-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626458</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12940827</doc-number>
<date>20101105</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>529</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>30</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>702 56</main-classification>
<further-classification>702182</further-classification>
<further-classification>702183</further-classification>
<further-classification>702184</further-classification>
<further-classification>702185</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Method and system for measuring the dynamic response of a structure during a machining process</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3967515</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nachtigal et al.</name>
<date>19760700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 82118</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>702 56</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>702121-123</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>702182-189</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61258551</doc-number>
<date>20091105</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110106467</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110505</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cone</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kihei</city>
<state>HI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cone</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kihei</city>
<state>HI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Patterson + Sheridan, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Vibration Technologies, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Rafael</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Huynh</last-name>
<first-name>Phuong</first-name>
<department>2857</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A machine implement includes sensors that measure a force imparted by the machine implement to a structure during a machining process. A sensor array coupled to the structure measures the vibrational response of the structure to the imparted force. Analysis software compares the imparted force to the vibrational response to generate a transfer function for the structure. Based on the transfer function, a tool-path of the machine implement may be adjusted such that the resulting structure has precise vibrational characteristics that substantially comply with a set of design goals for the structure.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="208.87mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US08626458-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="158.50mm" wi="166.37mm" file="US08626458-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="216.15mm" wi="172.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626458-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.95mm" wi="154.52mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626458-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="245.11mm" wi="178.90mm" file="US08626458-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="217.17mm" wi="172.30mm" file="US08626458-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="230.29mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US08626458-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the priority benefit of Provisional U.S. Patent Application Ser. No. 61/258,551, filed Nov. 5, 2009, the subject matter of which is hereby incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The invention relates generally to the design and manufacture of structures, and, more specifically, to a method and system for measuring the dynamic response of a structure during a machining process.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Conventional structural analysis techniques can be used to manufacture and/or modify a wide range of different structures, including musical instruments, buildings, airframes, and surfboards, among other things. A designer of a structure may implement one or more different structural analysis techniques to design and build the structure to have particular vibrational characteristics. Modern structural analysis techniques involve generating a computer model of the structure. A physical simulation of the computer model can be used to predict the vibrational characteristics of the structure. The design of the structure may then be modified based on the predicted vibrational characteristics of the structure.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One problem with this technique is that physical simulations are inherently inaccurate and cannot predict the vibrational characteristics of a structure with arbitrary accuracy. To solve this problem, designers often test the vibrational characteristics of structures once those structures have already been built. For example, the designer of a guitar may use a microphone to measure the resonant frequencies associated with the guitar. The designer may then make structural modifications to the guitar based on the measured resonant frequencies.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Through this technique, the vibrational characteristics of the structure can be measured directly instead of predicted. However, this approach suffers from certain drawbacks. Specifically, the vibrational characteristics of the structure can only be measured once fabrication of that structure is complete. Oftentimes, re-fabrication or modification of the structure is not possible, and, thus, the vibrational characteristics of the structure cannot be changed to comply with design goals.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Accordingly, what is needed in the art is a better way to fabricate a structure.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">One embodiment of the invention sets forth a method for measuring the dynamic response of a material during a machining process. The method includes the steps of receiving an excitation signal that corresponds to a force of impact of a machine tool with the material during a machining operation and is generated by one or more sensors included within the machine tool configured to measure the force of impact, and receiving a response signal that corresponds to the dynamic response of the material to the force. The method also includes the steps of determining a vibrational characteristic of the material by comparing the response signal to the excitation signal, and adjusting the parameters of the machining operation to modify the material based on the vibrational characteristic.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">One advantage of the disclosed approach is that the process of machining a material can be dynamically adjusted based on the measured response of the material. The conventional method of machining a material, measuring the vibrational characteristics of the material, and then modifying the material (if possible) based on the measured characteristics, in multiple, iterative passes, is time consuming. In contrast, a machining process that implements the disclosed approach may produce a structure with precise vibrational characteristics in a single step. Thus, a structure necessitating precise vibrational characteristics can be generated with relative ease compared to prior art approaches.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">So that the manner in which the above recited features of the invention can be understood in detail, a more particular description of the invention, briefly summarized above, may be had by reference to embodiments, some of which are illustrated in the appended drawings. It is to be noted, however, that the appended drawings illustrate only typical embodiments of this invention and are therefore not to be considered limiting of its scope, for the invention may admit to other equally effective embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conceptual diagram of a system configured to implement one or more aspects of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2E</figref> illustrate a machine tool with an integrated force gauge, according to one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3D</figref> illustrate a machine tool with an integrated force gauge, according to another embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A-4C</figref> illustrate a machine tool with an integrated force gauge, according to yet another embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow diagram of method steps for measuring the dynamic response of a structure during a machining process, according to one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The purpose of the invention is to simultaneously excite a material or a structure and measure the dynamic response of the material or structure to the excitation force during a machining process. Coupled with the capability to measure the vibrational characteristics of the material or structure in real-time, the machining process can be adjusted dynamically to cause the resulting material or structure to comply with certain design goals. This functionality can be used to quickly fabricate machined materials or structures having precise vibrational characteristics.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth to provide a more thorough understanding of the invention. However, it will be apparent to one of skill in the art that the invention may be practiced without one or more of these specific details. In other instances, well-known features have not been described in order to avoid obscuring the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As used herein, a &#x201c;machining process&#x201d; is the overarching process for modifying a material or creating a structure from a material by removing or modifying various amounts of material to generate a structure within the material having a particular shape. The machining process may include configuring a machine tool, generating an excitation signal, generating a dynamic response signal, analyzing the signals, and adjusting a tool-path of the machine tool to modify the material or adjust the shape of the structure. A machining process may include one or more &#x201c;machining operations&#x201d; that are defined as the actual physical modification of the material, such as a cutting operation by impacting a surface of the material with a cutting surface of the machine tool or a sanding operation such as impacting a surface of the material with an abrasive surface of the machine tool.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a conceptual diagram of a system <b>100</b> configured to implement one or more aspects of the present invention. System <b>100</b> includes a signal processing system <b>110</b> configured to communicate with a machine tool <b>120</b> via a communication path <b>112</b>. Signal processing system <b>110</b> may be configured to analyze an excitation force imparted to a material <b>140</b> being machined by machine tool <b>120</b> and a dynamic response of the material <b>140</b> to the excitation force. By comparing the excitation force to the dynamic response of the material <b>140</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> may perform a real-time modal analysis of the structure created in material <b>140</b> by the machining process. In response to such an analysis, signal processing system <b>110</b> may also be configured to adjust a tool-path of machine tool <b>120</b> such that that resulting structure created in material <b>140</b> has precise vibrational characteristics that substantially match vibrational characteristics embodied in a set of design goals for that structure. In one embodiment, signal processing system <b>110</b> is a computer system configured to execute analysis software <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Analysis software <b>115</b> may be configured to determine a tool-path for machine tool <b>120</b> such that the resulting structure created in material <b>140</b> by the machining process has precise vibrational characteristics. In one embodiment, analysis software <b>115</b> may be modeling software such as NASA Structural Analysis software (Nastrans). Analysis software <b>115</b> may be used to compute predicted effects resulting from removing various amounts of material from the structure being machined from material <b>140</b> during a machining process. Analysis software <b>115</b> may also be used to predict a discrepancy between the excitation force imparted to material <b>140</b> and the dynamic response of material <b>140</b> to the excitation force. Such a discrepancy could result from material being removed from the structure during the machining process.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Because the invention incorporates similar analyses as those analyses commonly performed in non-destructive testing procedures, analysis software <b>115</b> may incorporate commonly available analysis routines without many changes required. In some embodiments, analysis software <b>115</b> may incorporate commonly available analysis routines that have been modified to include calibration or signal processing adjustments. Such modifications may allow normal data acquisition processes used in modal analysis to be extended to real-time machining processes. For example, analysis software <b>115</b> may be calibrated to account for the weight of a tool or instrument directly connected to a force gauge that measures the excitation force imparted to the material.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Machine tool <b>120</b> may be configured to modify material <b>140</b> such that a structure is generated in material <b>140</b> having precise vibrational characteristics that substantially match a set of design goals for the structure. Machine tool <b>120</b> may include cutting surfaces or abrasive surfaces that impart an excitation force to material <b>140</b> during the machining operation. Machine tool <b>120</b> may also include one or more sensors that are configured to measure the excitation force imparted to the material <b>140</b> during the machining operation and generate an excitation signal to be transmitted to signal processing system <b>110</b>. One of ordinary skill in the art will readily appreciate that machine tool <b>120</b> may be any type of machine tool such as a belt sander, milling machine or other rotary machine tool configured to modify a material <b>140</b> in a manner that imparts an excitation force to the material <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Sensor <b>125</b> may be coupled to a material <b>140</b> during the machining process. Sensor <b>125</b> measures the dynamic response of the material <b>140</b> to the excitation force imparted to the material <b>140</b> by machine tool <b>120</b>. In one embodiment, Sensor <b>125</b> may include one or more sensors such as accelerometers, air velocity sensors, microphones, or other sensors placed in proximity to the point of contact between machine tool <b>120</b> and material <b>140</b>. Sensor <b>125</b> generates a dynamic response signal to be transmitted to signal processing system <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In some embodiments, material <b>140</b> may be clamped during the machining process. Because clamping material <b>140</b> may dampen the dynamic response, a transfer function for the clamps may be computed and filtered out of the measured dynamic response associated with the structure. One approach to computing the transfer function of the clamps is to measure the un-damped response of a target structure, measure the damped response of the target structure (i.e., while clamped), and then analyze the difference between the un-damped response and the damped response to calculate a transfer function for the clamps. When machining a structure to comply with a set of design goals with similar vibrational characteristics as the target structure, the damping effect of the clamps may be filtered out using the computed transfer function.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The excitation signal and the dynamic response signal generated during the machining process are transmitted to signal processing system <b>110</b> via communication path <b>112</b>. In one embodiment, communication path <b>112</b> is a wireless communication medium such as a wireless local area network (IEEE 802.11) or other radio frequency communication protocol. A wireless transmitter incorporated into machine tool <b>120</b> may be configured to transmit an excitation signal to a wireless receiver coupled to signal processing system <b>110</b>. In alternative embodiments, communication path <b>112</b> may be a wired connection to signal processing system <b>110</b>. Although a wireless system is not essential for the operation of system <b>100</b>, the wireless system may greatly simplify calibration and machining operations by allowing various tools to be interchanged without requiring a machinist to physically connect the tool to a communication interface disposed within system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As described above, the machining process may include one or more machining operations to modify material <b>140</b> to create the desired structure. Machining operations include cutting operations such as those commonly performed with a milling machine as well as sanding operations such as those commonly performed with a belt or disk sanding machine. As described more fully in detail below, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 4C</figref> illustrate various machine tools that may be implemented within system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2E</figref> illustrate a machine tool <b>200</b> with an integrated force gauge <b>215</b>, according to one embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B and <b>2</b>C are front, right and top views of machine tool <b>200</b>, respectively. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref> is a section view of machine tool <b>200</b> generated from a cutting plane as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2E</figref> is a detail view of force gauge <b>215</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>. As shown, machine tool <b>200</b> is a sanding drum that may be implemented as machine tool <b>120</b> of system <b>100</b>. Machine tool <b>200</b> includes an internal cylinder <b>204</b> coupled to a driveshaft <b>208</b> driven by a drive train (not shown) in rotary motion. An external cylinder <b>202</b> is mounted concentric to the internal cylinder <b>204</b> and supported by bearings <b>206</b>. When machine tool <b>200</b> is rotated by the drive train, causing an abrasive surface to be driven against a material <b>140</b>, the material <b>140</b> exerts a force on the external cylinder <b>202</b> in reaction to the machining operation. The force exerted on external cylinder <b>202</b> may be measured using a force gauge <b>215</b> disposed between the external cylinder <b>202</b> and the internal cylinder <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Machine tool <b>200</b> may also include onboard circuitry <b>210</b> configured to condition the signal generated by force gauge <b>215</b> and to transmit the conditioned signal to signal processing system <b>110</b>. Onboard circuitry <b>210</b> may include signal conditioning circuitry as well as wireless transmitters or other communication interface circuitry. In various embodiments, on-board piezoelectric or Terfenol-D components may generate sufficient current and voltage to power onboard circuitry <b>210</b>. In such embodiments, the piezoelectric or Terfenol-D components may provide power during machining to charge a battery or capacitor (not shown). When the battery or capacitor is sufficiently charged, the battery or capacitor may be coupled to field effect transistors (FETs) to provide power for onboard circuitry <b>210</b> as well as force gauge <b>215</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2D and 2E</figref>, force gauge <b>215</b> is disposed between boss <b>221</b> protruding from external cylinder <b>202</b> and boss <b>222</b> protruding from internal cylinder <b>204</b>. Internal cylinder <b>204</b> may also include boss <b>223</b> that holds set screw <b>225</b>, which is configured to adjust the backlash between the external cylinder <b>202</b> and internal cylinder <b>204</b> by applying a preload to force gauge <b>215</b>. Force gauge <b>215</b> may comprise an appropriate sensor material such as a piezoelectric material, Terfenol-D, or other material that generates an electrical signal in proportion to the force exerted against the material.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The integrated force gauge <b>215</b> generates an excitation signal in response to a force exerted by material <b>140</b> against external cylinder <b>202</b> during a machining operation. As the internal cylinder <b>204</b> is rotated, external cylinder <b>202</b> is driven in the same direction via the interference between boss <b>221</b>, boss <b>222</b> and the force gauge <b>215</b>. As material <b>140</b> is machined, the forces generated by the machining operation act against the external cylinder <b>202</b> such that boss <b>221</b> compresses force gauge <b>215</b> against boss <b>222</b>. This compressive force causes force gauge <b>215</b> to generate an excitation signal that is proportional to the force exerted against external cylinder <b>202</b> by the machining operation. The excitation signal may be transmitted to signal processing system <b>100</b> via onboard circuitry <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A-3D</figref> illustrate a machine tool <b>300</b> with an integrated force gauge <b>315</b>, according to another embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</figref>, <b>3</b>B, <b>3</b>C and <b>3</b>D are front, right, top and bottom views of machine tool <b>300</b>, respectively. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, machine tool <b>300</b> is a cutting bit that may be coupled to a machine such as a milling machine for performing machining operations. Machine tool <b>300</b> includes a body <b>302</b>, coupled to which are a number of cutting surfaces <b>304</b> and a corresponding number of force gauges <b>315</b> disposed between the body <b>302</b> and the cutting surfaces <b>304</b> and configured to measure the force of impact of each cutting action during a machining operation performed on material <b>140</b>. The force of impact corresponding to each cutting action excites material <b>140</b> in a random pattern similar to the force of an impact hammer or random noise signal generator.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The force signal measured by force gauges <b>315</b> may be amplified and transmitted to signal processing system <b>100</b> via onboard circuitry <b>310</b>. Similarly to onboard circuitry <b>210</b> of machine tool <b>200</b>, onboard circuitry <b>310</b> may include signal conditioning circuitry as well as wireless transmitters or other communication interface circuitry. Machine tool <b>300</b> includes power generation components <b>312</b> that may include piezoelectric or Terfenol-D components coupled to FETs and configured to charge a battery or capacitor that provides power to onboard circuitry <b>310</b> as well as force gauge <b>315</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A-4C</figref> illustrate a machine tool <b>400</b> with an integrated force gauge <b>415</b>, according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B and <b>4</b>D are front, right and top views of machine tool <b>400</b>, respectively. Similar to machine tool <b>300</b> described above, machine tool <b>400</b> is a cutting bit that may be coupled to a machine such as a milling machine for performing machining operations. Machine tool <b>400</b> includes a body <b>402</b> as well as a cutting surface <b>404</b> and a force gauge <b>415</b>. The force of the impact of cutting surface <b>404</b> with material <b>140</b> during the machining operation excites material <b>140</b> in a random pattern. Force gauge <b>415</b> measures the force of impact and generates an excitation signal that represents the excitation force applied to material <b>140</b> by machine tool <b>400</b> during a machining operation. Machine tool <b>400</b> also includes onboard circuitry <b>410</b> and power generation components <b>412</b> similar to those included in machine tool <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The force gauge <b>415</b> of machine tool <b>400</b> is disposed against cutting surface <b>404</b> such that the force of impact of cutting surface <b>404</b> with a material <b>140</b> during a machining operation may be measured. The backlash between the cutting surface <b>404</b> and the force gauge <b>415</b> may be adjusted with set screw <b>425</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow diagram of method steps <b>500</b> for measuring the dynamic response of a structure during a machining process, according to one embodiment of the present invention. Although the method steps are described in conjunction with the systems of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4C</figref>, persons skilled in the art will understand that any system configured to perform the method steps, in any order, is within the scope of the inventions.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The method <b>500</b> begins at step <b>510</b>, where signal processing system <b>110</b> receives an excitation signal from machine tool <b>120</b>. The excitation signal corresponds to the measured excitation force applied to material <b>140</b> during a machining operation. At step <b>520</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> receives a dynamic response signal from sensor <b>125</b>. Sensor <b>125</b> generates the dynamic response signal by measuring the dynamic response of material <b>140</b> to the excitation force imparted to material <b>140</b> by machine tool <b>120</b>. At step <b>530</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> analyzes the excitation signal received at step <b>510</b> and the dynamic response signal received at step <b>520</b> to determine the real-time vibrational characteristics of the material <b>140</b> or structure being machined in material <b>140</b>. In one embodiment, signal processing system <b>110</b> performs a modal analysis for the structure by comparing the dynamic response signal to the excitation signal to determine the resonant frequencies of the structure machined in material <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">At step <b>540</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> determines whether to adjust the parameters of the machining operation. Signal processing system <b>110</b> compares the vibrational characteristics of the material <b>140</b> or structure calculated in step <b>530</b> with a set of design goals for that material <b>140</b> or structure. If the vibrational characteristics of the material <b>140</b> or structure match the vibrational characteristics embodied within the set of design goals, then method <b>500</b> proceeds to step <b>560</b>. However, if the vibrational characteristics of the material <b>140</b> or structure do not match the vibrational characteristics embodied within the set of design goals, then method <b>500</b> proceeds to step <b>550</b> where signal processing system <b>110</b> adjusts the parameters of the machining operation such as by adjusting the tool-path of machine tool <b>120</b>. The method <b>500</b> then proceeds to step <b>560</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At step <b>560</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> determines whether the machining process is finished. If signal processing system <b>110</b> determines that the machining process is not finished, then method <b>500</b> returns to step <b>510</b> and the machining process continues. However, if at step <b>560</b>, signal processing system <b>110</b> determines that the machining process is finished, then method <b>500</b> terminates.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In sum, a method and system are disclosed for measuring the dynamic response of a material or structure during a machining process. The system includes a signal processing system connected to a machine tool that includes one or more sensors that dynamically measure a force that is applied to a material when the machine tool is used to modify the material or fabricate a structure from the material. The sensors generate a force signal based on the measured force and the force signal is transmitted to analysis software executing on a computer system. The analysis software compares the force signal to sensor readings that reflect the dynamic response produced by the material during the machining process. Through this comparison, the analysis software dynamically generates a transfer function associated with the material and may adjust the tool-path of the machine tool based on the transfer function.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">One advantage of the disclosed approach is that the process of machining a material can be dynamically adjusted based on the measured response of the material. The conventional method of machining a material, measuring the vibrational characteristics of the material, and then modifying the material (if possible) based on the measured characteristics, in multiple, iterative passes, is time consuming. In contrast, a machining process that implements the disclosed approach may produce a structure with precise vibrational characteristics in a single step. Thus, a structure necessitating precise vibrational characteristics can be generated with relative ease compared to prior art approaches</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">While the foregoing is directed to embodiments of the present invention, other and further embodiments of the present invention may be devised without departing from the basic scope thereof. For example, aspects of the present invention may be implemented in hardware or software or in a combination of hardware and software. One embodiment of the present invention may be implemented as a program product for use with a computer system. The program(s) of the program product define functions of the embodiments (including the methods described herein) and can be contained on a variety of computer-readable storage media. Illustrative computer-readable storage media include, but are not limited to: (i) non-writable storage media (e.g., read-only memory devices within a computer such as CD-ROM disks readable by a CD-ROM drive, flash memory, ROM chips or any type of solid-state non-volatile semiconductor memory) on which information is permanently stored; and (ii) writeable storage media (e.g., floppy disks within a diskette drive or hard-disk drive or any type of solid-state random-access semiconductor memory) on which alterable information is stored. Such computer-readable storage media, when carrying computer-readable instructions that direct the functions of the present invention, are embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In view of the foregoing, the scope of the present invention is determined by the claims that follow.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for measuring the dynamic response of a material during a machining process, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an excitation signal that corresponds to a force of impact of a machine tool with the material during a machining operation and is generated by one or more sensors disposed within the machine tool and configured to measure the force of impact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a response signal that corresponds to the dynamic response of the material to the force;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a vibrational characteristic of the material by comparing the response signal to the excitation signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the parameters of the machining operation to modify the material based on the vibrational characteristic.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the step of determining comprises performing a modal analysis of the excitation signal and the response signal to determine the resonant frequencies of the material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the step of adjusting comprises adjusting the tool-path of the machine tool during the machining operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a cutting operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a sanding operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more sensors comprise a force gauge made of a piezoelectric material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the response signal is generated by an accelerometer attached to the material in proximity to the machining operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A non-transitory computer readable medium storing instructions for causing a processor to measure the dynamic response of a material during a machining process by performing the steps of:
<claim-text>receiving an excitation signal that corresponds to a force of impact of a machine tool with the material during a machining operation and is generated by one or more sensors disposed within the machine tool and configured to measure the force of impact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a response signal that corresponds to the dynamic response of the material to the force;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a vibrational characteristic of the material by comparing the response signal to the excitation signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the parameters of the machining operation to modify the material based on the vibrational characteristic.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the step of determining comprises performing a modal analysis of the excitation signal and the response signal to determine the resonant frequencies of the material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the step of adjusting comprises adjusting the tool-path of the machine tool during the machining operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a cutting operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a sanding operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more sensors comprise a force gauge made of a piezoelectric material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The non-transitory computer readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the response signal is generated by an accelerometer attached to the material in proximity to the machining operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A system for measuring the dynamic response of a material during a machining process, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a machine tool comprising at least one sensor disposed within the machine tool and configured to measure a force of impact of the machine tool with the material during a machining operation and generate an excitation signal that corresponds to the force of impact;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor array comprising one or more sensors attached to the material and configured to measure the dynamic response of the material to the force of impact and generate a response signal that corresponds to the dynamic response of the material to the force of impact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal processing system configured to:
<claim-text>receive the excitation signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive the response signal,</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine a vibrational characteristic of the material by comparing the excitation signal to the response signal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjust the parameters of the machining operation to modify the material based on the vibrational characteristic.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the step of determining comprises performing a modal analysis of the excitation signal and the response signal to determine the resonant frequencies of the material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the step of adjusting comprises adjusting the tool-path of the machine tool during the machining operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a cutting operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the machining operation is a sanding operation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the sensor array comprises an accelerometer attached to the material in proximity to the machining operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
