<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623669-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623669</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13206033</doc-number>
<date>20110809</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>99137459 A</doc-number>
<date>20101101</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>240</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438  3</main-classification>
<further-classification>438481</further-classification>
<further-classification>136252</further-classification>
<further-classification>136254</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5963790</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Matsuno et al.</name>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438 72</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8330036</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Park</name>
<date>20121200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>136249</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0023145</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cohen et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205118</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>Schermer et al., 2006, &#x201c;Photon Confinement in High-Efficiency, Thin-film III-V Solar Cells Obtained by Epitaxial Lift-Off&#x201d;, Thin Solid Films, vol. 511-512 645-653.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438  3</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438481</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136243</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136244</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136249</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136252</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>136254</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-text>H01L 21/02293</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>H01L 2121/20</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>H01L 21/36</classification-cpc-text>
<classification-cpc-text>H01L 31/042</classification-cpc-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>15</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120107962</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120503</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Horng</last-name>
<first-name>Ray-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tseng</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Horng</last-name>
<first-name>Ray-Hua</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tseng</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Chun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kaohsiung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Law Offices of Albert Wai-Kit Chan, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>National Cheng Kung University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Khiem D</first-name>
<department>2823</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices includes: (a) forming an etch limiting film that includes a sacrificial layer on an epitaxial substrate; (b) growing epitaxially layers of a semiconductor structure on the sacrificial layer; (c) forming on the semiconductor structure a layer of a device substrate that can be magnetized, and a patterned passage unit that extends from the device substrate to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer such that a plurality of semiconductor units are defined in the semiconductor structure and the device substrate; and (d) separating the semiconductor units from the epitaxial substrate by etching laterally the sacrificial layer through the patterned passage unit while a magnetic attraction force is applied to the device substrate.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="84.67mm" wi="151.64mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="223.01mm" wi="124.29mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="112.78mm" wi="130.05mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="128.19mm" wi="168.57mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="218.52mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="105.75mm" wi="148.00mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="221.74mm" wi="165.35mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.09mm" wi="165.35mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="234.61mm" wi="158.41mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="233.68mm" wi="155.87mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="228.26mm" wi="147.83mm" file="US08623669-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority of Taiwanese application no. 099137459, filed on Nov. 1, 2010.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates to a method of fabricating semiconductor devices, more particularly to a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In general, the efficiency of an epitaxial semiconductor device, such as a light emitting diode, a laser diode, a solar cell, etc., is decided primarily by the crystal quality of an epitaxial layer of the epitaxial semiconductor device, which may function based on electroluminescence or photoelectric effects during operation. The epitaxial layer is generally formed by epitaxially growing a semiconductor material on an epitaxial substrate. However, most epitaxial substrates have a poor thermal dissipation property that may result in thermal accumulation during operation. Moreover, the cost of the epitaxial substrate is relatively expensive.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">At present, methods of separating the epitaxial layer from the epitaxial substrate and attaching an alternative substrate to the epitaxial layer are conducted for overcoming the above drawbacks. The alternative substrate has a superior thermal dissipation property, and the fabrication cost may be cut down by recycling the expensive epitaxial substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a conventional fabrication process for making an epitaxial semiconductor chip includes: (a) forming a sacrificial layer on an epitaxial substrate that is formed of single crystal GaAs in the form of a wafer and that has an etching property_quite different from that of the sacrificial layer; (b) epitaxially forming an epitaxial layer of a semiconductor structure on the sacrificial layer, the etching properties of the epitaxial layer and the sacrificial layer are also quite different such that the two layers have a highly selective etch ratio; (c) adhering a temporary layer on the epitaxial layer opposite to the sacrificial layer; (d) wet etching laterally the sacrificial layer along a periphery thereof in order to separate the epitaxial layer from the epitaxial substrate; (e) adhering a device substrate on the epitaxial layer opposite to the temporary layer using a polymer adhesive and removing the temporary layer; and (f) cutting the epitaxial layer and the device substrate to form a plurality of epitaxial semiconductor chips.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In the step (d) of the conventional fabrication process, the sacrificial layer is wet etched merely laterally along a periphery thereof. The efficiency of the etching may be reduced when the size of the epitaxial layer becomes larger.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, an epitaxial semiconductor chip <b>1</b> made from the aforesaid conventional fabrication process includes a device substrate <b>11</b>, an epitaxial layer <b>13</b> of a semiconductor structure, and a polymer adhesive layer <b>12</b> used to adhere the device substrate <b>11</b> to the epitaxial layer <b>13</b>. The polymer adhesive layer <b>12</b> of the epitaxial semiconductor chip <b>1</b> has a low thermal dissipation property and is easily influenced by the environment. When a device made from the epitaxial semiconductor chip <b>1</b> is in use, the internal heat generated by the epitaxial layer <b>13</b> may not be dissipated through the polymer adhesive layer <b>12</b> and the device substrate <b>11</b>, and failure of the device may occur.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, J. J. Schermer et al. (ELSEVIER, <i>Thin Solid Films, </i>511-512 (2006) 645-653) disclosed an epitaxial lift-off (ELO) process that is used at Radboud University and that is capable of efficiently separating an epitaxial layer <b>13</b> from an epitaxial substrate <b>16</b>. The steps of the lift-off process are similar to the aforesaid conventional fabrication process except that a temporary carrier <b>17</b> made from a flexible material and having a size larger than the epitaxial layer <b>13</b> is adhered thereto. When a release layer <b>15</b> is wet etched along a periphery thereof, the flexible temporary carrier <b>17</b> is bent attributed to an external force (Y) applied to the flexible temporary carrier <b>17</b>. A space <b>18</b> between the epitaxial substrate <b>16</b> and the epitaxial layer <b>13</b> is therefore formed and enlarged so as to increase the contact area of an etchant, thereby resulting in an increase in the etching rate. However, the lift-off method shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> has a disadvantage that the bending curvature of the flexible temporary carrier <b>17</b> involves a higher risk of breaking the epitaxial layer <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is desired in the art to provide a fabrication process for efficiently and safely separating the epitaxial layer from the epitaxial substrate.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Therefore, the object of the present invention is to provide a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices that can overcome the aforesaid drawbacks of the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to the present invention, a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices includes: (a) forming an etch limiting film that includes a sacrificial layer on an epitaxial substrate; (b) growing epitaxially layers of a semiconductor structure on the sacrificial layer; (c) forming on the semiconductor structure a layer of a device substrate that can be magnetized, and a patterned passage unit that extends from the device substrate to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer such that a plurality of semiconductor units are defined in the semiconductor structure and the device substrate; and (d) separating the semiconductor units from the epitaxial substrate by etching laterally the sacrificial layer through the patterned passage unit while a magnetic attraction force is applied to the device substrate.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent in the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments of the invention, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a flow chart showing a conventional fabrication process of fabricating an epitaxial semiconductor chip;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a conventional epitaxial semiconductor chip made from the conventional process of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an epitaxial lift-off (ELO) method of fabricating an epitaxial semiconductor device in the presence of a flexible temporary carrier;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> show successive steps of the first preferred embodiment of a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices according to the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an epitaxial semiconductor device made according to the first preferred embodiment of the method of this invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a step of forming a device substrate and a patterned passage unit of the second preferred embodiment of a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices according to the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Before the present invention is described in greater detail with reference to the accompanying preferred embodiments, it should be noted herein that like elements are denoted by the same reference numerals throughout the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 to 8</figref> illustrate the first preferred embodiment of a method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a first buffer layer <b>221</b>, an etch termination layer <b>222</b>, a second buffer layer <b>223</b>, and a sacrificial layer <b>224</b> are formed in the order as specified on an epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> that is made of single crystal GaAs in the form of a wafer. The first and second buffer layers <b>221</b>, <b>223</b> are formed to adjust the epitaxial structure of layers formed thereabove. The first buffer layer <b>221</b>, the etch termination layer <b>222</b>, the second buffer layer <b>223</b>, and the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> cooperatively define an etch limiting film <b>22</b>. The etching properties of the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> and the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> are quite different, i.e., the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> and the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> have a high selective etch ratio, such that the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> can be removed by etching in a successive step without damage to the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a layer of a semiconductor structure <b>23</b> is grown epitaxially on the sacrificial layer <b>224</b>. Similarly, the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> and the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> have a high selective etch ratio such that the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> may not be damaged when the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> is etched in a successive step.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a layer of a device substrate <b>24</b> that can be magnetized and a patterned passage unit <b>25</b> that extends from the device substrate <b>24</b> to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> are formed on the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> subsequently. Thus, a plurality of semiconductor units <b>2</b> are defined in the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> and the device substrate <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">To be specific, the steps of forming the device substrate <b>24</b> and the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> include: forming on the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> one of a conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> and a magnetic layer <b>242</b>; etching the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> and the etch limiting film <b>22</b> by using the one of the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> and the magnetic layer <b>242</b> as a mask to form the patterned passage unit <b>25</b>; filling a filler <b>27</b> in the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> until the filler <b>27</b> overflows from the patterned passage unit <b>25</b>; forming the other one of the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> and the magnetic layer <b>242</b> on the previous one of the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> and the magnetic layer <b>242</b> without covering the filler <b>27</b> that overflows; and etching the filler <b>27</b> from a part of the filler <b>27</b> that overflows and removing the filler <b>27</b> entirely from the patterned passage unit <b>25</b>. The patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> and the magnetic layer <b>242</b> cooperatively define the device substrate <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Particularly, in the first preferred embodiment, the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> is formed prior to the magnetic layer <b>242</b>, and the steps are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>a</i>), the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> made from a conductive material, e.g., Au, Ni, Cu, Co, or their relative alloys, is formed on the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> by electroplating. The patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> is formed to serve as a seed layer for electroplating a magnetic layer thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>b</i>), the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> and the etch limiting film <b>22</b> are dry etched using the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> as a mask to form the patterned passage unit <b>25</b>. The patterned passage unit <b>25</b> extends from the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer <b>224</b>. Preferably, the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> extends to the second buffer layer <b>223</b>. In such case, the etch termination layer <b>222</b> and the second buffer layer <b>223</b> are to be designed to have a highly selective etch ratio such that, in a successive step, the etching rate of the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> can be increased, thereby resulting in an improvement in removal of the sacrificial layer <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7(</figref><i>c</i>) and <b>7</b>(<i>d</i>), a filler <b>27</b> is filled in the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> until the filler <b>27</b> overflows to a surface of the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b>. Preferably, the filler <b>27</b> is made from a photoresist material commonly used in a photolithography process.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In particular, the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> may include a plurality of passages <b>251</b> arranged in a pattern and each of which extends downwardly from the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> to the second buffer layer <b>223</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7(</figref><i>c</i>) and <b>7</b>(<i>d</i>). The filler <b>27</b> forms a filler body <b>271</b> within each of the passages <b>251</b> and a protruding part <b>272</b> protruding laterally from a top periphery of the respective one of the passages <b>251</b>. Preferably, a distance from an outer peripheral end of the protruding part <b>272</b> to the top periphery of the respective passage <b>251</b> (indicated as &#x201c;L&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7(</figref><i>c</i>)) is larger than 30 &#x3bc;m such that, in a successive electroplating step, the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> may not be electrically connected with the device substrate <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7(</figref><i>e</i>) and <b>7</b>(<i>f</i>), a magnetic layer <b>242</b> made from a magnetic metal is formed on the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> by electroplating without covering the protruding part <b>272</b> of the filler <b>27</b>. The filler <b>27</b> is etched from the protruding part <b>272</b> thereof and is entirely removed from the patterned passage unit <b>25</b>. In the first preferred embodiment, the filler <b>27</b> is made from a photoresist material and is removed using acetone. Alternatively, the filler <b>27</b> may be SiO<sub>2 </sub>which may be removed using HF.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">After the device substrate <b>24</b> and the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> are formed on the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> to define a plurality of semiconductor units <b>2</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the semiconductor units <b>2</b> are separated from the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> by wet etching laterally the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> through the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> while a magnetic attractive force (indicated as &#x201c;X&#x201d;) is applied to the device substrate <b>24</b>. In particular, when the direction of the magnetic attractive force (X) is opposite to the direction of gravity (indicated as &#x201c;Z&#x201d; in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>), the upward magnetic attractive force (X) and the downward gravity force (Z) would enhance the removing rate of the sacrificial layer <b>224</b>. In this embodiment, the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> is etched using HF.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Preferably, after the semiconductor units <b>2</b> are separated from the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b>, the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> may be recovered by chemically washing and etching. To be specific, the reusable epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> is obtained by etching the second buffer layer <b>223</b> and the etch termination layer <b>222</b> while the first buffer layer <b>221</b> remains thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">More preferably, before the sacrificial layer <b>224</b> is etched laterally, a protective film (not shown) may be formed covering a surface of the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> opposite to the etch limiting film <b>22</b> so as to protect the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> from etching by an etchant used in the subsequent wet etching step.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, an epitaxial semiconductor device <b>2</b> made according to the first preferred embodiment of the method of this invention includes the device substrate <b>24</b> and the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> formed on the device substrate <b>24</b>. The device substrate <b>24</b> includes the magnetic layer <b>242</b> and the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> formed on the magnetic layer <b>242</b> and has a pattern the same as that of the magnetic layer <b>242</b>. In this embodiment, the conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> is made from a metal with a high light reflectivity, such as Cu. During operation, the internal heat generated by the epitaxial semiconductor device <b>2</b> may be dissipated through the metal conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> of the device substrate <b>24</b>, thereby resulting in improvement of stability and increase of service life of the epitaxial semiconductor device <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A solar cell <b>6</b> may be obtained by forming an electrode <b>61</b> on the epitaxial semiconductor device <b>2</b>. When exposed to light, a voltage or a corresponding electric current is generated between the electrode <b>61</b> and the device substrate <b>24</b> according to photovoltaic effect. The metal conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> of the device substrate <b>24</b> may reflect the light that is incident thereon, thereby resulting in an increase in the output photoelectric current. Alternatively, the epitaxial semiconductor device <b>2</b> may be used for manufacturing high-electron-mobility transistors (HEMTs) or any other semiconductor devices known to one skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the second preferred embodiment of the method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices of the present invention has steps the same as those of the first embodiment, except that the magnetic layer <b>242</b> of the device substrate <b>24</b> is formed prior to the patterned conductive substrate layer <b>241</b> of the device substrate <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In conclusion, according to the method of the present invention, the layer of a semiconductor structure <b>23</b> can be efficiently separated from the epitaxial substrate <b>21</b> by virtue of the formation of the patterned passage unit <b>25</b> on the layer of the semiconductor structure <b>23</b> which causes an improved wet etching rate of the sacrificial layer <b>224</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In addition, the method of the present invention is conducted without using a polymer adhesive that has a poor thermal dissipation property. During operation, the internal heat generated by the semiconductor device <b>2</b> may be dissipated by virtue of the device substrate <b>24</b> of the device <b>2</b> that is made from metal. Therefore, the drawback, i.e., the thermal accumulation, associated with the device made from a conventional method may be overcome.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">While the present invention has been described in connection with what are considered the most practical and preferred embodiments, it is understood that this invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiments but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretations and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices, comprising:
<claim-text>(a) forming an etch limiting film that includes a sacrificial layer on an epitaxial substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) growing epitaxially layers of a semiconductor structure on the sacrificial layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) forming on the semiconductor structure a layer of a device substrate that can be magnetized, and a patterned passage unit that extends from the device substrate to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer such that a plurality of semiconductor units are defined in the semiconductor structure and the device substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) separating the semiconductor units from the epitaxial substrate by etching laterally the sacrificial layer through the patterned passage unit while a magnetic attraction force is applied to the device substrate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the etch limiting film is formed by forming on the epitaxial substrate a first buffer layer, an etch termination layer, a second buffer layer, and the sacrificial layer in the order as specified.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the step (c) includes: forming a patterned conductive substrate layer from a conductive material on the semiconductor structure; etching the semiconductor structure and the etch limiting film using the patterned conductive substrate layer as a mask to form the patterned passage unit; filling a filler in the patterned passage unit until the filler overflows to a surface of the patterned conductive substrate layer; forming a magnetic layer from a magnetic metal on the patterned conductive substrate layer without covering the filler that overflows; and etching the filler from a part of the filler that overflows and removing entirely the filler from the patterned passage unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the patterned passage unit includes a plurality of passages, which are arranged in a pattern and each of which extends downwardly from the device substrate to the sacrificial layer, the filler forming a filler body within each of the passages and a protruding part protruding laterally from a top periphery of the respective one of the passages.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a step of recovering the epitaxial substrate by chemically washing and etching the epitaxial substrate after the step (d).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a step of forming a protective film covering a surface of the epitaxial substrate opposite to the etch limiting film before the sacrificial layer is etched laterally.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the device substrate includes a magnetic layer made of a magnetic metal, and a conductive substrate layer made of a conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the step (c) includes: forming on the semiconductor structure one of the conductive substrate layer and the magnetic layer; etching the semiconductor structure and the etch limiting film by using the one of the conductive substrate layer and the magnetic layer as a mask to form the patterned passage unit; filling a filler in the patterned passage unit until the filler overflows from the patterned passage unit; forming the other one of the conductive substrate layer and the magnetic layer on the previous one of the conductive substrate layer and the magnetic layer without covering the filler that overflows; and etching the filler from a part of the filler that overflows and removing the filler entirely from the patterned passage unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the filler is made from a photoresist material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of fabricating epitaxial semiconductor devices, comprising:
<claim-text>(a) forming an etch limiting film that includes a sacrificial layer on an epitaxial substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) growing epitaxially layers of a semiconductor structure on the sacrificial layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) forming on the semiconductor structure a layer of a device substrate that can be magnetized, and a patterned passage unit that extends from the device substrate to a depth as deep as the sacrificial layer such that a plurality of semiconductor units are defined in the semiconductor structure and the device substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) separating the semiconductor units from the epitaxial substrate by etching laterally the sacrificial layer through the patterned passage unit while a magnetic attraction force is applied to the device substrate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the step (c) includes: forming a patterned magnetic layer from a magnetic metal on the semiconductor structure; etching the semiconductor structure and the etch limiting film using the patterned magnetic layer as a mask to form the patterned passage unit; filling a filler in the patterned passage unit until the filler overflows to a surface of the magnetic layer; forming a conductive substrate layer from a conductive material on the magnetic layer without covering the filler that overflows; and etching the filler from a part of the filler that overflows and removing the filler entirely from the patterned passage unit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
