<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621926-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621926</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13083806</doc-number>
<date>20110411</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-107007</doc-number>
<date>20100507</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>191</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20120101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>19</main-group>
<subgroup>56</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>48</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350412</main-classification>
<further-classification>174264</further-classification>
<further-classification>257774</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Wiring substrate, piezoelectric oscillator and gyrosensor</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7400078</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Takahashi et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310348</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8299624</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Matsuo</name>
<date>20121000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257774</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0001173</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamano et al.</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0131721</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ito</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0267210</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamano et al.</name>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0014843</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kawashita et al.</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0309218</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kadiyska et al.</name>
<date>20090100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257737</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0283847</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kawasaki et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0233773</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kawashita et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-223265</doc-number>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-013330</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-179562</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-053149</doc-number>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-305897</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-158862</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20090700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7350412</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>174264</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257774</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>15</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110271757</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoda</last-name>
<first-name>Tsuyoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Matsumoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoda</last-name>
<first-name>Tsuyoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Matsumoto</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Harness, Dickey &#x26; Pierce, P.L.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Seiko Epson Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chapman, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A wiring substrate includes: a substrate having a first surface and a second surface; a first insulating layer stacked on the first surface; a pad electrode stacked on the first insulating layer; a through electrode connected to the pad electrode; and a second insulating layer disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode, wherein a diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side, the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section, when seen from a plan view, and the thickness of the first insulating layer in the area is thinner than the thickness of the first insulating layer in other areas.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="93.98mm" wi="202.18mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.32mm" wi="120.06mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="234.53mm" wi="174.92mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="225.55mm" wi="194.73mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="242.23mm" wi="157.65mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="239.69mm" wi="165.95mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="107.70mm" wi="101.85mm" file="US08621926-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a technology which enhances electric and mechanical reliability of a wiring substrate which has a through electrode formed in a semiconductor chip or the like, a piezoelectric oscillator using the same, and a gyrosensor.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In recent years, packages in which a resin layer is formed on an active surface of a semiconductor chip called a wafer level chip scale package (WCSP), a rearrangement wiring is formed thereon, and then an external terminal is formed on the wiring have been developed. In such a package, a pad electrode connected to the side of an element such as a piezoelectric oscillator and a pad electrode connected to a mounting destination are formed on the active surface of the semiconductor chip. Further, the pad electrode connected to the mounting destination and the above described wiring are electrically connected by a through electrode which passes through the resin layer, and the pad electrode connected to the element side is electrically connected to a rear surface of the semiconductor chip by the through electrode which passes through the semiconductor chip. Thus, it is possible to provide a configuration in which a front surface of the semiconductor chip is used as a mounting surface having a rearranged external terminal and an element such as a piezoelectric oscillator can be mounted on a rear surface thereof, thereby miniaturizing an overall device. Accordingly, electrical and mechanical reliability of the through electrode formed on the semiconductor chip is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a through electrode in the related art. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in a wiring substrate <b>200</b> on which a semiconductor chip <b>202</b>, a first insulating layer <b>204</b>, and a pad electrode <b>206</b> which is electrically connected to the semiconductor chip <b>202</b> are sequentially stacked, a through electrode <b>216</b> in the related art has a configuration in which a first through hole <b>208</b> is formed which passes through the semiconductor chip <b>202</b> from a side to which the semiconductor chip <b>202</b> is exposed toward the pad electrode <b>206</b> side and reaches the first insulating layer <b>204</b>; a second through hole <b>212</b> is formed in which a second insulating layer <b>210</b> is coated on an inner wall of the first through hole <b>208</b> and which has an inner wall smaller in diameter than the inner wall of the first through hole <b>208</b> with which the second insulating layer <b>210</b> is coated, passes through the second insulating layer <b>210</b> and the first insulating layer <b>204</b> and reaches the pad electrode <b>206</b>; the first through hole <b>208</b> and the second through hole <b>212</b> are filled with a conductive body <b>214</b>; and the conductive body <b>214</b> and the pad electrode <b>206</b> are electrically connected. (refer to JP-A-2007-053149).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, since the through electrode <b>216</b> in the related art has a smaller contact area between the pad electrode <b>206</b> and the conductive body <b>214</b>, there is a problem that reliability of electric connection and endurance during heat stress are reduced. Further, when the through electrode <b>216</b> in the related art is formed, a process of exposing a pad electrode to a through hole side is required, but at this time, damage occurs in the pad electrode, and thus, there is a concern that reliability of mechanical connection between the pad electrode and the conductive body may be reduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An advantage of some aspects of the invention is that it provides a wiring substrate, a piezoelectric oscillator, a gyrosensor and a method of manufacturing the wiring substrate in which reliability of mechanical connection is enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention is contrived to solve at least a part of the problems and can be realized as the following embodiments or application examples.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 1</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">This application example of the invention is directed to a wiring substrate including: a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface; a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface; a pad electrode which is stacked on the first insulating layer; a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer and is connected to the pad electrode; and a second insulating layer which is disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode. A diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side. Further, the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode, when seen from a plan view. Further, the thickness of the first insulating layer in the area is thinner than the thickness of the first insulating layer in other areas.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer is thinly formed, in the area where the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer overlap with each other, compared with the other areas. Accordingly, in the area where the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer overlap with each other, force applied to the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode can be reduced by a difference between a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the first insulating layer and a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the second insulating layer. On the other hand, insulation properties of the substrate and the pad electrode can be also secured by the first insulating layer in the other areas. Thus, electric reliability of the pad electrode and reliability for temperature change in mechanical connection of the overall through electrode can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Further, the portion of the second insulating layer stacked on the first insulating layer is formed in an L shape near the first insulating layer. Thus, a joint area between the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer can be increased, and a mechanical strength of the overall through electrode can be maintained.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 2</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">This application example is directed to the wiring substrate of the application example 1, wherein materials of the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer are different from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer are etched by different etching processes. Accordingly, at the time of etching of the second insulating layer, the first insulating layer is not etched, thereby making it possible to avoid damage to the pad electrode. Further, since an area opposite to the pad electrode of the first insulating layer before forming the second concave portion is formed to be thinner than other areas, the etching time in the portion can be reduced. Thus, etching damage to the pad electrode and the second insulating layer at the time of forming the second concave portion can be suppressed, and thus, reliability of electrical and mechanical connection between the pad electrode and the conductive body and reliability of the second insulating layer are enhanced.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 3</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">This application example is directed to the wiring substrate of the application example 1 or 2, wherein the through electrode has a wider diameter as it approaches the second surface from the first surface.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">With such a configuration, the first concave portion and the second insulating layer can be also formed to have wider diameters as they approach the second surface from the first surface. Thus, the through electrode can be easily coated in the first concave portion, and since a contact area between the through electrode and the second insulating layer and a contact area between the second insulating layer and the first concave portion are increased, a joint strength of the through electrode can be enhanced.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 4</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">This application example is directed to the wiring substrate of any one of the application examples 1 to 3, wherein the first insulating layer has a thinner thickness in the area, as it approaches the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">With such a configuration, a contact area between the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer is increased to thereby enhance a joint strength. Further, since the center portion of the first insulating layer, being in contact with the second concave portion, is thinly formed, it is possible to reduce stress applied to the contact portion between the pad electrode and the through electrode due to the thermal expansion and contraction difference between the first insulating layer and the conductive body at the time when a heat stress is applied.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 5</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">This application example is directed to the wiring substrate of any one of the application examples 1 to 4, wherein a material of the second insulating layer is an organic resin.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">With such a configuration, since the second insulating layer can be formed at low temperature, damage due to heat to the wiring substrate can be suppressed.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 6</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">This application of the invention is directed to a piezoelectric oscillator including: a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface; a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface; a pad electrode which is stacked on the first insulating layer; a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer and is connected to the pad electrode; a second insulating layer which is disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode; and a piezoelectric oscillator which is installed on the substrate and is electrically connected to the pad electrode. A diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side. Further, the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode, when seen from a plan view. Further, the thickness of the first insulating layer in the area is thinner than the thickness of the first insulating layer in other areas.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer is thinly formed, in the area where the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer overlap with each other, compared with the other areas. Thus, force applied to the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode can be reduced by a difference between a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the first insulating layer and a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the second insulating layer, and reliability for temperature change in the mechanical connection of the overall through electrode can be enhanced. Further, the portion of the second insulating layer stacked on the first insulating layer is formed in an L shape near the first insulating layer. Thus, a joint area between the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer can be increased, and the mechanical strength of the overall through electrode can be maintained.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 7</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">This application example of the invention is directed to a gyrosensor including: a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface; a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface; a pad electrode which is stacked on the first insulating layer; a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer and is connected to the pad electrode; a second insulating layer which is disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode; and a gyrosensor element which is installed on the substrate and is electrically connected to the pad electrode. A diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side. Further, the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode, when seen from a plan view. Further, the thickness of the first insulating layer in the area is thinner than the thickness of the first insulating layer in other areas.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer is thinly formed, in the area where the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer overlap with each other, compared with the other areas. Thus, force applied to the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode can be reduced by a difference between a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the first insulating layer and a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the second insulating layer, and reliability for temperature change in the mechanical connection of the overall through electrode can be enhanced. Further, the portion of the second insulating layer stacked on the first insulating layer is formed in an L shape near the first insulating layer. Thus, a joint area between the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer can be increased, and the mechanical strength of the overall through electrode can be maintained.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 8</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">This application example of the invention is directed to a method of manufacturing a wiring substrate which includes a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface, a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface, a pad electrode which is formed on the first insulating layer, and a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer, including: forming a through hole which passes through the substrate toward the pad electrode from the second surface of the substrate; forming a first concave portion which is continuously connected to the through hole on the first insulating layer; forming a second concave portion which is formed to pass through the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer with the pad electrode being a bottom section thereof, on an inner circumferential side of the second insulating layer stacked on the first concave portion, when seen from a plan view; and filling the first concave portion and the second concave portion with a conductive body or forming the conductive body to coat inner walls of the first concave portion and the second concave portion, and forming the through electrode connected to the pad electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer is thinly formed in the area where the second insulating layer and the first insulating layer overlap with each other, compared with the other areas. Accordingly, force applied to the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode can be reduced by a difference between a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the first insulating layer and a coefficient of the thermal expansion of the second insulating layer, and reliability for temperature change in the mechanical connection of the overall through electrode can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Further, the portion of the second insulating layer stacked on the first insulating layer is formed in an L shape near the first insulating layer. Thus, a joint area between the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer can be increased, and the mechanical strength of the overall through electrode can be maintained.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 9</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">This application example of the invention is directed to the method of manufacturing a wiring substrate of the application example 8, wherein the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer are formed of different materials.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">With such a configuration, the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer are etched by different etching processes. Accordingly, at the time of etching of the second insulating layer, the first insulating layer is not etched, thereby making it possible to avoid damage to the pad electrode. Further, since an area opposite to the pad electrode of the first insulating layer before forming the second concave portion is formed to be thinner than other areas, the etching time in the portion can be reduced. Thus, etching damage to the pad electrode and the second insulating layer at the time of forming the second concave portion can be suppressed, and thus, reliability of electrical and mechanical connection between the pad electrode and the conductive body and reliability of the second insulating layer can be enhanced.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">APPLICATION EXAMPLE 10</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">This application example of the invention is directed to the method of manufacturing a wiring substrate of the application example 9, wherein the first insulating layer is removed by dry etching when the second concave portion is formed.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">With such a configuration, etching damage to the pad electrode and the first insulating layer at the time of forming the second concave portion can be further suppressed.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The invention will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein like numbers reference like elements.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref> are diagrams schematically illustrating a wiring substrate having a through electrode according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> are diagrams illustrating a manufacturing process of a through electrode according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A to 3C</figref> are diagrams illustrating a manufacturing process of a through electrode according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A to 4C</figref> are diagrams illustrating a manufacturing process of a through electrode according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A to 5C</figref> are diagrams illustrating a manufacturing process of a through electrode according to the embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram schematically illustrating a through electrode in the related art.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Hereinafter, an embodiment will be described in detail with reference to the following drawings. Here, the range according to the invention is not limited by elements, types, combinations, shapes, relative positions, or the like disclosed in this embodiment, unless a limitative disclosure is particularly defined, which are merely explanation examples.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref> illustrate a wiring substrate having a through electrode according to the present embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a cross-sectional diagram of the wiring substrate and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a partial detail diagram in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>. A wiring substrate <b>10</b> in the embodiment includes a substrate (base substrate <b>12</b>) having a first surface (front surface <b>12</b><i>a</i>) and a second surface (rear surface <b>12</b><i>b</i>); a first insulating layer <b>14</b> stacked on the first surface (front surface <b>12</b><i>a</i>); a pad electrode <b>16</b> stacked on the first insulating layer <b>14</b>; a through electrode <b>20</b> which passes through the base substrate <b>12</b> and the first insulating layer <b>14</b> and is connected to the pad electrode <b>16</b>; and a second insulating layer <b>24</b> disposed between the base substrate <b>12</b> and the through electrode <b>20</b> and between the first insulating layer <b>14</b> and the through electrode <b>20</b>. The diameter of the through electrode <b>20</b> in a connection section (bottom section <b>22</b><i>a</i>) between the pad electrode <b>16</b> and the through electrode <b>20</b> is smaller than the diameter of the through electrode <b>20</b> on the second surface side. Further, the first insulating layer <b>14</b>, the second insulating layer <b>24</b> and the through electrode <b>20</b> overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section (bottom section <b>22</b><i>a</i>) between the through electrode <b>20</b> and the pad electrode <b>16</b>, when seen from a plan view. Further, the thickness of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>in the area (bottom section <b>22</b><i>a</i>) is thinner than the thickness of the first insulating layer <b>14</b> in other areas.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The base substrate <b>12</b> is formed of a semiconductor of Si or the like, and an integrated circuit (IC, not shown) is formed on its surface. Further, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> formed of SiO<sub>2</sub>, SiN or the like is formed on the surface of the integrated circuit. A plurality of pad electrodes <b>16</b> formed of Al or the like are formed in a predetermined position on the first insulating layer <b>14</b>. In this way, the wiring substrate <b>10</b> is formed by the base substrate <b>12</b>, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> and the pad electrode <b>16</b>. The pad electrode <b>16</b> and the integrated circuit (not shown) are electrically connected by a through electrode (not shown) which passes through the first insulating layer <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The integrated circuit (not shown) is formed on the front surface <b>12</b><i>a </i>on the base substrate <b>12</b>. The pad electrode <b>16</b> formed of the integrated circuit (not shown) is connected to a driving element <b>56</b> such as a piezoelectric oscillator (not shown), a gyrosensor element (not shown) or the like, and a pad electrode <b>18</b> for power supply or data transmission/reception, or the like is further provided to the integrated circuit (not shown). Here, the pad electrode <b>16</b> connected to the driving element <b>56</b> is connected to the through electrode <b>20</b> formed on the base substrate <b>12</b> and is electrically led out the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> through the through electrode <b>20</b>. Further, the through electrode <b>20</b> is connected to a rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> which is formed to be rearranged corresponding to electrode arrangement of the driving element <b>56</b> on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>. Further, the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> is connected to a connection electrode <b>36</b> which is connected to an electrode of the driving element <b>56</b> through a conductive adhesive <b>58</b>. Thus, the pad electrode <b>16</b> is electrically connected to the electrode of the driving element <b>56</b>. On the other hand, the pad electrode <b>18</b> for power supply or data transmission/reception is electrically connected to a rearrangement wiring <b>46</b> which is formed on a resin layer <b>40</b> stacked on the pad electrode <b>18</b> and is formed to be rearranged corresponding to electrode arrangement of a mounting destination and an external electrode, through a through electrode which passes through the resin layer. Further, the pad electrode <b>18</b> is electrically connected to the mounting destination.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Accordingly, in this embodiment, the driving element <b>56</b> is connected to the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>with the front surface <b>12</b><i>a </i>(surface on which the integrated circuit is formed) of the base substrate <b>12</b> being directed toward the mounting side, and the through electrode <b>20</b> is applied to the pad electrode <b>16</b> connected to the above-described driving element <b>56</b>. However, the driving element <b>56</b> may be connected to the front surface <b>12</b><i>a </i>with the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> being directed toward the mounting side, and the through electrode <b>20</b> may be applied to the pad electrode <b>18</b> for power supply or data transmission/reception.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A first concave portion <b>22</b> is formed in a taper shape with an inner radius that becomes larger as it approaches the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, passes through the base substrate <b>12</b> in a position of the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, which is opposite to the pad electrode <b>16</b>, and reaches a midstream position of the first insulating layer <b>14</b>. Accordingly, a first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>under the pad electrode <b>16</b> is formed to be thinner than other portions of the first insulating layer <b>14</b>. The first concave portion <b>22</b> may be formed in a cylindrical shape, not in the taper shape.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The second insulating layer <b>24</b> is formed of an organic resin such as polyimide, epoxy or the like, and is formed to cover the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, an inner wall <b>22</b><i>b </i>or the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>. Thus, since the second insulating layer <b>24</b> can be formed at low temperature, it is possible to suppress damage due to heat to the wiring substrate <b>10</b>. At this time, a portion of the second insulating section <b>24</b> stacked on the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b> becomes a bottom section <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the second insulating layer <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A second concave portion <b>26</b> is formed to pass through the second insulating layer <b>24</b> and the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and to reach the pad electrode <b>16</b>, on an inner circumferential side of the bottom section <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the second insulating layer <b>24</b>. Thus, the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the bottom section <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the second insulating layer <b>24</b> have a flange shape. Thus, as shown in the cross-sectional diagrams in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</figref>, the bottom section <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the second insulating section <b>24</b> has an L shape.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Here, the through electrode <b>20</b> has a wider diameter as it approaches the second surface (rear surface <b>12</b><i>b</i>) from the first surface (front surface <b>12</b><i>a</i>). That is, the first concave portion <b>22</b> is formed in a taper shape. Thus, the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> can be also formed to be wider in diameter as it approaches the second surface (rear surface <b>12</b><i>b</i>) from the first surface (front surface <b>12</b><i>a</i>). Thus, the through electrode <b>20</b> can be easily coated to the first concave portion <b>22</b>, and since a contact area between the through electrode <b>20</b> and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> and a contact area between the second insulating layer <b>24</b> and the first concave portion <b>22</b> are increased, it is possible to enhance a joint strength of the through electrode <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Further, in the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>, the thickness of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>becomes thin toward the center of the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a</i>, that is, is formed in a obtuse taper shape. Thus, the contact area between the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the second insulating layer can be increased to thereby enhance a joint strength. Further, since the center portion of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>being in contact with the second concave portion is thinly formed, it is possible to reduce stress applied to a contact portion between the pad electrode <b>16</b> and a conductive body due to the thermal expansion and contraction difference between the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the conductive body at the time when it is subjected to heat stress.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Further, the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> each have a circular inner wall from a plan view, but a diameter D<b>2</b> of the second concave portion is smaller than an inner circumferential diameter D<b>1</b> of the bottom section <b>24</b><i>a </i>of the second insulating layer <b>24</b>, and the second concave portion <b>26</b> is formed at the center of the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>. Thus, the second insulating layer <b>24</b> has an L-bent shape in a portion stacked on the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>. Thus, a joint area between the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> can be increased, and a mechanical strength of the overall through electrode <b>20</b> can be maintained.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In this way, the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> which include the first insulating layer <b>14</b> and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> are filled with a barrier layer <b>28</b>, a seed layer <b>30</b>, and a conductive body <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The barrier layer <b>28</b> is formed by sputtering a metal material such as TiW or the like, for example, and is formed to prevent diffusion to the base substrate <b>12</b> (Si) of the conductive body <b>32</b>. The barrier layer <b>28</b> is stacked on the second insulating layer <b>24</b> disposed on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, the second insulating layer <b>24</b> which is coated in the inner wall <b>22</b><i>b </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>, an end portion of the second insulating layer <b>24</b> in the second concave portion <b>26</b>, an end portion of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>, and the pad electrode <b>16</b>. The seed layer <b>30</b> is formed to coat the barrier layer <b>28</b> with Cu or the like, and is used for forming the conductive layer <b>32</b> by plating.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The conductive body <b>32</b> is formed by the plating of Cu or the like, and is formed to fill the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b>, or to coat the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> along the inner wall (on which the barrier layer <b>28</b> and the seed layer <b>30</b> are coated) thereof in a film shape. Further, the conductive layer <b>32</b> is also formed on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>(on which the barrier layer <b>28</b> and the seed layer <b>30</b> are coated) of the base substrate <b>12</b>, and the conductive body <b>32</b> is electrically connected to the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> and the connection electrode <b>36</b> which are formed on the side of the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>. Thus, the pad electrode <b>16</b> is electrically connected to the driving element <b>56</b> through the barrier layer <b>28</b>, the seed layer <b>30</b>, the conductive body <b>32</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b>, and the connection electrode <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">However, in this embodiment, the base substrate <b>12</b> is formed of Si. On the other hand, in this embodiment, a path <b>38</b> (L shape) which leads to the base substrate <b>12</b> of a contact interface between the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> which are electrically connected to the conductive body <b>32</b> becomes long. Accordingly, even though the base substrate <b>12</b> is formed of a semiconductor, a problem that an electric current leaks to the base substrate <b>12</b> through the above-described path <b>38</b> from the conductive body <b>32</b> is reduced. Accordingly, if such a through electrode <b>20</b> is applied to the semiconductor, the leakage current can be reduced and reliability of the through electrode <b>20</b> can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> through <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A to 5C</figref> illustrate a manufacturing process of the through electrode according to this embodiment. A manufacturing procedure of the through electrode <b>20</b> in this embodiment will be described. Firstly, a WCSP structure as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is formed on the side of the base substrate <b>12</b> of the wiring substrate <b>10</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>. An outer appearance of the wiring substrate <b>10</b> is formed by the base substrate <b>12</b> (IC), the first insulating layer <b>14</b>, and the pad electrodes <b>16</b> and <b>18</b>. Then, the resin layer <b>40</b> is formed on the pad electrodes <b>16</b> and <b>18</b>, and a through hole <b>42</b> is formed in a position opposite to the pad electrode <b>18</b> of the resin layer <b>40</b>. A through electrode <b>44</b> is filled in the though hole <b>42</b>, and the rearrangement wiring <b>46</b> connected to the through electrode <b>44</b> and an external electrode <b>48</b> which is connected to the rearrangement wiring <b>46</b> and is connected to the electrode for a mounting destination are formed on the resin layer <b>40</b>. Thus, the WCSP structure is formed by the resin layer <b>40</b>, the through electrode <b>44</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>46</b> and the external electrode <b>48</b>. The WCSP structure may be stacked over a plurality of stages so that the combination of the resin layer <b>40</b>, the through electrode <b>44</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>46</b>, and the external electrode <b>48</b> are electrically connected. The pad electrode <b>18</b> connected by the WCSP structure is used for power supply or data input/output. On the other hand, the pad electrode <b>16</b> to which the through electrode <b>20</b> in this embodiment is applied is the pad electrode <b>16</b> connected to the above-described driving element <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Secondly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref>, support glass <b>50</b> is attached to the front surface <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, that is, a surface with the WCSP structure, through an adhesive <b>52</b>. The support glass <b>50</b> reinforces the base substrate <b>12</b> which is thinly processed, to thereby prevent cracking in processes after the thinning process, and secure mobility. Since there is a possibility that the support glass <b>50</b> is heated in the subsequent processes, it is preferable that the support glass <b>50</b> has a line expansion coefficient close to that of the base substrate <b>12</b> (Si). For example, Pyrex (registered trademark), quartz glass or the like may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Thirdly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, the base substrate <b>12</b> is made thin. The rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> which is exposed is made thin to the thickness of about 100 &#x3bc;m, for example, by back grinding. With respect to the back-grinded surface, for example, a fractured layer of Si formed by the back grinding may be removed by a method such as dry etching, spin etching, polishing or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Fourthly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, the etching of the base substrate <b>12</b> is performed to form the first concave portion <b>22</b>. The etching is performed toward the pad electrode <b>16</b> from the position opposite to the pad electrode <b>16</b> of the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>, and a hole which leads to the first insulating layer <b>14</b> (first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>) under the pad electrode <b>16</b> is formed. To this end, a method of dry etching such as RIE, ICP or the like, and a laser method are used. In the case of dry etching, a Bosch process of digging while alternately repeating etching and deposition is used. In this case, gases of SF<sub>6 </sub>and O<sub>2 </sub>are used in the etching, and gases of C<sub>4</sub>F<sub>8 </sub>and O<sub>2 </sub>are used in the deposition. In this regard, a portion except a portion which is to be opened in the first concave portion <b>22</b> is coated and protected by resist or the like, and the coated layer such as a resist or the like is removed after the dry etching process. As described above, in this embodiment, the first concave portion <b>22</b> is formed in the taper shape. The taper shape may be formed without using the Bosch process, or may be formed as a hole tapered by forming a straight via by the Bosch process, separating the resist and then dry-etching a front surface.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Fifthly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> is partly removed to form the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>. In this embodiment, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> formed under the pad electrode <b>16</b> is partly removed by dry etching. In this embodiment, a case where the first insulating layer <b>14</b> uses SiO<sub>2 </sub>will be described. The amount of etching is adjusted in a range where a metal layer closest to the first concave portion <b>22</b> which is already opened in the pad electrode <b>16</b> is not exposed. As an apparatus for etching, an oxide film etcher is used, for example, and as process gases thereof, C<sub>2</sub>F<sub>6</sub>, CF<sub>4 </sub>and CHF<sub>3 </sub>are used. For example, in a case where the first insulating layer <b>14</b> of SiO<sub>2 </sub>has the thickness of about 1.5 &#x3bc;m, the etching is performed by about 1.0 &#x3bc;m, and the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>remains as the thickness of about 0.5 &#x3bc;m. The first concave portion <b>22</b> is formed through the fourth and fifth processes.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Sixthly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, the inner wall <b>22</b><i>b </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> are coated with the second insulating layer <b>24</b>. As the second insulating layer <b>24</b>, an inorganic film such as a SiO<sub>2</sub>, SiN or the like can be formed by a CVD method, but a photosensitive organic resin material is used in this embodiment. Film formation due to resin material is performed by a spin coating method, a spray coating method, a printing method, or the like. The film thickness is formed to be 3 to 9 &#x3bc;m in the inner wall <b>22</b><i>b </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>, and to be 5 &#x3bc;m or more on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b>. The film thickness of the second insulating layer <b>24</b> on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> is preferably 10 &#x3bc;m or more in terms of parasitic capacitance reduction.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Seventhly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, the second insulating layer <b>24</b> which is coated in the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b> is removed to form the second concave portion <b>26</b>. The second insulating layer <b>24</b> is removed corresponding to the shape of the second concave portion <b>26</b> by a method such as photolithography (exposure and development), and thus, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> of the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b> is exposed. At this time, since the pad electrode <b>16</b> is not exposed to the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>, damage such as metal corrosion due to developing solution is prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Eighthly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4C</figref>, the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>which is exposed to the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b> is removed to form the second concave portion <b>26</b>. The first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>formed under the pad electrode <b>16</b> is removed by dry etching, to thereby expose a metal layer closest to the base substrate of the pad electrode <b>16</b>. In this process, the above-described oxide film ether is used for removal of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>, and C<sub>2</sub>F<sub>6</sub>, CF<sub>4 </sub>and CHF<sub>3 </sub>are used as process gases.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In this way, since the first insulating layer <b>14</b> (inorganic material of SiO<sub>2 </sub>or the like) and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> (organic resin) are formed of different materials, the first insulating layer <b>14</b> and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> are etched by different etching processes. Accordingly, at the time of etching of the second insulating layer <b>24</b>, the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>is not etched, and thus, damage to the pad electrode <b>16</b> can be avoided. Further, since an area (first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>) of the first insulating layer <b>14</b> which is opposite to the pad electrode <b>16</b> is formed to be thinner than other areas, the etching time in the portion can be reduced. Thus, etching damage to the pad electrode <b>16</b> and the second insulating layer <b>24</b> at the time when the second concave portion <b>26</b> is formed can be suppressed, and reliability of electrical and mechanical connection between the pad electrode <b>16</b> and the conductive body <b>32</b> and reliability of the second insulating layer can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Further, compared with the etching rate of the base substrate <b>12</b> (Si), the etching rate of the first insulating layer <b>14</b> (SiO<sub>2</sub>, or the like) is slow and the first insulating layer <b>14</b> is thinly etched. Accordingly, the angle of the taper becomes sharp in etching of the base substrate <b>12</b>, but the angle of the taper becomes obtuse in etching of the first insulation layer <b>14</b><i>a</i>. Accordingly, the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>can be formed to be thinner in thickness as it approaches the center of the bottom section <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the first concave portion <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Ninthly, the barrier layer <b>28</b> and the seed layer <b>30</b> are formed on the first concave portion <b>22</b>, the second concave portion <b>26</b> and the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>). As the barrier layer <b>28</b>, Ti, TiW, TiN or the like can be used. Further, thereafter, the seed layer <b>30</b> is formed for the next plating process. For example, Cu can be used as the material of the seed layer <b>30</b>. In these processes, sputtering and CVD can be used. Preferably, the thickness of the barrier layer <b>28</b> is about 100 nm, and the thickness of seed layer <b>30</b> is about 300 nm. In order to remove a natural oxide film in a portion to which the pad electrode <b>16</b> formed of Al is exposed, reverse sputtering may be performed before the barrier layer <b>28</b> is formed. The amount of throughput of the reverse sputtering may correspond to etching of about 300 nm in terms of SiO<sub>2</sub>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Tenthly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, the through electrode <b>20</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> and the connection electrode <b>36</b> are formed by the conductive body <b>32</b>. When the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> are filled with the conductive body <b>32</b>, a resist (not shown) for plating is formed. In this case, in the resist (not shown), positions where the through electrode <b>20</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> which is formed on the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> and is connected to the through electrode <b>20</b>, and the connection electrode <b>36</b> connected to the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> are opened. Firstly, plating filling is performed for the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> by the conductive body <b>32</b>, and subsequently plating is performed for the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> and the connection electrode <b>36</b> by the conductive body <b>32</b>. Hole plugging of the first concave portion <b>22</b> and the second concave portion <b>26</b> and formation such as wiring of the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>are formed by a series of plating processes, but may be formed by different processes. The thickness of the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> and the connection electrode <b>36</b> is preferably about 6 &#x3bc;m. After completion of the above-described plating process, the remaining barrier layer <b>28</b> and seed layer <b>30</b> which are exposed as is to the rear surface <b>12</b><i>b </i>of the base substrate <b>12</b> are removed by etching.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Eleventhly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, a solder resist layer <b>54</b> is formed. The solder resist layer <b>54</b> is coated with a part of the through electrode <b>20</b>, the rearrangement wiring <b>34</b> and the connection electrode <b>36</b> to perform protection of the electrode or wiring and insulation from the outside. The thickness of the solder resist layer <b>54</b> is appropriately about 10 &#x3bc;m to 20 &#x3bc;m, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Further, finally, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref>, the side of the base substrate <b>12</b> to which the support glass <b>50</b> is attached is irradiated with laser, to thereby dissolve an adhesive which attaches the support glass <b>50</b>. Then, the support glass <b>50</b> is separated to expose the rearrangement wiring substrate and the external electrode. Thus, the wiring substrate <b>10</b> having the through electrode <b>20</b> according to this embodiment can be formed.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">A reliability test through a temperature cycle test has been performed with respect to the wiring substrate <b>10</b> having the through electrode <b>20</b> prepared using the above-described processes. As a result, the inventor has found out that an error due to separation or the like in the insulating layer portion between the pad electrode <b>16</b> and the through electrode <b>20</b> does not occur.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">In the wiring substrate <b>10</b> formed in this way, the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>is formed to be thinner in an area overlapping with the second insulating layer <b>24</b> than in other areas of the first insulating layer <b>14</b>. Accordingly, in an area of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>overlapping with the second insulating layer <b>24</b>, force applied to the connection section between the through electrode <b>20</b> and the pad electrode <b>16</b> due to the difference between the coefficient of the thermal expansion of the first insulating layer <b>14</b><i>a </i>and the coefficient of the thermal expansion of the second insulating layer <b>24</b> can be reduced. On the other hand, insulation properties between the base substrate <b>12</b> and the pad electrodes <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> can be secured by the first insulating layer <b>14</b> in the other areas. Accordingly, the wiring substrate <b>10</b> is obtained in which the electric reliability of the pad electrodes <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> and the reliability for temperature change in mechanical connection of the overall through electrode <b>20</b> can be enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The connection electrode <b>36</b> formed on the wiring substrate <b>10</b> is electrically and mechanically connected to the driving element <b>56</b> of a piezoelectric vibrator (not shown) or a gyrosensor element (not shown) through the conductive adhesive <b>58</b> or the like, thereby making it possible to form a piezoelectric oscillator (not shown) or a gyrosensor (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The entire disclosure of Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-107007, filed May 7, 2010 is expressly incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A wiring substrate comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pad electrode which is stacked on the first insulating layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer and is connected to the pad electrode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second insulating layer which is disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode, when seen from a plan view, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thickness of the first insulating layer gradually decreases from a position located outboard of the connection section to a position at the connection section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The wiring substrate according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein materials of the first insulating layer and the second insulating layer are different from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The wiring substrate according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein material of the second insulating layer is an organic resin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A gyrosensor comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate which has a first surface and a second surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first insulating layer which is stacked on the first surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pad electrode which is stacked on the first insulating layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a through electrode which passes through the substrate and the first insulating layer and is connected to the pad electrode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second insulating layer which is disposed between the substrate and the through electrode and between the first insulating layer and the through electrode; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving element which is installed on the substrate and is electrically connected to the pad electrode via the through electrode,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a diameter of the through electrode in a connection section between the pad electrode and the through electrode is smaller than a diameter of the through electrode on the second surface side,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first insulating layer, the second insulating layer and the through electrode overlap with each other in a peripheral area of the connection section between the through electrode and the pad electrode, when seen from a plan view, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thickness of the first insulating layer gradually decreases from a position located outboard of the connection section to a position at the connection section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
