<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624666-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624666</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13330670</doc-number>
<date>20111219</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>62</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327551</main-classification>
<further-classification>327552</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Interleaved noise reduction circuit and method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5410145</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Coroy</name>
<date>19950400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>250214 C</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5554944</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Van Buul et al.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327 91</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7957762</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Herz et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8017901</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mizoguchi et al.</name>
<date>20110900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>250214 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>23</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327551-559</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327 34</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130154724</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130620</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Smith</last-name>
<first-name>Robert B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pocatello</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Latimer</last-name>
<first-name>Stan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pocatello</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ercanbrack</last-name>
<first-name>Morgan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Arimo</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Smith</last-name>
<first-name>Robert B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pocatello</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Latimer</last-name>
<first-name>Stan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Pocatello</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ercanbrack</last-name>
<first-name>Morgan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Arimo</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dover</last-name>
<first-name>Rennie William</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Semiconductor Components Industries, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Dinh T.</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In accordance with an embodiment, a noise reduction circuit includes one or more phase sampling circuits that receive an electromagnetic signal and splits the signal into an illuminated component and an ambient component. The illuminated component is transmitted along an illuminated signal path and converted to a digital signal and the ambient component is transmitted along an ambient signal path and converted to a digital signal. The digitized ambient component is subtracted from the digitized illuminated component to generate a light signal with a reduced noise component.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="164.08mm" wi="166.45mm" file="US08624666-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="188.04mm" wi="176.45mm" file="US08624666-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="203.03mm" wi="187.37mm" file="US08624666-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.11mm" wi="190.75mm" file="US08624666-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates, in general, to electronics and, more particularly, to noise reduction in electronic circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In the past, the electronics industry used various techniques to determine the proximity of two objects to each other. For example, in portable communications applications such as telephones it is desirable to determine the distance between the telephone and its user's head so that the telephone's touch panel can be turned off as the telephone approaches the head, but before the phone touches the head. In these types of applications active optical proximity sensors may be employed to detect the proximity between the telephone and the user's head. Active proximity sensors include a light source that transmits light to the user's head and a sensor that detects the light reflected from the user's head. Proximity sensors are disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 7,957,762 issued to Scott M. Herz et al. on Jun. 7, 2011. A drawback with these types of systems is that the reflected light signal typically includes noise that degrades the accuracy of the measurement. Noise caused by sunlight and low frequency light sources may be reduced by transmitting the light in a series of pulses with a frequency higher than the interfering light sources and using a high pass filter to allow transmission of the light being transmitted at higher frequencies. This technique uses additional circuitry, increases power consumption, and may introduce additional sources of noise.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Accordingly, it would be advantageous to have a noise reduction circuit for optical applications and a method for reducing noise in the optical applications. In addition, it is desirable for the method and circuit to be cost and time efficient to implement.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention will be better understood from a reading of the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawing figures, in which like reference characters designate like elements and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a noise reduction circuit in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit schematic of a portion of the noise reduction circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a timing diagram in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a timing diagram in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For simplicity and clarity of illustration, elements in the figures are not necessarily to scale, and the same reference characters in different figures denote the same elements. Additionally, descriptions and details of well-known steps and elements are omitted for simplicity of the description. As used herein current carrying electrode means an element of a device that carries current through the device such as a source or a drain of an MOS transistor or an emitter or a collector of a bipolar transistor or a cathode or an anode of a diode, and a control electrode means an element of the device that controls current flow through the device such as a gate of an MOS transistor or a base of a bipolar transistor. Although the devices are explained herein as certain N-channel or P-channel devices, or certain N-type or P-type doped regions, a person of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that complementary devices are also possible in accordance with embodiments of the present invention. It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the words during, while, and when as used herein are not exact terms that mean an action takes place instantly upon an initiating action but that there may be some small but reasonable delay, such as a propagation delay, between the reaction that is initiated by the initial action and the initial action. The use of the words approximately, about, or substantially means that a value of an element has a parameter that is expected to be very close to a stated value or position. However, as is well known in the art there are always minor variances that prevent the values or positions from being exactly as stated. It is well established in the art that variances of up to about ten percent (10%) (and up to twenty percent (20%) for semiconductor doping concentrations) are regarded as reasonable variances from the ideal goal of exactly as described.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It should be noted that a logic zero voltage level (V<sub>L</sub>) is also referred to as a logic low voltage and that the voltage level of a logic zero voltage is a function of the power supply voltage and the type of logic family. For example, in a Complementary Metal Oxide Semiconductor (CMOS) logic family a logic zero voltage may be thirty percent of the power supply voltage level. In a five volt Transistor-Transistor Logic (TTL) system a logic zero voltage level may be about 0.8 volts, whereas for a five volt CMOS system, the logic zero voltage level may be about 1.5 volts. A logic one voltage level (V<sub>H</sub>) is also referred to as a logic high voltage level and, like the logic zero voltage level, the logic high voltage level also may be a function of the power supply and the type of logic family. For example, in a CMOS system a logic one voltage may be about seventy percent of the power supply voltage level. In a five volt TTL system a logic one voltage may be about 2.4 volts, whereas for a five volt CMOS system, the logic one voltage may be about 3.5 volts.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Generally the present invention provides an interleaved noise reduction circuit and a method for reducing noise. In accordance with embodiments, illuminated and ambient electromagnetic radiation measurements are taken during the time a source of electromagnetic radiation such as, for example, a light emitting diode (LED) is being modulated by synchronous phase sampling of a received electromagnetic radiation signal. It should be noted that the received electromagnetic radiation signal is comprised of an illuminated component and a noise component, wherein the noise component may be referred to as an ambient component. In an example where the electromagnetic radiation is light, the received electromagnetic radiation signal is comprised of an illuminated light component and an ambient light component. It should be noted that the signal intensity of the received light may span several decades. It should be further noted that the electromagnetic radiation is not limited to being visible light. The electromagnetic radiation signals may be radiowaves, microwaves, infrared radiation, ultraviolet radiation, X-rays, gamma rays, etc. A receiver receives the electromagnetic radiation signal, filters undesired frequency components from the electromagnetic radiation signal and amplifies the signal. The filtered and amplified electromagnetic radiation signal is transmitted to one or more phase splitters, which split the electromagnetic radiation signal into on-time and off-time components and processes them in separate analog channels into illuminated and ambient components. The illuminated component is a combination of a signal portion and a noise portion, i.e., the ambient component. After generating the illuminated and ambient components, the components are converted into digital signals in preparation for digital subtraction. The ambient component is digitally subtracted from the illuminated component, leaving the signal component.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a noise reduction portion <b>10</b> of a proximity sensor in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. Noise reduction portion <b>10</b> includes a noise reduction circuit <b>12</b> coupled to an oscillator <b>14</b> and a driver circuit <b>16</b>. By way of example, the electromagnetic radiation signal is a light signal generated by an LED <b>20</b> and driver circuit <b>16</b> is an LED driver circuit. LED <b>20</b> is connected to LED driver circuit <b>16</b> and transmits the light signal to an object whose proximity is to be sensed. The anode of LED <b>20</b> may be coupled for receiving a source of operating potential. The light signal transmitted by the LED is reflected from the object as a reflected light or electromagnetic radiation signal <b>22</b>, which is transmitted to a photodiode <b>24</b> of noise reduction circuit <b>12</b>. Thus, reflected electromagnetic radiation signal <b>22</b> represents the electromagnetic radiation signal that is transmitted from LED <b>20</b> and reflected back to noise reduction circuit <b>12</b> from an object or person. As discussed above, the type of electromagnetic radiation is not limited to light in the visible spectrum. In accordance with an embodiment, noise reduction circuit <b>12</b> includes a photodiode <b>24</b>, a receiver <b>30</b>, a phase sampling circuit <b>32</b>, an integrating Analog-to-Digital Converter (ADC) <b>34</b>, an integrating Analog-to-Digital Converter (ADC) <b>36</b>, a subtractor or difference circuit <b>38</b>, and control logic circuitry <b>40</b>. By way of example, receiver <b>30</b> may be comprised of a filter circuit and an amplifier circuit. Alternatively, receiver <b>30</b> may include a rectifying or signal adjustment circuit in addition to the filter and amplifier circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It should be noted that the configurations of integrating ADC's <b>34</b> and <b>36</b> are not limitations of the present invention. Integrating ADC's <b>34</b> and <b>36</b> can be implemented using an integrating current-to-frequency converter, a combination of an integrator and a dual slope ADC, a combination of an integrator and a conventional voltage ADC, or the like. Those skilled in the art understand that a combination of an integrator and an ADC may be referred to as an integrating ADC.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> is coupled to receive an output signal (V<sub>CLK</sub>) from oscillator <b>14</b> and an inverted output signal (V<sub>CLK</sub>B) from oscillator <b>14</b> through inverter <b>26</b>. The output signal V<sub>CLK </sub>from oscillator <b>14</b> is also transmitted to LED driver <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> separates the light signal into illuminated and ambient components, transmits the illuminated component along a signal path <b>42</b> that includes integrating ADC <b>34</b>, and transmits the ambient component along a signal path <b>44</b> that includes integrating ADC <b>36</b>. Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a circuit schematic of phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> in accordance with an embodiment is illustrated. What is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a field effect transistor <b>60</b> having a drain electrode connected to a gate electrode and a source electrode coupled for receiving a source of operating potential V<sub>DD</sub>. The commonly connected drain and gate electrodes serve as an input terminal for phase sampling circuit <b>32</b>. The gate electrode of field effect transistor <b>60</b> is connected to the gate electrode of a field effect transistor <b>66</b> through a capacitor <b>62</b>. Field effect transistor <b>66</b> has a source electrode and a drain electrode, where the source electrode is coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>DD</sub>. Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> further includes a field effect transistor <b>70</b> having a gate electrode coupled to the gate electrode of field effect transistor <b>66</b> through a resistor <b>64</b> and coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>DD </sub>through a capacitor <b>72</b>. Field effect transistors <b>60</b> and <b>66</b>, capacitor <b>62</b>, and resistor <b>64</b> form a filtering current mirror <b>68</b>, where capacitor <b>62</b> and resistor <b>64</b> form a high pass filter.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In addition, phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> includes field effect transistors <b>76</b>, <b>78</b>, and <b>80</b> configured as a current bias network <b>82</b>, wherein field effect transistor <b>76</b> has a source electrode coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>DD </sub>and a gate electrode coupled to its drain electrode. Current bias network <b>82</b> may be referred to as a bias circuit or a bias stage. Field effect transistor <b>78</b> has a source electrode connected to the commonly connected drain and gate electrodes of field effect transistor <b>76</b> and gate and drain electrodes that are commonly connected to each other and to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>80</b>. The gate electrode of field effect transistor <b>80</b> is commonly connected to the gate electrodes of field effect transistors <b>84</b>, <b>86</b>, and <b>88</b>. The source electrodes of field effect transistors <b>84</b>, <b>86</b>, and <b>88</b> are coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>SS</sub>. The drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>84</b> is coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>DD </sub>through a current source <b>90</b>. Current source <b>90</b> provides a bias current I<sub>BIAS</sub>. The drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>86</b> is connected to the commonly connected drain and gate electrodes of field effect transistor <b>70</b>. Field effect transistors <b>84</b>, <b>86</b>, <b>80</b>, and <b>88</b> form a current mirror <b>92</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> includes a pair of field effect transistors <b>94</b> and <b>96</b> configured as a current mirror <b>98</b>, wherein the gate electrodes of field effect transistors <b>94</b> and <b>96</b> are commonly connected together and to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>94</b> and the source electrodes of field effect transistors <b>94</b> and <b>96</b> are coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>SS</sub>. The drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>94</b> is connected to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>66</b> of current mirror <b>68</b> through a field effect transistor <b>100</b>, wherein the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>100</b> is connected to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>94</b>, the source electrode of field effect transistor <b>100</b> is connected to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>66</b>, and the gate electrode of field effect transistor <b>100</b> is connected to the commonly connected gate and drain electrodes of field effect transistor <b>78</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> includes field effect transistors <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, and <b>108</b> that have source electrodes commonly connected to the drain electrode of field effect transistor <b>96</b>. The gate electrodes of field effect transistors <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> are connected to corresponding input terminals of a two-input NOR gate <b>110</b>, the gate terminal of field effect transistor <b>108</b> is connected to the output terminal of two-input NOR gate <b>110</b>, and the drain terminal of field effect transistor <b>108</b> is coupled for receiving source of operating potential V<sub>DD</sub>. The input terminals of two-input NOR gate <b>110</b> are coupled for receiving the clock signal V<sub>CLK </sub>and the inverted clock signal V<sub>CLK</sub>B from oscillator <b>14</b>. The drain terminals of field effect transistors <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> serve as the output terminals of phase sampling circuit <b>32</b>. Field effect transistors <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> form an output stage <b>112</b></p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In operation, phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> receives the light signal represented as a current from receiver <b>30</b>. The current signal is filtered by high pass filter <b>74</b> to remove any residual DC signal that may be present in the signal from receiver <b>30</b> and mirrored by current mirror <b>68</b>. Field effect transistor <b>70</b> sets a reference voltage for high pass filter <b>74</b> and bias circuit <b>82</b> adds additional current that is mirrored into current mirror <b>68</b>. Thus, filter <b>74</b> removes a DC current signal that interferes with the AC current signal, which AC current signal includes the illuminated and ambient components. Because the AC signal may have a large dynamic range that can span several decades of current and the illuminated signal level may be much smaller than the ambient signal level, bias circuit <b>82</b> is included to inject a known DC current to center the AC signal and provide a sufficient dynamic range for the AC signal between the supply rails. The additional DC current and the AC current are transmitted to the input or front end of the current mirror <b>98</b>. If the current transmitted to the input of current mirror <b>98</b> is not reduced, a large mirrored current would be generated that represents an error signal. To reduce the error signal, field effect transistor <b>88</b> is included to divert the additional current provided by bias circuit <b>82</b>. Thus, bias circuit <b>82</b> adds a current and field effect transistor <b>88</b> subtracts the majority of the current added by bias circuit <b>82</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Current mirror <b>98</b> generates a current that is steered through field effect transistors <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> in accordance with the signals V<sub>CLK </sub>and V<sub>CLK</sub>B from oscillator <b>14</b>. The current flowing through field effect transistor <b>104</b> serves as the illuminated component and the current flowing through field effect transistor <b>106</b> serves as the ambient component.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In operation, LED driver circuit <b>16</b> drives LED <b>20</b> at a frequency sufficiently high to discern it from other noise or interference sources. LED <b>20</b> generates a signal that is reflected back to photodiode <b>24</b>, which is responsive to the wavelength of the signal produced by LED <b>20</b>. Receiver <b>30</b> receives the reflected signal and filters it with, for example, a high pass filter to reject low frequency noise signals. Receiver <b>30</b> amplifies the filtered signal to generate the illuminated component of the light signal and transmits the illuminated component to phase sampling circuit <b>32</b>. Phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> separates the illuminated component into the signal component and the ambient component in response to oscillator signals from oscillator <b>14</b> and control signals received from control logic circuitry <b>40</b>. By way of example, the illuminated component may be separated in accordance with the time that the light source is on, i.e., the portion that contains the signal plus ambient components, and the time that the light source is off, i.e., the portion containing the ambient component. The illuminated component, which includes the signal plus ambient components, is transmitted along signal path <b>42</b> and the ambient component is transmitted along signal path <b>44</b>. It should be noted that in response to the oscillator signal, LED driver <b>16</b> generates an LED status indicator signal V<sub>LED </sub>shown in plot <b>120</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> that indicates the state of LED <b>20</b>, i.e., whether LED <b>20</b> is on or off.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In response to the inverted oscillator signal and the illuminated component transmitted to illuminated signal path <b>42</b>, phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> samples the illuminated signal from receiver <b>30</b>. Typically, the light signal received from a given light pulse is very small, thus the light energy is accumulated over a series of pulses. The accumulated charge from the illuminated light signal may be stored using the integrator portion of integrating ADC <b>34</b> and converted to a digital signal using the analog-to-digital converter (ADC) portion of integrating ADC <b>34</b>. The integrator portion may be implemented as a capacitor. By way of example, the sampled signal is integrated over the time that LED <b>22</b> is on. The digital signal generated by integrating ADC <b>34</b> is representative of the illuminated signal and is transmitted to subtractor circuit <b>38</b>. The illuminated signal includes the light signal and noise from &#x201c;in-band&#x201d; ambient light sources and on-chip noise generated by, for example, LED driver <b>16</b> switching from an on state to an off state or from an off state to an on state.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In response to the noninverted oscillator signal and the ambient component transmitted to illuminated signal path <b>44</b>, phase sampling circuit <b>32</b> samples the illuminated signal from receiver <b>30</b>. As discussed above, the light signal received from a given light pulse is very small, thus the light energy is accumulated over a series of pulses. The accumulated charge from the ambient light signal may be stored using the integrator portion of integrating ADC <b>36</b> and converted to a digital signal using the analog-to-digital converter (ADC) portion of integrating ADC <b>36</b>. The digital signal generated by integrating ADC <b>36</b> is representative of the ambient light signal and is transmitted to subtractor circuit <b>38</b>. Like the illuminated light signal, the ambient light signal includes noise from &#x201c;in-band&#x201d; ambient light sources and on-chip noise generated by, for example, LED driver <b>16</b> switching from an on state to an off state or from an off state to an on state. However, the light signal itself is absent from the ambient light signal.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Subtractor <b>38</b> subtracts the ambient light signal from the illuminated light signal to generate a digital light signal having a reduced noise level at its output terminal <b>39</b>. It should be noted that control logic <b>40</b> controls the timing of the signal transmission along signal paths <b>42</b> and <b>44</b>. Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, plot <b>120</b> further illustrates that the illumination integration time occurs in response to LED drive circuit <b>16</b> generating an assertion signal that indicates when LED <b>20</b> is on and that the ambient integration time occurs in response to LED drive circuit <b>16</b> generating a non-assertion signal indicating when LED <b>20</b> is off.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a timing diagram <b>122</b> in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention. Because LED driver circuit <b>16</b> generates large amounts of noise in response to switching on and off and because filtering of the light signal may introduce group delay, it may be desirable to delay the sampling of the signal from receiver <b>30</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates that a portion <b>124</b> of the illuminated sampling time and a portion <b>126</b> of the ambient sampling time may be blanked or discarded. Delaying the sampling time ensures that sampling does not occur along illuminated signal path <b>42</b> at the time LED driver circuit <b>16</b> turns on or is asserted, i.e., transitions to a logic high state, or along ambient signal path <b>44</b> at the time LED driver circuit <b>16</b> turns off or is de-asserted, i.e., transitions to a logic low state. Sampling just before LED driver circuit <b>16</b> turns on or turns off ensures that bad data caused by, for example, the filter group delay that may skew the pulse is not sampled. It should be noted that the delayed signals replace the V<sub>CLK </sub>and V<sub>CLK</sub>B signals with signals V<sub>ILL </sub>and V<sub>AMB</sub>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">By now it should be appreciated that a noise reduction circuit and method have been provided. In accordance with embodiments, the illuminated signal is processed as if subtraction would not occur. Prior to integration, the signal is split into a component which represents the ambient content and a signal which represents the illuminated content plus the ambient content. Synchronous phase sampling can be accomplished because the time at which LED <b>22</b> is on is known. The split signals are integrated and converted into digital signals separately from each other, but substantially simultaneously with each other. Because the two signals are processed at substantially the same time, they may be referred to as interleaved signals. The interleaved signals may be processed through a difference circuit to reduce the noise in the illuminated signal.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Although specific embodiments have been disclosed herein, it is not intended that the invention be limited to the disclosed embodiments. Those skilled in the art will recognize that modifications and variations can be made without departing from the spirit of the invention. It is intended that the invention encompass all such modifications and variations as fall within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A noise reduction circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a phase sampling circuit responsive to a stream of pulses of known phase and frequency and having an input and first and second outputs, the first output configured to transmit a first component of a first signal along a first signal path and the second output configured to transmit a second component of the first signal along a second signal path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a difference circuit having a first input coupled for receiving the first component of the first signal, a second input for receiving the second component of the first signal, and an output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a receiver coupled for receiving an input signal and having an output through which the first signal is transmitted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising an oscillator having an output coupled to the first signal path through an inverter and coupled to the second signal path.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first signal path comprises
<claim-text>a first integrating analog-to-digital circuit having an input and an output, the input of the first integrating analog-to-digital circuit coupled to the first output of the phase sampling circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the phase sampling circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a filtering current mirror having an input terminal and an output terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bias circuit coupled to the output terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first current mirror having an input terminal and an output terminal, the output terminal coupled to the output terminal of the filtering current mirror;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second current mirror having an input terminal and an output terminal, the input terminal coupled to the output terminal of the filtering current mirror; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output stage having first and second output terminals, the output stage coupled to the output terminal of the second current mirror.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the filtering current mirror includes a high pass filter.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second signal path comprises a second integrating analog-to-digital circuit having an input and an output, the input of the second integrating analog-to-digital circuit coupled to the second output of the phase sampling circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The noise reduction circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a light emitting diode driver circuit coupled to the output of the oscillator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control logic circuitry coupled to at least the phase sampling circuit and to the light emitting diode driver circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method for reducing noise, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an electromagnetic radiation signal having a signal component and an ambient component;</claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the electromagnetic radiation signal into the signal component and the ambient component drive signal in response to a stream of pulses of known phase and frequency;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the signal component and the ambient component along a first signal path and the ambient component along a second signal path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the ambient component from the illuminated component to form an output signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further including receiving electromagnetic radiation in response to a light emitting diode drive signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further including generating a drive signal in response to an oscillator signal and a control signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further including asserting a light emitting diode in response to the drive signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further including sampling the signal component and the ambient component along a first signal path in response to an inverted oscillator signal to generate a first sampled signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further including sampling the signal component and the ambient component after a predetermined time delay.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further including sampling the ambient component along the second signal path in response to the oscillator signal to generate a second sampled signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further including sampling the signal component and ambient component in response to the drive signal being in an off state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further including sampling the ambient component after the drive signal is de-asserted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, further including delaying sampling the ambient component for a predetermined time after the drive signal is de-asserted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein transmitting the signal component and the ambient component along a first signal path and the ambient component along a second signal path further includes:
<claim-text>sampling the signal component and the ambient component along the first signal path to generate a first sampled signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating the first sampled signal to generate a first integrated signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>converting the first integrated signal to a first digital signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein transmitting the signal component and the ambient component along a first signal path and the ambient component along a second signal path further includes:
<claim-text>sampling the ambient component along a second signal path to generate a first sampled signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating the first sampled signal to generate a second integrated signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>converting the second integrated signal to a second digital signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A method for reducing noise, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an electromagnetic radiation signal having a signal component and an ambient component;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to a stream of pulses of known phase and frequency sampling the signal component and the ambient component in response to a clock signal to generate a sampled illumination signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sampling the ambient component in response to an inverted clock signal to generate a sampled noise signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating the sampled illumination signal to generate a first integrated signal and converting the first integrated signal into a digital illumination signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>integrating the sampled ambient to generate a second integrated sampled signal and converting the second integrated sampled signal into a digital ambient signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the digital ambient signal from the digital illumination signal to generate an output signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further including filtering the electromagnetic radiation signal before sampling the signal component and the ambient component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further including using an oscillator to generate the clock signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
