<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621952-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621952</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12845096</doc-number>
<date>20100728</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>655</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74457</main-classification>
<further-classification> 74439</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Zero backlash gearing</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>441460</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Atwood</name>
<date>18901100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>447552</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Atwood</name>
<date>18910300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1081996</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Weist</name>
<date>19131200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1093279</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Loftus</name>
<date>19140400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1147805</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kunz et al.</name>
<date>19150700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74460</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1871417</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mansur</name>
<date>19320800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74445</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74434</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74439</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74446</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74447</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74448</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74457</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 74460</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120024094</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120202</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sokolofsky</last-name>
<first-name>Phillip M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Akron</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Goupil, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Gerald M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>N. Tonawanda</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Corra</last-name>
<first-name>Craig A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Williamsville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sokolofsky</last-name>
<first-name>Phillip M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Akron</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Goupil, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Gerald M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>N. Tonawanda</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Corra</last-name>
<first-name>Craig A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Williamsville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chan</last-name>
<first-name>James M.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delphi Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Krause</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
<department>3658</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Each generic gear includes one tooth disposed in each of the sockets, and each tooth extends radially outward from one of the sockets and throat thereof. The teeth of the generic gear include resilient material adjacent the throat for compressing and allowing movement of each tooth relative to the outer periphery. In the species of FIG. <b>1</b>, each tooth is entirely of the resilient material and diverges or circumferentially widens from adjacent the throat to define a gap from the throat to the outer periphery. In the species of FIG. <b>2</b>, each tooth has a shell integral with the hub and a core of the resilient material fills each shell and extends into the socket to define a crescent-shaped gap with the socket end.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="173.48mm" wi="191.52mm" file="US08621952-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="266.36mm" wi="192.79mm" file="US08621952-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="196.85mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08621952-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The subject invention relates to a gear for transmitting mechanical power.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Like all manufactured components, gears and their installation are subject to manufacturing tolerances. In the prior art, if gear teeth are too large or if a first gear and its mating gear are too close together, there is interference between the first gear and its mating gear. As a result, the gears do not mate smoothly and excessive friction occurs between the gears. In addition, backlash takes place when the gear teeth are too small or if a first gear and its mating gear are too far apart. As a result, the gears do not remain in continuous contact, and transmission of power is not smooth and constant.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Prior art gears, such as U.S. Pat. No. 4,184,380 disclose using a coating of resilient material on the gear teeth. The thickness of the coating increases the overall width of the tooth to take up backlash space and the resilient material of the coating compresses and is compressed or displaced as it encounters the mating gear to reduce interference friction.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Other gears in the prior art enable movement of the gear teeth relative to the outer periphery of the gear to prevent backlash while reducing interference friction. For example, US2007/0180943 discloses gear teeth integral with and extending radially out from the outer periphery and defining openings and slots enabling circumferential movement of the teeth relative to the outer periphery of the gear.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Prior art gears include a cam groove in the gear hub to provide a path of motion for another machine element. The presence of a cam groove limits the size and depth of slots and openings defined by the gear teeth to enable circumferential movement. The slots and openings are also limited in size and depth as the gear diameter decreases.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">One type of gear in the prior art includes a hub that has an outer periphery and defines sockets about the outer periphery for retaining a gear tooth in each socket. Each socket extends from the outer periphery and into the hub and terminates at a socket end with a throat or waist that is narrower circumferentially than the socket end. A gear tooth is disposed in each socket and extends radially outward from each of the sockets and throat thereof to a top land surface. An example of such a gear is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,203,861 to Irwin et al., however each gear tooth is fixed and prevented from moving circumferentially thereby providing no accommodation for backlash.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The subject invention provides such a gear wherein each of the teeth extends out of a socket and includes a resilient material adjacent the throat of the socket for compressing and allowing movement of each tooth relative to the outer periphery of the gear hub.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">ADVANTAGES OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">This invention unexpectedly and ingeniously takes up backlash space and reduces interference friction through yielding of the gear teeth in two different modes simultaneously: circumferential movement and compression or displacement of resilient tooth material. As a first gear tooth encounters a mating gear tooth, the resilient material of the tooth bends at the throat of the socket providing circumferential movement of the gear teeth. Also, as the gear tooth encounters a mating gear tooth, the resilient material of the gear tooth adjacent the throat may compress or move to reduce interference friction. The unique structure of this invention is an improvement in gear design to eliminate backlash in gear teeth while avoiding interference friction. The improvements of this invention may also be adapted to have minimal penetration of slots or openings into the hub of the gear so that it can be used on small diameter gears and gears that contain cam grooves in the hub.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Other advantages of the present invention will be readily appreciated, as the same becomes better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view of a sector of a first species of gear constructed in accordance with the subject invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of a sector of a second species of gear constructed in accordance with the subject invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view taken along line <b>3</b>-<b>3</b>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to the Figures, wherein like numerals indicate corresponding parts throughout the several views, a species of a gear for transmitting mechanical power in accordance with the instant invention is shown in each of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Generically, each gear includes a disk-like hub <b>20</b> defining a bore <b>22</b> extending axially through the hub <b>20</b> and which defines a central axis <b>24</b> of rotation for the generic gear. The hub <b>20</b> also includes an outer periphery <b>26</b> encircling the outside of the hub <b>20</b> and which is coaxial with the central axis <b>24</b>. In the axial direction, the hub <b>20</b> has a first thickness T<sub>1 </sub>extending radially inward from the outer periphery <b>26</b>, and the hub has a second thickness T<sub>2 </sub>thinner than the first thickness T<sub>1 </sub>extending radially inward from the first thickness T<sub>1 </sub>toward the bore <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The hub <b>20</b> also defines sockets <b>28</b> equally spaced circumferentially from one another about the outer periphery <b>26</b>. Each socket <b>28</b> extends radially inward from the outer periphery <b>26</b> into the first thickness T<sub>1 </sub>and terminates at a socket end <b>30</b>. The socket ends <b>30</b> are arcuate or semi-circular and each socket <b>28</b> also includes a throat <b>32</b> that is circumferentially narrower than the socket ends <b>30</b>. The outer periphery <b>26</b> defines bottom land surfaces <b>34</b> that are interleaved with the sockets <b>28</b> about the outer periphery <b>26</b> so that bottom land surfaces <b>34</b> extend circumferentially between each of the sockets <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The generic gear includes one tooth <b>36</b> disposed in each of the sockets <b>28</b>, and each of the teeth <b>36</b> extends radially outward from the sockets <b>28</b> and throats <b>32</b> thereof to terminate at a top land surface <b>38</b>. The top land surface <b>38</b> may be of any contour, from flat to pointed. Each of the teeth <b>36</b> presents face/flank surfaces <b>40</b> spaced apart and extending radially with the top land surface <b>38</b> extending circumferentially therebetween. Each of the teeth <b>36</b> has a proximal end <b>42</b> disposed in its corresponding socket <b>28</b>. The proximal end <b>42</b> is arcuate and circumferentially wider than the throat <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Each tooth of the generic gear includes resilient material adjacent the throat <b>32</b> for compressing and allowing movement of each tooth <b>36</b> relative to the outer periphery <b>26</b>. The resilient material returns to its original shape after being bent, compressed, or stretched. The sockets <b>28</b> and the resilient material of each of the teeth <b>36</b> define at least one gap <b>44</b> therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the species of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the teeth <b>36</b> diverge or circumferentially widen from adjacent the throat <b>32</b> to the face/flank surfaces <b>40</b>. From the face/flank surfaces <b>40</b>, the teeth <b>36</b> converge or circumferentially narrow toward the top land surface <b>38</b>. Each of the sockets <b>28</b> also diverges or circumferentially widens from the throat <b>32</b> to the outer periphery <b>26</b>, but diverges to a lesser degree than the teeth <b>36</b> diverge to define one gap <b>44</b> from the throat <b>32</b> to the outer periphery <b>26</b> on each side circumferentially of each tooth <b>36</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each of the teeth <b>36</b> is entirely of the resilient material. The proximal ends <b>42</b> of the gear teeth <b>36</b> are complementary to and fill the arcuate socket ends <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The hub <b>20</b> of both species of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> (although not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) defines a boss <b>46</b> coaxial with the central axis <b>24</b> which has a third thickness T<sub>3 </sub>in the axial direction which is at least greater than the second thickness T<sub>2</sub>. The boss <b>46</b> defines a recess <b>48</b> having a hexagonal shape that could, for example, receive a nut. Fillets <b>50</b> extend between the boss <b>46</b> and the hub <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In the species of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each of the teeth <b>36</b> has a shell <b>52</b> integral with the hub <b>20</b>. The shell <b>52</b> extends about the top land surface <b>38</b> and radially outward from and integrally interconnecting adjacent bottom land surfaces <b>34</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a core <b>54</b> of the resilient material fills each of the shells <b>52</b> from beneath the top land surface <b>38</b> and extending into the socket <b>28</b> to define the proximal end <b>42</b> of each tooth <b>36</b>. The proximal ends <b>42</b> and the socket ends <b>30</b> define a crescent-shaped gap <b>44</b> between each of the proximal ends <b>42</b> and the socket ends <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">While the invention has been described with reference to two exemplary species, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular species disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all species falling within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A gear for transmitting mechanical power comprising;
<claim-text>a hub having an outer periphery and defining sockets about said outer periphery,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets extending radially from said outer periphery into said hub and each terminating in a socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets including a throat narrower circumferentially than said socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gear tooth disposed in each of said sockets and extending radially outward from each of said sockets and said throat thereof,</claim-text>
<claim-text>and each of said teeth including a resilient material adjacent said throat for compressing and allowing movement of said tooth relative to said outer periphery of said hub;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said resilient material of each of said teeth and each of said sockets define at least one gap therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said gear teeth has a proximal end disposed in said sockets and being circumferentially wider than said throat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said teeth extend radially outward from each of said sockets and said throat thereof to a top land surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said teeth diverge from adjacent said throat toward said top land surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said sockets diverge from said throat to said periphery to a lesser degree than said diverging teeth to define a pair of said gaps on each side circumferentially of each of said teeth from said throat to said outer periphery.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A gear as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each of said teeth are entirely of said resilient material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A gear for transmitting mechanical power comprising;
<claim-text>a hub having an outer periphery and defining sockets about said outer periphery,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets extending radially from said outer periphery into said hub and each terminating in a socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets including a throat narrower circumferentially than said socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gear tooth disposed in each of said sockets and extending radially outward from each of said sockets and said throat thereof,</claim-text>
<claim-text>and each of said teeth including a resilient material adjacent said throat for compressing and allowing movement of said tooth relative to said outer periphery of said hub;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said sockets and said resilient material of each of said teeth define at least one gap therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said gear teeth has a proximal end disposed in said sockets and being circumferentially wider than said throat</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said proximal ends is complementary to and fills said socket ends.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A gear for transmitting mechanical power comprising;
<claim-text>a hub with a bore defining a central axis of rotation,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said hub having an outer periphery coaxial with said central axis,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said hub having a first thickness in the axial direction extending radially inward from said outer periphery and a second thickness thinner than said first thickness extending radially inward from said first thickness toward said bore,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said hub defining sockets equally spaced circumferentially from one another about said outer periphery,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said outer periphery defining bottom land surfaces circumferentially spaced from one another and interleaved with said sockets about said outer periphery,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets extending from said outer periphery and into said first thickness and terminating in a socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said socket ends being arcuate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets including a throat circumferentially narrower than said socket end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gear tooth disposed in each said sockets and extending radially outward from each of said sockets and said throat thereof,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said teeth presenting a pair of radially extending and spaced face/flank surfaces,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top land surface extending circumferentially between said pair of face/flank surfaces,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said gear teeth having a proximal end disposed in said sockets and being arcuate and circumferentially wider than said throat,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said teeth including a resilient material adjacent said throat for compressing and allowing movement of said tooth relative to said outer periphery of said hub, and
<claim-text>each of said sockets and said resilient material of each of said teeth define at least one gap therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said teeth diverge from adjacent said throat to said face/flank surfaces and converge toward said top land surface,</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said sockets diverge from said throat to said periphery to a lesser degree than said diverging teeth to define a pair of said gaps on each side circumferentially of said teeth from said throat to said outer periphery,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said teeth being entirely of said resilient material,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said proximal ends is complementary to and fills said arcuate socket ends,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said hub defining a boss coaxial with said central axis and having a third thickness in the axial direction being greater than said second thickness,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said boss defining a recess having a hexagonal shape and coaxial with said central axis, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fillets between said boss and said hub. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
