<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624654-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624654</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13552326</doc-number>
<date>20120718</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-171202</doc-number>
<date>20110804</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327308</main-classification>
<further-classification>4551272</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Automatic step variable attenuator and radio communication device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5204976</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Baldwin et al.</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6590437</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Imai</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7205817</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0176665</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhang et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327308</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-286654</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Dmitriy Rozenblit, Darioush Agahi, Gain Control Systems and Methods for Controlling and Adjustable Power Level, Oct. 6, 2011, WO2011/123100, Figure 1.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Extended European Search Report issued Nov. 19, 2012 for corresponding European Application No. 12175138.2-1233.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327308</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4551272</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130033316</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130207</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sasho</last-name>
<first-name>Noboru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoshikawa</last-name>
<first-name>Naoto</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sasho</last-name>
<first-name>Noboru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoshikawa</last-name>
<first-name>Naoto</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sony Corporation</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sony Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Poos</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An automatic step variable attenuator includes: a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style; a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="158.24mm" wi="242.23mm" file="US08624654-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="243.59mm" wi="135.30mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.23mm" wi="157.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="167.81mm" wi="148.34mm" file="US08624654-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="193.38mm" wi="152.06mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="77.13mm" wi="99.99mm" file="US08624654-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="187.37mm" wi="140.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="182.71mm" wi="149.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="249.17mm" wi="148.76mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624654-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to an automatic step variable attenuator which is capable of being applied to a front-end portion in a receiver of either a radio communication device or a television (TV) system, and a radio communication device to which the automatic step variable attenuator is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">For the purpose of enabling an RF received signal having a wide range to be received, a radio receiver includes a variable gain function.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Normally, for enabling the range to be obtained as largely as possible, the variable function is not consolidated into one element, but is dispersed into plural elements in many cases.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The variable gain functional element is roughly classified into a variable gain amplifier and a variable attenuator depending on whether or not the variable gain functional element has a gain of one or more power.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In particular, the latter is normally high in linearity because it can be mainly composed of a passive element such as a resistive element or a switch. Thus, the latter is mounted to the front-end of the receiver, whereby a variable gain function is obtained without deteriorating a signal when an excessive RF received signal is inputted thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For example, there is known a Low-IF type radio receiver including an element having three variable gain functions in a receiver signal path. In this case, an automatic step variable attenuator, a low-noise variable gain amplifier or an IF variable gain amplifier corresponds to the variable gain functional element.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An automatic gain controlling circuit in which the automatic step variable attenuator is mounted to the front-end portion of the receiver is known as this sort of technique. This sort of technique, for example, is disclosed in Japanese Patent Laid-Open No. 2000-286654.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The known technique described above is configured as a feedback system in which a detector is mounted to a subsequent stage of a step attenuator in order to realize the automatic step variable function.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The feedback system has an advantage that a signal dynamic range in which the detector is operated has only to be small.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">However in the circuit which is autonomously operated, the input of the RF signal to the detector is changed whenever the step is switched over to another one. Thus, time until stabilization of the output signal is required, and thus time until decision of the final step attenuation value from start of the operation has a tendency to become long.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">For example, when the system described above is utilized in a terrestrial analog TV receiver, the attenuation value of the automatic step attenuator needs to be decided for a period of time required for the receiver channel setting (for this period of time, no output to a TV image is carried out because the initial setting such as the gain setting is carried out in the receiver and the demodulator in the subsequent stage).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">When the switching is carried out in the step attenuator after completion of the channel setting, the noise is provided to the image, which is not preferable.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It is desirable to provide an automatic step variable attenuator in which time ranging from start of an operation to decision of a final step attenuation value can be shortened, and a radio communication device to which the automatic step variable attenuator is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In order to attain the desire described above, according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, there is provided an automatic step variable attenuator including: a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style; a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to said step variable attenuator.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to another embodiment of the present disclosure, there is provided a radio communication device including: an automatic step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in a step-like style; and a low-noise amplifier amplifying a received signal outputted from the automatic step variable attenuator with a predetermined gain, the automatic step variable attenuator including: a step variable attenuator attenuating the received signal of the electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style, and outputting the resulting received signal to the low-noise amplifier; a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from said detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As set forth hereinabove, according to the present disclosure, it is possible to shorten the time ranging from start of the operation to decision of the final step attenuation value.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram, partly in block, showing a configuration of a radio communication device according to a first embodiment of the present disclosure in which an automatic step variable attenuator according to a second embodiment of the present disclosure is adopted;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram showing a configuration of the automatic step variable attenuator according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a graph showing input/output characteristics of a detector in the automatic step variable attenuator according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a circuit diagram showing a configuration of a step variable attenuator in the automatic step variable attenuator according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing an example of correspondence between a control signal of the step variable attenuator shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and an attenuation area;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a graphical representation showing a situation in which thresholds of comparators in a hysteresis comparator portion in accordance with an output voltage from the detector;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a graphical representation showing a situation in which the thresholds of the comparators in the hysteresis comparator portion in accordance with the output voltage from the detector in the case where the automatic step variable attenuator has an upper side (high-level side) threshold shifting function; and</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a graphical representation explaining the case where the upper side (high-level side) threshold shifting function is necessary.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Embodiments of the present disclosure will be described in detail hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is noted that the description will be given below in accordance with the following order.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0027">1. First Embodiment: Radio Communication Device</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0028">2. Second Embodiment: Automatic Step Variable Attenuator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0029">2-1. Configuration of Detector</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0030">2-2. Configuration of Step Variable Attenuator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0031">2-3. Configuration of Reference Voltage Generating Portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0032">2-4. Configuration of Hysteresis Comparator Portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0033">2-5. Configuration of Upper Side (High-Level Side) Threshold Shifting Functional Portion
<br/>
1. First Embodiment: Radio Communication Device
</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a circuit diagram, partly in block, showing a configuration of a radio communication device according to a first embodiment of the present disclosure in which an automatic step variable attenuator according to a second embodiment of the present disclosure is adopted.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0035">The radio communication device <b>10</b> of the first embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows, as an example, a configuration of a front-end portion of a Low-IF type tuner as a radio receiver.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0036">The radio communication device <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, includes an antenna <b>11</b>, the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b>, a register setting portion <b>13</b>, a low-noise variable amplifier (LNA) <b>14</b>, and band-pass filters (BPFs) <b>15</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>15</b>-<i>n </i>(n=3 in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0037">The radio communication device <b>10</b> further includes a local oscillator <b>16</b>, a frequency divider <b>17</b>, mixers <b>18</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>18</b>-<b>2</b>, a polyphase filter <b>19</b>, and an IF variable gain amplifier <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0038">Thus, the radio communication device <b>10</b> is configured so as to include the three variable gain elements: the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b>; the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b>; and the IF variable gain amplifier <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0039">The radio communication device <b>10</b>, for example, has a variable gain dynamic range of 80 dB or more by utilizing the three variable gain elements. Thus, the radio communication device <b>10</b> can maintain the optimal output level for an input signal level having a wide range.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0040">In addition, the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> composed of a passive element is mounted to an input portion of the radio communication device <b>10</b>. As a result, when a large interfering wave is inputted, a signal inputted to the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b> composed of an active element which is easy to generate a distortion can be reduced without generating any of the distortions.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0041">The automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> automatically selects an optimal attenuator amount corresponding to both of a received signal electric power and the interfering wave electric power, attenuates a radio received signal (RF signal) received at the antenna <b>11</b> with the attenuation amount thus selected, and outputs the resulting attenuated signal S<b>12</b> to the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0042">The automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> has a function with which the attenuation amount is not perfectly fixed after completion as well of reception initial setting, and switches the threshold over to another one after completion of reception processing setting (such as channel switching) to prevent an unnecessary step switching operation during the receiving operation.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0043">The automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> has a function of shifting an upper side (high-level side) threshold in response to an upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> corresponding to a receiver channel setting completion signal set in the register setting portion <b>13</b>. It is noted that the receiver channel setting completion signal is supplied from an external control system to the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0044">A concrete configuration and function of the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> will be described in detail later.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0045">The low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b> amplifies the output signal S<b>12</b> from the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> with a predetermined gain, and outputs the resulting signal S<b>14</b> thus amplified to each of the BPFs <b>15</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>15</b>-<i>n </i>(n=3 in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0046">The BPFs <b>15</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>15</b>-<i>n </i>extract signals having predetermined frequency bands, respectively, from the output signal S<b>14</b> from the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b>, and output the signals thus extracted to the mixers <b>18</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>18</b>-<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0047">The mixers <b>18</b>-<b>1</b> and <b>18</b>-<b>2</b> mix the output received signals from BPFs <b>15</b>-<b>1</b> to <b>15</b>-<i>n</i>, and an oscillation signal of the local oscillation <b>16</b> with each other to generate an intermediate frequency signal (IF signal), and outputs the IF signal thus generated to the polyphase filter <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0048">The polyphase filter <b>19</b> removes away any of unnecessary components of the IF signal, and outputs the resulting IF signal to the IF variable gain amplifier <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0049">The IF variable gain amplifier <b>20</b> amplifies the IF signal with a predetermined gain.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">2. Second Embodiment: Automatic Step Variable Attenuator</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0050">Next, a description will be given with respect to a concrete configuration and function of the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit diagram showing a configuration of the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0052">The automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, includes a detector <b>121</b>, a step variable attenuator <b>122</b>, a reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>, a hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>, and an upper side (high-level side) threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">2-1. Configuration of Detector</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0053">The detector <b>121</b> is disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> in relation to input of an electric wave received signal (RF signal) (disposed in a preceding stage of the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>), and converts an electric power of the RF signal (electric wave signal) thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of such a voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0054">The detector <b>121</b> outputs the voltage signal S<b>121</b> obtained through the conversion to the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0055">The detector <b>121</b> generates the resulting signal (intensity signal) S<b>121</b> corresponding to a time constant of a resistive element R<b>1</b> and a capacitor C<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a graph representing input/output characteristics of the detector in the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> according to the second embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0057">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an axis of abscissa represents an RF input electric potential [dBm], and an axis of ordinate represents an output voltage [V] from the detector <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0058">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is outputted from the detector <b>121</b> in correspondence to the electric power of the RF signal so as to be monotonously increased.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0059">The detector <b>121</b> shows an operation in which the output voltage from the detector <b>121</b> becomes approximately 0 V before application of the RF signal, and is increased from the moment the RF signal is inputted in accordance with the built-in time constant.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0060">Since in the second embodiment, a feedback system is not adopted, the RF signal inputted to the detector <b>121</b> is not changed in a step-like style.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0061">The time constant of the detector <b>121</b> is selected as a suitable value in such a way that all of the operations for setting the suitable attenuation value of the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> are completed for a receiver channel setting period of time.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">2-2. Configuration of Step Variable Attenuator</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0062">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> attenuates the RF signal (received signal) in a step-like style in accordance with a control signal CTL which is supplied as a feed forward system signal from the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0063">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> in the second embodiment, as an example, is configured as a variable attenuator for carrying out switching in five stages at a step of 5 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0064">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> carries out the switching in the five stages at a step of 5 dB: 5 dB; 10 dB; 15 dB; and 20 dB with 0 dB as a reference as the attenuation value in accordance with the control signal CTL.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0065">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> includes control terminals T<b>1</b> to t<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0066">The reason why the four control terminals T<b>1</b> to t<b>4</b> are disposed in the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> because as an example, the control signal CTL supplied from the hysteresis comparator <b>124</b> contains four (4-bits) signals Vc<b>1</b> to Vc<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0067">The control signal Vc<b>1</b> is supplied to the control terminal T<b>1</b> and the control signal Vc<b>2</b> is supplied to the control terminal T<b>2</b>. Also, the control signal Vc<b>3</b> is supplied to the control terminal T<b>3</b> and the control signal Vc<b>4</b> is supplied to the control terminal T<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0068"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a circuit diagram showing a configuration of the step variable attenuator in the second embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0069">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> includes resistive elements R<b>11</b> to R<b>14</b>, resistive elements Rs<b>11</b>, Rs<b>12</b>, Rs<b>21</b>, Rs<b>22</b>, Rs<b>31</b>, Rs<b>32</b>, Rs<b>41</b>, and Rs<b>42</b>, and nodes ND<b>11</b> and ND<b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0070">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> includes switching transistors ST<b>11</b> to ST<b>14</b>, and switching transistors Ss<b>11</b>, Ss<b>12</b>, Ss<b>21</b>, Ss<b>22</b>, Ss<b>31</b>, Ss<b>32</b>, Ss<b>41</b>, and Ss<b>42</b> each composed of an N-channel field effective transistor (EFT).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0071">Also, the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> includes inverters INV<b>1</b> to INV<b>8</b>, an input terminal TI for the RF signal, and an output terminal TO for the RF signal.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0072">The inverters INV<b>1</b> and INV<b>5</b> are connected in series with the control terminal T<b>1</b>, and the inverters INV<b>2</b> and INV<b>6</b> are connected in series with the control terminal T<b>2</b>. Also, the inverters INV<b>3</b> and INV<b>7</b> are connected in series with the control terminal T<b>3</b>, and the inverters INV<b>4</b> and INV<b>8</b> are connected in series with the control terminal T<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0073">The node ND<b>11</b> is connected to the input terminal T<b>1</b>, and the node ND<b>12</b> is connected to the output terminal TO. Also, one terminal of the resistance element R<b>11</b> is connected to the node ND<b>11</b>, and the other terminal of the resistance element R<b>11</b> is connected to the node ND<b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0074">A drain terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>11</b> is connected to the node ND<b>11</b>, a source terminal thereof is connected to the node ND<b>12</b>, and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0075">One terminal of the resistive element R<b>12</b> is connected to the node ND<b>11</b>, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>12</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>12</b> is connected to the node ND<b>12</b>, and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0076">One terminal of the resistive element R<b>13</b> is connected to the node ND<b>11</b>, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>13</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>13</b> is connected to the node ND<b>12</b>, and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0077">One terminal of the resistive element R<b>14</b> is connected to the node ND<b>11</b>, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>14</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor ST<b>14</b> is connected to the node ND<b>12</b>, and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0078">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>11</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>11</b> and the input terminal TI, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>11</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>11</b> is connected to a reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0079">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>12</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>12</b> and the output terminal TO, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>12</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>12</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and the gate terminal thereof is connected to the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0080">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>21</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>11</b> and the input terminal TI, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>21</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>21</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and the gate terminal thereof is connected to the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0081">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>22</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>12</b> and the output terminal TO and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>22</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>22</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and the gate terminal thereof is connected to the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0082">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>31</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>11</b> and the output terminal TI, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>31</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>31</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and the gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0083">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>32</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>12</b> and the output terminal TO, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>32</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>32</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and the gate terminal thereof is connected to the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0084">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>41</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>11</b> and the input terminal TI, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>41</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>41</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and a gate terminal thereof is connected to an output terminal of the inverter INV<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0085">One terminal of the resistive element Rs<b>42</b> is connected to each of the node ND<b>12</b> and the output terminal TO, and the other terminal thereof is connected to a drain terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>42</b>. A source terminal of the switching transistor Ss<b>42</b> is connected to the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND in this case), and a gate terminal thereof is connected to the output terminal of the inverter INV<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0086">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> composes a so-called &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator. Thus, a suitable resistive value is selected in such a way that in any state, an input impedance becomes constant and an attenuation amount is obtained in a 5 dB step style.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0087"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing an example of correspondence between the control signals of the step variable attenuator shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and attenuation areas.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0088">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, &#x201c;H&#x201d; represents a High level (logic 1) at which the switching transistor is caused to conduct (is turned ON), and &#x201c;L&#x201d; represents a Low level (logic 0) at which the switching transistor becomes non-conduction (is turned OFF). In the second embodiment, an H level corresponds to a first level, and an L level corresponds to a second level.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0089">When the control signals Vc<b>1</b>, Vc<b>2</b>, Vc<b>3</b>, and Vc<b>4</b> supplied to the control terminals T<b>1</b> to T<b>4</b>, respectively, are set at H, H, H, and H levels, each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>1</b> to INV<b>4</b> becomes the L level, and each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>5</b> to INV<b>8</b> becomes the H level. As a result, the switching transistors ST<b>11</b> (ST<b>12</b> to ST<b>14</b>) is (are each) turned ON, and the switching transistors Ss<b>11</b> to Ss<b>42</b> are each turned OFF.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0090">In this case, a bypass state is provided in which the input terminal TI and the output terminal TO are connected to each other through the switching transistor(s) ST<b>11</b>, and thus the attenuation value is 0 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0091">When the control signals Vc<b>1</b>, Vc<b>2</b>, Vc<b>3</b>, and Vc<b>4</b> supplied to the control terminals T<b>1</b> to T<b>4</b> are set at the L, H, H, and H levels, respectively, each of the input signals from the inverters INV<b>2</b> to INV<b>4</b>, and INV<b>5</b> becomes the L level and each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>1</b>, and INV<b>6</b> to INV<b>8</b> becomes the H level. As a result, the switching transistors ST<b>12</b> to ST<b>14</b>, Ss<b>11</b>, and Ss<b>12</b> are each turned ON, and the switching transistors ST<b>11</b>, and Ss<b>21</b> to Ss<b>42</b> are each turned OFF.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0092">In this case, the resistive elements R<b>12</b> to R<b>14</b>, Rs<b>11</b>, and Rs<b>12</b> compose the &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator, and thus the attenuation value becomes 5 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0093">When the control signals Vc<b>1</b>, Vc<b>2</b>, Vc<b>3</b>, and Vc<b>4</b> supplied to the control terminals T<b>1</b> to T<b>4</b> are set at the L, L, H, and H levels, respectively, the following states are obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0094">In this case, each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>3</b>, INV<b>4</b>, INV<b>5</b>, and INV<b>6</b> becomes the L level, and each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>1</b>, INV<b>2</b>, INV<b>7</b>, and INV<b>8</b> becomes the H level. As a result, the switching transistors ST<b>13</b>, ST<b>14</b>, Ss<b>11</b>, Ss<b>12</b>, Ss<b>21</b>, and Ss<b>22</b> are each turned ON, and the switching transistors ST<b>11</b>, ST<b>12</b>, and Ss<b>31</b> to Ss<b>42</b> are each turned OFF.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0095">In this case, the resistive elements R<b>13</b>, R<b>14</b>, Rs<b>11</b>, Rs<b>12</b>, Rs<b>21</b>, and Rs<b>22</b> compose the &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator, and thus the attenuation value becomes 10 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0096">When the control signals Vc<b>1</b>, Vc<b>2</b>, Vc<b>3</b>, and Vc<b>4</b> supplied to the control terminals T<b>1</b> to T<b>4</b> are set at the L, L, L, and H levels, respectively, the following states are obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0097">In this case, each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>4</b>, INV<b>5</b>, INV<b>6</b>, and INV<b>7</b> becomes the L level, and each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>1</b>, INV<b>2</b>, INV<b>3</b>, and INV<b>8</b> becomes the H level. As a result, the switching transistors ST<b>14</b>, Ss<b>11</b>, Ss<b>12</b>, Ss<b>21</b>, Ss<b>22</b>, Ss<b>31</b>, and Ss<b>32</b> are each turned ON, and the switching transistors ST<b>11</b>, ST<b>12</b>, ST<b>13</b>, Ss<b>41</b>, and Ss<b>42</b> are each turned OFF.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0098">In this case, the resistive elements R<b>14</b>, Rs<b>11</b>, Rs<b>12</b>, Rs<b>21</b>, Rs<b>22</b>, Rs<b>31</b>, and Rs<b>32</b> compose the &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator, and thus the attenuation value becomes 15 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0099">When the control signals Vc<b>1</b>, Vc<b>2</b>, Vc<b>3</b>, and Vc<b>4</b> supplied to the control terminals T<b>1</b> to T<b>4</b> are set at the L, L, L, and L levels, respectively, the following states are obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0100">In this case, each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>5</b>, INV<b>6</b>, INV<b>7</b>, and INV<b>8</b> becomes the L level, and each of the output signals from the inverters INV<b>1</b>, INV<b>2</b>, INV<b>3</b>, and INV<b>4</b> becomes the H level. As a result, the switching transistors Ss<b>11</b>, Ss<b>12</b>, Ss<b>21</b>, Ss<b>22</b>, Ss<b>31</b>, Ss<b>32</b>, Ss<b>41</b>, and Ss<b>42</b> are each turned ON, and the switching transistors ST<b>11</b>, ST<b>12</b>, ST<b>13</b>, and ST<b>14</b> are each turned OFF.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0101">In this case, the resistive elements Rs<b>11</b>, Rs<b>12</b>, Rs<b>21</b>, Rs<b>22</b>, Rs<b>31</b>, Rs<b>32</b>, Rs<b>41</b>, and Rs<b>42</b> compose the &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator, and thus the attenuation value becomes 20 dB.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0102">In such a way, the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> carries out the operation having the five states shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0103">With the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>, even when the RF input signal having the excessively large magnitude is inputted to the system, the level of the signal which is outputted to the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b> in the subsequent stage is adjusted in the range within 5 dB in the step variable range.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">2-3. Configuration of Reference Voltage Generating Portion</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0104">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b>, and Vth<b>1</b> to Vth<b>5</b> each serving as a reference voltage used to give a comparison voltage to the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0105">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, includes a current source I<b>21</b>, resistive elements R<b>21</b> to R<b>26</b>, and nodes ND<b>21</b> to ND<b>26</b>. In this case, the current source I<b>21</b> is connected to a power source side. Also, the resistive elements R<b>21</b> to R<b>26</b> are connected in series between the current source I<b>21</b> and the reference electric potential VSS (the grounding electric potential GND).</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0106">In the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>, the node ND<b>21</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>21</b> and the resistive element R<b>22</b>. Also, the node ND<b>22</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>22</b> and the resistive element R<b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0107">The node ND<b>23</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>23</b> and the resistive element R<b>24</b>, and the node ND<b>24</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>24</b> and the resistive element R<b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0108">The node ND<b>25</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>25</b> and the resistive element R<b>26</b>, and the node ND<b>26</b> is composed of a connection point between the resistive element R<b>26</b> and the current source I<b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0109">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> as a voltage PstartV with which electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>22</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0110">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as a voltage (PstartV+5 dB) corresponding to a voltage which is 5 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>23</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0111">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as a voltage (PstartV+10 dB) corresponding to a voltage which is 10 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>24</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0112">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> as a voltage (PstartV+15 dB) corresponding to a voltage which is 15 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>25</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0113">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> as a voltage (PstartV+20 dB) corresponding to a voltage which is 20 dB lower than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>26</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0114">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> generates the zero-th threshold voltage Vth<b>0</b> as a voltage (PstartV&#x2212;5 dB) corresponding to a voltage which is 5 dB lower than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> in the node ND<b>21</b> through the series resistor.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0115">The reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> outputs the zero-th to fifth threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b> to Vth<b>5</b> thus generated to the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> through the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">2-4. Configuration of Hysteresis Comparator Portion</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0116">The hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> generates the control signals CTLs (Vc<b>1</b> to Vc<b>4</b>) corresponding to results of comparison between the voltage signal S<b>121</b> which is basically monotonously increased and which is detected by the detector <b>121</b>, and the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b> to Vth<b>5</b> (Vth<b>0</b>) supplied thereto. The hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> outputs the control signals Vc<b>1</b> to Vc<b>4</b> thus generated to the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0117">The hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> includes plural comparators which compare the threshold voltages Vth<b>2</b> to Vth<b>5</b>, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b> with each other in order from the lowest threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b>, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0118">The hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> switches the comparison starting threshold voltage used in the first comparison from the comparator which compares the lowest threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> with the voltage signal S<b>121</b> and whose output signal is inverted over to the threshold voltage which, for example, is 5 dB lower than the comparison starting threshold voltage, thereby carrying out the comparing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0119">The hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> includes comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>14</b>, and switches SW<b>11</b> to SW<b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0120">The comparator CMP<b>11</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>1</b> set at either the H level or the L level, and the comparator CMP<b>12</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>2</b> set at either the H level or the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0121">The comparator CMP<b>13</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>3</b> set at either the H level or the L level, and the Comparator CMP<b>14</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>4</b> set at either the H level or the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0122">An inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the comparator CMP<b>11</b> is connected to a supply line for the voltage signal S<b>121</b> by the detector <b>121</b>, and a non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof is connected to a terminal, a, of each of the switch SW<b>11</b> and the switch SW<b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0123">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>11</b> is connected to the node ND<b>21</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>. That is to say, the zero-th threshold voltage Vth<b>0</b> as the voltage (PstartV&#x2212;5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower that the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0124">The terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>12</b> is connected to either the node ND<b>22</b> or the node ND<b>23</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> through the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0125">That is to say, either the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> as the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started or the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is higher than the start voltage PstartV is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0126">The switches SW<b>11</b> and SW<b>12</b> are each turned ON or OFF in a complementary style in accordance with the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>11</b>. Specifically, the switch SW<b>12</b> is turned ON and the switch SW<b>11</b> is turned OFF when the output control signal Vc<b>1</b> from the comparator CMP<b>11</b> is set at the H level. On the other hand, the switch SW<b>12</b> is turned OFF and the switch SW<b>11</b> is turned ON when the output control signal Vc<b>1</b> from the comparator CMP<b>11</b> is set at the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0127">In a phase of start of the detection, the comparator CMP<b>11</b> compares the voltage signal S<b>121</b> supplied to the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) thereof, and the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> supplied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0128">The comparator CMP<b>11</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>1</b> set at the H level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is lower than the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b>, and outputs the control signal Vc<b>1</b> set at the L level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is increased to exceed the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0129">As a result, the switch SW<b>12</b> is turned OFF, and the switch SW<b>11</b> is turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0130">The comparator CMP<b>11</b> carries out an operation for comparing the zero-th threshold voltage Vth<b>0</b> as the voltage (PstartV&#x2212;5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b> with each other after the level of the output signal has been inverted. The comparing operation using the zero-th threshold voltage Vth<b>0</b> is continuously carried out until the voltage signal S<b>121</b> becomes lower than the zero-th threshold voltage Vth<b>0</b> and as a result, the level of the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>11</b> is switched over to the H level.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0131">An inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the comparator CMP<b>12</b> is connected to a supply line for the voltage signal S<b>121</b> by the detector <b>121</b>, and a non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof is connected to a terminal, a, of each of the switch SW<b>13</b> and the switch SW<b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0132">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>13</b> is connected to the node ND<b>22</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>. That is to say, the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> as the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0133">The terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>14</b> is connected to either the node ND<b>23</b> or the node ND<b>24</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> through the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0134">That is to say, the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>14</b>. Or, the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 10 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0135">The switches SW<b>13</b> and SW<b>14</b> are each turned ON or OFF in a complementary style in accordance with the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>12</b>. Specifically, the switch SW<b>14</b> is turned ON and the switch SW<b>13</b> is turned OFF when the output control signal Vc<b>2</b> from the comparator CMP<b>12</b> is set at the H level. On the other hand, the switch SW<b>14</b> is turned OFF and the switch SW<b>13</b> is turned ON when the output control signal Vc<b>2</b> from the comparator CMP<b>12</b> is set at the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0136">In a phase of start of the detection, the comparator CMP<b>12</b> compares the voltage signal S<b>121</b> supplied to the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) thereof, and the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> supplied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0137">The comparator CMP<b>12</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>2</b> set at the H level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is lower than the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b>, and outputs the control signal Vc<b>1</b> set at the L level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is increased to exceed the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0138">As a result, the switch SW<b>14</b> is turned OFF, and the switch SW<b>13</b> is turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0139">The comparator CMP<b>12</b> carries out an operation for comparing the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> as the voltage (PstartV&#x2212;5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower than the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b>, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b> after the level of the output signal has been inverted. The comparing operation using the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> is continuously carried out until the voltage signal S<b>121</b> becomes lower than the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> and as a result, the level of the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>12</b> is switched over to the H level.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0140">An inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the comparator CMP<b>13</b> is connected to a supply line for the voltage signal S<b>121</b> by the detector <b>121</b>, and a non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof is connected to a terminal, a, of each of the switch SW<b>15</b> and the switch SW<b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0141">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>15</b> is connected to the node ND<b>23</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>. That is to say, the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0142">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>16</b> is connected to either the node ND<b>24</b> or the node ND<b>25</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> through the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0143">That is to say, the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 10 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>16</b>. Or, the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> as the voltage (PstartV+15 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 15 dB higher than the start voltage PstartV is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0144">The switches SW<b>15</b> and SW<b>16</b> are each turned ON or OFF in a complementary style in accordance with the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>13</b>. Specifically, the switch SW<b>16</b> is turned ON and the switch SW<b>15</b> is turned OFF when the output control signal Vc<b>3</b> from the comparator CMP<b>13</b> is set at the H level. On the other hand, the switch SW<b>16</b> is turned OFF and the switch SW<b>15</b> is turned ON when the output control signal Vc<b>3</b> from the comparator CMP<b>13</b> is set at the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0145">In a phase of start of the detection, the comparator CMP<b>13</b> compares the voltage signal S<b>121</b> supplied to the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) thereof, and the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> supplied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0146">The comparator CMP<b>13</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>3</b> set at the H level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is lower than the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b>, and outputs the control signal Vc<b>3</b> set at the L level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is increased to exceed the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0147">As a result, the switch SW<b>16</b> is turned OFF, and the switch SW<b>15</b> is turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0148">The comparator CMP<b>13</b> carries out an operation for comparing the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower than the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b>, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b> after the level of the output signal has been inverted. The comparing operation using the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> is continuously carried out until the voltage signal S<b>121</b> becomes lower than the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> and as a result, the level of the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>13</b> is switched over to the H level.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0149">An inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) of the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is connected to a supply line for the voltage signal S<b>121</b> by the detector <b>121</b>, and a non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof is connected to a terminal, a, of each of the switch SW<b>17</b> and the switch SW<b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0150">A terminal, b of the switch SW<b>17</b> is connected to the node ND<b>24</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>. That is to say, the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 10 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric potential detection is started.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0151">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>18</b> is connected to either the node ND<b>25</b> or the node ND<b>26</b> of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> through the upper side threshold voltage shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0152">That is to say, the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> as the voltage (PstartV+15 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 15 dB higher than the voltage PstartV with which the electric power detection is started is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>18</b>. Or, the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> as the voltage (PstartV+20 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 20 dB higher than the start voltage PstartV is supplied to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0153">The switches SW<b>17</b> and SW<b>18</b> are each turned ON or OFF in a complementary style in accordance with the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>14</b>. Specifically, the switch SW<b>18</b> is turned ON and the switch SW<b>17</b> is turned OFF when the output control signal Vc<b>4</b> from the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is set at the H level. On the other hand, the switch SW<b>18</b> is turned OFF and the switch SW<b>17</b> is turned ON when the output control signal Vc<b>4</b> from the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is set at the L level.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0154">In a phase of start of the detection, the comparator CMP<b>14</b> compares the voltage signal S<b>121</b> supplied to the inverting input terminal (&#x2212;) thereof, and the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> supplied to the non-inverting input terminal (+) thereof with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0155">The comparator CMP<b>14</b> outputs the control signal Vc<b>4</b> set at the H level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is lower than the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b>, and outputs the control signal Vc<b>4</b> set at the L level when the voltage signal S<b>121</b> is increased to exceed the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0156">As a result, the switch SW<b>18</b> is turned OFF, and the switch SW<b>17</b> is turned ON.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0157">The comparator CMP<b>14</b> carries out an operation for comparing the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower than the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b>, and the voltage signal S<b>121</b> with each other after the level of the output signal has been inverted. The comparing operation using the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> is continuously carried out until the voltage signal S<b>121</b> becomes lower than the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> and as a result, the level of the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is switched over to the H level.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0158">In the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> having such a configuration, the inverting operation is carried out from the comparator CMP<b>11</b> which carries out the comparing operation with the lowest threshold voltage as the output voltage from the detector <b>121</b> rises from 0 V.</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0159"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a graphical representation showing a situation in which the threshold voltages of the respective comparators in the hysteresis comparator portion are changed in accordance with the output voltage from the detector.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0160"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> represents an example of the operations of the comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>14</b> in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> by using a time axis. In addition, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an example of the operations when an upper side shifting function of the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> is not developed.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0161">In this example, there is inputted the RF signal having such a level as to exceed each of the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b> of the first three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> except for the comparator CMP<b>14</b> in the four comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>14</b> in total.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0162">The moment the voltage signal S<b>121</b> of the detector <b>121</b> exceed each of the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b>, the thresholds of the comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> fall to the threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b>, Vth<b>1</b>, and Vth<b>2</b> corresponding to the voltages which are 5 dB lower than the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0163">As a result, an operation in which the comparator states return back to the original states, respectively, due to the presence of the noise or the like is prevented from being caused.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0164">In the second embodiment, the control signals CTLs (Vc<b>1</b> to Vc<b>4</b>) in accordance with which the attenuation for 15 dB is carried out for the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> are outputted from the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">2-5. Configuration of Upper Side (High-Level Side) Threshold Shifting Functional Portion</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0165"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a graphical representation showing a situation in which the thresholds of the comparators of the hysteresis comparator portion are changed in accordance with the output voltage from the detector in the case where the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> has an upper side (high-level side) threshold shifting function.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0166"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a graphical representation explaining the case where the upper side (high-level side) threshold shifting function is required.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0167">The upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> has a function in which as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, when an upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level is received, the threshold voltage Vth of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> is switched over to a high-level threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0168">The upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> shifts the threshold voltage Vth of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted to the threshold voltage corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the threshold voltage before the shift.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0169">In the second embodiment (in the case shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>, the output signals from the three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are inverted, and thus the threshold voltages of the three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are shifted from Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b> to the lower threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b>, Vth<b>1</b>, and Vth<b>2</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0170">Also, in the case described above, the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is not inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0171">When the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level has been received in this state, the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> shifts the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> of the comparator CMP<b>14</b> to the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> of the comparator CMP<b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0172">The reason why the upper side threshold shifting function is mounted will be given below.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0173">A hysteresis margin of 5 dB or more is usually obtained for the lower side (low-level side) threshold by the hysteresis operation for shifting the threshold voltage of the comparator whose output signal is inverted to the threshold voltage corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB lower than the threshold voltage concerned with respect to the threshold voltages within the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0174">For this reason, even when some change as the input level reduction of the RF signal is generated, the output signal from the comparator is prevented from returning back to original one. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, however, there is no hysteresis margin in any of the upper side thresholds.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0175">For this reason, when some RF signal input level increase is generated after the receiver channel setting period of time, it is possible that the switching is caused in the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>. In this case, the image noise is generated in the manner described above.</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0176">In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, when a state is held in which the convergence is made at the voltage which does not barely reach the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b>, the possibility that the third threshold Vth<b>3</b> of the comparator CMP<b>13</b> is exceeded due to the superposition of a minute noise is large.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0177">In addition, there is known a receiving system in which the image noise is generated when the switching operation of the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> is generated during the reception.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0178">Then, for the purpose of preventing the malfunction due to the noise, the upper side threshold shifting function is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0179">For the receiver channel setting period of time, the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> is set at the low level to hold the upper side threshold shifting function in the OFF state, and thus the operation of the system is the same as that described above.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0180">After completion of the receiver channel setting period of time, a signal representing the completion of the receiver channel setting period of time is inputted from the outside to set the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> at the high level, thereby holding the upper side threshold shifting function in the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0181">In this case, the threshold voltage of the comparator CMP<b>14</b> whose output signal is not yet inverted is shifted to the threshold voltage which is 5 dB higher than the threshold voltage concerned.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0182">As a result, the hysteresis margin is obtained on the upper side (high-level side) as well, and thus a state is obtained in which the step attenuator switching is not generated for the objective RF signal input increase/decrease.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0183">The upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> includes switches SW<b>21</b> to SW<b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0184">When the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> is held at the L level, the switches SW<b>21</b>, SW<b>23</b>, SW<b>25</b>, and SW<b>27</b> are each held in the ON state, and the switches SW<b>22</b>, SW<b>24</b>, SW<b>26</b>, and SW<b>28</b> are each held in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0185">On the other hand, when the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> is held at the H level, the switches SW<b>21</b>, SW<b>23</b>, SW<b>25</b>, and SW<b>27</b> are each switched over to the OFF state, and the switches SW<b>22</b>, SW<b>24</b>, SW<b>26</b>, and SW<b>28</b> are each switched over to the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0186">As far as the connection concerned, a terminal, a, of each of the switches SW<b>21</b> and SW<b>22</b> is connected to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>12</b> in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0187">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>21</b> is connected to the node ND<b>22</b> at which the first threshold voltage Vth<b>1</b> as the voltage (PstartV) of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0188">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>22</b> is connected to the node ND<b>23</b> at which the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0189">A terminal, a, of each of the switches SW<b>23</b> and SW<b>24</b> is connected to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>14</b> in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0190">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>23</b> is connected to the node ND<b>23</b> at which the second threshold voltage Vth<b>2</b> as the voltage (PstartV+5 dB) of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0191">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>24</b> is connected to the node ND<b>24</b> at which the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0192">A terminal, a, of each of the switches SW<b>25</b> and SW<b>26</b> is connected to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>16</b> in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0193">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>25</b> is connected to the node ND<b>24</b> at which the third threshold voltage Vth<b>3</b> as the voltage (PstartV+10 dB) of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0194">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>26</b> is connected to the node ND<b>25</b> at which the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> as the voltage (PstartV+15 dB) is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0195">A terminal, a, of each of the switches SW<b>27</b> and SW<b>28</b> is connected to the terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>18</b> in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0196">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>27</b> is connected to the node ND<b>25</b> at which the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> as the voltage (PstartV+15 dB) of the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b> is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0197">A terminal, b, of the switch SW<b>28</b> is connected to the node ND<b>26</b> at which the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> as the voltage (PstartV+20 dB) is developed.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0198">As described above, in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>, the output signals from the three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are each inverted, and thus the threshold voltages of the three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are shifted from Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b> to the lower-side threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b>, Vth<b>1</b>, and Vth<b>2</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0199">Also, in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>4</b> is not inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0200">When the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level has been received in the state, the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> switches the switches SW<b>22</b>, SW<b>24</b>, SW<b>26</b>, and SW<b>28</b> over to the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0201">At this time, the switches SW<b>12</b>, SW<b>14</b>, and SW<b>16</b> of the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> as connection destinations of the switches SW<b>22</b>, SW<b>24</b>, and SW<b>26</b> of the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> are each held in the OFF state, and only the switch SW<b>18</b> of the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> as a connection destination of the switch SW<b>28</b> is held in the ON state.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0202">As a result, the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> of the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is shifted to the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0203">Next, a description will be given with respect to an operation of the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> having the configuration described above.</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0204">Firstly, the RF signal (radio received signal) received through the antenna <b>11</b> is converted into the different signal S<b>121</b> representing the intensity of the</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0205">RF signal such as the voltage or the current in the detector <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0206">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the voltage signal S<b>121</b> which is monotonously increased because it is originated from the RF signal is outputted from the detector <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0207">As far as an operation of the detector <b>121</b> concerned, the output signal from the detector <b>121</b> is approximately the voltage of 0 V before application of the RF signal, and the output signal is increased from the moment the RF signal is inputted in accordance with the built-in time constant.</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0208">Here, since the feedback system is not adopted, the RF signal inputted to the detector <b>121</b> is not changed in the step-like style.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0209">In the reference voltage generating portion <b>123</b>, the threshold voltage as the reference voltage used to give the voltage for comparison in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> is generated in the style of a fixed current with a resistive element.</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0210">At this time, each of the threshold voltages is previously set so as to represent a desired electric power in correspondence to the conversion characteristics of the detector <b>121</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0205" num="0211">In the example concerned, the voltages are decided so as to become the 5 dB-step thresholds in the RF signal electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0206" num="0212">The output voltage signal S<b>121</b> from the detector <b>121</b> is inputted to the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0207" num="0213">In the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>, the inverting operation is carried out from the comparator having the lowest threshold voltage as the detector output voltage rises from 0 V.</p>
<p id="p-0208" num="0214">For example, in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the RF signal having such a level as to exceed each of the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b> to Vth<b>3</b> is inputted up to each of the first three comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> of the four comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>14</b> in total.</p>
<p id="p-0209" num="0215">The moment the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b> to Vth<b>3</b> are each exceeded, the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b> to Vth<b>3</b> of the comparators CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are each reduced by 5 dB. As a result, the operation in which the comparator states return back to the original states, respectively, due to the presence of the noise or the like is prevented from being carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0210" num="0216">The control signals CTLs (Vc<b>1</b> to Vc<b>4</b>) in accordance which the attenuation for 15 dB is carried out are outputted from the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> to the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0211" num="0217">The step variable attenuator <b>122</b> composes the so-called &#x3c0; type resistive attenuator. Thus, the suitable resistive value is selected in such a way that in any state, an input impedance becomes constant and an attenuation amount is obtained in a 5 dB step style.</p>
<p id="p-0212" num="0218">For example, in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the step variable attenuator <b>122</b> is operated in such a way that the step attenuation value for 15 dB is finally obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0213" num="0219">With the step variable attenuator <b>122</b>, even when the RF input signal having the excessively large magnitude is inputted to the system, the level of the signal which is outputted to the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b> in the subsequent stage is adjusted in the range within 5 dB in the step variable range.</p>
<p id="p-0214" num="0220">The suitable time constant in the detector <b>121</b> is selected in such a way that all of the operations described above are completed for the receiver channel setting period of time.</p>
<p id="p-0215" num="0221">The description described above is a description of the operation when the upper side threshold shifting function is not developed.</p>
<p id="p-0216" num="0222">When the upper side threshold shifting function is developed, the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level is supplied to the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0217" num="0223">When the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> has received the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level, the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b> switches the threshold voltage Vth of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted over to the high-level side threshold voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0218" num="0224">The upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> shifts the threshold voltage Vth of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted to the threshold voltage corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the threshold voltage before the shift.</p>
<p id="p-0219" num="0225">In each of the examples shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, in the hysteresis comparator portion <b>124</b>, the output signals from the three components CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are each inverted, and thus the threshold voltages of the three components CMP<b>11</b> to CMP<b>13</b> are shifted from the threshold voltages Vth<b>1</b>, Vth<b>2</b>, and Vth<b>3</b> to the lower-side threshold voltages Vth<b>0</b>, Vth<b>1</b>, and Vth<b>2</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0220" num="0226">Also, the output signal from the comparator CMP<b>14</b> is not inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0221" num="0227">When the upper side threshold shift signal S<b>13</b> set at the high level has been received in this state, the upper side threshold shifting functional portion <b>125</b> shifts the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> of the comparator CMP<b>14</b> to the fifth threshold voltage Vth<b>5</b> corresponding to the voltage which is 5 dB higher than the fourth threshold voltage Vth<b>4</b> of the comparator CMP<b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0222" num="0228">As a result, the hysteresis margin is obtained for the upper side as well, and thus the state is obtained in which the step attenuator switching is not generated for the objective RF signal input increase/decrease.</p>
<p id="p-0223" num="0229">As described above, according to the first and second embodiments of the present disclosure, since the feed forward system is adopted for the step control for the step variable attenuator, the convergence time of the system, that is, the final decision time of the step attenuation amount can be simply decided in accordance with the selection through the selection of the detector time constant.</p>
<p id="p-0224" num="0230">That is to say, the radio communication device <b>10</b> of the first embodiment, for example, has the variable gain dynamic range of 80 dB or more in total by including the three variable gain elements, and can maintain the optimal output level for the input signal level having the wide range.</p>
<p id="p-0225" num="0231">In addition, the automatic step variable attenuator <b>12</b> composed of the passive elements is mounted to an input portion of the radio communication device <b>10</b>. As a result, when the large interfering wave is inputted, the signal inputted to the low-noise variable amplifier <b>14</b> composed of the active element which is easy to generate the distortion can be reduced without generating any of the distortions.</p>
<p id="p-0226" num="0232">In addition, it is possible to realize the automatic step variable attenuator such that since the hysteresis margin is suitably ensured, the generation of the step attenuation switching can be prevented for some change in the RF signal after completion of the receiver channel setting period of time.</p>
<p id="p-0227" num="0233">It is noted that the present disclosure can adopt the following constitutions.</p>
<p id="p-0228" num="0234">(1) An automatic step variable attenuator including:</p>
<p id="p-0229" num="0235">a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style;</p>
<p id="p-0230" num="0236">a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and</p>
<p id="p-0231" num="0237">a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator.</p>
<p id="p-0232" num="0238">(2) The automatic step variable attenuator described in the paragraph (1), in which the comparator portion includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in a step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another, and carries out a comparing operation in such a way that an output signal is inverted from the comparator comparing the lowest threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal with each other, and the lowest threshold of the comparator whose output signal is inverted is switched over to a threshold lower than the threshold which is used in the first comparison.</p>
<p id="p-0233" num="0239">(3) The automatic step variable attenuator described in the paragraph (1) or (2), in which the intensity signal is a signal which is basically monotonously increased;</p>
<p id="p-0234" num="0240">the comparator portion includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in a step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another;</p>
<p id="p-0235" num="0241">each of the plural components outputs the control signal set at a first level when the intensity signal does not exceed a threshold for comparison start given so as to correspond thereto, and outputs the control signal set at a second level obtained by inverting the first level when the intensity signal exceeds the threshold for comparison start; and</p>
<p id="p-0236" num="0242">compares a threshold which is given so as to be substituted for the threshold for comparison start, and which is at least one step lower than the threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal when the control signal set at the second level is outputted.</p>
<p id="p-0237" num="0243">(4) The automatic step variable attenuator described in the paragraph (2) or (3), further including:</p>
<p id="p-0238" num="0244">a threshold shifting functional portion shifting the thresholds for comparison start of the comparators to thresholds which are higher than the thresholds for comparison start, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0239" num="0245">(5) The automatic step variable attenuator described in the paragraph (4), in which the threshold shifting functional portion shifts the threshold(s) of the comparator(s) whose output signal(s) is(are) not inverted of the plural comparators as a result of comparing the intensity signal and the thresholds for comparison start with one another to the threshold(s) which is(are) higher than the threshold(s) of the comparator(s) whose output signal(s) is(are) not inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0240" num="0246">(6) A radio communication device including:</p>
<p id="p-0241" num="0247">an automatic step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in a step-like style; and</p>
<p id="p-0242" num="0248">a low-noise amplifier amplifying a received signal outputted from said automatic step variable attenuator with a predetermined gain, the automatic step variable attenuator including:
<ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0249">a step variable attenuator attenuating the received signal of the electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style, and outputting the resulting received signal to the low-noise amplifier;</li>
        <li id="ul0003-0002" num="0250">a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and</li>
        <li id="ul0003-0003" num="0251">a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to said step variable attenuator.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0243" num="0252">(7) The radio communication device described in the paragraph (6), in which the comparator portion includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in a step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another, and carries out a comparing operation in such a way that an output signal is inverted from the comparator comparing the lowest threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal with each other, and the lowest threshold of the comparator whose output signal is inverted is switched over to a threshold lower than the threshold which is used in the first comparison.</p>
<p id="p-0244" num="0253">(8) The radio communication device described in the paragraph (6) or (7), in which the intensity signal is a signal which is basically monotonously increased;</p>
<p id="p-0245" num="0254">the comparator portion includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in a step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another;</p>
<p id="p-0246" num="0255">each of the plural components outputs the control signal set at a first level when the intensity signal does not exceed a threshold for comparison start given so as to correspond thereto, and outputs the control signal set at a second level obtained by inverting the first level when the intensity signal exceeds the threshold for comparison start; and</p>
<p id="p-0247" num="0256">compares a threshold which is given so as to be substituted for the threshold for comparison start, and which is at least one step lower than the threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal when the control signal set at the second level is outputted.</p>
<p id="p-0248" num="0257">(9) The radio communication device described in the paragraph (7) or (8), further including:</p>
<p id="p-0249" num="0258">a threshold shifting functional portion shifting the thresholds for comparison start of the comparators to thresholds which are higher than the thresholds for comparison start, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0250" num="0259">(10) The radio communication device described in the paragraph (9), in which the threshold shifting functional portion shifts the threshold(s) of the comparator(s) whose output signal(s) is(are) not inverted of the plural comparators as a result of comparing the intensity signal and the thresholds for comparison start with one another to the threshold(s) which is(are) higher than the threshold(s) of the comparator(s) whose output signal(s) is(are) not inverted.</p>
<p id="p-0251" num="0260">The present disclosure contains subject matter related to that disclosed in Japanese Priority Patent Application JP 2011-171202 filed in the Japan Patent Office on Aug. 4, 2011, the entire content of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0252" num="0261">It should be understood by those skilled in the art that various modifications, combinations, sub-combinations and alterations may occur depending on design requirements and other factors insofar as they are within the scope of the appended claims or the equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An automatic step variable attenuator comprising:
<claim-text>a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator, wherein the comparator portion
<claim-text>includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in the step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>carries out a comparing operation in such a way that an output signal is inverted from the comparator comparing a lowest threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal with each other, and the lowest threshold of the comparator whose output signal is inverted is switched over to a threshold lower than the threshold which is used in first comparison.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The automatic step variable attenuator according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the intensity signal is a signal which is basically monotonously increased; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said plural comparators
<claim-text>outputting the control signal set at a first level when the intensity signal does not exceed the threshold for comparison start given so as to correspond thereto, and outputting the control signal set at a second level obtained by inverting the first level when the intensity signal exceeds the threshold for comparison start, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing a threshold which is given so as to be substituted for the threshold for comparison start, and which is at least one step lower than the threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal when the control signal set at the second level is outputted.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The automatic step variable attenuator according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a threshold shifting functional portion shifting the thresholds for comparison start of the comparators to thresholds which are higher than the thresholds for comparison start, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The automatic step variable attenuator according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said threshold shifting functional portion shifts the threshold of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted of said plural comparators as a result of comparing the intensity signal and the thresholds for comparison start with one another to the threshold which is higher than the threshold of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A radio communication device comprising:
<claim-text>an automatic step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in a step-like style; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a low-noise amplifier amplifying a received signal outputted from the automatic step variable attenuator with a predetermined gain,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the automatic step variable attenuator including
<claim-text>a step variable attenuator attenuating the received signal of the electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in the step-like style, and outputting the resulting received signal to the low-noise amplifier,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator, wherein the comparator portion</claim-text>
<claim-text>includes plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in the step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>carries out a comparing operation in such a way that an output signal is inverted from the comparator comparing a lowest threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal with each other, and the lowest threshold of the comparator whose output signal is inverted is switched over to a threshold lower than the threshold which is used in first comparison.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The radio communication device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the intensity signal is a signal which is basically monotonously increased; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said plural comparators
<claim-text>outputting the control signal set at a first level when the intensity signal does not exceed the threshold for comparison start given so as to correspond thereto, and outputting the control signal set at a second level obtained by inverting the first level when the intensity signal exceeds the threshold for comparison start, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing a threshold which is given so as to be substituted for the threshold for comparison start, and which is at least one step lower than the threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal when the control signal set at the second level is outputted.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The radio communication device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a threshold shifting functional portion shifting the thresholds for comparison start of the comparators to thresholds which are higher than the thresholds for comparison start, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The radio communication device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said threshold shifting functional portion shifts the threshold of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted of said plural comparators as a result of comparing the intensity signal and the thresholds for comparison start with one another to the threshold which is higher than the threshold of the comparator whose output signal is not inverted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An automatic step variable attenuator comprising:
<claim-text>a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a threshold shifting functional portion shifting thresholds for comparison start of plural comparators, included in the comparator portion, to thresholds which are higher than the thresholds for comparison start, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An automatic step variable attenuator comprising:
<claim-text>a step variable attenuator attenuating a received signal of an electric wave signal in an attenuation amount corresponding to a control signal in a step-like style;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector disposed in parallel with the step variable attenuator for input of the received signal of the electric wave signal, and converting an electric power of the received signal thus inputted into an intensity signal representing an intensity of the received signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator portion generating the control signal corresponding to a result of comparison for differences between the intensity signal obtained from the detector and plural threshold values, and outputting the control signal thus generated to the step variable attenuator, wherein the intensity signal is a signal which is basically monotonously increased, wherein the comparator portion comprises plural comparators comparing thresholds whose values are different from one another in the step-like style, and the intensity signal with one another, and wherein each of the plural comparators:
<claim-text>outputs the control signal set at a first level when the intensity signal does not exceed a threshold for comparison start given so as to correspond thereto, and outputs the control signal set at a second level obtained by inverting the first level when the intensity signal exceeds the threshold for comparison start, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>compares a threshold which is given so as to be substituted for the threshold for comparison start, and which is at least one step lower than the threshold for comparison start, and the intensity signal when the control signal set at the second level is outputted. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
