<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626137-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626137</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13214098</doc-number>
<date>20110819</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>98</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>42</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455415</main-classification>
<further-classification>455566</further-classification>
<further-classification>4554143</further-classification>
<further-classification>455418</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Providing caller identification to mobile devices</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6253075</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Beghtol et al.</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455415</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0157732</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hao et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>707102</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0298489</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chitturi et al.</name>
<date>20091200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455418</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0056117</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wolfman et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4554143</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0198854</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chitturi et al.</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>707760</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0203874</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Scott et al.</name>
<date>20100800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>455415</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455410-417</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>455567</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>379 8821- 8823</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>37914201-14218</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61375416</doc-number>
<date>20100820</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Devitt</last-name>
<first-name>Jason A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wells</last-name>
<first-name>Michael L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Redwood City</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Devitt</last-name>
<first-name>Jason A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Francisco</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wells</last-name>
<first-name>Michael L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Redwood City</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fenwick &#x26; West LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>WhitePages, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Seattle</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Siddiqui</last-name>
<first-name>Kashif</first-name>
<department>2646</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A caller information server provides caller identification (ID) information to a mobile device. The server receives caller ID information from local address books stored on multiple mobile devices. The caller information server aggregates the received caller ID information to generate a pooled address book. The caller information server may determine whether names within the caller ID information are legitimate and store or filter the information accordingly. When a mobile device receives a call from a telephone number for which it lacks caller ID information in its local address book, the mobile device sends a request for the caller ID information for the telephone number, to the caller information server. The server identifies caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book, and sends this information to the mobile device.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="189.48mm" wi="235.97mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="238.51mm" wi="192.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626137-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="239.86mm" wi="168.66mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="155.87mm" wi="152.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626137-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="191.77mm" wi="171.37mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626137-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="251.71mm" wi="182.54mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="178.90mm" wi="108.37mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="179.24mm" wi="152.23mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="186.77mm" wi="135.72mm" file="US08626137-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 61/375,416, Aug. 20, 2010, which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of Disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates generally to mobile communications, and more specifically to techniques for determining caller ID information associated with telephone calls.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Users of a mobile device can send and receive telephone calls and text messages to and from a wide range of telephone numbers. Mobile devices include, for example, cellular telephones. Many mobile devices are capable of saving and accessing information related to telephone calls and text messages. A mobile device may include an address book that lists contacts stored by a user of the device along with telephone numbers and other information about the contacts. The mobile device may also store a history of telephone numbers corresponding to outbound and inbound calls, and may store a history of sent and received text messages. The user can use this information in order to answer particular telephone calls that may be urgent to the user or to screen particular telephone calls. However, if a telephone number is not stored on the user's mobile device, the user cannot determine whether the telephone call is from a contact that the user wants to communicate with or from a third party that a user wants to screen.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Phone operators may provide caller ID information for an incoming or outgoing telephone call by matching a telephone number against a particular database. For example, a mobile or a landline telephone operator may maintain a database of user telephone numbers associated with a user-provided billing name. Thus, a telephone operator may provide the billing name associated with a particular telephone number. However, most databases associated with a mobile telephone operator are incomplete because telephone operators only have access to billing information associated with their own customers. In general, telephone operators do not share their customer billing information with their competitors. Additionally, the user-provided billing name may be an inaccurate description of a telephone number in a case where one billing name is provided for several associated telephone numbers such as employer-provided telephone plans or telephone numbers in a family or a group payment plan. Finally, users of prepaid phones generally do not provide a billing name to mobile phone operators, thus a vast number of billing names associated with mobile device phone numbers are not available to mobile telephone operators. In practice, major mobile telephone operators in the US generally do not provide caller ID services to its customers at this time.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The above and other needs are addressed by a method, computer and computer-readable storage media storing instruction for providing caller identification (ID) information to a mobile device. Embodiments of the method comprise receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices and generating a pooled address book that aggregates the received caller ID information. Additionally, the method comprises receiving a request from a mobile device for caller ID information associated with a telephone number wherein caller ID information associated with the telephone number is not present in a local address book of the mobile device. The method further comprises identifying caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book and sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the mobile device. The method may further comprise receiving caller ID information requests from plurality of mobile devices, wherein the caller ID information is associated with telephone numbers from which calls were made to the mobile device. The method comprises analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance calls that users are likely to decline to answer. Furthermore, responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a call was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, the method comprises identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance call in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Embodiments of the computer-readable storage medium store executable computer program instructions. The instructions, in turn comprise receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices and generating a pooled address book that aggregates the received caller ID information. The instructions further comprise receiving a request from a mobile device for caller ID information associated with a telephone number wherein caller ID information associated with the telephone number is not present in a local address book of the mobile device. The instructions additionally comprise identifying caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book and sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the mobile device. The instructions further comprise receiving caller ID information requests from plurality of mobile devices, wherein the caller ID information is associated with telephone numbers from which calls were made to the mobile device. The instructions comprise analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance calls that users are likely to decline to answer. Furthermore, responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a call was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, the instructions comprise identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance call in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Embodiments of the computer comprise a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing executable computer program instructions. The instructions, in turn comprise receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices and generating a pooled address book that aggregates the received caller ID information. The instructions further comprise receiving a request from a mobile device for caller ID information associated with a telephone number wherein caller ID information associated with the telephone number is not present in a local address book of the mobile device. The instructions additionally comprise identifying caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book and sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the mobile device. The instructions further comprise receiving caller ID information requests from plurality of mobile devices, wherein the caller ID information is associated with telephone numbers from which calls were made to the mobile device. The instructions comprise analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance calls that users are likely to decline to answer. Furthermore, responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a call was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, the instructions comprise identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance call in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Additionally, a computer-implemented method of obtaining caller identification (ID) information associated with a telephone number is provided. Embodiments of the method comprise sending caller ID information from a local address book of a mobile device to a caller information server that is adapted to generate a pooled address book that aggregates caller ID information received from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices. The method further comprises sending a request to the caller information server requesting caller ID information for a telephone number responsive to detecting an incoming communication received by the mobile device from the telephone number, wherein the caller information server is adapted to identify caller ID information for the telephone number in the pooled address book. Additionally, the method comprises receiving the caller ID information for the telephone number from the caller information server. The method further comprises determining whether to block the incoming communication responsive to the received caller ID information and blocking the incoming communication responsive to a positive determination.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high-level block diagram that illustrates a computing environment for determining caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a typical computer for use as a caller information server or mobile device according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a detailed view of modules within a mobile application according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a detailed view of modules within a caller information server according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of providing caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of determining caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates an exemplary user interface presented by a display module in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates an exemplary user interface presented by a display module in one embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The figures (FIGS.) and the following description describe certain embodiments by way of illustration only. One skilled in the art will readily recognize from the following description that alternative embodiments of the structures and methods illustrated herein may be employed without departing from the principles described herein. Reference will now be made in detail to several embodiments, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying figures. It is noted that wherever practicable similar or like reference numbers may be used in the figures and may indicate similar or like functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a high-level block diagram that illustrates a computing environment <b>100</b> for determining caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment. As shown, the computing environment <b>100</b> includes a caller information server <b>110</b>, a conventional database <b>112</b> and multiple mobile devices <b>114</b>A-B connected through a network <b>116</b>. Only one caller information server <b>110</b>, one conventional database <b>112</b> and two mobile devices <b>114</b> are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in order to simplify and clarify the present description. Embodiments can have millions of mobile devices <b>114</b>, multiple caller information servers <b>110</b> and multiple conventional databases <b>112</b>. There can be other entities in the computing environment <b>100</b> as well.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The mobile devices <b>114</b> are electronic devices that are used by users to place and receive telephone calls. Examples of mobile devices <b>114</b> include mobile telephones, portable digital assistants (PDAs), notebook and tablet computers, and other devices with telephone functionality. Although this description refers to the devices as &#x201c;mobile,&#x201d; the devices need not be portable. The phrase &#x201c;mobile device&#x201d; can also include a device that is typically stationary, such as a desktop computer.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one embodiment, the mobile devices <b>114</b> include local address books <b>102</b> storing information associated with people or businesses with whom the users communicate. The information in a local address book <b>102</b> of a mobile device <b>114</b> can be manually entered by the user of the mobile device and/or synchronized from another source, such as a MICROSOFT EXCHANGE server. The local address book <b>102</b> information can include, for example, the name of a person and a picture of the person, along with contact details for that person such as one or more telephone numbers, work and/or business addresses, an email address, etc. The local address book <b>102</b> information can also include communication data, including call statistics describing calls placed or received by the mobile devices <b>114</b>, such as the date, frequency and/or duration of calls to people listed in the local address book. For purposes of this description, the information about a person or other entity stored in a local address book <b>102</b> is called the &#x201c;caller identification (ID) information.&#x201d; The phrase &#x201c;caller ID information&#x201d; can also refer to a subset of the information about a person stored in the address book, such as the person's name, telephone numbers, and picture. Caller ID information may include whether a communication was initiated by the mobile device, received by the mobile device, the time and date of the communication.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In typical use, the mobile device <b>114</b> uses the caller ID information in the local address book <b>102</b> to display information about calling and called parties to the user. When the mobile device <b>114</b> receives an inbound call, the mobile device determines the telephone number from which the inbound call was placed and accesses the local address book <b>102</b> to obtain caller ID information associated with the telephone number. For example, the mobile device <b>114</b> can display the name and picture of the caller to the user. If, however, the local address book <b>102</b> lacks information about the calling telephone number, the mobile device <b>114</b> typically displays only the telephone number to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">This limitation of the mobile device <b>114</b> is overcome by a mobile application <b>104</b> that executes on a mobile device <b>114</b> and provides caller ID information for callers that are not listed within the device's local address book <b>102</b>. The mobile application <b>104</b> can be incorporated into the operating system of the mobile device <b>114</b> and/or provided by a third party, such as the operator of the caller information server <b>110</b>. For example, the user of the mobile device <b>114</b> can download the mobile application from an application store and install it on the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> provides the caller ID information in the mobile device's local address book <b>102</b> to the caller information server <b>110</b> via the network <b>116</b>. For example, the mobile application <b>104</b> can provide names, telephone numbers, and pictures from the local address book <b>102</b> to the caller information server <b>110</b>. In addition, the mobile application <b>104</b> receives caller ID information for unknown callers from the caller information server <b>110</b>. When the mobile device <b>114</b> receives a call from an unknown caller (i.e., from a telephone number not listed in the local address book <b>102</b>), the mobile application <b>104</b> queries the caller information server <b>110</b> for caller ID information associated with the telephone number that called the mobile device <b>114</b>. The mobile application <b>104</b> receives the caller ID information from the caller information server <b>110</b> and presents the information to the mobile device <b>114</b> for display to the user. The mobile application <b>104</b> can also use the caller ID information to perform auxiliary services, such as blocking nuisance calls.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The caller information server <b>110</b> is a hardware device and/or software program configured to provide the mobile devices <b>114</b> with caller ID information. The caller information server <b>110</b> interfaces with the mobile application <b>104</b> of the mobile devices <b>114</b> and receives the caller ID information from the local address books <b>102</b> of the devices. The caller information server <b>110</b> aggregates the received information to form a &#x201c;pooled address book.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Upon receiving a request for caller ID information from a mobile device <b>114</b>, the caller information server <b>110</b> determines whether the information is stored within the pooled address book or a conventional database <b>112</b>. Because the pooled address book aggregates caller ID information from local address books <b>102</b> of many mobile devices, the requested information is likely to be included therein. If the caller ID information is in the pooled address book or a conventional database, the caller information server <b>110</b> provides the caller ID information to the requesting mobile device <b>114</b>. The caller information server <b>110</b> can also perform other functions, such as detecting nuisance calls based on caller ID information requests from mobile devices, and purging stale information from the pooled address book.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The one or more conventional databases <b>112</b> provide caller ID information to the caller information server <b>110</b>. In one embodiment, if caller ID information associated with a phone number is not present in the pooled address book, the caller information server <b>110</b> queries a conventional database <b>112</b> to retrieve the caller ID information. In one embodiment, a conventional database <b>112</b> is maintained by a telephone service provider, a commercial database provider, or by another entity. Thus, the conventional databases <b>112</b> are supplemental sources of information the caller information server <b>110</b> can use in addition to the pooled address book. The network <b>116</b> enables communications between the caller information server <b>110</b>, the mobile devices <b>114</b>, and the conventional databases <b>112</b>. In one embodiment, the network <b>116</b> uses standard communications technologies and/or protocols and can include the Internet as well as mobile telephone networks. Thus, the network <b>116</b> can include links using technologies such as Ethernet, 802.11, worldwide interoperability for microwave access (WiMAX), 2G/3G/4G mobile communications protocols, digital subscriber line (DSL), asynchronous transfer mode (ATM), InfiniBand, PCI Express Advanced Switching, etc. Similarly, the networking protocols used on the network <b>116</b> can include multiprotocol label switching (MPLS), the transmission control protocol/Internet protocol (TCP/IP), the User Datagram Protocol (UDP), the hypertext transport protocol (HTTP), the simple mail transfer protocol (SMTP), the file transfer protocol (FTP), etc. The data exchanged over the network <b>116</b> can be represented using technologies and/or formats including image data in binary form (e.g. Portable Network Graphics (PNG)), the hypertext markup language (HTML), the extensible markup language (XML), etc. In addition, all or some of links can be encrypted using conventional encryption technologies such as secure sockets layer (SSL), transport layer security (TLS), virtual private networks (VPNs), Internet Protocol security (IPsec), etc. In another embodiment, the entities on the network <b>116</b> can use custom and/or dedicated data communications technologies instead of, or in addition to, the ones described above.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a typical computer <b>200</b> for use as a caller information server <b>110</b> or mobile device <b>112</b>. Illustrated are a processor <b>202</b> coupled to a chipset <b>204</b>. Also coupled to the chipset <b>204</b> are a memory <b>206</b>, a storage device <b>208</b>, a keyboard <b>210</b>, a graphics adapter <b>212</b>, a pointing device <b>214</b>, and a network adapter <b>216</b>. A display <b>218</b> is coupled to the graphics adapter <b>212</b>. In one embodiment, the functionality of the chipset <b>204</b> is provided by a memory controller hub <b>220</b> and an I/O controller hub <b>222</b>. In another embodiment, the memory <b>206</b> is coupled directly to the processor <b>202</b> instead of the chipset <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The storage device <b>208</b> is a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium, such as a hard drive, compact disk read-only memory (CD-ROM), DVD, or a solid-state memory device. The memory <b>206</b> holds instructions and data used by the processor <b>202</b>. The pointing device <b>214</b> is a mouse, track ball, or other type of pointing device, and is used in combination with the keyboard <b>210</b> to input data into the computer system <b>200</b>. The graphics adapter <b>212</b> displays images and other information on the display <b>218</b>. The network adapter <b>216</b> couples the computer <b>200</b> to the network <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As is known in the art, a computer <b>200</b> can have different and/or other components than those shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In addition, the computer <b>200</b> can lack certain illustrated components. In one embodiment, a computer <b>200</b> acting as the caller information server <b>110</b> is formed of multiple blade computers and lacks a keyboard <b>210</b>, pointing device <b>214</b>, graphics adapter <b>212</b>, and/or display <b>218</b>. Moreover, the storage device <b>208</b> can be local and/or remote from the computer <b>200</b> (such as embodied within a storage area network (SAN)). As another example, a mobile device <b>114</b> might comprise a Smartphone with limited processing power and a touch screen interface.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">This description uses the term &#x201c;module&#x201d; to refer to computer program logic for providing a specified functionality. A module can be implemented in hardware, firmware, and/or software. A module is typically stored on a computer-readable storage medium such as the storage device <b>208</b>, loaded into the memory <b>206</b>, and executed by the processor <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a detailed view of modules within the mobile application <b>104</b> according to one embodiment. The mobile application includes an interface module <b>302</b>, a call interception module <b>304</b>, an information lookup module <b>306</b>, a display module <b>308</b>, a blocking module <b>310</b> and a local cache <b>312</b>. Some embodiments of the mobile application <b>104</b> have different and/or other modules than the ones described herein. Similarly, the functions can be distributed among the modules in accordance with other embodiments in a different manner than is described here. Likewise, the functions can be performed by other entities.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The interface module <b>302</b> interfaces the mobile device <b>114</b> with the caller information server <b>110</b> to exchange information. In one embodiment, the interface module <b>302</b> sends caller ID information from the mobile device's local address book <b>102</b> to the caller information server <b>110</b>. To this end, the interface module <b>302</b> accesses the local address book <b>102</b>, identifies caller ID information contained therein, and sends the caller ID information to the caller information server <b>110</b>. As mentioned above, in one embodiment the interface module <b>302</b> sends only a subset of information in the local address book to the caller information server <b>110</b>. For example, in one embodiment the interface module sends the names and telephone numbers of people described in the local address book <b>102</b> to the server <b>110</b>, but does not send addresses, job titles, and other information that may be present in the address book. In addition, an embodiment of the interface module <b>302</b> also sends communications data including call statistics, such as dates on when the mobile device <b>114</b> last placed or received a call with a person identified in the local address book, to the caller information server <b>110</b>. The interface module <b>302</b> can send the caller ID information to the caller information server <b>110</b> on a periodic basis, at the request of the user, upon update of the local address book <b>102</b>, and/or at other times. In one embodiment, a user of a mobile device <b>114</b> can send caller ID information associated with his or her own mobile device <b>114</b>. To this end, a user can announce a user name, business, purpose of call or other contact information to others.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The call interception module <b>304</b> intercepts processing of telephone calls incoming to the mobile device <b>114</b>. In one embodiment, the call interception module <b>304</b> detects when an incoming telephone call is received by the mobile device <b>114</b>, and supplements or replaces functionality on the mobile device <b>114</b> for displaying caller ID information to the user. While this description refers to processing of telephone calls, &#x201c;telephone calls,&#x201d; as used herein, also refers to other communications made using the mobile device <b>114</b>, such as text and multimedia messages.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Upon intercepting the telephone call, the call interception module <b>304</b> determines the telephone number of the calling party, and determines whether this telephone number is in the local address book <b>102</b>. In one embodiment, if the number is in the local address book <b>102</b>, the call interception module <b>304</b> returns processing to the mobile device <b>114</b> and lets the mobile device resume normal processing of the call. If, however, the telephone number is not in the local address book, an embodiment of the call interception module <b>304</b> activates the information lookup module <b>306</b> to obtain caller ID information from a local cache <b>312</b> of caller ID information obtained from the caller information server <b>110</b> or by communicating with the caller information server <b>110</b>. The call interception module <b>304</b> can also activate the information lookup module <b>306</b> in other situations where the caller information server <b>110</b> might have more accurate caller ID information than the local address book <b>102</b>, such as when a predetermined amount of time has elapsed since the last communication from the caller and/or when the information in the local address book <b>102</b> is incomplete.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The information lookup module <b>306</b>, in turn, performs a lookup operation in the local cache <b>312</b> or with the caller information server <b>110</b> to determine caller ID information associated with a telephone number. The local cache <b>312</b> may contain results from recent lookups, or it may contain a predetermined and regularly updated list of numbers that are likely callers, such as a list of nuisance callers. In one embodiment, the information lookup module <b>306</b> receives the telephone number of the calling party from the call interception module <b>304</b> and sends the number to the caller information server <b>110</b> within a request for caller ID information. Assuming the telephone number has associated caller ID information within the pooled address book or conventional databases <b>112</b>, the information lookup module <b>306</b> receives caller ID information from the caller information server <b>110</b> in response to the lookup. The caller ID information can also indicate whether the call is likely from a nuisance caller, such as a telemarketer.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Some embodiments of the mobile application <b>114</b> include a blocking module <b>310</b> that automatically blocks certain types of incoming telephone calls before they are displayed to the user by the display module <b>308</b>. In one embodiment, a user can provide a blacklist of phone numbers or user names to the blocking module <b>310</b>. The user names may include an individual's name or an entity's name. The blocking module <b>310</b> blocks incoming communications from the blacklisted phone number. Additionally, the blocking module <b>310</b> may receive a name associated with an incoming phone call or communication from the interface module <b>302</b> or the information lookup module <b>306</b>. If the user name matches a name on the blacklist, the block module <b>310</b> may block the incoming communication. In one embodiment, the user can configure the blocking module <b>310</b> to automatically block calls flagged as nuisance calls by the caller ID information returned from the caller information server <b>110</b>. Other embodiments can block different and/or additional types of calls.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The display module <b>308</b> displays the caller ID information retrieved by the information lookup module <b>306</b> to the user of the mobile device <b>114</b>. In one embodiment, the display module <b>308</b> receives the caller ID information from the information lookup module <b>306</b>. As mentioned above, the caller ID information can include, e.g., a name and picture associated with the telephone number. The display module <b>308</b> interacts with the mobile device <b>114</b> to cause the caller ID information to be displayed on a display of the mobile device. The display module <b>308</b> can also display information related to previous communications with the caller, such as a date and length of a prior call. In one embodiment, the call interception and information lookup performed by the call interception <b>304</b> and information lookup <b>306</b> modules are performed quickly, such that the received caller ID information is presented to the user by the display module <b>308</b> contemporaneously with when the user evaluates whether to answer the call on the mobile device <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In some embodiments, the display module <b>308</b> also displays other information associated with the incoming call. The display module <b>308</b> can provide an indication of whether the call is likely a nuisance call (e.g., from a telemarketer or similar type of calling party). In addition, the display module <b>308</b> can display a user interface permitting the user to save the retrieved caller ID information in the local address book <b>102</b> or to report the caller as a nuisance caller.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref> illustrate exemplary user interfaces presented by the display module <b>308</b> in some embodiments. The user interface includes caller ID information such as a name <b>702</b> of the person associated with the telephone number, employment information <b>704</b> of the person associated with the telephone number and the telephone number <b>706</b>. Additionally, the user interface illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> allows a user to save <b>708</b> the caller ID information of a previously unknown number to the local address book <b>102</b> of a mobile device <b>114</b>, or to ignore the prompt to save the unknown number to the local address book <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a high-level block diagram illustrating a detailed view of modules within the caller information server <b>110</b> according to one embodiment. The modules include a communications module <b>402</b>, a pooled address book module <b>404</b>, a conventional database module <b>405</b>, a nuisance call detection module <b>406</b>, a data-cleaning module <b>408</b>, and a pooled address book database <b>410</b>. Some embodiments of the caller information server <b>110</b> have different and/or other modules than the ones described herein. Similarly, the functions can be distributed among the modules in accordance with other embodiments in a different manner than is described here. Likewise, the functions can be performed by other entities.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The communications module <b>402</b> interfaces with the mobile devices <b>114</b>. In one embodiment, the communications module <b>402</b> receives the caller ID information from the local address books <b>102</b> of the mobile devices <b>114</b>. The caller ID information may be received on a periodic basis, at a request of a mobile device's user, upon update of a local address book of the mobile device, and/or at other times. The communication module <b>402</b> sends the received caller ID information to the pooled address book module <b>404</b>, wherein the pooled address book module <b>404</b> updates the pooled address book database <b>410</b>. As such, the pooled address book database <b>410</b> may be continually updated as caller ID information is received from a mobile device. In addition, the communications module <b>402</b> receives caller ID information lookup requests from the mobile devices <b>114</b>. The communications module <b>402</b> also sends information to the mobile devices <b>114</b>, including caller ID information sent in response to lookup requests. In one embodiment, the communications module <b>402</b> also interfaces with one or more conventional databases <b>112</b>. In such an embodiment, the communications module <b>402</b> receives caller ID information from the conventional databases <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The pooled address book module <b>404</b> maintains the pooled address book database <b>410</b>. The pooled address book module <b>404</b> receives the caller ID information from the local address books <b>102</b> of the mobile devices <b>114</b>, any conventional databases <b>112</b>, and other sources of caller ID information and aggregates the information into a pooled address book. The pooled address book module <b>404</b> also processes the caller ID information to detect irregularities, canonicalize the data, and/or for other purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In one embodiment, the pooled address book module <b>404</b> checks names in the caller ID information for validity. For example, the name that a user supplies for a person in a local address book <b>102</b> may be a nickname or other name that is not suitable for use by users of other mobile devices <b>114</b>. The pooled address book module <b>404</b> detects such issues by checking names in the caller ID information against a white list of legitimate names, such as the U.S. Census name database. If a name does not appear in the white list, an embodiment of the pooled address book module <b>404</b> removes the name from the information or otherwise marks it as not suitable for sharing with mobile devices <b>114</b>. The pooled address book module <b>404</b> can also use a list of subjective identifiers to filter such identifiers from the caller ID information. For example, the filter can identify and remove subjective identifiers such as &#x2018;husband,&#x2019; &#x2018;wife,&#x2019; &#x2018;dad&#x2019; and &#x2018;mom&#x2019; from the caller ID information.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In addition, an embodiment of the pooled address book module <b>404</b> detects conflicting caller ID information received from the mobile devices <b>114</b> and analyzes the caller ID information to select resolved information that resolve the conflicts. For example, if the caller ID information identifies two different names associated with the same telephone number, the pooled address book module can use a voting system to select the resolved name. The voting system uses the name indicated by the majority of the caller ID information received from the various mobile devices <b>114</b>. In another embodiment, if there is a name inconsistency, the pooled address book module <b>404</b> defaults to the name listed in the conventional database <b>112</b>. In another embodiment, the pooled address book module <b>404</b> weighs information such as the duration, frequency, recency, and reciprocity of communication between different users and a single telephone number to determine which user is most likely to have accurate caller ID information for that number, and uses the name from that user's mobile device <b>114</b> as the resolved name. The pooled address book module <b>404</b> thus filters and refines caller ID information associated with one or more telephone numbers to generate an accurate pooled address book.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The pooled address book database <b>410</b> stores the pooled address book. In one embodiment, the pooled address book database <b>410</b> is a relational database using telephone numbers as the primary key. Given a telephone number, the other caller ID information associated with the telephone number can be rapidly obtained from the database. Other embodiments of the pooled address book database <b>410</b> are configured differently and/or use different types of databases.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The conventional database module <b>405</b> queries one or more of the conventional databases <b>112</b> when a suitable result corresponding to a phone number is not found in the pooled address book database <b>410</b>. In one embodiment, the conventional database module <b>405</b> connects to a remote service via the network <b>116</b> to query for a result. In other embodiments, the conventional database module <b>405</b> is configured differently and may return caller ID information in different ways from the conventional database <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> identifies nuisance calls based on the lookup requests and caller ID information. In general, nuisance calls are calls that users of the mobile devices <b>114</b> are likely to decline to answer. Nuisance calls are typically placed by telemarketers, pollsters, political advertisers and other such callers who use automated technology to call a large number of mobile devices <b>114</b>. Since the telephone numbers from which these calls are placed are unlikely to be in the local address books <b>102</b> of the mobile devices <b>114</b>, nuisance calls will typically cause the mobile applications <b>104</b> in the mobile devices to generate lookup requests to the caller information server <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">An embodiment of the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> analyzes the lookup requests and applies one or more heuristics to assign nuisance indication scores to detect nuisance calls based on the lookup requests. For example, if the same telephone number is used to call multiple users who are widely-dispersed geographically, the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> may flag the telephone number as being associated with nuisance calls. Such a phone number may receive a high nuisance indication score. Similarly, if the same telephone number is used to call a large number of users within a short period of time, the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> may flag the telephone number as being associated with nuisance calls or assign a high nuisance score to the phone number. Additionally, the heuristics can use other communication data, including call data such as the time of call, day of the week, duration of the calls, time interval in between two calls, whether the telephone number is stored as a contact in one or more local address books, the number of address books storing the telephone number, and the patterns of numbers called to detect nuisance calls. In one embodiment, if a phone number is not associated with a user in the pooled address book database <b>410</b> and conventional databases, the phone number may be flagged as a nuisance call or a nuisance phone number if it initiates communication with several mobile devices within a short period of time. As such, the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> may detect a nuisance call in substantially real time as the nuisance caller initiates calling mobile devices. The nuisance call detection module <b>406</b> may also flag a phone number as a nuisance phone number if a user of a mobile device indicates that the phone number is associated with a nuisance caller.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As mentioned above, nuisance calls are flagged (i.e., identified as nuisance calls) when responding to caller ID information lookup requests from mobile devices <b>114</b>, thereby giving the users the opportunity to decline to answer such calls. Further, in some embodiments users can flag nuisance calls they receive. The mobile devices <b>114</b> provide caller ID information about such flagged calls to the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b>. The detection module <b>406</b> uses the provided information to identify subsequent nuisance calls from the same telephone number.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The data-cleaning module <b>408</b> determines whether the caller ID information within the pooled address book is current. The information in local address books <b>102</b> can grow stale over time as people change telephone numbers, jobs, etc. Therefore, there is a risk that caller ID information submitted to the caller information server <b>110</b> is stale (i.e., inaccurate) at the time of submission or has become stale since it was submitted. The data-cleaning module <b>408</b> analyzes the caller ID information in the pooled address book to detect and remove stale information. The analyzed information includes the communications data and call statistics received from the mobile devices <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In one embodiment, the data-cleaning module <b>408</b> analyzes the communications history involving telephone numbers to identify stale information. Communications history such as duration, frequency, recency and reciprocity of communication between a user and a telephone number affect whether caller ID information associated with a telephone number is determined to be stale. For example, if a user recently communicated with a particular telephone number, as indicated by the caller ID information, the data-cleaning module <b>408</b> would determine that the telephone number is not stale (i.e., is &#x201c;fresh&#x201d;). Similarly, if a user frequently communicates with a telephone number for a long duration of time, or the communications are initiated by both parties, the telephone number also is not stale. In one embodiment, the data-cleaning module <b>408</b> analyzes a variety of factors indicated by the communications history and assigns a particular telephone number entry a &#x201c;freshness score&#x201d; indicating the likelihood that the entry is stale. Entries having scores below a threshold are removed or otherwise designated as stale. In one embodiment, if one or more entries in a mobile device's local address book are deemed to be stale, the mobile application <b>104</b> executing on the mobile device may automatically replace the stale entries in the local address book with fresh data from the caller information server <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of providing caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment. In one embodiment, the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is performed by the mobile application <b>104</b>, although some or all of the method can be performed by other modules in other embodiments. In addition, other embodiments can perform the steps of the method in different orders and can include different and/or additional steps.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The mobile application <b>104</b> initially sends <b>502</b> caller ID information from a local address book <b>102</b> of a mobile device <b>114</b> to the caller information server <b>110</b>. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> sends <b>502</b> updated caller ID information automatically every time the user executes the mobile application <b>104</b>. In other embodiments, the caller ID information is sent <b>502</b> when the mobile application <b>104</b> is first executed, or on a periodic schedule. Further, in one embodiment the mobile application <b>104</b> sends the caller ID information when the mobile device <b>114</b> is in a low consumption state, such as being set on standby or on recharge mode.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> detects <b>504</b> a telephone call incoming to the mobile device <b>114</b> and ascertains the telephone number of the caller. Additionally, the mobile application <b>104</b> determines <b>506</b> whether the telephone number associated with the detected call is a blacklisted telephone number. For example, the mobile application <b>104</b> performs a lookup operation in a table of blacklisted numbers. In another embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> determines <b>506</b> whether a phone number is blacklisted based on rules configured via the application or via an automatically updated set of rules. For example, the automatic rules may be configured to identify and block all nuisance callers as determined by the nuisance call detection module <b>406</b>. If the incoming telephone number is associated with a blacklisted number, the mobile application blocks <b>520</b> the incoming phone call. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> automatically routes the phone call to a voice mailbox system. In another embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> hangs up on the incoming telephone such that the voice mail system is inaccessible by the caller. In another embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> routes nuisance calls to a voice system which states that the user will no longer accept calls from the caller and does not allow the caller to access the phone's voice mailbox system. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> stores information associated with a blocked phone call in a blocked calls database. In such an embodiment, the user is not notified of an incoming phone call or that a phone call was blocked unless the user accesses the blocked call database. In one embodiment, text and multi-media messages from blacklisted numbers are deleted immediately with no other record left on the mobile device. In another embodiment, text and multi-media messages are routed to a separate folder that can be accessed through the mobile application <b>104</b>. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> routes all communication away from the mobile devices native applications, including but not limited to, native voice calling application, messaging application and voice mailbox application. By routing all communication through the mobile application <b>104</b>, a seamless experience can be provided to the mobile device's user wherein communication may not need to be transferred between the mobile application <b>104</b> and native applications executing on the mobile device.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In one embodiment, if the incoming telephone number is not a blacklisted phone number, the mobile application <b>104</b> determines <b>506</b> whether the telephone number associated with the detected call is stored in the local address book <b>102</b>. If the telephone number associated with the incoming phone call is not found in the local address book, the mobile application <b>104</b> sends <b>510</b> a caller ID request to the caller information server <b>110</b>. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> receives <b>512</b> the requested caller ID information from the caller information server <b>110</b>. In one embodiment, the received caller ID information includes a name of a caller associated with the detected phone number. In another embodiment, the mobile application receives <b>512</b> detailed information associated with the detected phone number, such as a business name, type of business, operating hours, name of a caller most associated with the business etc. Once the mobile application receives caller ID information associated with the incoming phone call, the process continues to step <b>514</b> as shown below.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In an embodiment, where the phone number associated with the detected phone number is stored <b>508</b> in a local address book of the user or once the caller ID information associated with the phone number is received <b>512</b>, the mobile application <b>104</b> determines <b>514</b> if a name associated with the phone number is a blacklisted name. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> performs a lookup operation in a database of blacklisted names to determine <b>514</b> if the name associated with the detected call should be blocked. In another embodiment, the mobile application determines <b>514</b> whether a name is blacklisted according to the rules configured via the application or as provided by the call detection module <b>406</b>. If the name associated with the detected telephone number is a blacklisted name, the mobile application <b>104</b> blocks <b>522</b> the incoming phone call. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> automatically routes the phone call to a voice mailbox system. In another embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> hangs up on the incoming telephone such that the voice mail system is inaccessible by the caller. In one embodiment, the mobile application stores information associated with a blocked phone call in a blocked calls database. In such an embodiment, the user is not notified of an incoming phone call or that a phone call was blocked unless the user accesses the blocked call database.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In an embodiment, where the mobile application <b>104</b> determines <b>514</b> that a name associated with the detected phone number is not a blacklisted name, the mobile application allows <b>516</b> a user to interact with the phone call by accepting or rejecting the incoming call.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In one embodiment, after the user either accepts or rejects the incoming phone call, the mobile application <b>104</b> offers the user an opportunity to add information about the caller to the local address book <b>102</b>. For example, if the mobile application <b>104</b> does not receive <b>512</b> caller ID information responsive to a request <b>510</b>, and the user knows additional information about the caller associated with the detected phone number, the user may add the additional information to a local address book <b>102</b> for future reference. In one embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> sends an updated address book to the caller information server <b>110</b> each instance the local address book is updated. In another embodiment, the mobile application <b>104</b> sends the address book to the caller information server <b>110</b> at periodic intervals or as disclosed above.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method of determining caller ID information associated with a telephone number according to one embodiment. In one embodiment, the method of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is performed by the caller information server <b>110</b>, although some or all of the method can be performed by other entities in other embodiments. In addition, other embodiments can perform the steps of the method in different orders and can include different and/or additional steps.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The caller information server <b>110</b> receives <b>602</b> caller ID information. The information is received from local address books of multiple mobile devices <b>114</b> and/or from conventional database providers <b>112</b>. The caller information server <b>110</b> generates <b>604</b> a pooled address book from the caller ID information. The caller information server <b>110</b> receives <b>606</b> a caller ID information lookup request from a mobile device <b>114</b>. For example, the lookup request may be received responsive to the telephone number of an incoming call to a mobile device <b>110</b> not matching a number in that device's local address book <b>102</b>. The caller information server <b>110</b> responds to the lookup request by searching for the telephone number identified by the lookup request in the pooled address book or in a conventional database. If a positive telephone number match is found, the caller information server <b>110</b> responds to the lookup request by sending <b>608</b> the caller ID information identified in the pooled address book as associated with the telephone number to the mobile device <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The above description is included to illustrate the operation of certain embodiments and is not meant to limit the scope of the invention. From the above discussion, many variations will be apparent to one skilled in the relevant art that would yet be encompassed by the spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A computer-implemented method of providing caller identification (ID) information to a mobile device, comprising
<claim-text>receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices used by a plurality of different users;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a pooled address book that aggregates the caller ID information received from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a request from a first mobile device used by a first user for caller ID information associated with a telephone number of a second mobile device used by a second user, the caller ID information associated with the telephone number not present in a local address book of the first mobile device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book, the identified caller ID information received from a local address book of a third mobile device used by a third user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the first mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein receiving caller ID information from local address books comprises:
<claim-text>receiving one or more of telephone numbers, names, addresses, job titles, and pictures from local address books stored on the plurality of mobile devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a white list of legitimate names; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the white list of legitimate names.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a list of subjective identifiers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>not storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the list of subjective identifiers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>detecting conflicting information associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information, wherein the conflicting information results from the received caller ID information indicating different information associated with a same telephone number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the received caller ID information to select resolved information that resolves the conflicting information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving requests from the plurality of mobile devices for caller ID information associated with telephone numbers from which communications were made to the plurality of the mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance communications that the plurality of different users are likely to decline to answer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a communication was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance communication in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving communications data describing communication statistics from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the communications data to identify stale caller ID information within the pooled address book; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the stale caller ID information from the pooled address book.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A non-transitory computer-readable storage medium encoded with executable computer program code for providing caller identification (ID) information to a mobile device, the computer program code comprising program code for:
<claim-text>receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices used by a plurality of different users;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a pooled address book that aggregates the caller ID information received from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a request from a first mobile device used by a first user for caller ID information associated with a telephone number of a second mobile device used by a second user, the caller ID information associated with the telephone number not present in a local address book of the first mobile device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the caller ID information in the pooled address book associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book, the identified caller ID information received from a local address book of a third mobile device used by a third user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the first mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, herein receiving caller ID information from local address books comprises:
<claim-text>receiving one or more of telephone numbers, names, addresses, job titles, and pictures from local address books stored on the plurality of mobile devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a white list of legitimate names; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the white list of legitimate names.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a list of subjective identifiers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>not storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the list of subjective identifiers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>detecting conflicting information associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information, wherein the conflicting information results from the received caller ID information indicating different information associated with a same telephone number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the received caller ID information to select resolved information that resolves the conflicting information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving requests from the plurality of mobile devices for caller ID information associated with telephone numbers from which communications were made to the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance communications that the plurality of different users are likely to decline to answer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a communication was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance communication in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The non-transitory computer-readable storage medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving communications data describing communication statistics from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the communications data to identify stale caller ID information within the pooled address book; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the stale caller ID information from the pooled address book.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A computer for providing caller identification (ID) information to a mobile device, comprising:
<claim-text>a non-transitory computer-readable storage medium storing executable computer program instructions comprising instructions for:
<claim-text>receiving caller ID information from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices used by a plurality of different users;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a pooled address book that aggregates the caller ID information received from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a request from a first mobile device used by a first user for caller ID information associated with a telephone number of a second mobile device used by a second user, the caller ID information associated with the telephone number not present in a local address book of the first mobile device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the caller ID information associated with the telephone number in the pooled address book, the identified caller ID information received from a local address book of a third mobile device used by a third user; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the identified caller ID information associated with the telephone number to the first mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein receiving caller ID information from local address books comprises:
<claim-text>receiving one or more of telephone numbers, names, addresses, job titles, and pictures from local address books stored on the plurality of mobile devices.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a white list of legitimate names; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the white list of legitimate names.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>identifying a name associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether the name is within a list of subjective identifiers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>not storing the name in the pooled address book in association with the telephone number in the received caller ID information responsive to the name being within the list of subjective identifiers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein generating the pooled address book comprises:
<claim-text>detecting conflicting information associated with a telephone number in the received caller ID information, wherein the conflicting information results from the received caller ID information indicating different information associated with a same telephone number; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the received caller ID information to select resolved information that resolves the conflicting information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving requests from the plurality of mobile devices for caller ID information associated with telephone numbers from which communications were made to the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the requests from the plurality of mobile devices to detect nuisance communications that the plurality of different users are likely to decline to answer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the analysis indicating that a telephone number from which a communication was made to a mobile device is associated with a nuisance call, identifying the telephone number as being associated with a nuisance communication in the identified caller ID information sent to the mobile device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The computer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving communications data describing communication statistics from the plurality of mobile devices;</claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the communications data to identify stale caller ID information within the pooled address book; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the stale caller ID information from the pooled address book.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A computer-implemented method of obtaining caller identification (ID) information associated with a telephone number, comprising:
<claim-text>sending caller ID information from a local address book of a first mobile device used by a first user to a caller information server, the caller information server adapted to generate a pooled address book that aggregates caller ID information received from local address books of a plurality of mobile devices used by a plurality of different users;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting an incoming communication received by the first mobile device from a telephone number of a second mobile device used by a second user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>responsive to the telephone number not being stored in the local address book of the first mobile device, sending a request to the caller information server requesting caller ID information for the telephone number, wherein the caller information server is adapted to identify caller ID information for the telephone number in the pooled address book, the identified caller ID information received from a local address book of a third mobile device used by a third user; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, from the caller information server, the caller ID information for the telephone number.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>determining whether to block the incoming communication responsive to the received caller ID information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>blocking the incoming communication responsive to a positive determination.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>storing the received caller ID information in the local address book of the first mobile device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
