<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626997-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626997</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12504029</doc-number>
<date>20090716</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1209</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711105</main-classification>
<further-classification>711  5</further-classification>
<further-classification>711154</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Phase change memory in a dual inline memory module</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5758056</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Barr</name>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714  632</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8244971</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Rajan et al.</name>
<date>20120800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>711105</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711  5</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711100</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711105</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711154</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>711200</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110016268</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110120</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Qawami</last-name>
<first-name>Shekoufeh</first-name>
<address>
<city>El Dorado Hills</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hulbert</last-name>
<first-name>Jared E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shingle Springs</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Qawami</last-name>
<first-name>Shekoufeh</first-name>
<address>
<city>El Dorado Hills</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hulbert</last-name>
<first-name>Jared E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shingle Springs</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Knobbe, Martens, Olson &#x26; Bear LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Micron Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Thai</last-name>
<first-name>Tuan</first-name>
<department>2185</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Subject matter disclosed herein relates to management of a memory device.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="125.39mm" wi="233.26mm" file="US08626997-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="162.39mm" wi="154.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626997-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="197.10mm" wi="154.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626997-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.52mm" wi="138.51mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626997-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="203.45mm" wi="134.28mm" file="US08626997-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="220.56mm" wi="152.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626997-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Subject matter disclosed herein relates to management of a memory device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Information</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Memory devices are employed in many types of electronic devices, such as computers, cell phones, PDA's, data loggers, games, and navigational equipment, for example. Among such electronic devices, various types of memory devices may be employed, such as NAND and NOR flash, SRAM, DRAM, and phase-change, just to name a few examples. Corresponding to increases in operating speed and cache line sizes, memory devices may be packaged in a dual inline memory module (DIMM) configuration. For example, such a DIMM, which may be used as a main memory in a computing platform, may comprise a number of DRAM memory modules mounted in parallel on the DIMM. Accordingly, a read/write request to the DIMM may be split across parallel DRAM modules so that individual DRAM modules provide a subset of total cache line request. Such DRAM devices typically have particular intrinsic parameters associated with read/write timing, memory page size, and/or addressing protocol, just to name a few examples.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Non-limiting and non-exhaustive embodiments will be described with reference to the following figures, wherein like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the various figures unless otherwise specified.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a memory configuration, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of a memory configuration, according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a timing diagram of a memory control process, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow diagram of a memory control process, according to an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of a computing system and a memory device, according to an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Reference throughout this specification to &#x201c;one embodiment&#x201d; or &#x201c;an embodiment&#x201d; means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of claimed subject matter. Thus, the appearances of the phrase &#x201c;in one embodiment&#x201d; or &#x201c;an embodiment&#x201d; in various places throughout this specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment. Furthermore, the particular features, structures, or characteristics may be combined in one or more embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In an embodiment, a memory device may comprise a dual inline memory module (DIMM) that includes phase change memory (PCM) modules. Such PCM modules may be mounted and electronically connected in parallel on a DIMM. In one implementation, such a DIMM, which may comprise at least a portion of a main memory of a computing system for example, may include a memory bus to communicate with a memory controller. Through such a memory bus, a computing system may access PCM modules on a DIMM via a memory controller.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one embodiment, a DIMM may be adapted to electronically operate based, at least in part, on dynamic random access memory (DRAM) modules. For example, a DIMM may comprise one or more DRAM sockets to receive one or more PCM modules, though claimed subject matter is not so limited. For another example, one or more PCM modules may comprise DRAM mode registers and/or a DRAM interface including connections adapted for a DRAM. PCM modules may be incorporated in such a DIMM by using appropriate memory-level and/or system-level processes and/or parameters, as explained in greater detail below. For example, a computing system may comprise a basic input/output system (BIOS) that maintains parameters corresponding to PCM modules. Such parameters may, for example, comprise values for timing, latencies, and/or size of PCM modules. In a particular implementation, a BIOS need not test PCM modules upon a system boot. Such a BIOS may include a low-level driver configured to operate PCM modules. In addition, such a BIOS may include executable code to read PCM module identification (ID) and to be responsive to PCM module configuration. For another example, PCM modules may be associated with an additive latency that enables a column address, generated by a memory controller for example, to be provided to a DIMM immediately after the DIMM receives a row address. Such additive latency may be introduced in a timing scheme of PCM modules so that consecutive read commands directed to the PCM may immediately follow one another without delay and without introducing timing gaps in output data, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In general, writing or programming processes may be used to store information in memory devices, while a read process may be used to retrieve stored information. Stored information may be erased from all or a portion of a memory device and/or new information may be written into all or a portion of memory device. Relatively large numbers of such program-erase and/or program-re-program cycles may degrade the physical integrity of a PCM. For example, thousands of program-erase cycles imposed on a DIMM that incorporates PCM may reduce a reliability of the DIMM. If using such PCM memory, it may be beneficial to limit and/or reduce the number of occurrences of program-erase cycles, or &#x201c;cycling&#x201d;, that a PCM memory may otherwise be subjected to. Accordingly, in one embodiment, a technique to manage cycling of PCM modules on a DIMM may comprise caching write data. In particular, a memory device, such as a DRAM cache memory, may be used to cache write data corresponding to particular addresses of a PCM DIMM. A memory size of such a DRAM cache memory may be selected based, at least in part, on properties of PCM modules comprising a PCM DIMM. Such properties may include PCM DIMM size, for example. Such properties may include, for example, cycling specifications of PCM, PCM failure rate, PCM write speed, write usage model of a system incorporating a PCM DIMM, and/or PCM write wear leveling techniques used. As a particular example, a size of such a DRAM cache memory may range from about 100 KB to several tens of megabytes RAM, though claimed subject matter is not so limited.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one implementation, a PCM DIMM may include PCM modules stacked in a package with multiple memory dice per package. For example, such a package may comprise two, four, or eight dice per package, providing one, two, four, or eight I/O pins, respectively. A result of such an implementation may be that additional PCM may be used without presenting extra loading on output drivers, for example. Also, if PCM used in a DIMM has a smaller number of banks (partitions) than that of a DRAM, bank address bits may be used to access multiple banks across multiple PCM devices, as explained in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a DRAM DIMM <b>100</b> that comprises multiple DRAM modules, according to an embodiment, including DRAM <b>110</b>, DRAM <b>120</b>, and DRAM <b>130</b>, which are shown in the figure. Although eight DRAM modules may be included in a particular embodiment, a DRAM DIMM may include any number of DRAM modules. For example, a ninth DRAM module may be present to provide error correction, though claimed subject matter is not so limited to such an example. Individual DRAM modules may comprise a matrix of addressable memory cells that are accessed by first specifying a row address after which a column address is specified. Block arrow <b>150</b> represents an address bus through which a memory controller (not shown) may provide a read/write address to DRAM DIMM <b>100</b>. In one particular implementation, such an address bus may be sixteen bits wide. Block arrow <b>160</b> represents a data bus through which parallel data from/to DRAM modules may provide read data or receive write data to/from the memory controller and/or other portion of a computing system (not shown). In one particular implementation, such a data bus may be sixty-four bits wide to account for eight eight-bit DRAM modules connected in parallel, though claimed subject matter is not so limited. To address a particular location on DRAM DIMM <b>100</b>, an activate command, explained in further detail below, may be accompanied by a row address provided to DRAM modules <b>110</b> through <b>130</b> by a memory controller, for example, on a bus represented by block arrows <b>140</b>. Such a row address bus <b>140</b> may be connected in parallel to individual DRAM modules. Subsequent to providing a row address, a memory controller may generate a read/write command accompanied by a column address provided to the individual DRAM modules via a bus represented by block arrows <b>170</b>. Of course, such features and details of a DRAM DIMM are merely examples, and claimed subject matter is not so limited.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram view of a PCM DIMM <b>200</b> that comprises multiple PCM modules, according to an embodiment, including PCM <b>214</b>, PCM <b>218</b>, PCM <b>224</b>, and PCM <b>228</b>. PCM DIMM <b>200</b> may be adapted to electronically operate based, at least in part, on DRAM modules. In such a case, more than one PCM module may be used in place of one DRAM module, depending, at least in part, on the number of memory banks in individual PCM modules. Accordingly, PCM DIMM <b>200</b> may comprise a memory site <b>210</b> where PCM <b>214</b> and/or PCM <b>218</b> are used in place of one DRAM module and a memory site <b>220</b>, where PCM <b>224</b> and/or PCM <b>228</b> may used in place of another DRAM module. Here, a memory site refers to a location of PCM DIMM <b>200</b> where electronic connections between PCM DIMM <b>200</b> and a DRAM or PCM modules may be made. In a particular implementation, a PCM module may involve more electronic connections than a DRAM module. For example, PCM DIMM <b>200</b> may include PCM modules that have four banks and three-bit bank addresses (capable of addressing up to eight banks); two PCM devices each with four bank addresses may then be accessed. Accordingly, in a particular implementation, a PCM DIMM may be provided with bank address bits that correspond to multiple memory banks across multiple PCM devices. Of course, such memory sites may include more or less than the number of PCM modules shown and described in the present example embodiment. Similarly, PCM DIMM <b>200</b> may include more or less than the number of such memory sites shown and described in the present example embodiment. Accordingly, claimed subject matter is not so limited to such details.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Similar to DRAM modules described above, individual PCM modules may comprise a matrix of addressable memory cells which are accessible by first specifying a row address after which a column address is specified. Block arrow <b>240</b> represents an address bus through which a memory controller (not shown) may provide a read/write address to PCM DIMM <b>200</b>. In one particular implementation, such an address bus may be sixteen bits wide, for example. Block arrow <b>250</b> represents a data bus through which parallel data from/to PCM modules may provide read data or receive write data to/from the memory controller and/or other portion of a computing system (not shown). In one particular implementation, such a data bus may be sixty-four bits wide to account for eight parallel groups of PCM modules, each group having eight bits connected in parallel, though claimed subject matter is not so limited. To address a particular location on PCM DIMM <b>200</b>, an activate command, explained in further detail below, may be accompanied by a row address provided to PCM modules <b>214</b> through <b>228</b> by a memory controller, for example, on a bus represented by block arrows <b>230</b>. Such an address bus <b>230</b> may be connected in parallel to individual PCM modules. Subsequent to providing a row address, a memory controller may generate a read/write command accompanied by a column address provided to individual memory sites <b>210</b> through <b>220</b> via a bus <b>230</b>. Such a column address accompanied by a read/write command may also be provided to individual PCM modules <b>214</b> though <b>228</b> via a bus represented by block arrows <b>260</b>. Of course, such features and details of a PCM DIMM are merely examples, and claimed subject matter is not so limited.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a timing diagram of a memory control process <b>300</b>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow diagram of a memory control process <b>400</b>, according to an embodiment. The following descriptive example is based on memory control process <b>300</b> and memory control process <b>400</b> comprising the same process, though claimed subject matter is not so limited. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a clock signal <b>305</b> may establish timing of memory processes. At block <b>410</b>, a memory controller may issue an activate command <b>310</b> to open a page or memory bank of a PCM module, such as PCM module <b>214</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, for example. During such an activate phase, a PCM module may receive a row address <b>315</b> from a memory controller, as in block <b>420</b>. At blocks <b>430</b> and <b>440</b>, a memory controller may issue a read instruction <b>320</b> and a column address <b>325</b>, thus providing a memory address (row and column) of one or more memory cells from where data is to be read. In a particular implementation, an additive latency may be used to improve memory process scheduling: a row address and a column address may be issued back-to-back, thereby avoiding timing gaps in output data, for example. Such timing gaps, however, may be desirable in some applications, and claimed subject matter is not so limited. For example, though not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, there may be one or more clock cycles between activate command <b>310</b> and read instruction <b>320</b>. In detail, utilizing column address strobe (CAS) latency and/or additive latency, a read instruction may be issued immediately after an activate command. Such a read instruction need not be delayed internally by a predetermined number of clock cycles (hence additive latency) before being executed. Because such a timing process is performed without need for an additional command, collision among memory instructions may be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Though not needed for one or more embodiments described herein, a value for additive latency may be maintained in a mode register of the PCM module. Accordingly, at block <b>450</b>, a period ICCD lapses before another read instruction <b>330</b> is issued, at block <b>460</b>. Concurrently, another column address may be issued, as at block <b>470</b>. After one or more latencies, such as read latency and column addressing latency for example, data <b>340</b> may result from read instruction <b>320</b> and data <b>350</b> may result from read instruction <b>330</b>. In one implementation, a process of providing column addresses and reading memory at the corresponding addresses may repeat until, for example, a final column of the opened page is reached, as checked at block <b>480</b>. In such a case, another activate command may be issued by a memory controller to open another page. As indicated above, PCM modules may be incorporated in a DIMM that is adapted to electronically operate based, at least in part, on DRAM modules. To accommodate such PCM modules, appropriate memory-level and/or system-level processes and/or parameters, may be implemented. For example, at a system level, a BIOS may retrieve parameters from one or more mode registers maintained in PCM modules or other memory. Such parameters, comprising values for read latency, write latency, CAS latency, internal read command to first data time, activate to internal read/write delay, and/or additive delay, just to name a few examples, may correspond to the PCM modules.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating an exemplary embodiment of a computing system <b>500</b> including a memory device <b>510</b>. A computing device <b>504</b> may be representative of any device, appliance, or machine that may be configurable to manage memory device <b>510</b>. Memory device <b>510</b> may include a memory controller <b>515</b> and a memory <b>522</b>. By way of example but not limitation, computing device <b>504</b> may include: one or more computing devices and/or platforms, such as, e.g., a desktop computer, a laptop computer, a workstation, a server device, or the like; one or more personal computing or communication devices or appliances, such as, e.g., a personal digital assistant, mobile communication device, or the like; a computing system and/or associated service provider capability, such as, e.g., a database or data storage service provider/system; and/or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It is recognized that all or part of the various devices shown in system <b>500</b>, and the processes and methods as further described herein, may be implemented using or otherwise including hardware, firmware, software, or ally combination thereof. Thus, by way of example but not limitation, computing device <b>504</b> may include at least one processing unit <b>520</b> that is operatively coupled to memory <b>522</b> through a bus <b>540</b> and a host or memory controller <b>515</b>. Processing unit <b>520</b> is representative of one or more circuits configurable to perform at least a portion of a data computing procedure or process. By way of example but not limitation, processing unit <b>520</b> may include one or more processors, controllers, microprocessors, microcontrollers, application specific integrated circuits, digital signal processors, programmable logic devices, field programmable gate arrays, and the like, or any combination thereof. Processing unit <b>520</b> may communicate with memory controller <b>515</b> to process memory-related operations, such as read, write, and/or erase, as well as memory partition processes discussed above, for example. Processing unit <b>520</b> may include an operating system adapted to communicate with memory controller <b>515</b>. Such an operating system may, for example, generate commands to be sent to memory controller <b>515</b> over bus <b>540</b>. Such commands may include read/write instructions, for example. Computing device <b>504</b> may comprise a basic input/output system (BIOS) that maintains parameters corresponding to PCM modules, which may be associated with an additive latency that enables a column address, generated by memory controller <b>515</b> for example, to be provided to a DIMM immediately after the DIMM receives a row address.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Memory <b>522</b> is representative of any data storage mechanism. Memory <b>522</b> may include, for example, a primary memory <b>524</b> and/or a secondary memory <b>526</b>. In a particular embodiment, memory <b>522</b> may comprise a PCM DIMM, as described above. In particular, primary memory <b>524</b> may include, for example, a random access memory, read only memory, etc. While illustrated in this example as being separate from processing unit <b>520</b>, it should be understood that all or part of primary memory <b>524</b> may be provided within or otherwise co-located/coupled with processing unit <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to an embodiment, one or more portions of memory <b>522</b> may store signals representative of data and/or information as expressed by a particular state of memory <b>522</b>. For example, an electronic signal representative of data and/or information may be &#x201c;stored&#x201d; in a portion of memory <b>522</b> by affecting or changing the state of such portions of memory <b>522</b> to represent data and/or information as binary information (e.g., ones and zeros). As such, in a particular implementation, such a change of state of the portion of memory to store a signal representative of data and/or information constitutes a transformation of memory <b>522</b> to a different state or thing.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Secondary memory <b>526</b> may include, for example, the same or similar type of memory as primary memory and/or one or more data storage devices or systems, such as, for example, a disk drive, an optical disc drive, a tape drive, a solid state memory drive, etc. In certain implementations, secondary memory <b>526</b> may be operatively receptive of, or otherwise configurable to couple to, a computer-readable medium <b>528</b>. Computer-readable medium <b>528</b> may include, for example, any medium that can carry and/or make accessible data, code and/or instructions for one or more of the devices in system <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Computing device <b>504</b> may include, for example, an input/output <b>532</b>. Input/output <b>532</b> is representative of one or more devices or features that may be configurable to accept or otherwise introduce human and/or machine inputs, and/or one or more devices or features that may be configurable to deliver or otherwise provide for human and/or machine outputs. By way of example but not limitation, input/output device <b>532</b> may include an operatively configured display, speaker, keyboard, mouse, trackball, touch screen, data port, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">While there has been illustrated and described what are presently considered to be example embodiments, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various other modifications may be made, and equivalents may be substituted, without departing from claimed subject matter. Additionally, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation to the teachings of claimed subject matter without departing from the central concept described herein. Therefore, it is intended that claimed subject matter not be limited to the particular embodiments disclosed, but that such claimed subject matter may also include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims, and equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a dual inline memory module (DIMM) comprising one or more phase change memory (PCM) modules;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory bus electronically connected to said system, wherein said PCM modules are electronically connected in parallel to said memory bus; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a basic input/output system (BIOS) configured to maintain parameters corresponding to said PCM modules,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the DIMM comprises a plurality of memory sites, at least some of the memory sites comprising PCM modules and at least some of the memory sites comprising DRAM modules, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the DIMM is configured to cache write data corresponding to addresses corresponding to PCM modules in the DRAM modules.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said parameters include a value for additive latency of said PCM modules or a column address strobe (CAS) latency.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said PCM modules are associated with an additive latency that enables a column address to be provided to said DIMM immediately after a row address is provided to said DIMM.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>dynamic random access memory (DRAM) cache memory to cache write data corresponding to particular addresses of said DIMM.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein bank address bits correspond to multiple memory banks across multiple said one or more PCM modules.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said DIMM comprises a main memory of said system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said one or more PCM modules comprise dynamic random access memory (DRAM) mode registers and/or a DRAM interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A memory device comprising:
<claim-text>a dual inline memory module (DIMM) adapted to electronically operate based, at least in part, on dynamic random access memory (DRAM) modules, wherein said DIMM comprises one or more phase change memory (PCM) modules and is configured to operate based on parameters maintained in a basic input/output system (BIOS),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the DRAM module is included in the DIMM, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the DIMM is configured to cache write data corresponding to addresses corresponding to PCM modules in the DRAM modules.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a memory bus configured to electronically connect to a computing system, wherein said PCM modules are electronically coupled in parallel to said memory bus.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The memory device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>DRAM cache memory to cache write data corresponding to particular addresses of said DIMM. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
