<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624197-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624197</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13882105</doc-number>
<date>20101028</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>T</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25037009</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Flat panel detector incorporating silk layer(s)</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3202820</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Norton et al.</name>
<date>19650800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7687792</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Rowlands et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>331022</doc-number>
<date>19580600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2008085904</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>Int. Preliminary Report on Patentability cited in PCT Application No. PCT/US2010/054415 dated Apr. 30, 2013, 8 pgs.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>&#x201c;The optimal optical readout for the x-ray light valve&#x2014;Document scanners&#x201d;, P. Oakham, Robert D. MacDougall and J.A. Rowlands, Dec. 2008, Medical Physics, Radiation Imaging Physics, vol. 35, Issue 12, pp. 5672-5683.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>&#x201c;The x-ray light valve: A low-cost, digital radiographic imaging system&#x2014;Spatial resolution&#x201d;, Robert D. MacDougall, Ivaylo Koprinarov and J.A. Rowlands, Sep. 2008, Medical Physics, Radiation Imaging Physics, vol. 35, Issue 9, pp. 4216-4227.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>&#x201c;The x-ray light valve: A potentially low-cost, digital radiographic imaging system&#x2014;a liquid crystal cell design for chest radiography&#x201d;, Timothy C. Szeto, Christie Ann Webster, Ivaylo Koprinarov and J.A. Rowlands, Mar. 2008, Medical Physics, Radiation Imaging Physics, vol. 35, Issue 3, pp. 959-967.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>&#x201c;The x-ray light valve: A low-cost digital radiographic imaging system&#x201d;, Ivaylo Koprinarov, Christie Ann Webster, Robert D. MacDougall and A.J. Rowlands, Dec. 2007, Medical Physics, Radiation Imaging Physics, vol. 34, Issue 12, pp. 4609-4611.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report cited in related application No. PCT/US2010/054415 dated Jul. 12, 2011.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Tousignant 0 et al: &#x201c;A-Se Flat Panel Detectors for Medical Applications&#x201d;, Proceedings of the 2007 IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium, IEEE&#x2014;Piscataway, NJ, USA, Feb. 1, 2007, pp. 1-5.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>Kim Dae-Hyeong et al: &#x201c;Silicon electronics on silk as a path to bioresorbable, implantable devices&#x201d;, Applied Physics Letters, AIP, American Institute of Physics, Melville, NY, US, vol. 95, No. 13, Sep. 29, 2009, pp. 1-3.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25037008</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25037009</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130214170</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130822</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Marcovici</last-name>
<first-name>Sorin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Marcovici</last-name>
<first-name>Sorin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cooper Legal Group LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Analogic Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Peabody</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bryant</last-name>
<first-name>Casey</first-name>
<department>2884</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/US2010/054415</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20101028</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20130426</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2012/057759</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20120503</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">One or more techniques and/or systems described herein implement, among other things, a flat panel detector component for detecting actinic and non-actinic radiation, or the formation thereof. The flat panel detector component comprises a plurality of layers, where at least one of the layers comprises silk. Further, a silk layer may be in direct physical contact with a radiation detection layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="223.27mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="252.14mm" wi="181.95mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624197-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="248.33mm" wi="179.15mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="254.34mm" wi="172.64mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="261.96mm" wi="184.66mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="260.35mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="250.53mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="247.82mm" wi="168.32mm" file="US08624197-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application relates to the field of radiographic imaging. It finds particular application with the provision of radiation detectors in a radiography imaging system (e.g., mammography system, general radiology system, etc).</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Radiographic imaging systems, such as projection radiography, computed tomography (CT) systems, line scanners, etc., provide information, or images, of the inside of an object under examination (e.g., interior aspects of an object under examination). Generally, the object is exposed to radiation, and one or more images are formed based upon the radiation absorbed by the object, or rather an amount of radiation that is able to pass through the object. Typically, highly dense objects absorb (e.g., attenuate) more radiation than less dense objects, and thus an object having a higher density, such as a bone or gun, for example, will appear differently than less dense objects, such as fatty tissue or clothing, for example. A detector array, generally positioned opposite a radiation source from which radiation is emitted relative the object under examination, is configured to detect radiation that traverses the object under examination and convert such radiation into signals and/or data that may be processed to produce the image(s). Such an image(s) may be viewed by security personnel to detect threat items (e.g., weapons, explosives, etc.) and/or viewed by medical personnel to detect medical condition.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In some scanners, such as projection radiography and three-dimensional imaging scanners (e.g., CT scanners), for example, the detector array and radiation source are mounted on opposing sides of a radiographic system, with the object under examination disposed there-between. In such a scanner, the radiation source emits a desired fluence of radiation directed toward the object under examination. The radiation is attenuated as it passes through the object under examination and reaches the detector on the other side. Digital image data of the object under examination can be produced by converting the detected radiation into an electrical signal (e.g., current or voltage) and measuring it. The number of photons that impact the detector is proportional to the amount of electrical signal measured by the detector. After that, an analog electrical signal from the detector is converted to a digital signal, and the digital signal can be used to create the image.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Flat panel detectors are typically used for projection radiography, where a burst of x-rays are directed toward an object and the flat panel detector is positioned behind the object. Projection radiography is typically utilized to produce two-dimensional images of an object (e.g., to diagnose internal medical issues in a patient, to examine internal objects in a suitcase). A flat panel detector can create digital image data, which can be used to produce images on a computer monitor or some other form of electronic display (or print-out).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Flat panel detectors (FPDs) can convert radiation to electrical signal(s), either directly or indirectly. An indirect FPD uses scintillators, for example, that convert x-ray photons to visible light photons, and has photodiodes distributed in a 2D array that detect the visible light photons and covert them to an electrical charge, which can then be converted to a digital signal. Alternately, direct FPDs utilize a radiation detection material that can convert x-ray photons directly into an electrical charge. For example, an amorphous selenium layer can create an electrical charge proportional to a number of impinging x-ray photons, and a 2D capacitor array can collect the electrical charges. In this both cases, the detector array can be addressed or mapped to respective pixels of the image.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Blocking layers are often implemented in a direct conversion FPD to allow (substantially) only one type of electrical charge (positive or negative) to transition or pass through one or more layers in the FPD while (substantially) blocking the transit of the opposite type of electrical charge. For example, blocking layers can be disposed at either side of a radiation detection layer to &#x201c;block in&#x201d; one type of charge within the radiation detection layer while allowing the opposite type of charge to &#x201c;exit&#x201d; the radiation detection layer. However, blocking layers, separation layers, and insulating layers are typically challenging to deposit. Furthermore, blocking layers are difficult to implement when they have to interface with chemically incompatible materials and/or there are contradictory requirements between their thickness and/or dielectric properties, for example.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Aspects of the present application address the above matters, and others. According to one aspect, flat panel detector component is provided. The flat panel detector component comprises a plurality of layers where at least one of the layers comprises silk.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to another aspect, a method is provided for forming a flat panel detector component used to detect actinic and non-actinic radiation. The method comprises forming at least one layer of silk that is in direct contact with a radiation detection layer.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to yet another aspect, an apparatus for detecting x-rays is provided. The apparatus for detecting x-rays comprises an x-ray detector layer. The apparatus for detecting x-rays further comprises at least one silk layer that is in direct physical contact with the x-ray detector layer.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">FIGURES</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The application is illustrated by way of example and not limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings, in which like references indicate similar elements and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating an example radiographic imaging apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view illustration of existing technology for use in a direct conversion flat panel detector.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view illustration of an example flat panel detector component as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view illustration of an example flat panel detector component as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating an example method for forming a flat panel detector component.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating an example method for forming a flat panel detector component.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view illustration of an example flat panel detector component as described herein.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The claimed subject matter is now described with reference to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals are generally used to refer to like elements throughout. In the following description, for purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the claimed subject matter. It may be evident, however, that the claimed subject matter may be practiced without these specific details. In other instances, structures and devices are illustrated in block diagram form in order to facilitate describing the claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an illustration of an example environment <b>100</b> in which data that is generated from components in a radiographic system <b>102</b> (e.g., flat panel detector) may be acquired so that one or more images of an object <b>104</b> under examination may be produced and displayed on a monitor <b>126</b>, for example, such as for viewing by a human user <b>128</b> (e.g., radiologist). Such a system <b>102</b> may be used to diagnose medical conditions (e.g., broken bones) in a human patient at a medical center or in an animal at a veterinary clinic, and/or to identify objects of interest (e.g., potential threat objects, banned objects) associated with (e.g., comprising, comprised within, etc.) an object <b>104</b> (e.g., luggage) under examination at a security checkpoint, for example. In another embodiment, no image is generated, but a density (or some other object physico-chemical property) of respective objects (or aspects or parts thereof) can be identified and compared with a list of densities associated with predetermined items (e.g., banned items) to determine if the object <b>104</b> potentially comprises one or more of the predetermined items.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the example environment <b>100</b>, the radiographic system <b>102</b> can be configured to examine one or more objects <b>104</b> (e.g., a human patient, a series of suitcases at an airport, etc.). The radiographic system <b>102</b> can comprise a radiation source <b>106</b> (e.g., an ionizing or non-ionizing radiation source) and a detector <b>108</b> that can be mounted on a substantially diametrically opposite side of the radiographic system <b>102</b> relative to the radiation source <b>106</b>. During an examination of the object(s) <b>104</b>, the radiation source <b>106</b> emits radiation <b>110</b> towards the object(s) <b>104</b> under examination. Generally, when using a flat panel scanner, the radiation <b>110</b> is emitted substantially continuously during the examination. However, in some radiographic system, the radiation <b>110</b> may be pulsed during the examination.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As the radiation <b>110</b> traverses the object(s) <b>104</b>, the radiation <b>110</b> may be attenuated differently by different parts of the object(s) <b>104</b>. Because different parts attenuate differently the radiation <b>110</b>, an image may be produced based upon the attenuation, or rather indirectly from it based on the variations in the number of photons that are detected by the detector <b>108</b>. For example, more dense aspects of the object(s) <b>104</b>, such as a bone or metal plate, for example, may attenuate more of the radiation <b>110</b> (e.g., causing fewer photons of different energies to strike the detector <b>108</b>) than less dense materials, such as skin or clothing.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Radiation <b>110</b> that impinges the detector <b>108</b> generally creates an electrical charge that may be detected by one or more pixels, or elements, of the detector <b>108</b> that are in well defined spatial proximity to the location where the radiation impinged. Respective pixels/detector elements generate an analog signal proportional to the electrical charge detected (e.g., generated by direct x-ray detector elements in the detector <b>108</b>), and such signals are fed to a data acquisition component <b>120</b> (which may be integral with the system <b>102</b>). Because the electrical charge detected by the one or more pixels is directly related to the number of photons, the output is indicative of the attenuation of the radiation <b>110</b> as it traversed the object(s) <b>104</b>. It will be appreciated that, in one embodiment, when a pixel is not collecting electrical charge, the pixel will produce an analog, baseline signal that indicates that the pixel has detected no electrical charge.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It will be understood to those skilled that in some embodiments, an analog to digital (A/D) signal converter (not shown, but generally operably coupled with or comprised within the detector array <b>108</b> and/or the data acquisition component <b>120</b>) may be configured to receive the analog signals and convert the signals into digital signals. The data acquisition component <b>120</b> is configured to prepare the output signals to produce an image, such as by a computer system <b>124</b>. In one embodiment, configuring the output signals for producing an image can comprise remapping (also referred to herein as converting or encoding) the output signals from a first format to a second format that is more suitable for image generation, transmission and/or presentation.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the example environment <b>100</b>, signal data from the data acquisition component <b>120</b> is transmitted to a work station <b>124</b> that is configured to receive the image data, for example. The work station <b>124</b> is configured to produce one or more images of the object <b>104</b> under examination using algebraic, iterative, or other image processing techniques known to those skilled in the art (e.g., filtered back projection). In this way, the data is converted from an electrical signal to an image, so as to be more understandable to a user <b>128</b> (e.g., medical personnel, security, personnel, etc.) viewing the image(s) on a monitor <b>126</b> of the work station <b>124</b>, for example. A user <b>128</b> can thus inspect the image(s) to identify areas of interest within the object(s) <b>104</b>. The work station <b>124</b> can also be configured to receive user input which can direct operations of the radiography system <b>102</b> (e.g., radiation dose, etc.) and/or can direct the work station <b>124</b> to display an image or series of images of the object(s) <b>104</b> in a particular manner, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the example environment <b>100</b>, a controller <b>130</b> is operably coupled to the work station <b>124</b>. In one example, the controller <b>130</b> is configured to receive user input from the work station <b>124</b> and generate instructions for the radiography system <b>102</b> indicative of operations to be performed. For example, the user <b>128</b> may want to rescan the object(s) <b>104</b> using a different dose or energy of radiation and the controller <b>130</b> may issue an instruction instructing the radiation source <b>106</b> to emit a desired dose or energy of radiation <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the example environment <b>100</b>, the detector <b>108</b> can comprise radiation detector film and/or chemicals, image plates, image intensifiers, or flat-panel radiation detectors. A flat-panel detector (FPD) can comprise an apparatus that digitally produces images for radiographic systems <b>102</b>, for example, instead of utilizing analog-based films/screen or image plates. FPDs utilize solid-state technology combined with integrated circuits that perform similar functions as those found in digital photography and videography.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A FPD (e.g., <b>108</b>) can comprise thin-film-transistor (TFT) 2D arrays or CMOS 2D arrays coupled with one or more components that detect radiation and convert it into an electrical current or voltage. For example, indirect FPDs utilize a scintillator layer that reacts to a detected x-ray photon by producing light. In this example, the light produced by the scintillator is converted to an electrical charge by coupled photodiodes that convert light into electrons. The electrons produced by the photodiodes are stored in the pixel capacitors and switched out by the TFTs and used to produce an image based on an amount of electrical charge detected, at least as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As another example, a direct FPD utilizes a radiation detection layer that converts detected x-ray photons to an electrical charge. In this example, the charge produced by the radiation detection layer can be stored at a particular pixel location on the pixel capacitor, to indicate a number of photons detected at that pixel location. The charge detected is switched out by associated TFTs to create a digital image of the irradiated object, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a component diagram illustrating an example embodiment <b>200</b> of one or more portions of existing technology used in a direct conversion FPD. A radiation detection layer <b>202</b> is configured to detect radiation, such as actinic (ionizing) and non-actinic (non-ionizing) type radiation. The radiation detection layer may be comprised of different materials capable of absorbing radiation and responding by producing an electrical charge, often referred to as an x-ray photoconductive material. For example, a commonly used photoconductive material is amorphous selenium that absorbs x-rays and converts them into an electrical charge, such as an electron hole pair.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In one embodiment, an applied voltage bias can be used to direct the charge carriers to a desired side of the radiation detection layer <b>202</b>, such as where the negative charge is desired to move in a direction toward the bottom (e.g., <b>214</b>) and the positive charge in a direction toward the top (e.g., <b>212</b>), for example. It will be appreciated that +/&#x2212; and &#x2212;/+ notations are used in the Figures to depict a positive or negative bias applied to a top electrical contact and a corresponding negative or positive bias applied to a bottom electrical contact. By way of example, to move negatively charged electrons in a direction from the top to the bottom, a negative bias may be applied to the top of the FPD (to drive the like charged electrons in a direction away from the top) and a positive bias may be applied to the bottom of the FPD (to attract the oppositely charged electrons in a direction toward the bottom). This same applied bias would move positively charged holes to move in a direction away from the positively biased bottom electrical contact and toward the negatively biased top electrical contact. In the exemplary embodiment <b>200</b>, a top blocking layer <b>204</b> and bottom blocking layer <b>206</b> are directly in contact with the radiation detection layer <b>202</b>. In one embodiment, a blocking layer can be configured to block either a positive charge carrier (N-type blocking layer) or a negative charge carrier (P-type blocking layer). Therefore, for example, the top blocking layer <b>204</b> can comprise a P-type blocking layer (e.g., that only blocks negatively charged electrons), thereby only allowing the positive charge carriers to move toward the top <b>212</b>; and the bottom layer <b>206</b> can comprise an N-type blocking layer (e.g., that only blocks positive charges), thereby only allowing the negative charge carriers to move toward the bottom <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Typically, a blocking layer is made or comprised of a thin layer of the radiation detection layer, such as amorphous selenium, that has been doped. Regions, such as layers, can be doped by different techniques, such as implantation and/or diffusion, for example. N-type dopants may comprise alkalies, for example, and P-type dopants may comprise arsenic, for example. It will be appreciated that doping is not limited by the one or more examples set forth herein, and may comprise other/different techniques, and/or doping agents, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In one embodiment, the blocking layer (e.g., <b>204</b>, <b>206</b>) may be replaced by an isolation layer. An isolation layer can be comprised of a dielectric material that is configured to electrically isolate the radiation detection layer <b>202</b>, at least at the side of direct contact. Parylene is a polymer that is commonly used as a dielectric, isolation barrier in FPDs and other solid-state circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the example embodiment <b>200</b>, a top electrical contact <b>208</b> and a bottom electrical contact <b>210</b> are disposed in direct contact, respectively, with the top blocking layer <b>204</b> and bottom blocking layer <b>206</b>. In an alternate embodiment, for example, the top blocking layer <b>204</b> is replaced with an isolation layer and the contact layer <b>208</b> is applied on top of it. The electrical contact layer <b>210</b> may be deposited on a 2D TFT and capacitor array on a glass substrate where a plurality of capacitors receive and temporarily store the electrical charge from the radiation detection layer <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In one embodiment, x-ray photons may be directed toward the FPD, such as from the top. The x-ray photons are absorbed by the radiation detection layer, such as amorphous selenium, and converted to electrical charge carriers, such as electron-hole pairs. In one embodiment, an applied bias drives the positive charge carriers to migrate in a direction toward the top, and the negative charge carriers to migrate in a direction toward the bottom. Further, the top blocking layer can be a P-type blocker that only allows the positive charge carriers to pass therethrough; and the bottom blocking layer can be an N-type blocker that only allows the negative charge carriers to pass therethrough. In one embodiment, a pixel addressing scheme can be used for respective capacitors in the electrical contacts, where an electrical charge received by a capacitor is assigned to a particular pixel location. In this way, for example, an image can be digitally created from electrical charges collected by the respective capacitors.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a component diagram of an example flat panel detector component <b>300</b> for detecting actinic and non-actinic radiation as provided herein. In this embodiment, the flat panel detector <b>300</b> comprises a plurality of layers, where at least one of the layers comprises silk <b>302</b>. Silk has properties that are desirable for use in a FPD. Depending on a thickness of the silk layer, for example, the silk layer may act as an insulating layer due to its dielectric properties. Further, as an example, the silk layer may serve as a blocking layer as it may provide N-type blocking properties. A silk layer may be thinner than conventional blocking layers, however, and thus may provide for use in special applications like, for example, with liquid crystals. Additionally, the formation (e.g., deposition) process of silk in the flat panel detector is typically easier to perform that that of other materials used in this manner in a FPD.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A bottom electrical contact <b>308</b> is disposed on a substrate (not shown), such as glass, silicon or some other suitable substrate. The bottom electrical contact can, for example, be deposited on capacitors configured to temporarily store an electrical charge, for example, where respective capacitors are arranged in a 2D pixel-type array addressed by rows and columns. In this way, in this example, an electrical charge received by a capacitor can be associated with a specific location in the FPD in order to create a digital image. The charges accumulated on the capacitors can be read out by using a 2D matching array of TFTs or CMOS electronics, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A bottom blocking layer <b>306</b> is disposed in direct contact with the bottom electrical contact <b>308</b>. As described above, the bottom blocking layer <b>308</b> can be configured to block a desired charge, such as a negative or positive charge carrier (e.g., negatively charged electron, or positively charged hole). In one embodiment, the bottom blocking layer <b>306</b> can be or comprise a doped portion of a radiation detection layer <b>304</b>. As described above, the radiation detection layer can be doped with a desired material that provides blocking of desired charge carriers. As an example, the bottom blocking layer <b>306</b> can be radiation detection layer material doped with alkalies to provide an N-type blocking layer, thereby only allowing negative charge carriers (e.g., electrons) to pass through to the bottom electrical contact <b>308</b>. It will be appreciated that other materials can be used and doped (or not) for the blocking layer (and/or other blocking layers mentioned herein), alone or in combination with one another.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The radiation detection layer <b>304</b> is disposed in direct contact with the bottom blocking layer <b>306</b>. As described above, the radiation detection layer comprises a material that absorbs radiation and produces a proportional electrical charge. In one embodiment, the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> can comprise amorphous selenium. When amorphous selenium is utilized, the FPD is considered to be a &#x201c;direct&#x201d; detector as incident x-ray photons that strike the amorphous selenium are converted directly to an electrical charge. For example, when an x-ray photon is absorbed by the amorphous selenium layer many electron-hole pairs are created. A bias is applied to the amorphous selenium layer (and across the FPD generally) to drive the charge carriers (negative electrons and positive holes) to separate sides according to the polarity of the bias. For example, the negative charge carriers may be driven to migrate in a direction toward the top <b>312</b>, such as where an opposing polarity positive bias is applied to the top <b>312</b>, and the positive charge carriers may be driven to migrate in a direction toward the bottom <b>310</b>, such as where an opposing polarity negative bias is applied to the bottom <b>310</b> of the detector component <b>300</b>. Moreover, where the bottom blocking layer <b>306</b> comprises a P-type blocking material, electrons may not be able pass therethrough. Similarly, where the silk layer comprises an N-type blocking material, holes may not be able to pass there-through.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">It will be appreciated that the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> is not limited to the embodiments described herein. The radiation detection layer can comprise any appropriate material that provides radiation detection properties suitable for use in a flat panel detector (e.g., doped amorphous selenium monocrystals and polysilicon). Further, in one embodiment, the radiation detection layer may comprise a combination of materials, such as a particle in binder (PIB) combination, for example, that comprises a radiation detection material suspended in a binder material.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In the example FPD component <b>300</b>, the silk layer <b>302</b> is disposed in direct physical contact with the radiation detection layer <b>304</b>. In one embodiment, the silk layer <b>302</b> can be configured to electrically insulate a side of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> with which it is in contact. That is, for example, the silk layer <b>302</b> can provide an insulation or dielectric layer, such that neither positive or negative electrical charges can transition past one side of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> (e.g., the top side <b>312</b>). In this way, in this example, the desired electrical charge (e.g., positive or negative) produced when radiation impacts the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> can be directed to accumulate on one side of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> (e.g., the bottom side of <b>302</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In one embodiment, the FPD component may comprise a silk layer on both a first and second side of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b>. In this embodiment, the silk layers can electrically insulate the radiation detection layer on two sides. For example, the FPD component may be configured such that a bias applied thereacross produces a substantially planar distribution of charges at a first and second side of the radiation detection layer. That is, in this example, the bias may provide for a substantially planar distribution of the negative electrical charge (e.g., electrons) toward the bottom of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b>, with a corresponding substantially planar distribution of the positive electrical charge (e.g., holes) toward the top of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b>. In this embodiment, the resulting charge distributions may be utilized by one or more other component in the FPD to facilitate image generation.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In one embodiment, the silk layer can behave as a blocking layer. For example, depending on an amount of silk and/or a thickness of the silk in the layer, the silk layer may be utilized as an N-type blocking layer (or P-type blocking layer if appropriately doped, for example). As described above, for example, the N-type blocking properties of the silk layer can block positive charge carriers from transitioning past the silk layer, and only allow negative charge carriers to transition across the silk layer. In one embodiment, another layer may be disposed at the other side of the silk layer (e.g., the opposite side of the radiation detection layer <b>304</b>). For example, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the silk layer <b>302</b> may be disposed between the radiation detection layer <b>304</b> and a top electrical contact layer (not shown). In this example, the top silk layer can comprise an N-type blocking layer that merely allows the negative charge carriers to transition to the top electrical contact layer for use in imaging.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a component diagram illustrating an example embodiment <b>400</b> of one or more components described herein. In this example embodiment <b>400</b>, a flat panel detector component (e.g., <b>300</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) is configured for use in a liquid crystal display apparatus. As described above, a bottom electrical contact <b>414</b> (e.g., used to apply a voltage bias) can be disposed on a substrate (not shown), and a bottom blocking layer <b>412</b> can be disposed in direct contact with the bottom electrical contact <b>414</b>. A radiation detection layer <b>410</b> (e.g., comprising amorphous selenium) is disposed in direct contact with the bottom blocking layer <b>412</b>, where the bottom blocking lay may comprise or be comprised of a doped layer of radiation detection layer material.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A first silk layer <b>408</b> is disposed in direct physical contact with the radiation detection layer <b>410</b>, for example, at a top of the radiation detection layer <b>410</b> opposite the bottom blocking layer <b>412</b>. A liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> can be disposed in contact with the silk layer <b>408</b>, such as at an opposite side from the radiation detection layer <b>410</b>. By way of example, a polarizer layer (not shown) may be formed over liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> (e.g., on top of, with or without other layers in between the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> and the polarizer layer), which can facilitate image read-out. In this example, the crystals in the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> can have a twisted or relaxed alignment, where, utilizing polarized light, a first phase (e.g., relaxed or twisted) allows light to pass through and a second phase (e.g., twisted or relaxed) inhibits light from passing through.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The alignment of the liquid crystals can be changed by an electrical field, such that molecular axes of the liquid crystals align with the electrical field (e.g., parallel to field lines). Therefore, for example, an electrical field can be used to align the liquid crystals as desired, where respective aligned liquid crystals form respective pixels. In one embodiment, the electrical charges produced by the radiation detection layer <b>410</b> create an electrical field which changes the liquid crystal phases, thus allowing for light to selectively pass through pixel related locations for an image to be formed thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In the example embodiment <b>400</b>, a second silk layer <b>404</b> is disposed between the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> and a glass layer. That is, although the second silk layer <b>404</b> and the glass layer are illustrated as a single layer, generally the second silk layer is in direct physical contact with the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b> and a glass layer is formed over the second silk layer. A top electrical contact <b>402</b> (e.g., used to apply a voltage bias) is formed over the glass layer. In one embodiment, the second silk layer <b>404</b> may comprise a pattern that can provide a desired pattern template for a non-silk layer, such as the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b>, that is disposed in contact with the silk layer <b>404</b>. In this way, for example, when an electrical field is applied to the liquid crystal layer <b>406</b>, the liquid crystals may align in the desired pattern when in the appropriate phase, thereby creating a desired visual effect. In yet another embodiment, the silk layer <b>404</b> may be absent and the pattern is applied directly on the glass layer.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As an illustrative example, x-ray photons may be directed toward the radiation detection layer <b>410</b> from the top side <b>418</b>. The photons are converted to electrical charge carriers in the radiation detection layer <b>410</b>, which move toward the top and/or bottom of the device <b>400</b> depending on the bias applied (e.g., a negative voltage bias applied to the top electrical contact <b>402</b> and a positive voltage bias applied to the bottom electrical contact <b>414</b>). In this example, the bottom blocking layer <b>412</b> can inhibit positive charge carrier movement and merely allow negative charge carriers to transition toward the bottom <b>416</b>. Similarly, the first silk layer <b>408</b> can inhibit negative charge carrier movement and merely allow positive charge carriers to transition toward the top <b>418</b> of the detector component <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In one embodiment, the first silk layer <b>408</b> may comprise a thickness of ten to hundreds of nanometers. In this way, when the silk layer serves as an insulating or dielectric layer, for example, an electrical field created by a substantially planar distribution of positive charge carriers (or negative charge carriers if an opposite bias is applied across the device <b>400</b>) at a location where an x-ray photon impinged the radiation detection layer <b>410</b> can be contained by the first silk layer <b>408</b> and resultantly affect the phase of the liquid crystals. In one embodiment, the liquid crystal layer can be considered as pixels, where respective pixels comprise liquid crystals that can be switched between phases depending on the electrical field created at the first silk layer <b>408</b>. As an example, an image may be created reading through the liquid crystal layer, where respective pixels are affected proportionally by an amount of electrical charge converted from photons. In this way, the FPD component may comprise a direct read capability, where a radiologist, for example, can directly read an image produce by the FPD from a radiographic scan.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">A method may be devised for forming a flat panel detector (FPD) that can be used to detect actinic and non-actinic radiation. Such a FPD may be formed with at least one layer of silk. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow diagram <b>500</b> illustrating an example method for forming a FPD. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref> are perspective views of a flat panel detector component <b>300</b>, <b>400</b> whereon such a method may be implemented, or rather which may result from implementing such a method. While the method <b>100</b> is illustrated and described as a series of acts or events, it will be appreciated that the present disclosure is not limited by the illustrated ordering of such acts or events. For example, some acts may occur in different orders and/or concurrently with other acts or events apart from those illustrated and/or described herein. In addition, not all illustrated acts may be required to implement a methodology in accordance with one or more aspects or embodiments set forth herein. Further, one or more of the acts depicted herein may be carried out in one or more separate acts and/or phases.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The example method <b>500</b> begins at <b>502</b> and includes forming a first electrical contact layer on top of a suitable substrate, at <b>504</b>. For example, a CMOS or thin-film transistor (TFT) layer forming an Active Matrix Array, Electrometer Probes and/or Microplasma Line Addressing, etc. may be formed together with an electrical contact layer on top of glass, silicon, polysilicon, and/or some other appropriate substrate. For example, the contact may be formed, at least in part, by chemical vapor deposition, sputtering and/or spin on coating, etc. Further, a 2D capacitor array may be formed connected to the electrical contact layer, which can be used to collect electrical charge produced by the flat panel detector. It will be appreciated that substrate as used herein may comprise any type of appropriate body (e.g., glass, silicon, SiGe, SOI, etc.) such as a glass sheet, semiconductor wafer and/or one or more die on a wafer, as well as any other type of epitaxial and/or other organic and/or inorganic layers formed thereover or otherwise associated therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">At <b>506</b>, a blocking layer is formed on top of the first electrical contact layer. In one embodiment, the blocking layer can comprise a doped layer of radiation detection layer material. For example, an amorphous selenium can be doped with (e.g., by evaporation or diffusion) arsenic, cesium, sodium, or some other appropriate doping agent. It will be appreciated that regions (e.g., layers) can be doped by different techniques, such as evaporation and/or diffusion, for example, and that doping is not meant to be limited by the one or more examples set forth herein. N-type dopants may comprise alkalies from sodium to cesium, for example, and p-type dopants may comprise arsenic, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">At <b>508</b>, a radiation detection or detector layer is formed on top of the blocking layer. The radiation detection layer can be formed in direct contact with the blocking layer by any appropriate semiconductor application method, including but not limited to, chemical vapor deposition, physical vapor deposition, electrochemical deposition, molecular beam epitaxy, and/or atomic layer deposition, etc. (where any one or more other layers mentioned herein can likewise be formed using any one or more of these and/or other techniques) Further, the deposition of the radiation detection layer may be determined, at least in part, by a type of material used in the layer. For example, amorphous selenium can be applied by a conventional vacuum evaporation technique, at an appropriate temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">At <b>510</b>, a silk layer is formed on top of the radiation detection layer. Silk is a natural protein fiber that is produced by silk-worms making a cocoon. The silk can be formed into a silk solution (e.g., silk fibroin solution) by dissolving the silk in an appropriate solvent. For example, silk can be dissolved in an aqueous salt solution and/or an organic solvent, such as hexafluoroisopropanol. In one embodiment, the silk solution can be deposited on the radiation detection layer by spin coating. Spin coating can be used to apply a very thin and uniform coating of the solution to a flat substrate. For example, a desired amount of the silk solution can be placed on the substrate, which is rotated at a high speed, spreading the solution by centrifugal force. Once a desired thickness is applied, the solvent can be evaporated, thereby leaving a desired thickness of the silk as a layer on the radiation detection layer, for example. In this way, as an example, the silk can be deposited at room temperatures, under controlled conditions that provide for a substantially precise thickness (e.g., very thin as desired) of silk to be layered uniformly, and that does not substantially impact other existing layers, components, materials, etc. (e.g., as the silk is not applied at elevated temperatures that could adversely affect (e.g., melt or crystallize) existing layers, elements, features, etc). Further, a silk layer can be patterned to facilitate alignment of liquid crystals in a desired orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">It will be appreciated that the deposition of the silk layer is not limited to the examples described herein. It is anticipated that those skilled in the art may devise alternate techniques for applying a silk coating layer in a FPD.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">At <b>512</b>, in the example method <b>500</b>, a second or top electrical contact layer is formed on top of the silk layer (e.g., in a manner similar to that for forming the first or bottom electrical contact layer). Having formed the second electrical contact layer, the example method <b>500</b> ends at <b>514</b>. It will be appreciated that one or more of the acts of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> may be used in forming one or more of the component parts or layers of the structures illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>4</b> and/or <b>7</b>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating one embodiment <b>600</b> of techniques described herein. This embodiment <b>600</b> begins at <b>602</b> and involves forming a first electrical contact layer on top a suitable substrate, at <b>604</b>; forming a blocking layer on top of the first electrical contact layer, at <b>606</b>; forming a radiation detection layer on top of the blocking layer, at <b>608</b>; and forming a first silk layer on top of the radiation detection layer, at <b>610</b>, as described above in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">At <b>612</b>, a liquid crystal layer is formed on top of, and in direct contact with, the first silk layer. In this way, the first silk layer is disposed between the radiation detection layer and the liquid crystal layer. At <b>614</b> a second silk layer is formed on a glass layer or one or more other optically transparent materials, such as by spin coating or some other appropriate technique. In one embodiment, a pattern can be formed on the second silk layer, in order to provide a template for a non-silk layer that can be formed in contact with the second silk layer. For example, a pattern can be formed in the silk layer to provide a desired lining pattern for the liquid crystal layer.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">It will be appreciated that lithographic techniques can be implemented in forming any one or more of the layers (or portions thereof) described herein, such as for performing patterning, masking, etching, etc. actions, for example, where lithography broadly refers to processes for transferring one or more patterns between various media. In lithography, a light sensitive resist coating is formed over one or more layers to which a pattern is to be transferred. The resist coating is then patterned by exposing it to one or more types of radiation and/or light that (selectively) passes through an intervening mask containing the pattern. The light causes exposed or unexposed portions of the resist coating to become more or less soluble, depending on the type of resist used (e.g., positive or negative), and the pattern in the intervening mask is indelibly formed therein. A developer is then used to remove the more soluble areas leaving the patterned resist. The patterned resist can then serve as a template for the underlying layer or layers which can be selectively etched or doped or otherwise treated. Once the underlying layer is treated, the patterned resist is removed (e.g., chemically stripped) leaving the treated layer (e.g., having the pattern formed therein).</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">At <b>616</b> the combined second silk layer and glass are applied on top of the liquid crystal layer (e.g., with the second silk layer in contact with the liquid crystal layer). For example, liquid crystal layer is typically surrounded by walls to form a complete seal, such that the liquid crystals cannot leak out of the component. At <b>618</b>, a second electrical contact can be formed on top of the glass. Having formed the second electrical contact layer, the example embodiment <b>600</b> ends at <b>620</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It will be appreciated that the one or more silk layers formed in a FPD can have many uses and are not limited to the uses described herein. In one embodiment, for example, a silk layer may be formed as an insulating layer, such as to provide electrical insulation to one or more components/layers of the FPD. Further, a silk layer may be formed as a blocking layer, for example, to provide blocking of a desired electrical charge. Additionally, a silk layer may be formed as a separation layer, providing physical separation between two layers, such as to mitigate interaction between materials (e.g., chemical interaction). As described above, the silk layer may also be formed as a pattern layer. It will be appreciated that one or more of the acts of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> may be used in forming one or more of the component parts or layers of the structures illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>4</b> and/or <b>7</b>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a component diagram illustrating an alternate embodiment of an apparatus <b>700</b> for detecting x-rays. The apparatus <b>700</b> comprises an x-ray detection layer <b>706</b>, such as amorphous selenium. As described above, when x-rays are absorbed in amorphous selenium, electrical charges can be produced, for example, where the electrical charges are proportional to the number of x-ray photons that impact the amorphous selenium. The x-ray detection layer can comprise various materials appropriate for detecting x-rays. For example, the x-ray detection layer may comprise: a lead oxide based material; cadmium selenide, cadmium telluride; mercury iodide; cadmium zinc telluride; lead iodide; titanium tetrabromide; and/or an x-ray detecting particles in a binder, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The apparatus <b>700</b> further comprises at least one silk layer <b>704</b>, which is in direct contact with the x-ray detection layer <b>706</b>. In one embodiment, the silk layer <b>704</b> is an N-type blocking layer, where the silk layer blocks transition of positive charge carriers (e.g. holes) between the x-ray detection layer <b>706</b> and a top electrical contact layer <b>702</b>. In this way, for example, only negative charges may transition from the x-ray detection layer <b>706</b> to the top electrical contact layer <b>702</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In one embodiment, the apparatus may further comprise a P-type blocking layer <b>708</b>. In this embodiment, the P-type blocking layer <b>708</b> can inhibit negative charge carriers (e.g., electrons) from entering a bottom electrical contact layer <b>710</b>, and thus only allow positive charges to reach the bottom electrical contact layer <b>710</b>. The P-type blocking layer may comprise or be comprised of a portion of the x-ray detection layer that has been doped with arsenic, for example. As an illustrative example, when one or more x-ray photons are absorbed by the x-ray detection layer <b>706</b> many electron-hole pairs can be produced. The electrons (negative charge carriers) can transition across the N-type blocking layer <b>704</b> to the top electrical contact layer. The positive electrical charges (e.g., holes) can transition across the P-type blocking layer <b>708</b> to the bottom electrical contact layer <b>710</b>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In one embodiment, a liquid crystal display component (not shown) may be used with the apparatus, and be configured to provide an indication of detected x-rays (e.g., for direct read-out of a digital image representative of x-rays attenuated by an object being scanned). In this embodiment, the liquid crystal display component can comprise a first silk layer that is in direct contact with a liquid crystal layer. Further, the liquid crystal display component can comprise a second silk layer in direct contact with the x-ray detection layer. In this way, for example, an electrical field can be generated in the x-ray detection layer at the second silk layer. The electrical field can affect the liquid crystals phase to create an image indicative of the photons received by the x-ray detection layer at the corresponding locations in the x-ray detection layer. Further, the first silk layer can be patterned such that the liquid crystals will align in a desired orientation.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">It will be appreciated that while reference may be made throughout this document to exemplary structures in discussing aspects of one or more methodologies described herein (e.g., those structures presented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>4</b> and/or <b>7</b> while discussing the methodologies set forth in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-6</figref>), that those methodologies are not to be limited by the corresponding structures presented. Rather, the methodologies and structures are to be considered independent of one another and able to stand alone and be practiced without regard to any of the particular aspects depicted in the Figs. Additionally, the structures and/or layers described herein can be formed in any number of suitable ways, such as with spin-on techniques, sputtering techniques (e.g., magnetron or ion beam sputtering), (thermal) growth techniques and/or deposition techniques such as chemical vapor deposition (CVD), for example.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Moreover, the words &#x201c;example&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;exemplary&#x201d; are used herein to mean serving as an example, instance, or illustration. Any aspect, design, etc. described herein as &#x201c;example&#x201d; and/or &#x201c;exemplary&#x201d; is not necessarily to be construed as advantageous over other aspects, designs, etc. Rather, use of these terms is intended to present concepts in a concrete fashion. As used in this application, the term &#x201c;or&#x201d; is intended to mean an inclusive &#x201c;or&#x201d; rather than an exclusive &#x201c;or&#x201d;. That is, unless specified otherwise, or clear from context, &#x201c;X employs A or B&#x201d; is intended to mean any of the natural inclusive permutations. That is, if X employs A; X employs B; or X employs both A and B, then &#x201c;X employs A or B&#x201d; is satisfied under any of the foregoing instances. In addition, the articles &#x201c;a&#x201d; and &#x201c;an&#x201d; as used in this application and the appended claims may generally be construed to mean &#x201c;one or more&#x201d; unless specified otherwise or clear from context to be directed to a singular form.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Also, although the disclosure has been shown and described with respect to one or more implementations, equivalent alterations and modifications will occur to others skilled in the art based upon a reading and understanding of this specification and the annexed drawings. The disclosure includes all such modifications and alterations and is limited only by the scope of the following claims. In particular regard to the various functions performed by the above described components (e.g., elements, resources, etc.), the terms used to describe such components are intended to correspond, unless otherwise indicated, to any component which performs the specified function of the described component (e.g., that is functionally equivalent), even though not structurally equivalent to the disclosed structure which performs the function in the herein illustrated example implementations of the disclosure. In addition, while a particular feature of the disclosure may have been disclosed with respect to only one of several implementations, such feature may be combined with one or more other features of the other implementations as may be desired and advantageous for any given or particular application. Furthermore, to the extent that the terms &#x201c;includes&#x201d;, &#x201c;having&#x201d;, &#x201c;has&#x201d;, &#x201c;with&#x201d;, or variants thereof are used in either the detailed description or the claims, such terms are intended to be inclusive in a manner similar to the term &#x201c;comprising.&#x201d;</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A flat panel detector component for detecting at least one of actinic radiation or non-actinic radiation, comprising:
<claim-text>a first layer configured to detect the at least one of actinic radiation or non-actinic radiation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second layer comprising silk.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second layer is in direct physical contact with the first layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first layer comprises amorphous selenium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>a third layer comprising silk, the first layer disposed between the second layer and the third layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second layer is configured to filter electrical charge generated at the first layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>a third layer comprising a liquid crystal, the second layer disposed between the first layer and the third layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>a fourth layer comprising silk; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth layer comprising glass, the fourth layer disposed between the third layer and the fifth layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the silk is arranged within the second layer according to a specified pattern.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The flat panel detector component of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flat panel detector component is configured for use in a liquid crystal apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A method for forming a flat panel detector component used to detect at least one of actinic radiation or non-actinic radiation, comprising:
<claim-text>forming a second layer adjacent a first layer, the first layer configured to detect the at least one of actinic or non-actinic radiation and the second layer comprising silk.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, the forming comprising:
<claim-text>depositing the silk onto the first layer to form the second layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>forming a third layer adjacent the second layer, the third layer comprising a liquid crystal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, comprising:
<claim-text>forming a combination comprising a fourth layer and a fifth layer, the fourth layer comprising silk and the fifth layer comprising glass; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying the combination to the third layer such that the fourth layer is disposed between the third layer and the fifth layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, the forming comprising:
<claim-text>forming a pattern in the second layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, the forming comprising forming the second layer to function as at least one of:
<claim-text>an insulating layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blocking layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a separation layer; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>a patterning layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. An apparatus for detecting x-rays, comprising:
<claim-text>a first layer configured to detect the x-rays; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second layer comprising silk, the second layer adjacent the first layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first layer comprises one or more of:
<claim-text>amorphous selenium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lead oxide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>cadmium selenide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>cadmium telluride</claim-text>
<claim-text>mercury iodide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>cadmium zinc telluride;</claim-text>
<claim-text>lead iodide;</claim-text>
<claim-text>titanium tetrabromide; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>an x-ray detector particle in binder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, comprising a third layer comprising liquid crystal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, the second layer forming an N-type blocking layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, the second layer forming a P-type blocking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
