<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622295-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622295</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13250639</doc-number>
<date>20110930</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235437</main-classification>
<further-classification>235379</further-classification>
<further-classification>235380</further-classification>
<further-classification>235444</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Unit of a media depository</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0205024</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Washington et al.</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>705 43</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235379</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235380</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235437</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>235444</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>G06Q 20/1085</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>G06Q 20/18</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>G07D 11/0054</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>G07D 7/0084</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>G07D 11/0006</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>B65H 2701/1912</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>B65H 29/40</classification-cpc-combination-text>
<classification-cpc-combination-text>B65H 2402/30</classification-cpc-combination-text>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130081561</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130404</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Peterek</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kitchener</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Peterek</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kitchener</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chan</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>NCR Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Duluth</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Michael G</first-name>
<department>2876</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Chedekel</last-name>
<first-name>Tabitha</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A unit of a media depository is described. The unit comprises: a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one supporting member between the working position and a pivot position; a first hinge member adapted to be movably mounted on the at least one support member; and, a second hinge member attached to or integral with the body. When the body is moved from the working position to the pivot position, the first and second hinge members engage such that the first hinge member is forced by the second hinge member to move with the body to the pivot position at which the first and second hinge members form a pivoting mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.06mm" wi="162.73mm" file="US08622295-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="205.74mm" wi="166.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622295-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="158.92mm" wi="169.84mm" file="US08622295-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="229.45mm" wi="174.33mm" file="US08622295-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="226.23mm" wi="156.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622295-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to improvements in, or relating to, a unit of a media depository.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Media depositories are used to receive media items from a customer. One common type of media depository is a sheet media depository for receiving media items in sheet form (such as banknotes, cheques, tickets, giros, and the like).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Sheet media depositories are used in ATMs and other self-service terminals (such as vending machines, change machines, and the like) to identify and validate deposited sheets.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Sheet media depositories may comprise a number of units each performing a different task. For instance, a sheet media depository may comprise a rebuncher unit which forms part of a media depository. Mixed notes are fed by a customer into the depository which presents each note individually to a validator unit. Invalid notes are stored or returned to the customer. Valid notes are typically reformed into a bunch. The rebuncher unit is used to reform the bunch which is either returned to the customer or sent to storage hoppers. Sometimes media fed into or out of the rebuncher unit becomes jammed.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The term &#x201c;depository&#x201d; should be understood to include a module of an ATM sometimes referred to as a &#x201c;recycler&#x201d; whose manner of operation is somewhat similar to a depository albeit that a recycler may be used to dispense deposited notes to a subsequent customer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Units and other hardware are often grouped within a depository very closely together, not only so that they can easily interact with one another, but also because space is often at a premium. This can make it difficult for an operator wishing to work on a unit, for example, to service or to release jammed media, to access its internal workings.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Some units in a depository may be racked out to facilitate servicing. To rack out a unit, a release handle or door is typically provided. Sometimes a unit's release door can only be reached by removing other, adjacent units or hardware. For instance, a rebuncher unit part of a depository in an ATM may be located adjacent bins, and the release door, which may be underneath the unit, may be accessed only by removing the bins, which is inconvenient and requires considerable effort.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a first aspect, there is provided a unit of a media depository, the unit comprising:</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one supporting member between the working position and a pivot position;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">a first hinge member adapted to be movably mounted on the at least one support member; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">a second hinge member attached to or integral with the body;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">wherein, as the body is moved from the working position to the pivot position, the first and second hinge members engage such that the first hinge member is forced by the second hinge member to move with the body to the pivot position at which the first and second hinge members form a pivoting mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A pivotal attachment enables the unit to be pivoted away from the pivot position to a service position at which the unit can be worked on more conveniently. For example, if the unit has a release door that is inaccessible when the unit is in the normal, working position, the unit can be moved out of the working position, to the pivot position and pivoted to the service position at which the door is accessible.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the working position of the body, the at least one support member extends through the body and, in the pivot position, the body is substantially removed from the at least one support member.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The at least one support member may be attached or fastened to or integral with at least one structural member of the depository. The structural member may be a wall, a beam, a strut or any other type of member that forms part of the structure of the depository. Alternatively, the wall, beam or strut may form part of the structure of the machine of which the depository forms part or of another unit that forms part of the same machine.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The at least one support member may be, for example, a rod or a rail. Preferably, there are two supporting members.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, the second hinge member comprises at least one hook-like finger and engagement between the first hinge member and the at least one hook-like finger involves the first hinge member being hooked by the at least one hook-like finger. The first hinge member may comprise a pin, a bar, an eye or any other part that is capable of being hooked by the at least one hook-like finger. Further preferably, the second hinge member comprises two hook-like fingers.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Preferably, the first hinge member remains stationary on the at least one support member during a first phase of movement of the body from the working position to the pivot position and moves relative to the at least one support member during a second phase of movement of the body from the working position to the pivot position, and wherein the second phase of movement ends with the first hinge member being releasably locked to the at least one support member at the pivot position. The first hinge member may comprise a bushing, sleeve or collar which is mounted on the at least one support member by being slid on to the at least one support member, and the at least one support member may slide through the first hinge member during the second phase of movement of the body to the pivot position. Further preferably, the first hinge member comprises an engaging part and the at least one support member comprises a feature, and wherein engagement between the engaging part and the feature results in the first hinge member being releasably locked to the at least one support member at the pivot position. Equally, the at least one support member could comprise an engaging part and the first hinge member could comprise a feature. Preferably, the feature comprises a groove and the engaging part comprises at least one resilient finger, and engagement between the engaging part and the feature comprises the at least one finger extending into the groove. Preferably, the groove is also used by a latching mechanism to latch the at least one support member in the support position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Preferably, there is at least one cavity in the body through which the at least one support member extends when the body is in the working position, and, when the body is in the working position, the first hinge member is housed in the at least one cavity.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further preferably, the first hinge member remains locked to the at least one support member during a first phase of movement of the body back from the pivot position to the working position. A release arrangement is provided for unlocking the first hinge member from the at least one support member after the first phase of movement of the body back to the working position so that, during the latter part of the movement, the first hinge member moves relative to the at least one support member. In the case where the body has at least one cavity, the release arrangement is provided by the cavity, in particular, an end wall of the cavity.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The unit may be a rebuncher unit part of a depository module of an ATM. The rebuncher unit may comprise an escrow rebuncher unit.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to a second aspect, there is provided a unit of a media depository, the unit comprising:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one support member between the working position and a pivot position;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">wherein in the working position the at least one support member extends through the body and in the pivot position the body is substantially removed from the at least one support member; and</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">a pivot mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member at least when the body is at the pivot position.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">According to a third aspect, there is provided a unit of a media depository, the unit comprising a support arrangement adapted to adopt either one of two states: a working state in which the unit is supported by at least one support member of the depository; and, a pivot state in which the unit is pivotally attached to the at least one support member.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">According to a fourth aspect, there is provided a method of working on a unit of a media depository, the method comprising changing the state of the unit from a support state in which the unit is supported by at least one support member of the depository to a pivot state in which the unit is pivotally attached to the at least one support member.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">These and other aspects will now be described, by way of example, with reference to the following drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of part of a sheet media depository used in an ATM, including a unit (in the form of an escrow rebuncher) according to one embodiment of the invention, with the rebuncher shown in a support position;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a side view of the rebuncher unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partial, transverse cross sectional view (taken through the elongate axis of the support member) of the rebuncher shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partial, transverse cross sectional view (taken through the elongate axis of the support member) of the rebuncher of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, shown in a pivot position;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial end view of the rebuncher of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, shown pivotally attached to a structural member of the media depository, in a pivoted position; and,</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a first hinge member of the rebuncher of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 1A</figref>, indicated generally at <b>1</b> is part of a media depository. Visible within <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> (but most clearly seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>) is a rebuncher unit <b>2</b> which is part of the media depository <b>1</b>. The part of the media depository illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> includes a transport arrangement <b>3</b> including elongated slots <b>4</b> on an upper portion thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A customer (not shown) feeds notes (not shown) into the depository <b>1</b> in bunches. The individual notes are presented to a note validator unit (not shown). Following validation, the rebuncher unit <b>2</b> reforms the notes into a bunch.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With reference also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the rebuncher unit <b>2</b> has a body <b>10</b> of a moulded plastics material construction separated broadly into first and second body halves <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>. In the normal, working position of the rebuncher unit <b>2</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the body <b>10</b> is supported on a pair of support members in the form of rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> attached to and extending from a wall <b>6</b>. The rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> and wall <b>6</b> are part of the depository. Access to the internal workings of the rebuncher unit <b>2</b> is gained by a release door (not visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) which is underneath the body <b>10</b>. From time to time, the rebuncher unit <b>2</b> becomes jammed with notes and access is required in order to free the jam.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Each rod <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>: has a proximal end <b>30</b> adjacent the wall <b>6</b> and a distal end <b>32</b> adjacent an open side <b>8</b> of the body <b>10</b>; is attached to the wall <b>6</b> by a head <b>17</b> at its proximal end <b>30</b> on the remote side of the wall <b>6</b> to the body <b>10</b>; and, extends through the wall <b>6</b> and the body <b>10</b>, that is, through an opening <b>20</b> in the wall <b>6</b>, through the material of the first body half <b>16</b>, through the material of the second body half <b>18</b> and through an opening <b>26</b> in the side <b>8</b>. The body <b>10</b> is held in the working position by a unitary latch mechanism <b>28</b> which latches the distal ends <b>32</b> of the rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The latch mechanism <b>28</b> is provided with two teardrop-shaped apertures <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> whose spacing matches that of the openings <b>26</b> in the side <b>8</b>. The latch mechanism <b>28</b> is urged by a spring <b>38</b> into its default position in which each of the narrow sections of the apertures <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> is aligned with a corresponding opening <b>26</b> in the side <b>8</b>. Each rod <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> has a circumferential groove <b>40</b> adjacent its distal end <b>32</b> and the narrower part of the apertures <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> are so sized that the web of the latch around the apertures <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> extends into the circumferential groove <b>40</b> and latches the rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> in place.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The latch mechanism <b>28</b> has a handle <b>42</b>, and the body <b>10</b> is released from the rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> by moving the latch mechanism <b>28</b> to the disengaged position, against the urging force of the spring <b>38</b>, so that the web of the latch mechanism <b>28</b> is pulled out of the groove <b>40</b> and aligns the wider part of the apertures <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> with the opening <b>26</b> in the second wall, whereupon, because the wider section of the aperture <b>34</b>, <b>36</b> is bigger than the opening <b>26</b>, the body <b>10</b> is free to slidably move relative to the rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For simplicity's sake, the embodiment will be further described with reference to one of the rods <b>12</b> only, although it will be appreciated that other embodiments comprises two such rods <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> and two sets of associated components, even though only one set of associated components are described in relation to the one rod <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Each body half <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> contains a cavity <b>44</b>, <b>46</b> through which the rod <b>12</b> extends. In the working position of the body <b>10</b>, the first cavity <b>44</b> in the first body half <b>16</b> is adjacent the wall <b>6</b> and the second cavity <b>46</b> in the second body half <b>18</b> is adjacent the side <b>8</b>. The first cavity <b>44</b> is divided broadly into two parts: a first part <b>43</b>, remote from the wall <b>6</b>, is of the same diameter as the rod <b>12</b>; and, a second part <b>45</b>, adjacent the wall <b>6</b>, has an enlarged diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A first hinge member in the form of a bushing <b>48</b> is slid on to the rod <b>12</b>. Again, in the working position of the body <b>10</b>, the bushing <b>48</b> sits around the rod <b>12</b> in the enlarged diameter part <b>45</b> of the first cavity <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">With further reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the bushing <b>48</b> is generally cylindrical except that at one end it has inwardly directed resilient fingers <b>50</b> and, at the same end, a pin <b>52</b>, which is slightly longer than the diameter of the bushing <b>48</b>, is transversely mounted (in relation to the cylindrical axis of the bushing <b>48</b>) on the outer cylindrical surface of the bushing <b>48</b>. The pin <b>52</b> is mounted generally at its midpoint so that its ends <b>54</b>, <b>56</b> are free, each one projecting in an opposite direction to the other. The enlarged diameter part <b>45</b> of the first cavity <b>44</b> is sized and shaped so as to house the bushing <b>48</b> in the support position with the pin <b>52</b> uppermost. The second cavity <b>46</b>, which is cylindrical, is the same diameter as the rod <b>12</b>. When the bushing <b>48</b> is housed in the enlarged diameter part of the first cavity <b>44</b>, the resilient fingers <b>50</b> butt up against the in-board end wall <b>58</b> of the enlarged diameter portion <b>45</b> of the first cavity <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Attached to the outside of the first body half <b>16</b>, adjacent the opening <b>20</b> in wall <b>6</b> is a second hinge member in the form of two, spaced-apart, j-shaped, hook-like fingers <b>60</b> which project such that each one is to an opposite side of the elongate axis of the rod <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">It will now be explained how the dispenser unit <b>2</b> is taken out of the depository by removing the body <b>12</b> from the rod <b>12</b>: with the latch mechanism <b>28</b> moved to the disengaged position (not shown), the body <b>10</b> is free to move transversely of the rod <b>12</b>, that is, to the right as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">During the first phase of movement of the body <b>10</b>, the bushing <b>48</b> remains stationary on the rod <b>12</b>, held by the frictional contact between the bushing <b>48</b> and the rod <b>12</b>. Continued removal of the body <b>10</b> results in the hook-like fingers <b>60</b> engaging the bushing <b>48</b>, which involves each one of the hook-like fingers <b>60</b> hooking around one of the free ends <b>54</b>, <b>56</b> of the pin <b>52</b>. The radius of curvature of the hook-like fingers <b>60</b> may be such that the hook-like fingers <b>60</b> clip on to the ends <b>54</b>, <b>56</b> of the pin. This engagement marks the beginning of the second phase of movement of the body <b>10</b>. Once the bushing <b>48</b> is hooked by the fingers, continued movement of the body <b>10</b> forces the bushing <b>48</b> to move with the body <b>10</b>, relative to the rod <b>12</b>. In effect, the bushing <b>48</b> is pulled along by the hook-like fingers <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The second phase of movement continues with the body <b>10</b> continuing to be moved until it is substantially removed from the rod <b>12</b>, at which point the resilient fingers <b>50</b> of the bushing <b>48</b> engage the groove <b>40</b> in the rod <b>12</b> by extending into it, causing the bushing <b>48</b> to lock onto the rod <b>12</b>. This is the end of the second phase of movement. The body <b>10</b> is then in the pivot position and, because the body <b>10</b> is substantially removed from the rod <b>12</b> and the rod <b>12</b> no longer extends through the body <b>10</b>, the fingers <b>60</b> and the pin <b>52</b> form a pivoting mechanism by which the unit <b>2</b> is pivotally attached to the rod <b>12</b>. In this position, the unit <b>2</b> is able to pivot upwardly about the rod <b>12</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The body <b>10</b> can be pivoted such that the transverse axis of the body <b>10</b> is substantially orthogonal to how it is in the pivot position. With the body <b>10</b> in the pivoted-upwards position, known as the service position, it is possible to access the door underneath the rebuncher unit, for example, to free any jams.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">When the body <b>10</b> is returned (pivoted downwards in this embodiment) to the pivot position, the body <b>10</b> can be re-inserted into the media dispenser <b>1</b> by sliding it over the rod <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">During the first phase of movement of the body <b>10</b> back from the pivot position to the working position, the bushing <b>48</b> initially remains locked to the rod <b>12</b> until the body <b>10</b> reaches a position where the bushing is re-housed within the enlarged diameter portion <b>45</b> of the first cavity <b>44</b>, whereupon the in-board end wall <b>58</b> of the first cavity <b>44</b> butts up against the resilient fingers <b>50</b> of the bushing <b>48</b>. This marks the beginning of the second phase of movement of the body <b>10</b> back to the working position and, from then on, further movement of the body <b>10</b> causes the bushing <b>48</b> to unlock from the rod <b>12</b>, allowing the bushing <b>48</b> and body <b>10</b> to slide together over the rod <b>12</b> until the body <b>10</b> reaches the working position where it is again latched by the latch mechanism <b>28</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A unit of a media depository, the unit comprising:
<claim-text>a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one supporting member between the working position and a pivot position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hinge member adapted to be movably mounted on the at least one support member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge member attached to or integral with the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, as the body is moved from the working position to the pivot position, the first and second hinge members engage such that the first hinge member is forced by the second hinge member to move with the body to the pivot position at which the first and second hinge members form a pivoting mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second hinge member comprises at least one hook-like finger and engagement between the first hinge member and the at least one hook-like finger involves the first hinge member being hooked by the at least one hook-like finger.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, in the working position, the at least one support member extends through the body and, in the pivot position, the body is substantially removed from the at least one support member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein there is at least one cavity in the body through which the at least one support member extends when the body is in the working position, and, when the body is in the working position, the first hinge member is housed in the at least one cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first hinge member remains locked to the at least one support member during a first phase of movement of the body back from the pivot position to the working position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a release arrangement is provided for unlocking the first hinge member from the at least one support member after the first phase of movement of the body from the pivot position to the working position such that, during a second phase of movement of the at least one supporting member from the pivot position to the working position, the first hinge member moves with the body relative to the at least one supporting member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, where the unit comprises a rebuncher unit part of a media depository.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A unit of a media depository, the unit comprising:
<claim-text>a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one supporting member between the working position and a pivot position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hinge member adapted to be movably mounted on the at least one support member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge member attached to or integral with the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, as the body is moved from the working position to the pivot position, the first and second hinge members engage such that the first hinge member is forced by the second hinge member to move with the body to the pivot position at which the first and second hinge members form a pivoting mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first hinge member remains stationary on the at least one support member during a first phase of movement of the body from the working position to the pivot position and moves relative to the at least one support member during a second phase of movement of the body from the working position to the pivot position, and wherein the second phase of movement ends with the first hinge member being releasably locked to the at least one support member at the pivot position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the first hinge member comprises a bushing, sleeve or collar which is slid on to the at least one support member, and the at least one support member slides through the first hinge member during the second phase of movement of the body to the pivot position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein, in the working position, the at least one support member extends through the body and, in the pivot position, the body is substantially removed from the at least one support member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein there is at least one cavity in the body through which the at least one support member extends when the body is in the working position, and, when the body is in the working position, the first hinge member is housed in the at least one cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, where the unit comprises a rebuncher unit part of a media depository.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A unit of a media depository, the unit comprising:
<claim-text>a body adapted to be supported by at least one support member of the depository in a working position and further adapted to be slidably moveable on the at least one supporting member between the working position and a pivot position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first hinge member adapted to be movably mounted on the at least one support member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge member attached to or integral with the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, as the body is moved from the working position to the pivot position, the first and second hinge members engage such that the first hinge member is forced by the second hinge member to move with the body to the pivot position at which the first and second hinge members form a pivoting mechanism by which the body is pivotally attached to the at least one support member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein one of the first hinge member and the at least one support member comprises an engaging part and the other of the first hinge member and the at least one support member comprises a feature, and wherein engagement between the engaging part and the feature results in the first hinge member being releasable locked to the at least one support member at the pivot position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the feature comprises a groove and the engaging part comprises at least one resilient finger, and engagement between the engaging part and the feature comprises the at least finger extending into the groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the groove is in the at least one support member and the groove is also used by a latching mechanism to latch the at least one support member in the support position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein, in the working position, the at least one support member extends through the body and, in the pivot position, the body is substantially removed from the at least one support member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein there is at least one cavity in the body through which the at least one support member extends when the body is in the working position, and, when the body is in the working position, the first hinge member is housed in the at least one cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, where the unit comprises a rebuncher unit part of a media depository.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A media depository comprising:
<claim-text>a rod having elongate axis and an outer cylindrical surface extending lengthwise along the elongate axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a body slidably moveable along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod between a working position in which the rod extends through the body and a pivot position in which the rod no longer extends through the body and the body is able to pivot in a direction transverse to lengthwise direction of the elongate axis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pivot mechanism arranged to (i) support sliding movement of the body along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod between the working position and the pivot position, and (ii) support pivoting movement of the body in the direction transverse to lengthwise direction of the elongate axis when the body is in the pivot position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A media depository according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the pivot mechanism includes (i) a first hinge member slidably moveable along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod between a first position which corresponds to when the body is in the working position and a second position which corresponds to when the body is in the pivot position, and (ii) a second hinge member attached to the body and moveable with the body when the body moves between the working position and the pivot position, wherein the second hinge member engages the first hinge member to forcibly slide the first hinge member along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod from the first position to the second position when the body slidably moves long the outer cylindrical surface of the rod from the working position to the pivot position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A method of a service operator servicing a media depository which includes (i) a rod having elongate axis and an outer cylindrical surface extending lengthwise along the elongate axis, and (ii) a body slidably moveable along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod between a working position in which the rod extends through the body and a pivot position in which the rod no longer extends through the body and the body is able to pivot in an upward direction transverse to lengthwise direction of the elongate axis, the method comprising:
<claim-text>sliding the body along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod from the working position of the body to the pivot position of the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>pivoting the body in the upward direction transverse to lengthwise direction of the elongate axis of the rod when the body is in the pivot position to allow the service operator to gain access to components underneath the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the service operator has gained access to the components underneath the body, pivoting the body in a downward direction to return the body to the pivot position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the body has returned to the pivot position, sliding the body along the outer cylindrical surface of the rod from the pivot position to the working position of the body and thereby to return the body to the working position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
