<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622029-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622029</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12571279</doc-number>
<date>20090930</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>1134</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>122  4D</main-classification>
<further-classification>16510416</further-classification>
<further-classification>110245</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Circulating fluidized bed (CFB) with in-furnace secondary air nozzles</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4665864</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Seshamani et al.</name>
<date>19870500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>122  4 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5239946</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Garcia-Mallol</name>
<date>19930800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>122  4 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5313913</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ohshita et al.</name>
<date>19940500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>122  4 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5678497</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Goidich</name>
<date>19971000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>110245</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5836257</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Belin et al.</name>
<date>19981100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>110245</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6500221</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Walker et al.</name>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 55444</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6532905</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Belin et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>122  4 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6631698</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hyppanen et al.</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>122  4 D</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6709636</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Oshita et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>422146</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110073050</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110331</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maryamchik</last-name>
<first-name>Mikhail</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairlawn</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alexander</last-name>
<first-name>Kiplin C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wadsworth</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Godden</last-name>
<first-name>Mark C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mogadore</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kraft</last-name>
<first-name>David L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Massillon</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Maryamchik</last-name>
<first-name>Mikhail</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairlawn</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alexander</last-name>
<first-name>Kiplin C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Wadsworth</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Godden</last-name>
<first-name>Mark C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mogadore</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kraft</last-name>
<first-name>David L.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Massillon</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Marich</last-name>
<first-name>Eric</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Babcock &#x26; Wilcox Power Generation Group, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Barberton</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>McAllister</last-name>
<first-name>Steven B</first-name>
<department>3749</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Bargero</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A circulating fluidized bed (CFB) boiler includes a reaction chamber, where a bubbling fluidized bed (BFB) is contained within an enclosure within the lower portion of the reaction chamber and contains an in-bed heat exchanger (IBHX) that occupies part of the reaction chamber floor. A plurality of in-bed secondary air nozzles comprise a plurality of tubes which are grouped together and run across the width of the BFB between the BFB enclosure wall and an outside wall of the CFB. The nozzles are positioned to prevent the deflection of solids falling onto the BFB from the CFB by the secondary air jets while avoiding a complicated structure that would interfere with gas and/or solids movement in the furnace. The nozzles' exit openings are flush, or almost flush, with the BFB enclosure wall.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="202.35mm" wi="128.69mm" file="US08622029-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="226.31mm" wi="199.31mm" file="US08622029-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="211.84mm" wi="164.42mm" file="US08622029-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="259.33mm" wi="174.92mm" file="US08622029-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD AND BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to the field of circulating fluidized bed (CFB) reactors or boilers such as those used in industrial or electric power generation facilities and, in particular, to in-furnace secondary air nozzles designed to prevent deflection of solids falling onto a bubbling fluidized bed (BFB) from the CFB by secondary air jets.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. Pat. No. 6,532,905 to Belin et al. describes a CFB boiler with controllable in-bed heat exchanger (IBHX). The boiler comprises a CFB reaction chamber as well as a BFB heat exchanger located inside the reaction chamber. Heat transfer in the heat exchanger is controlled by means of controlling the rate of solids discharge from the lower part of the BFB into the reaction chamber. The overall heat transfer capacity of the IBHX depends on the solids downflow on the top of the bubbling bed in the IBHX from the CFB furnace. A higher downflow rate results in a higher heat transfer capacity. Secondary air is typically supplied to a CFB furnace via nozzles located at the front and rear furnace walls. The nozzles are located outside the furnace enclosure and their exit openings are flush with those walls. Because the IBHX is located adjacent to the wall(s) containing the nozzles, jets from the nozzles will deflect part of the solids downflow from the IBHX thus reducing its heat transfer capacity.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 5,836,257 to Belin et al. describes a CFB furnace with an integral secondary air plenum. Such a plenum allows placing secondary air nozzles inside the furnace thus preventing interference of their jets with the solids downflow to the IBHX. However, the supporting structure and/or air supply means of the plenum may interfere with the gas and/or solids movement in the furnace, and accommodating nozzles of the size sufficient to allow adequate jet penetration into a large CFB requires plenum which is larger than desirable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention prevents deflection of the solids falling onto the BFB from the CFB by secondary air jets while avoiding a complicated structure that would interfere with the gas and/or solids movement in the furnace.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, one aspect of the present invention is drawn to a circulating fluidized bed (CFB) boiler comprising: a CFB reaction chamber having side walls and a grid defining a floor at a lower end of the CFB reaction chamber for providing fluidizing gas into the CFB reaction chamber; a bubbling fluidized bed (BFB) located within a lower portion of the CFB reaction chamber and being bound by outer wall(s) of the CFB reaction chamber, the floor of the CFB reaction chamber and enclosure wall(s) formed by cooled tubes that extend upward from the floor of the CFB to the height of the BFB; at least one controllable in-bed heat exchanger (IBHX), the IBHX comprising a heating surface and occupying part of the CFB reaction chamber floor and being surrounded by the enclosure walls of the BFB; and at least one in-furnace secondary air nozzle formed by the cooled tubes of the BFB enclosure wall that are formed into at least one group that extends from the top of the BFB enclosure wall across the width of the BFB until reaching the outer wall of the CFB.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The tubes forming the at least one in-furnace secondary air nozzle may become part of the outer wall when they reach the outer wall of the CFB. Additionally, the exit opening of the least one in-furnace secondary air nozzle is flush, or almost flush, with the enclosure wall of the BFB.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The various features of novelty which characterize the invention are pointed out with particularity in the claims annexed to and forming part of this disclosure. For a better understanding of the invention, its operating advantages and specific benefits attained by its uses, reference is made to the accompanying drawings and descriptive matter in which exemplary embodiments of the invention are illustrated.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional side elevational view of a CFB boiler according to the invention illustrating the secondary air nozzles;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional plan view of the CFB boiler of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, viewed in the direction of arrows <b>2</b>-<b>2</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic perspective view of the BFB enclosure, where tubes forming the in-furnace secondary air nozzles are represented as single lines;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional side elevational view of a CFB boiler according to another embodiment of the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional plan view of the CFB boiler of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, viewed in the direction of arrows <b>5</b>-<b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The present invention relates generally to the field of circulating fluidized bed (CFB) reactors or boilers such as those used in industrial or electric power generation facilities and, in particular, to in-furnace secondary air nozzles designed to prevent the deflection of solids falling into the BFB from the CFB by secondary air jets.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As used herein, the term CFB boiler will be used to refer to CFB reactors or combustors wherein a combustion process takes place. While the present invention is directed particularly to boilers or steam generators which employ CFB combustors as the means by which the heat is produced, it is understood that the present invention can readily be employed in a different kind of CFB reactor. For example, the invention could be applied in a reactor that is employed for chemical reactions other than a combustion process, or where a gas/solids mixture from a combustion process occurring elsewhere is provided to the reactor for further processing.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring now to the drawings, wherein like reference numerals designate the same or functionally similar elements throughout the several drawings and to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in particular, a sectional side elevational view of a CFB furnace <b>1</b> is shown comprising walls <b>2</b> and an IBHX <b>3</b> immersed in a BFB <b>4</b>. The CFB is predominantly comprised of solids made up of the ash from the combustion of the fuel <b>5</b>, sulfated sorbent <b>6</b> and, in some cases, external inert material <b>7</b> fed through at least one of the walls <b>2</b> and fluidized by the primary air <b>8</b> supplied through a distribution grid <b>9</b>. Some solids are entrained by gases resulting from the fuel combustion and move upward <b>15</b> eventually reaching a particle separator <b>16</b> at the furnace exit. While some of the solids <b>17</b> pass the separator, the bulk of them 18 are captured and recycled back to the furnace. Those solids along with others <b>19</b>, falling out of the upflow solids stream <b>15</b>, feed the BFB <b>4</b> that is being fluidized by the fluidizing medium <b>25</b> fed through a distribution grid <b>26</b>. Means for removing solids from CFB and BFB (<b>27</b> and <b>28</b> respectively) are provided in the pertinent areas of the furnace floor.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The BFB is separated from the CFB by an enclosure <b>30</b>. Rate of solids recycle <b>35</b> back to the CFB through a valve <b>40</b> is controlled by controlling streams of fluidizing medium <b>45</b> and <b>46</b>. The enclosure is made of tubes <b>50</b> that are typically cooled by water or steam. The tubes are usually protected from the erosion and/or corrosion by a protective layer, commonly formed by a refractory held by studs welded to the tubes. The tubes forming the enclosure extend upward to the elevation allowing the required BFB <b>4</b> height within the CFB furnace <b>1</b>. Above the required height, the tubes <b>50</b> group into forming secondary air nozzles <b>55</b>. Air <b>60</b> fed to these nozzles is injected into the CFB beyond the BFB <b>4</b>, thus its jets <b>65</b> do not deflect streams of solids <b>18</b> and <b>19</b> from falling onto the BFB <b>4</b>. Grouping the tubes <b>50</b> allows forming the openings <b>70</b> through which the solids streams <b>18</b> and <b>19</b> fall onto the BFB <b>4</b>. After reaching the wall <b>2</b><i>b</i>, the tubes <b>50</b> can become part of this wall. Secondary air nozzles <b>75</b> on the opposite wall <b>2</b><i>d </i>are located externally to the CFB furnace <b>1</b>. Since no IBHX is placed below the nozzles <b>75</b>, their jets <b>80</b> do not cause any undesired effect.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates one possible construction of the in-furnace secondary air nozzles <b>55</b> formed by tubes <b>50</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the tubes <b>50</b> forming the in-furnace secondary air nozzles <b>55</b> are schematically represented as single lines.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In an alternative embodiment, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, BFB <b>4</b> with immersed IBHX <b>3</b> is located on both of opposite furnace walls <b>2</b><i>b </i>and <b>2</b><i>d</i>. Tubes <b>50</b> of enclosure <b>30</b> on both sides of the furnace group to form secondary air nozzles <b>55</b>. In order to feed fuel, limestone and other solids streams directly into the CFB, the BFB on at least one furnace wall (the <b>2</b><i>d </i>wall in this embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>) is broken into several compartments <b>80</b>. Each compartment <b>80</b> is formed by a furnace wall <b>2</b><i>d</i>, enclosure <b>30</b> and two side walls <b>85</b> (or one side wall <b>85</b> and a furnace wall <b>2</b><i>a </i>or <b>2</b><i>c</i>). The compartments are separated from each other by gaps <b>90</b> where the fuel, limestone, etc. is fed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">While specific embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described in detail to illustrate the application and principles of the invention, it will be understood that it is not intended that the present invention be limited thereto and that the invention may be embodied otherwise without departing from such principles. In some embodiments of the invention, certain features of the invention may sometimes be used to advantage without a corresponding use of the other features. Accordingly, all such changes and embodiments properly fall within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circulating fluidized bed (CFB) boiler comprising:
<claim-text>a CFB reaction chamber having side walls and a grid defining a floor at a lower end of the CFB reaction chamber for providing fluidizing gas into the CFB reaction chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bubbling fluidized bed (BFB) located within a lower portion of the CFB reaction chamber and being bound by one or more of the side walls of the CFB reaction chamber, the floor of the CFB reaction chamber, and an enclosure wall formed by cooled tubes that extend upward from the floor of the CFB to a height of the BFB; at least one controllable in-bed heat exchanger (IBHX) immersed in the BFB, the IBHX comprising a heating surface and occupying part of the CFB reaction chamber floor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one in-furnace secondary air conduit and nozzle defined by a plurality of the cooled tubes of the BFB enclosure wall, wherein the cooled tubes further extend from a top of the BFB enclosure wall across the width of the BFB to one of the side walls of the CFB reaction chamber, and wherein the plurality of the cooled tubes forms openings through which solids can fall into the BFB.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the tubes forming the at least one in-furnace secondary air nozzle reach the one side wall of the CFB, the tubes become part of the one side wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exit opening of the least one in-furnace secondary air nozzle is flush, or almost flush, with the enclosure wall of the BFB.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tubes comprising the BFB enclosure wall are covered with a protective layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the protective layer is formed by a refractory held by studs welded to the tubes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tubes forming the in-furnace secondary air nozzles are covered with a protective layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The CFB boiler according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the protective layer is formed by a refractory held by studs welded to the tubes.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
