<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624706-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624706</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13198716</doc-number>
<date>20110805</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2011 1 0076126</doc-number>
<date>20110329</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>235</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>340  61</main-classification>
<further-classification>340635</further-classification>
<further-classification>340432</further-classification>
<further-classification>323268</further-classification>
<further-classification>315293</further-classification>
<further-classification>330 10</further-classification>
<further-classification>362466</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Control circuit for indicator light</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5350997</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ghotbi et al.</name>
<date>19940900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323268</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5828138</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McIver et al.</name>
<date>19981000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>307 101</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0083011</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Buhr et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>362466</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0046520</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Liu et al.</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>341155</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0111500</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hoover</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>315293</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0143541</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zhang</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>340635</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0284508</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Walker et al.</name>
<date>20081100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>330 10</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0187517</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Roths</name>
<date>20110800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>340432</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>340635</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>340432</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>340  61</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>323268</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>315293</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>330 10</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362466</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>1</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120249299</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121004</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xu</last-name>
<first-name>Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Deng</last-name>
<first-name>Yong-Qian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Xu</last-name>
<first-name>Feng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Deng</last-name>
<first-name>Yong-Qian</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hong Fu Jin Precision Industry (ShenZhen) Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Benjamin C</first-name>
<department>2684</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Foxx</last-name>
<first-name>Chico A</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A control circuit for an indicator light includes a power source, a switch unit, a ground resistor, and a first adjusting unit. The power source supplies a voltage. The switch unit is connected between the power source and the indicator light and turns on or turns off the indicator light. The ground resistor is connected between the power source and the ground via the indicator light and the switch unit. The first adjusting unit includes a first adjusting resistor and a first control switch. The adjusting resistor is connected between the indicator light and the ground via the first control switch. The first control switch is capable of connecting the first adjusting resistor with the ground resistor in parallel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="159.34mm" wi="171.87mm" file="US08624706-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="160.61mm" wi="170.86mm" file="US08624706-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to control circuits, and particularly, to a control circuit for an indicator light.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Electronic products, such as computers, usually include indicator lights that indicate the working status of the electronic products or the components of the electronic products, such as a working state of a network or a power supply of the electronic products. However, typical indicator lights will remain at a preset brightness or a preset state when the electronic products or the components of the electronic products remain in a certain state. For example, when the electrical product is powered on and works properly, the indicator lights will remain at the preset brightness or they will flash. However, sometimes, the users may wish to turn off or turn down the indicator light if the electronic product works properly. However, at this time, this cannot be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, it is desirable to overcome the limitations described above.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The FIGURE is a circuit diagram of a control circuit for an indicator light, according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Exemplary embodiments of the disclosure will be described in detail, with reference to the accompanying drawing.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Referring to the drawing, a control circuit <b>100</b> for controlling brightness of an indicator light <b>200</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment is shown. The control circuit <b>100</b> includes a switch unit <b>10</b>, a first adjusting unit <b>30</b>, a second adjusting unit <b>40</b>, and a status control unit <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The indicator light <b>200</b> includes a first electrode <b>201</b> and a second electrode <b>202</b>. The indicator light <b>200</b> is turned on when a voltage is applied to the first electrode <b>201</b> and the second electrode <b>202</b>. The first electrode <b>201</b> is connected to a power source Vs via the switch unit <b>10</b>. The second electrode <b>202</b> is grounded via a ground resistor <b>20</b>. In one embodiment, the indicator light <b>200</b> is a light emit diode (LED). The first electrode <b>201</b> is the positive terminal of the LED. The second electrode <b>202</b> is the negative terminal of the LED. In one exemplary embodiment, resistance of the resistor <b>20</b> is about 168 ohms, and the power source Vs supplies an about 3.3V direct current (DC) voltage s to the indicator light <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The switch unit <b>10</b> includes a first terminal <b>101</b>, a second terminal <b>102</b>, and a control terminal <b>103</b>. The first terminal <b>101</b> electrically connects to the second terminal <b>102</b> when the control terminal <b>103</b> receives a low voltage level (for example, a low voltage level of logic 0) or disconnects from the second terminal <b>102</b> when the control terminal <b>103</b> receives a high voltage level (for example, a high voltage level of logic 1). In one embodiment, the switch unit <b>10</b> is a p-channel MOSFET and includes a source connection, a drain connection, and a gate connection which respectively serves as the first terminal <b>101</b>, the second terminal <b>102</b> and the control terminal <b>103</b>. The first terminal <b>101</b> is connected to the power source Vs. The second terminal <b>102</b> is connected to the first electrode <b>201</b>. The control terminal <b>103</b> is connected to the power source Vs via a first resistor <b>104</b>. In one embodiment, the resistance of the first resistor <b>104</b> is about 470 kilo ohms.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The first adjusting unit <b>30</b> includes a first adjusting resistor <b>301</b>, a second resistor <b>302</b>, a third resistor <b>303</b>, a first operation switch K<b>1</b>, a first control switch <b>304</b> and a control power source Vc. The first control switch <b>304</b> includes a first connection <b>3041</b>, a second connection <b>3042</b>, and a third connection <b>3043</b>. The third connection <b>3043</b> connects or disconnects the first connection <b>3041</b> and the second connection <b>3042</b>. In one embodiment, the first control switch <b>304</b> is an npn type BJT Q<b>1</b>. The collector, the emitter and the base of the BJT Q<b>1</b> respectively serves as the first connection <b>3041</b>, the second connection <b>3042</b> and the third connection <b>3043</b>. The first connection <b>3041</b> is connected to the second electrode <b>202</b> via the first adjusting resistor <b>301</b>. The second connection <b>3042</b> is grounded. One end of the second resistor <b>302</b> is connected to the third connection <b>3043</b>, the other end is connected to the operation switch K<b>1</b>. The first operation switch K<b>1</b> is connected between the control power source Vc and the second resistor <b>302</b>. The third resistor <b>303</b> is connected between the third connection <b>3043</b> and the ground.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The second adjusting unit <b>40</b> is similar to and connected in parallel to the first adjusting unit <b>30</b>. The second brightness adjusting unit <b>40</b> includes a second adjusting resistor <b>401</b>, a fourth resistor <b>402</b>, a fifth resistor <b>403</b>, a second operation switch K<b>2</b>, a second control switch <b>404</b> and the control power source Vc. The second control switch <b>404</b> includes a fourth connection <b>4041</b>, a fifth connection <b>4042</b> and a sixth connection <b>4043</b>. In one embodiment, the second control switch <b>404</b> is also an npn type BJT Q<b>2</b>. The collector, the emitter and the base of the BJT Q<b>2</b> respectively serves as the fourth connection <b>4041</b>, the fifth connection <b>4042</b> and the sixth connection <b>4043</b>. The fourth connection <b>4041</b> is connected to the second electrode <b>202</b> via the second adjusting resistor <b>401</b>. The fifth connection <b>4042</b> is grounded. One end of the fourth resistor <b>402</b> is connected to the sixth connection <b>4043</b>, the other end is connected to the second operation switch K<b>2</b>. The second operation switch K<b>2</b> is connected between the control power source Vc and the fourth resistor <b>402</b>. The fifth resistor <b>403</b> is connected between the sixth connection <b>4043</b> and the ground. In one embodiment, the resistances of the first adjusting resistor <b>301</b> and the second adjusting resistor <b>401</b> are both about 168 ohms. The resistances of the second resistor <b>302</b>, the third resistor <b>303</b>, the fourth resistor <b>402</b>, and the fifth resistor <b>403</b> are all about 4.7 kilo ohms.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The state control unit <b>50</b> includes a pulse width modulation (PWM) controller <b>501</b>, a state converting switch K<b>3</b>. The PWM controller <b>501</b> outputs a square-wave pulse voltage having an adjustable duty ratio. In one embodiment, the PWM controller <b>501</b> outputs square-wave pulse voltage having an amplitude of about 3.3 volts. An output terminal of the PWM controller <b>501</b> is connected to the control terminal <b>103</b> via the state switch K<b>1</b> and a sixth resistor <b>502</b>. In one embodiment, the value of the sixth resistor <b>502</b> is about 10 thousands ohms. In alternative embodiments, the sixth resistor <b>502</b> can be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In use, when the state converting switch K<b>3</b> is turned off, the control terminal <b>103</b> receives a low voltage level (a low voltage level of logic 0), the first terminal <b>101</b> receives a high voltage level (a high voltage level of logic 1). The switch unit <b>10</b> is turned on. The control circuit <b>100</b> may control the indicator light <b>200</b> in one of the following three states according to user operations. In detail, when the first operation switch K<b>1</b> and the second operation switch K<b>2</b> are both turned off, the indicator light <b>200</b> is serially connected with the ground resistor <b>20</b>. A first electric current I<sub>1 </sub>passing through the indicator light <b>200</b> is proportional to the voltage of the power source Vs and inversely proportional to the resistance of the ground resistor <b>20</b>, as the resistance of the indicator light <b>200</b> is very small and can be ignored for simplicity. In this situation, the indicator light <b>200</b> has a first brightness. If only one of the first operation switch K<b>1</b> or the second operation switch K<b>2</b> is turned on, for example, the first operation switch K<b>1</b> is turned on, the base of the BJT Q<b>1</b> receives a high voltage level (a low voltage level of logic 1) and thus the BJT Q<b>1</b> is turned on while the BJT Q<b>2</b> is turned off. The first adjusting resistor <b>301</b> is connected with the ground resistor <b>20</b> in parallel. A second electric current I<sub>2 </sub>passing through the indicator light <b>200</b> is proportional to the voltage of the power source Vs and inversely proportional to the effective resistance of the ground resistor <b>20</b> and the first adjusting resistor <b>301</b>. In this situation, the indicator light <b>200</b> is adjusted to a second brightness which is brighter than the first brightness as the second current I<sub>2 </sub>is greater than the first current I<sub>1</sub>. When the first operation switch K<b>1</b> and the second operation switch K<b>2</b> are both turned on, both the BJT Q<b>1</b> and the BJT Q<b>2</b> are turned on. The first adjusting resistor <b>301</b>, the second adjusting resistor <b>401</b>, and the ground resistor <b>20</b> are connected in parallel. A third electric current I<sub>3 </sub>passing through the indicator light <b>200</b> is proportional to the voltage of the power source Vs and inversely proportional to the effective resistance of the ground resistor <b>20</b>, the first adjusting resistor <b>301</b>, and the second adjusting resistor <b>401</b>. In this case, the indicator light <b>200</b> lights at a third brightness which is brighter than the second brightness as the third current I<sub>3 </sub>is greater than the second current I<sub>2</sub>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">As such, provided that the state operation switch K<b>3</b> is turned off, the brightness of the indicator light <b>200</b> can be adjusted to the first brightness, the second brightness, or the third brightness through adjusting the first adjusting unit <b>30</b> and the second unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">However, if the state operation switch K<b>3</b> is turned on, the PWM outputs a square-wave pulse voltage. When the duty cycle of the square-wave is adjusted to 100%, the control terminal <b>103</b> received a high voltage level (a high voltage level of logic 1). The switch unit <b>10</b> is turned off. The indicator light <b>200</b> is turned off accordingly. When duty ratio of the square-wave is adjusted to below 100%. The indicator light <b>200</b> is driven to flash.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The control circuit <b>100</b> can only include the first adjusting unit <b>30</b> or can include more adjusting units as well as the first adjusting unit <b>30</b> and the second adjusting unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It will be understood that particular exemplary embodiments are shown and described by way of illustration only. The principles and the features of the present disclosure may be employed in various and numerous exemplary embodiments thereof without departing from the scope of the disclosure as claimed. The above-described exemplary embodiments illustrate the scope of the disclosure but do not restrict the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A control circuit for controlling an indicator light, comprising:
<claim-text>a power source supplying a voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch unit connected between the power source and the indicator light and configured for turning on or turning off the indicator light;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground resistor connected between the power source and the ground via the indicator light and the switch unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first adjusting unit connected in parallel with ground resistor, the first adjusting unit comprising a first adjusting resistor and a first control switch, the adjusting resistor connected between the indicator light and the ground via the first control switch, the first control switch being capable of connecting the first adjusting resistor with the ground resistor in parallel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the switch unit comprises a first terminal, a second terminal, and a control terminal, the first terminal electrically connects to the second terminal when the control terminal receives a low voltage level and disconnects from the second terminal when the control terminal receives a high voltage level, the first terminal is connected to the power source, the second terminal is connected to the indicator light, the control terminal is connected to the power source via a first resistor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control circuit further comprises a PWM controller connecting to the control terminal for outputting square-wave pulse voltage to the control terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the switch unit is a p-channel MOSFET comprises a source connection, a drain connection and a gate connection which respectively serves as the first terminal, the second terminal and the control terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the indicator light comprises a first electrode and a second electrode, the first electrode is connected to the power source via the switch unit, the second electrode is grounded via the ground resistor, the indicator light is an LED, the first electrode is the positive terminal of the LED, the second electrode is the negative terminal of the LED.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein first adjusting unit further comprise a second resistor, a third resistor, a first operation switch, and a control power source, the first control switch comprises a first connection, a second connection and a third connection, the third connection connects or disconnects the first connection and the second connection, the first connection is connected to the second electrode via the first adjusting resistor, the second connection is grounded, one end of the second resistor is connected to the third connection, the other end of the second resistor is connected to the first operation switch, the first operation switch is connected between the control power source and the second resistor, the third resistor is connected between the third connection and the ground.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the first control switch is an npn type BJT, the collector, the emitter and the base of the BJT are respectively serves as the first connection, the second connection and the third connection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control circuit further comprises a second adjusting unit, the second adjusting unit comprises a second adjusting resistor capable of being connected in parallel with the first adjusting unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The control circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the resistance of the second adjusting resistor is equal to that of the first resistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
