<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623195-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623195</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13125123</doc-number>
<date>20090917</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>08018734</doc-number>
<date>20081027</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>84</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205628</main-classification>
<further-classification>205637</further-classification>
<further-classification>204254</further-classification>
<further-classification>204256</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">High pressure electrolyser</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4758322</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sioli</name>
<date>19880700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5783051</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hirai et al.</name>
<date>19980700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6153083</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hofmann et al.</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0157354</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Harada</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205637</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>4418999</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19951200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102005011316</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0212240</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19870300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006131935</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006307262</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205628-639</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204253-256</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110210012</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110901</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sioli</last-name>
<first-name>Giancarlo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cernobbio</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IT</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sioli</last-name>
<first-name>Giancarlo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cernobbio</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Akerman LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Casale Chemicals SA</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Phasge</last-name>
<first-name>Arun S</first-name>
<department>1756</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2009/062066</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090917</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110420</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/049214</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100506</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electrolyser (<b>100</b>) comprising an electrolysis cell stack (<b>101</b>) inside a pressure vessel (<b>115</b>), wherein the first terminal end plate (<b>107</b><i>a</i>) of the cell stack is integral with one a closed ends of the pressure vessel, thus forming a stationary head (<b>107</b>) of the cell stack equipped with the fluid and electric connections, and the second terminal end plate (<b>108</b><i>a</i>) of the cell stack is inside the vessel and is free to move in a longitudinal direction in response to thermal expansion or contraction, thus forming a floating head (<b>108</b>) of the stack. The pressure vessel (<b>115</b>) is preferably pressurized using a gaseous product obtained in the process of electrolysis.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="147.66mm" wi="220.47mm" file="US08623195-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="168.23mm" wi="220.39mm" file="US08623195-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="154.60mm" wi="231.56mm" file="US08623195-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.03mm" wi="253.32mm" file="US08623195-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a national phase of PCT/EP2009/062066, filed Sep. 17, 2009, and claims priority to EP 08018734.7, filed Oct. 27, 2008, the entire contents of both of which are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to the field of electrolysers, especially for the electrolysis of water. More in detail, the invention relates to an electrolyser comprising a cell stack inside a pressure vessel, for operation under high-pressure.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">PRIOR ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Electrolysis is a well-known process for separating chemically bonded elements. The process can be operated under pressure when it is desired to obtain the products of the electrolysis under the same pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">One of the most common applications of the electrolysis is the production of hydrogen (H<sub>2</sub>) via electrolysis of water and, in the rest of this specification, reference will be made to this preferred use of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generation of hydrogen by electrolysis of water is well known at pressures up to around 30 bar, to serve chemical processes. In recent years, however, the need of producing hydrogen at much higher pressure has appeared.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Hydrogen is a best candidate for energy storage and transportation, especially for distributed power generation from renewable energy sources and for powering hydrogen-fueled or fuel-cell vehicles. The storage of hydrogen for use as a fuel or energy carrier, however, requires a very high pressure, for example 200 bar or more. Currently, suitable pressures for fuel hydrogen storage are considered 350 bar (5000 psi) or 700 bar (10.000 psi). The compression of hydrogen to these very high pressures requires expensive multi-stage compressors and consumes a lot of energy. Hence, there is a strong need of an electrolysis capable of directly producing the hydrogen at the above pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">U.S. Pat. No. 4,758,322 discloses a well-known structure of an electrolyser, the so-called filter-press configuration. A number of bipolar cells are stacked in series, and set together between two end plates, interconnected by tie rods. Each one of the bipolar cells comprises an anodic compartment, and a cathode compartment, separated by a diaphragm or a membrane. In turn, each cell is separated from the next one by a conductive wall, the so-called bipolar plate, having opposite polarity on the two faces. The stack of cells is set together by the end plates forming the anode (+) and the cathode (&#x2212;) terminal connections of the stack. The end plates are forced each other by the tie rods which are electrically insulated to avoid a short circuiting of the cells. A liquid electrolyte is introduced in the cells, and the produced gases are collected therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">This electrolyser has a limited capability to operate under internal pressure, that is with the electrolyte and produced gases under pressure. The cell frames and the end plates of the cell stack, in fact, must withstand the whole difference of pressure (delta-p) between the inside and the outside, usually at atmospheric pressure. Over a certain delta-p, the cell frames are not able to endure the mechanical stresses, nor their gaskets to prevent leakage of the electrolyte or gases and, in practice, this electrolyser is limited to an internal pressure of a few tens of bar.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">To overcome this problem, a different kind of pressurized electrolysers has been proposed. The basic idea is to balance the internal pressure of the cell stack, operating the same cell stack inside a pressurized vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">U.S. Pat. No. 6,153,083 discloses an electrolyser for the electrolysis of water under pressure, where the stack of bipolar cells, responding to the already mentioned filter-press configuration, is encapsulated in a pressure vessel. The two end electrodes of the stack are connected to the electricity source by two leading-in cables running through the pressure vessel, the interior of the pressure vessel being filled with pressurized water surrounding the cell stack. Faults of this design, however, because not described in detail, although very difficult to be solved in the practice, are the cables passage through the pressurized vessel, and devices for feeding the alkaline electrolyte inside the cell stack, as well for collecting the hydrogen and oxygen gases delivered by the stack. In practice, there is the need to provide inputs/outputs through the pressurized vessel, where tightness is crucial and any leakage may compromise the operation of the electrolyser. A pressure drop in the vessel, in particular, would cause, in most cases, irreparable damage to the electrolyser inside. Moreover, this design has been used for pressures of up to 30 bar, insufficient for hydrogen storage as above discussed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A different encapsulation technique is disclosed in DE 44 18 999. The cell block is surrounded by a pressure tube, closed at the two ends by two respective flanges, which are also the end covers of the cell block, and therefore are provided with the necessary connections for leading the fluids in and out the electrolysis cells. The space inside the pressure tube and outside the cell block is put under hydraulic pressure by the electrolyte feed to the electrolysis cells. In order to compensate for the differential expansion between the cell block and the vessel, forced to have the same length, the cell frames (in non-conductive material) are alternated with elastomeric flat gaskets. This design has a weak point in the tightness of said gaskets and, moreover, the use of the conductive electrolyte as pressurizing fluid increases the risk of short circuit in case of cell leakage.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Another problem of the prior art is the different thermal expansion of the vessel or pressure tube, compared to thermal expansion of the cell stack inside, which may be the cause of mechanical stress with the risk of leakage and release of electrolyte. In a water-pressurized system, even a small leakage of electrolyte is fatal because the water becomes conductive with occurrence of electric shunts and parasitic currents, and related power losses, or even short circuits and serious damage of the cell stack.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Hence, the drawbacks of the prior art can be summarized as follows. Some of the known pressurized electrolysers can operate at pressure levels well below the need for a reasonable reduction of the hydrogen specific volume to the end of the gas bulk storage; fluid and electrical connections through the pressure vessel, in particular, are critical for the tightness of the system; the generalised use of water as a pressurizing medium leaves the risk of parasitic currents or dangerous short-circuits in case of electrolyte leakage; the alternative use of the electrolyte to pressurize the vessel is even more dangerous for the reasons discussed above. These drawbacks, discussed in relation to the electrolysis of water, can also be generalized to other applications.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The problem underlying the invention is to provide a structure of a pressurized cell-stack electrolyser adapted to overcome the above limitations, and in particular to safely and reliably generate hydrogen from water, at the high pressure required by the use of hydrogen as a fuel or energy carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">This problem is solved with an electrolyser comprising:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0016">a pressure vessel having a shell and opposite closed ends;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0017">an electrolysis cell stack inside said pressure vessel, comprising a plurality of bipolar electrolysis cells stacked between a first and a second terminal end plates, the cell stack being arranged to operate under internal pressure;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0018">fluid connections for feeding an electrolyte to the cell stack and for collecting the product(s) of the electrolysis from the cell stack, and electric connections comprising at least an anode and a cathode connection,
<br/>
the electrolyser being characterized in that:
</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0019">the first terminal end plate of the cell stack is integral with one of said closed ends of the pressure vessel, thus forming a stationary head of the cell stack;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0020">said stationary head is equipped with said fluid connections and electric anode and cathode connections with the cell stack;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0021">the second terminal end plate of the cell stack is inside the vessel and is free to move in a longitudinal direction relative to the first terminal end plate and to the vessel, in response to thermal expansion or contraction, thus forming a floating head of the cell stack</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0022">In a preferred embodiment of the invention, said closed ends are a cover on one side, and a flat end cover or dead flange, which also constitutes the first terminal end plate of the cell stack, on the other side.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0023">According to preferred features, said anode and cathode electric connections comprise: at least a first electric connector, preferably in the form of a tie-rod, passing through the first terminal end plate, insulated from said plate and electrically connected to the first cell of the stack, namely the cell closer to the stationary head; at least a second electric connector associated and electrically connected to the first terminal end plate, the first terminal end plate being electrically connected with the second terminal end plate. For example, the first electric connector is positive, carrying the anodic current to the first cell, and said second electric connector is the negative, thus having the duty of cathode termination for the last cell of the stack.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0024">In a preferred realization, the terminal end plates of the cell stack are set together by tie rods, providing mechanical and electrical connection between the two plates.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0025">A preferred embodiment of the invention provides that the electrolyser is fully polarized at the same potential of the floating head, and that only one of the electric connections (anode/cathode) has to be taken from the inside of the electrolyser, through the shell or any cover of the vessel. For example, tie rods constituting the negative electric connection are fixed to the closed end forming the stationary head, which is electrically and mechanically connected by tie-rods to the internal floating head and then to the terminal end plate of the cell stack; an insulated tic rod passes through the floating head, providing the positive electric connection to the first end plate of the stack.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0026">According to another aspect of the invention, the vessel is kept under pressure with a gas, rather than a liquid as in the prior art. Hence, an aspect of the invention is an electrolyser comprising a pressure vessel and an electrolysis cell stack inside said pressure vessel, the cell stack comprising a plurality of bipolar electrolysis cells stacked between a first and a second terminal end plates, characterized in that the vessel is pressurized by a gas.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0027">The gas pressurising the vessel can take part or not into the electrolysis process. More specifically, the gas pressurising the vessel is for example an inert gas, i.e. having an inert nature in relation to the electrolysis process or, as an alternative, a gas produced under pressure in the electrolysis process itself. Preferably, the gas is taken from the electrolysis process, which is carried out in the cell stack at a pressure which can be higher than the pressure level in the vessel, so that no intermediate compression is required for the use of said gas to pressurize the vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0028">An equipment for electrolysis, according to the invention, comprises: an electrolyser with a cell stack inside a pressure vessel, the cell stack being adapted to supply at least a gas product under pressure; at least a vessels receiving said gas product and adapted to separate the gas product from entrained electrolyte; a flow line feeding at least a portion of said gas product as a pressurizing medium into said pressure vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0029">Preferably, in a gas-pressurized electrolyser according to the invention, the cell stack has the above arrangement with a stationary head and a floating head, namely: the first terminal end plate of the cell stack is integral with one of the end covers of the pressure vessel, thus forming the stationary head, equipped with suitable fluid connections for feeding the electrolyte to the cell stack, and for collecting the product(s) of the electrolysis, and also equipped with anode and cathode electric connections with the cell stack; the second terminal end plate is movable in a longitudinal direction relative to the first terminal end and the vessel, in response to thermal expansion and contraction, thus constituting the floating head.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0030">Referring now to the preferred application to the electrolysis of water, nitrogen or any other inert gas in relation to the electrolysis of water can be used as a pressurizing medium in a gas-pressurized electrolyser according to the invention; in a second option, at least a portion of the hydrogen or a portion of the oxygen delivered under pressure by the cell stack is used to pressurize the vessel. The internal pressure of the cell stack in operation is preferably at least 30 bar, more preferably greater than 100 bar and even more preferably in the range 100 to 700 bar.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0031">An equipment for the electrolysis of water, according to a preferred embodiment of the invention, comprises: an electrolyser comprising a cell stack inside a pressure vessel, the cell stack being adapted to furnish hydrogen and oxygen under pressure; at least a separation vessel receiving the hydrogen and another separation vessel receiving the oxygen produced in the electrolyser, said vessels being adapted to separate the hydrogen and oxygen, respectively, from entrained electrolyte; a flow line feeding at least a portion of said hydrogen or a portion of said oxygen as a pressurizing medium into said pressure vessel, from the respective vessel. The electrolyser of said equipment for electrolysis of water has preferably the above discussed arrangement with a stationary head and a floating head.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0032">The pressure can be controlled e.g. with a differential pressure controller, sensitive to the delta-p between the two vessels, or keeping constant the level of the entrained electrolyte in the respective vessel, from which the pressurizing medium (hydrogen or oxygen) is taken.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0033">In all the above embodiments of the invention, the fluid-tightness of the cell stack is preferably obtained in accordance with the disclosure of EP 0212240. Each bipolar cell has two elements, called separating element and bipolar element, in form of frames internally carrying the diaphragm or membrane and, respectively, the bipolar plate. The frames are preferably of circular shape to withstand to the internal pressure, and are moulded in reinforced plastics, with the result to be electrically non-conductive. Their tightness is simply obtained by O-ring gaskets, requiring a very low effort to the tie rods and related end covers completing the filter-press configuration of the stack. Liquid electrolyte and product gases are distributed and collected from the cells by channels moulded inside the frames, ending on one of the terminal, metal plates.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0034">Frames are relatively thin, in the range of few millimeters, as well as the cathode and anode chamber of each cell, which are occupied by very thin and flexible electrodes. The moulding technique allows to producing large series of frames in a short time. Moreover, frames of different size may be easily moulded to produce cells of different capacity. The high current density and the limited size of the cells allow a very compact construction, with the possibility of assembling totally the electrolysis plant before shipment.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0035">The invention has many advantages that allow to safely and reliably carry out the process of electrolysis at a pressure much greater than in the prior art. The invention allows to make available the gas product at a pressure well above the 30 bar which are substantially the limit of the prior art; in particular, the invention is suitable for production of H<sub>2 </sub>from electrolysis of water, directly at a pressure of hundreds of bar, as required for hydrogen-fueled vehicles. As the hydrogen is directly available from the electrolysis at the pressure of use, the costs related to compression are saved, or greatly reduced, and the use of hydrogen as fuel or energy carrier is made more attractive.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0036">The cell stack with stationary head and floating head solves the problems of differential thermal elongation between the stack and the containing vessel, as the floating head is not firmly associated with the shell of the vessel, but on the contrary is free to move under the thermal expansion. Moreover, thanks to the invention the electric connections are available at the stationary head, being no longer necessary to provide the electrical connections through the shell or the cover of the vessel, which are critical points for the tightness of the system. A further advantage of the invention, as it will be shown, is the guarantee of a safe grounding of the whole electrolyser, to prevent accidents to the operating people.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0037">Use of a gaseous pressurizing medium maintains a better electrical insulation and reduces the risk of power losses or short circuit caused by electrolyte leakage. In prior-art, water-pressurized systems, a small loss of electrolyte due to leakage from the stack, can make conductive the water pressurising the vessel, favouring parasitic currents involving the stack and the vessel. Much harmful consequences may be incurred when the hydraulic pressure is directly provided by the electrolyte, because the electrolyte solution is much more conductive than water.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0038">The use of a gas produced in the process itself, as a pressurizing medium, has the further advantage that no external compression unit is required. The gas delivered by the cell stack, for example hydrogen or oxygen in water electrolysis, can be sent to the vessel with no intermediate compression between the output of the cell stack and the inlet into the pressure vessel, or with a much less expensive compression, e.g. a single stage instead of multi-stage. Furthermore, when dealing with very high pressure electrolysers operating at 5000 psi or more, inert gases are not commercially available at such pressure levels, and it would be necessary to provide an additional and expensive gas compressing system.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0039">Another advantage is that from the start up of the electrolysis process at low pressure, up to the final operating pressure, the gas pressurisation of the electrolyser pressure vessel grows proportionally, following the building up of the electrolysis process pressure.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates schematically an electrolyser in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a detail of the anodic current feed of the electrolyser of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> show examples of flow diagram relating to the application of this invention to the high-pressure electrolysis of water.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0038" num="0043">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an electrolyser <b>100</b> is set up by enclosing a cell stack item <b>101</b> in a pressure vessel <b>115</b>, internally pressurised by a gas phase when in operation. The vessel is formed by a horizontal, cylindrical shell, with closed ends, one of which is a flanged cover, the second one a flanged cover, or an integral end, of flat or dished type. The preferred embodiment of the second end is a dished end, welded to the cylindrical shell. The material of construction of the vessel can be a metal, or a composite material, as for instance a fiber-reinforced manufacture.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0044">The cell stack <b>101</b> is formed by bipolar cells, each one comprising an anode <b>102</b> and a cathode <b>103</b>, separated by a diaphragm or a membrane <b>104</b>. In turn, each cell is separated from the next one by a bipolar plate <b>105</b>. Cells have frames <b>106</b> containing channels <b>113</b> for the distribution of the electrolyte, and further channels <b>114</b> for the collection of the electrolysis products.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0045">In accordance with the invention, a first terminal end plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>of the cell stack <b>101</b> is integral with an end plate cover of the pressure vessel, while the second end plate <b>108</b><i>a </i>of the cell stack <b>101</b> is movable inside the vessel, in a longitudinal direction relative to the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>and the shell of the vessel <b>115</b>, in response to thermal expansion and contraction. Hence, the end plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>forms a stationary head <b>107</b> of the cell stack <b>101</b>, while the opposite end plate <b>108</b><i>a </i>forms a floating head <b>108</b> of the same cell stack.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0046">The stationary head <b>107</b> is equipped with the fluid connections for feeding an electrolyte to the cell stack, and for collecting the product(s) of the electrolysis, and is also equipped with anode and cathode electric connections with the cell stack.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0047">Turning again to the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, all process connections <b>122</b> of the stack <b>101</b>, regarding gases and liquids, are grouped on the plate <b>107</b><i>a</i>, leaving the stack free of expanding inside the vessel <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0048">The anodic connection is given by a rod <b>120</b>, passing through the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>and electrically insulated with respect to said cover by a bush <b>119</b>, carrying the anodic current directly to the first anode <b>117</b> of the stack <b>101</b>. Said first anode <b>117</b> is electrically insulated from the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>by an insulating plate <b>118</b>. The rod <b>120</b> is provided with adequate gaskets, making it leak-tight with respect to the internal space under pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0049">The end plate <b>108</b><i>a </i>is electrically in contact with the end cathode <b>116</b> of the stack <b>101</b>, and is connected via tie rods <b>109</b> to the plate <b>107</b><i>a</i>. Hence, the plates <b>107</b><i>a </i>and <b>108</b><i>a </i>are equi-potential.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0050">The cathode terminal connection is also located directly on the plate <b>107</b><i>a</i>, in the form of a tie rod <b>121</b>. By grounding this connection, the whole electrolyser is grounded, besides the only anodic connection <b>120</b>, which can be easily protected from any contact with the operating personnel, thus making the design particularly safe.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0051">It should be noted that the vessel <b>115</b> is equi-potential with the cell stack plates <b>107</b><i>a </i>and <b>108</b><i>a</i>, due to the electrical connection given by tie rods <b>109</b>. Hence, the only insulated connection to be passed from inside to outside of the electrolyser is the rod <b>120</b>, in the example passing through the end cover of the vessel represented by the plate <b>107</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0052">A preferred embodiment of the anodic connection rod <b>120</b> is shown in further detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The tie rod <b>120</b> is welded to the first anode <b>117</b> of the stack, while at the opposite end it is threaded, and carries two washers <b>131</b> and two nuts <b>132</b>, devised to fix the anodic electric cable. The electrically insulating, tubular bush <b>119</b> avoids the contact between the rod <b>120</b>, under anodic polarisation, and the grounded plate <b>107</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0053">An insulating bush <b>125</b> and flat gaskets <b>126</b> separate the high-pressure space, acting on the outside diameter of said bush <b>125</b> and gaskets <b>126</b>, from the low-pressure space, surrounding the rod <b>120</b>. The two gaskets <b>126</b> are compressed between the bush <b>125</b> and the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>and, respectively, between the bush <b>125</b> and the anode <b>117</b>. In order to keep tight the gaskets <b>126</b>, a nut <b>130</b> draws the anode <b>117</b> against the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>by means of the tie rod <b>120</b>, cup springs <b>129</b>, located between two washers <b>128</b>, and an insulating bush <b>127</b>. The space between the plate <b>107</b><i>a </i>and the anode <b>117</b> is occupied by an insulating plate <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0054">The selection of the materials for the realisation of the electrically insulating bushes <b>125</b> and <b>127</b> requires a special care, because both must withstand high compressive forces and, mainly the item <b>125</b>, must by impermeable to the ambient humidity, avoiding to creating electric shunts between the items under anodic polarisation and the ground. A material usable for the item <b>125</b> is, for instance, a glass-mica composite, while for the item <b>127</b> a mica-paper laminate material may be adequate.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0055">Reverting to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a port <b>123</b> is provided on the stationary head <b>107</b> for the pressurizing of the space internal to the pressure vessel <b>115</b>, and external to the cell stack <b>101</b>. Alternatively, this connection may be located at any place on the shell <b>115</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0056">In a preferred embodiment of this invention, wherein the sealing each other of the cell frames of the stack are obtained by o-ring gaskets, as disclosed in EP 0212240, the pressure internal to the vessel <b>115</b> has to be proportioned to the operating pressure inside the stack <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0057">The pressurizing medium, according to an aspect of the invention, is preferably a gas. The pressurising gas may be for instance nitrogen, or argon, or carbon dioxide, all extraneous to the electrolysis process. A source of one of such inert gases, like a bottle, may be connected to the port <b>123</b>, by means of a tubular connection, provided with a pressure reducer or controller. In a second example the gas pressurising the electrolyser jacket may be a gas product delivered by the electrolysis process, such as hydrogen or oxygen in the case of water electrolysis.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an example of equipment for the electrolysis of water, comprising a gas-pressurized electrolyser <b>200</b> substantially realised as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0059">The electrolyser <b>200</b> comprises a cell stack <b>210</b> inside a pressure vessel <b>220</b>, and produces hydrogen and oxygen, which are delivered from the stationary head of the cell stack to the vessels V-<b>1</b> and V-<b>2</b>, respectively, by pipes <b>201</b> and <b>202</b>. Together with the gases some electrolyte is entrained and said vessels V-<b>1</b> and V-<b>2</b> have the duty of separating out the gases from the entrained liquid, which is returned to the electrolyser by pipes <b>203</b> and <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0060">Hydrogen exits the vessel V-<b>1</b> through the pipe <b>205</b>, whereon the pressure controller PC-<b>1</b> sets the hydrogen-side pressure inside the vessel by throttling the valve PCV-<b>1</b>, and afterwards hydrogen is delivered to its final use by a pipe <b>207</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0061">Oxygen exits the vessel V-<b>2</b> through the pipe <b>206</b>, to be delivered to its final use by the pipe <b>209</b>. Oxygen-side pressure inside the vessel V-<b>2</b> is controlled by a differential pressure controller PDC, throttling a valve PDCV, so as to remain in the range of the hydrogen-side pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0062">A line <b>208</b>, connecting the line <b>206</b> to the pressure vessel <b>200</b>, keeps the inside pressure of the vessel itself at a value controlled by the instrument PC-<b>2</b> by throttling the valve PCV-<b>02</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0063">The described embodiment can be reversed, by exchanging the role of the two gases, using then hydrogen as a pressurization means of the vessel <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0064">A further example is depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, corresponding to alternative control criteria of the electrolysis process. The vessels V-<b>1</b> and V-<b>2</b> are interconnected on the lower part by a pipe, so as to equalize the internal pressure of the two vessels, and consequently of the cathode and anodic compartments of the cells. In this case hydrogen delivery pressure is controlled as in the previous case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Oxygen delivery is controlled by keeping constant the electrolyte level inside V-<b>2</b>. The pressurisation of the vessel <b>220</b> is shown as made by hydrogen itself, through the loop PC-<b>2</b>/PCV-<b>2</b>, although it could be made by oxygen, as in the case of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. Alternative control criteria may be selected by the skilled person.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0065">The invention reaches the aims and purposes stated above, and is particularly suitable for the production of high pressure hydrogen from the electrolysis of water.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is: </us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electrolyser comprising:
<claim-text>a pressure vessel having a shell and opposite closed ends;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electrolysis cell stack inside said pressure vessel, comprising a plurality of bipolar electrolysis cells stacked between a first terminal end plate and a second terminal end plate, the cell stack being arranged to operate under internal pressure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>fluid connections for feeding an electrolyte to the cell stack and for collecting the product(s) of the electrolysis from the cell stack, and electric connections comprising at least an anode and a cathode connection,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first terminal end plate of the cell stack is integral with one of said closed ends of the pressure vessel, thus forming a stationary head of the cell stack;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said stationary head is equipped with said fluid connections and electric anode and cathode connections with the cell stack;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second terminal end plate of the cell stack is inside the pressure vessel and is free to move in a longitudinal direction relative to the first terminal end plate and to the vessel, in response to thermal expansion or contraction, thus forming a floating head of the cell stack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the vessel has a flat end cover which also constitutes said first terminal end plate of the cell stack.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said electric connections comprise:
<claim-text>at least a first electric connector passing through said first terminal end plate of the cell stack, insulated from said plate and electrically connected to the first cell of the stack;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a second electric connector associated and electrically connected to the first terminal end plate, the first terminal end plate being electrically connected with the second terminal end plate of the stack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second terminal end plates of the cell stack are set together by tie rods, providing mechanical and electrical connection between said first and second end plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said a first electric connector and/or said a second electric connector are realized with a tie rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said first electric connector is the positive, carrying the anodic current to the first cell of the cell stack, and said second electric connector is the negative, thus having the duty of cathode termination for the last cell of the stack.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first electric connector is a tie-rod passing through the stationary head of the cell stack, and insulated from said stationary head by a tubular bush;
<claim-text>the tie rod is fixed to the first anode of the stack; an insulating plate is provided between said first anode and the stationary head;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulating bush and gaskets are provided to separate said tie-rod from the pressure space inside the cell stack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An electrolysis process for electrolysis of water, in an electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> comprising a pressure vessel and an electrolysis cell stack inside said pressure vessel, the cell stack comprising a plurality of bipolar electrolysis cells stacked between a first and a second terminal end plates, and arranged to operate under internal pressure, the method comprising pressurizing the vessel during operation of the cell stack by a gaseous medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The electrolysis process according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein said gaseous medium is produced under pressure in said cell stack.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electrolysis process according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the pressure in the cell stack is greater than the pressure level in the vessel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The electrolysis process according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> for electrolysis of water, wherein the pressure of hydrogen furnished by the cell stack is greater than 30 bar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An equipment for electrolysis, comprising:
<claim-text>an electrolyser according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising a cell stack inside a pressure vessel, the cell stack being adapted to furnish at least a gas product under pressure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a vessel receiving said gas product and adapted to separate the gas product from entrained electrolyte;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow line feeding at least a portion of said gas product as a pressurizing medium into said pressure vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The equipment according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> for electrolysis of water, wherein the cell stack is adapted to furnish hydrogen and oxygen under pressure, comprising;
<claim-text>at least a vessel receiving the hydrogen and another vessel receiving the oxygen produced in the electrolyser; said vessel being adapted to separate the hydrogen and oxygen, respectively, from the entrained electrolyte;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow line feeding at least a portion of said hydrogen or a portion of said oxygen as a pressurizing medium into said pressure vessel, from the respective vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. Use of an electrolyser or equipment according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, for the production of hydrogen at a high pressure from the electrolysis of water.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The electrolysis process according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the pressure of hydrogen furnished by the cell stack is in the range 100 to 700 bar. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
