<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623571-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623571</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12698446</doc-number>
<date>20100202</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2009-022291</doc-number>
<date>20090203</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>901</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429512</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Fuel cell system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-054409</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-221836</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-226513</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>Japanese Office Action dated May 10, 2011, issued in corresponding Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-022291.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>1</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20100196772</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20100805</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kasuya</last-name>
<first-name>Kuri</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wakabayashi</last-name>
<first-name>Takuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kasuya</last-name>
<first-name>Kuri</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wakabayashi</last-name>
<first-name>Takuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Westerman, Hattori, Daniels &#x26; Adrian, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Honda Motor Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Laios</last-name>
<first-name>Maria J</first-name>
<department>1727</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention discloses a fuel cell system that blocks the oxidant gas flow passage. This fuel cell system includes a fuel cell stack, the oxidant gas supply passage, the oxidant gas exhaust passage, the first valve and second valve of normally open type, the first motor that operates open and close operations of the first valve, the second motor that operates open and close operations of the second valve, and the ECU that controls the first motor and the second motor. This ECU controls the first valve and the second valve to be in the open state during the power generation in the fuel cell stack, thereby to open the cathode flow passage, and controls the first valve and the second valve to be in the close state after the power generation in the fuel cell stack is stopped, thereby to block the cathode flow passage. The fuel cell system of the present invention further includes the first solenoid device and the second solenoid device that lock the respective valve bodies of the first valve and the second valve so as to maintain the close state of the first valve and the second valve.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="248.41mm" wi="180.17mm" file="US08623571-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="275.08mm" wi="186.77mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623571-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="277.88mm" wi="196.00mm" file="US08623571-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="270.68mm" wi="199.90mm" file="US08623571-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="279.06mm" wi="200.74mm" file="US08623571-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the foreign priority benefit under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 of Japanese Patent Application No. 2009-022291 filed on Feb. 3, 2009, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a fuel cell system.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Recently, there have been rapidly progressed various developments of fuel cells that generate power by supply with hydrogen (fuel gas) and oxygen (oxidant gas); for example, fuel cells are increasingly applied to a fuel cell vehicle as its power source. Such fuel cells include an anode flow passage (fuel gas flow passage) and a cathode flow passage (oxidant gas flow passage) therein.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, while power generation in fuel cells is stopped, that is, in a state in which fuel cells are electrically disconnected to an external load, when air externally flows into the cathode flow passage and this air (oxygen) is consumed by an electrode reaction under a cathode catalyst (such as Pt, Ru), so that potential of the cathode may increase, or residual moisture may be discomposed, consequently generating high-activated OH radical, etc. Such an increase of the cathode potential or generation of OH radical, etc. may cause oxidation of carbon (C) of carbon paper constituting the cathode and the catalyst, or decomposition of electrolyte membrane, resulting in deterioration of the fuel cells.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Some of the air flown in the cathode flow passage passes through the electrolyte membrane so that there cross-leak of the air to the anode occurs, and if this cross-leaked air is consumed under the anode catalyst, potential of the anode may increase or OH radical, etc., may be generated, so that carbon (C) of carbon paper constituting the cathode and the catalyst may be oxidized, or decomposition of electrolyte membrane may be caused, resulting in deterioration of the fuel cells.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To address such a problem, there has been proposed a fuel cell system in which normally closed type electromagnetic valves, each of which incorporates a solenoid, are provided in upper and lower reaches of the cathode, respectively; while power generation in the fuel cells is stopped, the electromagnetic valves are closed to block the cathode flow passage so as to prevent a fresh air flow externally flowing into the cathode flow passage, thereby to reduce cross leak amount of the air from the cathode to the anode (see JP 2006-221836 A).</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">However, the fuel cell system, as disclosed in JP 2006-221836 A, includes the normally closed type electromagnetic valves at the upper and lower reaches of the cathode flow passage, and while the air is being flown through the cathode flow passage in order to generate power in the fuel cells, current is needed to be continuously supplied for the solenoids of the electromagnetic valves to maintain the electromagnetic valves in the open state. Specifically, while maintaining the electromagnetic valve in the open state, power generated by the fuel cells and power stored in a battery are being consumed at the solenoids, resulting in inefficiency of power generation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention has an object to provide a fuel cell system that blocks an oxidant gas flow passage, as well as reducing consumption of energy such as electric power.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention provides a fuel cell system including fuel cells including a fuel gas flow passage and an oxidant gas flow passage, and generating power with fuel gas supply for the fuel gas flow passage and oxidant gas supply for the oxidant gas flow passage, respectively; an oxidant gas supply passage in which oxidant gas flows toward the oxidant gas flow passage; an oxidant gas exhaust passage in which oxidant gas discharged from the oxidant gas flow passage flows; a first valve of normally open type provided in the oxidant gas supply passage; a second valve of normally open type provided in the oxidant gas exhaust passage; a first operating member for operating open and close of the first valve; a second operating member for operating open and close of the second valve; and a controller for controlling the first operating member and the second operating member. In this fuel cell system, during power generation in the fuel cells, the controller controls the first operating member to operate the first valve to be in an open state, and controlling the second operating member to operate the second valve to be in an open state, thereby to open the oxidant gas flow passage, after the power generation in the fuel cells is stopped, the controller controls the first operating member to operate the first valve to be in a close state, and the controller controlling the second operating member to operate the second valve to be in a close state, thereby to close the oxidant gas flow passage. The fuel cell system further includes a close state maintaining member for locking at least one of valve bodies of the first valve and the second valve, thereby to maintain the close stat of at least one of the first valve and the second valve whose valve body is locked after the power generation in the fuel cells is stopped and after the first valve and the second valve are closed.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to this fuel cell system, since the first valve and the second valve are of normally open type, the first valve and the second valve can be set to be in the open state with consuming no energy such as electric power when oxidant gas is supplied in the oxidant gas flow passage to generate power in the fuel cells.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">On the other hand, in order to block the oxidant gas flow passage in the fuel cells to prevent a new oxidant gas flow into the oxidant gas flow passage after the power generation in the fuel cells is stopped and while the system is out of operation, the first and second valves are set to be in the close state by the first and second operating members, and then the close state maintaining member locks at least one of valve bodies of the first valve and the second valve so that the close state of at least one of the first valve and the second valve whose valve body is locked can be maintained. This means that the close state of at least one of the first valve and the second valve can be maintained with consuming no energy such as electric power.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The first and second valves may preferably be provided with this close state maintaining member respectively, as described later in the embodiment. Blocking the oxidant gas flow passage may also be referred to as a &#x201c;cathode block&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the above fuel cell system, the close state maintaining member includes a first close state maintaining member for maintaining the close state of the first valve and a second close state maintaining member for maintaining the close state of the second valve, the first operating member includes a first electric drive device for driving the first valve from the open state into the close state with current supply, the second operating member includes a second electric drive device for driving the second valve from the open state into the close state with current supply, and after the first valve and the second valve are maintained in the close state by the first close state maintaining member and the second close state maintaining member, the current supply for the first electric drive device and for the second electric drive device is stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to this fuel cell system, the first electric drive device drives the first valve to be from the open state into the close state, and the second electric drive device drives the second valve to be from the open state into the close state. Specifically, since the first operating member and the second operating member are of electric driving type, a regulator, a flow rate control valve, a switching valve, etc. can be eliminated, which is different from those of pneumatic driving type or of hydraulic driving type, so that the entire system can be simplified and down-sized.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The first close state maintaining member can maintain the close state of the first valve and the second close state maintaining member can maintain the close state of the second valve.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">After the close states are maintained by the first close state maintaining member and the second close state maintaining member, current supply for the first electric drive device and for the second electric drive device is stopped, so that power consumption in the first electric drive device and the second electric drive device can be stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the above fuel cell system, each of the first valve and the second valve comprises a lost motion mechanism for applying seal force in the close state thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to this fuel cell system, the lost motion mechanism can apply a seal force in the close states of the first valve and the second valve. Specifically, with this lost motion mechanism, tight contact between the valve seat and the valve body seated to this valve seat can be maintained while the first valve and the second valve are in the close state, so that the close states of the first valve and the second valve can be maintained.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the above fuel cell system, the first valve and the second valve, each having the lost motion mechanism, are provided in such a manner that each valve body of the first valve and the second valve that is seated to a valve seat is pushed in a direction of the open state by pressure at an upper reach of the first valve and the second valve, and the first valve and the second valve comes in the open state if the pressure at the upper reach becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to this fuel cell system, the first valve and the second valve having the lost motion mechanism respectively are provided in such a manner that the pressure at the upper reach of these valves is applied (urged) to these valves in their open direction, and the first valve and the second valve are set to be in the open state if the pressure at the upper reach thereof becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure. This means that the first valve and the second valve function as relief valves to release the pressure at the upper reach thereof if the pressure at the upper reach becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Specifically, if the first valve provided in the oxidant gas supply passage is operated to be in the open state by the first operating member (first electric drive device) but actually the first valve still stays in the close state (in case of failure), the first valve is then set to be in the open state when the pressure at the upper reach of this valve becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure. Accordingly, damages and or failures due to an abnormal rise in pressure can be prevented in the first valve, the pipes constituting the oxidant gas supply passage, various devices (such as an intercooler) provided on these pipes and the oxidant gas supply member (compressor in the embodiment described later).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In addition, if the second valve provided in the oxidant gas supply passage is operated to be in the open state by the second operating member (second electric drive device) but actually the second valve still stays in the close state (in case of failure), the second valve is then set to be in the open state when the pressure at the upper reach of this valve becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure. Accordingly, damages and or failures due to an abnormal rise in pressure can be prevented in the second valve, the fuel cells and the pipes constituting the oxidant gas exhaust passage.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The second predetermined pressure that defines the second valve to be in the open state is preferably smaller than the first predetermined pressure that defines the first valve to be in the open state. In other words, the first predetermined pressure that defines the first valve to be in the open state may be different from the second predetermined pressure that defines the second valve to be in the open state.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying exemplary drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a structure of a fuel cell system according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional side view of a first valve device or second valve device of normally open type according the present embodiment, showing that the valve device is in an open state.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional side view of a first valve device or second valve device of normally open type according the present embodiment, showing that the valve device is in a close state.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a sectional side view of a first valve device or second valve device of normally open type according the present embodiment, showing that the valve device is in the open state at the time of relief when a pressure at the upper reach becomes equal to or greater than a predetermined pressure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Hereinafter, detailed descriptions are provided on an embodiment of the present invention with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">&#x3c;&#x3c;Configuration of Fuel Cell System&#x3e;&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The fuel cell system <b>100</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is mounted in a not shown fuel cell vehicle (mobile body), for example. The fuel cell system <b>100</b> includes a fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, an anode system that supplies and discharges hydrogen (fuel gas, reactive gas) for and from an anode of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, a cathode system that supplies and discharges air containing oxygen (oxidant gas, reactive gas) for and from a cathode of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, a scavenging gas introduction system that introduces scavenging gas into the anode system at the time of scavenging the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, and an ECU (Electronic Control Unit) <b>160</b> that electronically controls the above components.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">&#x3c;Fuel Cell Stuck&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is a stack constituted by plural cells (200 to 400 cells, for example) formed in a layer stack, a single of which is a polymer electrolyte cell, and plural of these single cells are connected in series. A single cell includes an MEA (Membrane Electrode Assembly), and a pair of conductive separators that hold MEA therebetween. The MEA includes an electrolyte membrane (polymer electrolyte membrane) constituted by a univalent cationic exchange membrane, and an anode and a cathode (electrodes) that hold this electrolyte membrane therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Each anode and cathode respectively include porous solids having a carbon-paper-like conductive property or the like, and catalyst (such as Pt, Pu) supported by each own porous solid, causing an electrode reaction in the anode and the cathode.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Each separator includes grooves for supplying hydrogen or air to a whole surface of each MEA and through holes for supplying or discharging hydrogen or air to or from every single cell, and these grooves and through holes serve as the anode flow passage <b>111</b> (fuel gas flow passage) and the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> (oxidant gas flow passage).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">When hydrogen is supplied for each anode via the anode flow passage <b>111</b>, electrode reaction as represented by the formula (1) occurs, and when air is supplied for each cathode via the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>, electrode reaction as represented by the formula (2) occurs, and then potential (electro motive force based on OCV (Open Circuit Voltage)) occurs in each single cell. Then, the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is electrically connected to an external circuit of a driving motor or the like, and current is taken out therefrom, and then the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> generates power.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>2H2&#x2192;4H++4<i>e&#x2212;</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>O2+4H++4<i>e&#x2212;&#x2192;</i>2H2O&#x2003;&#x2003;(2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
&#x3c;Anode&#x3e;
</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The anode system includes the hydrogen tank <b>121</b>, the normally closed type shutoff valve <b>122</b>, an ejector <b>123</b>, a normally closed type purge valve <b>124</b> and a normally closed type scavenging gas exhaust valve <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The hydrogen tank <b>121</b> is connected to an inlet of the anode flow passage <b>111</b> via the pipe <b>121</b><i>a</i>, the shutoff valve <b>122</b>, the pipe <b>122</b><i>a</i>, the ejector <b>123</b> and the pipe <b>123</b><i>a</i>. When the shutoff valve <b>122</b> is opened in response to an instruction from the ECU <b>160</b> in order for the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> to generate power, hydrogen is supplied from the hydrogen tank <b>121</b> via the shutoff valve <b>122</b> to the anode flow passage <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The outlet of the anode flow passage <b>111</b> is connected to the intake port of the ejector <b>123</b> via the pipe <b>123</b><i>b</i>. After anode off-gas containing unconsumed hydrogen that is exhausted from the anode flow passage <b>111</b> is returned to the ejector <b>123</b>, this anode off-gas is re-supplied for the anode flow passage <b>111</b>, consequently circulating hydrogen. The pipe <b>123</b><i>b </i>is provided with a gas-liquid separator (not shown) that separates water in a liquid state accompanied with the anode off-gas.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The pipe <b>123</b><i>b </i>at the midstream portion thereof is connected to a diluter (described later) via the pipe <b>124</b><i>a</i>, the purge valve <b>124</b> and the pipe <b>124</b><i>b</i>. The purge valve <b>124</b> is periodically opened by control of the ECU <b>160</b> so as to discharge impurities (such as vapor and nitrogen) contained in the anode off-gas circulating in the pipe <b>123</b><i>b </i>at the time of power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The pipe <b>123</b><i>b </i>in the upper reach than the connection point to the pipe <b>124</b><i>a </i>is connected to the pipe <b>132</b><i>c </i>(described later) via the pipe <b>125</b><i>a</i>, the scavenging gas exhaust valve <b>125</b> and the pipe <b>125</b><i>b</i>. The scavenging gas exhaust valve <b>125</b> along with the scavenging gas introducing valve <b>141</b> (described later) are opened by control of the ECU <b>160</b> during the compressor <b>131</b> operation at the time of scavenging the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, more specifically, at the time of scavenging the anode flow passage <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the present embodiment, the time of scavenging the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> denotes a time when temperature of the system detected by a temperature sensor (not shown) is less than a predetermined temperature (such as 0&#xb0; C.) while the system is out of operation after power generation is stopped in fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, and if it is determined that the inside of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> will be frozen thereafter.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As described above, there are provided the shutoff valve <b>122</b> and the scavenging gas introducing valve <b>141</b> (described later) at the upper reach of the anode flow passage <b>111</b>, and there are provided the purge valve <b>124</b> and the scavenging gas exhaust valve <b>125</b> at the lower reach of the anode flow passage <b>111</b>. All the above valves are of normally closed type, and are normally maintained in the close state while power generation in fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is stopped (the system is out of operation), so that the anode flow passage <b>111</b> stays in the blocked state. Therefore, air outside a vehicle can be prevented from flowing through the scavenging gas exhaust valve <b>125</b> and the like into the anode flow passage <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">&#x3c;Cathode System&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The cathode system includes the compressor <b>131</b> (also referred to as the &#x201c;oxidant gas supply member&#x201d;), the first valve device <b>1</b> of normally open type, the second valve device <b>2</b> of normally open type, the back pressure valve of normally open type and the diluter <b>133</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The compressor <b>131</b> is connected to the outlet of the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> via the pipe <b>131</b><i>a</i>, the first valve device <b>1</b> and the pipe <b>131</b><i>b</i>. The compressor <b>131</b> starts operation in response to an instruction from the ECU <b>160</b>, and takes in air containing oxygen via the pipe <b>131</b><i>a</i>, etc., and supplies this air for the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Specifically, the oxidant gas supply passage in which air (oxidant gas) flows in the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> (oxidant gas flow passage) includes the pipe <b>131</b><i>a </i>and the pipe <b>131</b><i>b</i>, and the first valve device <b>1</b> is provided in this oxidant gas supply passage. The first valve device <b>1</b> is a normally open type electromagnetic valve controlled by the ECU <b>160</b>, and comes in the open state while power is being generated in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> (the system is in operation), and comes in the close state after the power generation is stopped, that is, while the power generation is out of operation (the system is out of operation).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The structure of the first valve device <b>1</b> will be described in detail later on.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The outlet of the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> is connected to the diluter <b>133</b> via the pipe <b>132</b><i>a</i>, the second valve device <b>2</b>, the pipe <b>132</b><i>b</i>, the back pressure valve <b>132</b> and the pipe <b>132</b><i>c</i>. Cathode off-gas (oxidant gas) discharged from the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> is exhausted via the pipe <b>132</b><i>a</i>, etc., to the diluter <b>133</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Specifically, the oxidant gas exhaust passage in which cathode off-gas exhausted from the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> (oxidant gas flow passage) flows includes the pipe <b>132</b><i>a</i>, the pipe <b>132</b><i>b</i>, the pipe <b>132</b><i>c </i>and the pipe <b>133</b><i>a</i>, and the second valve device <b>2</b> is provided in this oxidant gas exhaust passage. The second valve device <b>2</b> is a normally open type electromagnetic valve controlled by the ECU <b>160</b>, and comes in the open state while power is being generated in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> (the system is in operation), and comes in the close state after the power generation is stopped, that is, while the power generation is out of operation (the system is out of operation).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The structure of the second valve device <b>2</b> will be described later on.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The back pressure valve <b>132</b> is a normally open type valve including components such as a butterfly valve, etc., and its opening is controlled by the ECU <b>160</b> in accordance with the power generation demand such as an acceleration opening.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The diluter <b>133</b> is a container in which anode off-gas and cathode off-gas are mixed and hydrogen in the anode off-gas is diluted with the cathode off-gas (diluent gas), and includes a diluting space therein. The diluted gas is externally exhausted via the pipe <b>133</b><i>a </i>outside the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A humidifier (not shown) is provided across the pipe <b>313</b><i>b </i>and the pipe <b>132</b><i>a</i>. The humidifier accommodates plural hollow fiber membranes having a moisture permeable property, through which moisture exchange is carried out between air flowing toward the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> and humid cathode off-gas exhausted from through the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> so as to humidify the air flowing toward the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">&#x3c;Scavenging Gas Introduction System&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The scavenging gas introduction system includes a scavenging gas introducing valve <b>141</b> of normally closed type. The upper reach of the scavenging gas introducing valve <b>141</b> is connected to the pipe <b>131</b><i>a </i>via the pipe <b>141</b><i>a</i>, the lower reach of the scavenging gas introducing valve <b>141</b> is connected to the pipe <b>123</b><i>a </i>via the pipe <b>141</b><i>b</i>. When scavenging the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> with the compressor <b>131</b> in operation, the ECU <b>160</b> opens the scavenge gas introducing valve <b>141</b> so as to introduce scavenge gas from the compressor <b>131</b> into the anode flow passage <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">&#x3c;IG&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The IG <b>151</b> is a start up switch of the fuel cell system <b>100</b> (fuel cell vehicle), and is provided in vicinity of a driving seat. The IG <b>151</b> is connected to the ECU <b>160</b> so that the ECU <b>160</b> detects on/off signals from the IG <b>151</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0011" num="0000">&#x3c;ECU&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The ECU <b>160</b> (controller) is a controller that electronically controls the fuel cell system <b>100</b>, and includes CPU, ROM, RAM, various interfaces, electronic circuits, etc., and controls various devices and executes various processes in accordance with programs stored therein.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The ECU <b>160</b> has functions to control the first motor <b>40</b> (described later) of the first valve device <b>1</b>, the second motor <b>40</b>A (described later) of the second valve device <b>2</b>, and to control the open and close operations of the first valve <b>10</b> and the second valve <b>10</b>A (described later).</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The ECU <b>160</b> also has functions to control the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (described later) of the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second solenoid device <b>50</b> A (described later) of the second valve device <b>2</b>, and to control the lock and unlock operations of the first solenoid device <b>50</b> and the second solenoid device <b>50</b>A.</p>
<p id="h-0012" num="0000">&#x3c;First Valve Device, Second Valve Device&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The structure of the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second valve device <b>2</b> is specifically described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The first valve device <b>1</b> includes the normally open type first valve <b>10</b>, the first motor <b>40</b> (first electric drive device, first operating member) that operates open and close of the first valve <b>10</b> with current supply, and the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (first close state maintaining member) that maintains the first valve <b>10</b> in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The second valve device <b>2</b> includes the normally open type second valve <b>10</b>A, the second motor <b>40</b>A (second electric drive device, second operating device) that operates open and close of the second valve <b>10</b>A with current apply, and the second solenoid device <b>50</b>A (second close state maintaining member) that maintains the second valve <b>10</b>A in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Note that the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second valve device <b>2</b> have an identical structure to each other, which means that the first valve <b>10</b> and the second valve <b>10</b>A, the first motor <b>40</b> and the second motor <b>40</b>A, the first solenoid device <b>50</b> and the second solenoid device <b>50</b>A have the identical structure to each other, respectively. Therefore, descriptions are provided only on the first valve device <b>1</b>, and descriptions on the second valve device <b>2</b> is omitted hereinafter.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">[First Valve]</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The first valve <b>10</b> includes the body <b>11</b> (valve box) provided with the inlet port <b>12</b> and the outlet port <b>13</b>, the valve body <b>20</b> detachably seated to the valve seat <b>14</b> provided around the inlet port <b>12</b>, and the compressed coil springs <b>31</b>, <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The valve body <b>20</b> includes the plate body <b>21</b> detachably seated to the valve seat <b>14</b> around the inlet port <b>12</b>, the first rod <b>23</b> integral with the plate body <b>21</b> and extending upward from the center of the plate body <b>21</b>, and the second rod <b>25</b> in whose inside at the lower end portion the first rod <b>23</b> slidably moves and whose top portion extends through the ceiling wall of the body <b>11</b> that extends externally. This means that the rod including the first and second rods <b>23</b>, <b>25</b> is retractable.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The plate body <b>21</b> of the valve body <b>20</b> has a disk shape, and the first valve <b>10</b> comes in the open state when the plate body <b>21</b> is unseated from the valve seat <b>14</b> so that the inlet port <b>12</b> comes in communication with the outlet port <b>13</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). On the other hand, the first valve <b>10</b> comes in the close state when the plate body <b>21</b> is seated to the valve seat <b>14</b>, so that the inlet port <b>12</b> comes in communication with the outlet port <b>13</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">There is provided the annular seal member <b>22</b> of rubber material or the like on a side face of the valve seat <b>14</b> of the plate body <b>21</b>. When the plate body <b>21</b> is seated (when the first valve <b>10</b> is closed), the seal member <b>22</b> elastically deforms thereby to enhance the sealing performance. The seal member <b>22</b> may be provided on the valve seat <b>14</b>, instead.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">There is formed the flange <b>24</b> at the middle portion of the first rod <b>23</b>, and the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> is installed between the flange <b>24</b> and the second rod <b>25</b>. The compressed coil spring <b>32</b> urges the plate body <b>21</b> integral with the flange <b>24</b> in the closing direction (downward) so as to apply the sealing force of the plate body <b>21</b> (valve body <b>20</b>) in the close state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Accordingly, even when the thickness of the seal member <b>22</b> becomes smaller by long-term use, the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> urges the plate body <b>21</b> in the closing direction so that the plate body <b>21</b> tightly contacts the valve seat <b>14</b> via the seal member <b>22</b>, thereby to secure and maintain the tight close state therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In addition, even if the flange <b>26</b> (described later) and the latch shaft <b>51</b> (described later) of the first solenoid device <b>50</b> become worn out by long-term use and the lock position of the flange <b>26</b> varies, because the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> urges the plate body <b>21</b> in the closing direction, the plate body <b>21</b> is preferably seated to the valve seat <b>14</b>, thereby to secure and maintain the first valve <b>10</b> to be in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Specifically, the lost motion mechanism L included in the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A), which applies the sealing force in the close state, includes the plate body <b>21</b>, the first rod <b>23</b> having the flange <b>24</b>, the lower end portion of the second rod <b>25</b> and the compressed coil spring <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The upper portion of the second rod <b>25</b> externally extending through the ceiling wall of the body <b>11</b> is provided with a rack (not shown) meshed with the pinion <b>41</b> (described later) of the first motor <b>40</b> around the outer circumferential face of this upper portion of the second rod <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">There is provided the flange <b>26</b> around the middle portion of the second rod <b>25</b>, and the compressed coil spring <b>31</b> is installed between the flange <b>26</b> and the body <b>11</b>. The compressed coil spring <b>31</b> urges the flange <b>26</b> (the second rod <b>25</b>), the first rod <b>23</b> and the plate body <b>21</b> in the opening direction (upward), thereby to make the first valve <b>10</b> (the second valve <b>10</b>A) be a normally open type valve.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The spring force of the compressed coil spring <b>31</b> is defined to be greater than the static torque of the first motor <b>40</b>. Therefore, when the lock is released by the first solenoid device <b>60</b> when stopping current supply to the first motor <b>40</b>, the compressed coil spring <b>31</b> moves the second rod <b>25</b> upward against the static torque of the first motor <b>40</b>, accordingly the plate body <b>21</b> comes unseated from the valve seat <b>14</b> so that the first valve <b>10</b> opens.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Even when the second rod <b>25</b> moves upward, since the flange <b>24</b> of the first rod <b>23</b> is locked at the lower end of the second rod <b>25</b>, the first rod <b>23</b> does not come off the second rod <b>25</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">The inlet port <b>12</b> is connected to the pipe <b>131</b><i>a </i>in which air from the compressor <b>131</b> (air as the scavenging gas at the time of scavenging) flows, and the outlet port <b>13</b> is connected to the pipe <b>131</b><i>b</i>. Specifically, the first valve <b>10</b> is installed in such a manner that the plate body <b>21</b> (valve body <b>20</b>) seated to the valve seat <b>14</b> is pushed in the opening direction (upward in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, etc.) by the air pressure from the compressor <b>131</b> (at the upper reach).</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">In other words, in the close state of the first valve <b>10</b>, if the pressure at the upper reach of the first valve <b>10</b> becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure due to a certain reason, the plate body <b>21</b> (valve body <b>20</b>) is pushed in the opening direction by the above pressure and comes unseated from the valve seat <b>14</b>, so that the first valve <b>10</b> comes into the open state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Specifically, the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) including the lost motion mechanism L has a relief function to release the pressure at the upper reach when, the pressure at the upper reach becomes equal to or greater than the predetermined pressure in the close state of the first valve <b>10</b>, the first valve <b>10</b> opens and comes into the open state to release this pressure.</p>
<p id="h-0014" num="0000">[First Motor]</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">The first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) is the first electric drive device (second electric drive device) that drives the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) from the open state into the close state, and the first motor <b>40</b> includes a stepping motor, etc. When current is supplied for the first motor <b>40</b> in response to an instruction from the ECU <b>160</b>, the first motor <b>40</b> rotates in the positive rotation direction or in the negative rotation direction.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The output shaft of the first motor <b>40</b> is provided with the pinion <b>41</b>, which is meshed with the rack (not shown) of the second rod <b>25</b>. When the first motor <b>40</b> rotates, the second rod <b>25</b> moves downward so that the plate body <b>21</b> is seated to the valve seat <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) starts rotating after the system is stopped (after the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is stopped) in order to drive the first valve <b>10</b> (the second valve <b>10</b>A) from the open state into the close state, thereby to block the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The first motor <b>40</b> is fixed to the body <b>11</b> via a bracket (not shown), and is supplied with power from the battery (not shown) as a power source.</p>
<p id="h-0015" num="0000">[First Solenoid Device]</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The first solenoid device <b>50</b> (second solenoid device <b>50</b>A) is the first locking device (second locking device), which, after the first valve <b>10</b> comes in the close state by the first motor <b>40</b> after the system stop (after the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is stopped), latches the upper face of the flange <b>26</b> of the second rod <b>25</b>, thereby to lock the second rod <b>25</b> in the up and down direction in order to hold the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) in the close state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The first solenoid device <b>50</b> includes the latch shaft <b>51</b> that latches the flange <b>26</b> at the time of locking, the compressed coil spring <b>52</b> that urges the latch shaft <b>51</b> in the forward direction (projecting direction) toward the flange <b>26</b>, and the solenoid <b>53</b> that retracts the latch shaft <b>51</b> with current supply in response to an instruction from the ECU <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Specifically, in the close state of the first valve <b>10</b>, even though the latch shaft <b>51</b> is in the state of latching the flange <b>26</b> of the second rod <b>25</b> (in the lock state), the plate body <b>21</b> and the first rod <b>23</b> are still movable relative to the second rod <b>25</b>, that is, the plate body <b>21</b> can be unseated from the seat valve <b>14</b>, thereby to secure the function as a relief valve (described later) of the first valve <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Then, when current is supplied for the solenoid <b>53</b>, a magnetic force is generated by a fixed core (not shown) in the vicinity of the solenoid <b>53</b>, and this fixed core attracts a movable core (not shown) integral with the latch shaft <b>51</b>, so that the latch shaft <b>51</b> moves inward. After the latch shaft <b>51</b> is retracted in the above manner, the latch shaft <b>51</b> does not latch the flange <b>26</b> any more, so that the second rod <b>25</b> (valve body <b>20</b>) becomes movable in the up and down direction.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The first solenoid device <b>50</b> is fixed to the body <b>11</b> via the bracket <b>54</b>, as similar to the first motor <b>40</b>, and is supplied with power from the not shown battery as a power source.</p>
<p id="h-0016" num="0000">&#x3c;&#x3c;Operational Effects of Fuel Cell System&#x3e;&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Hereinafter, operational effects of the fuel cell system <b>100</b> are described.</p>
<p id="h-0017" num="0000">&#x3c;System In Operation (During Power Generation in Fuel Cell Stack)&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The fuel cell system <b>100</b> in operation (during the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>) is described hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The ECU <b>160</b> controls the first valve device <b>1</b> (first valve <b>10</b>) and the second valve device <b>2</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) to be in the open state so as to open the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>, thereby to let air flow through the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Now, the first valve device <b>1</b> is specifically explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The ECU <b>160</b> stops current supply for the first motor <b>40</b> and the first solenoid device <b>50</b>, and unseats the valve body <b>20</b> from the valve seat <b>14</b> by the compressed coil spring <b>31</b>, so that the first valve <b>10</b> of normally open type comes into the open state. Specifically, the first valve <b>10</b> of normally open type is held in the open state with consuming no energy such as electric power and the like. This is the same as in the second valve device <b>2</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A).</p>
<p id="h-0018" num="0000">&#x3c;System Out of Operation (After Power Generation in Fuel Cell Stack is Stopped)&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Next, the fuel cell system <b>100</b> out of operation (when the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is stopped) is described hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">When a driver switches off the IG <b>151</b> in order to stop a fuel cell vehicle, the ECU <b>160</b> detects its off signal, and then stops the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> so as to stop the fuel cell system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Specifically, the ECU <b>160</b> controls an electric power controller (not shown) connected to an output terminal of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> to stop taking out power from the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> so as to stop the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>. The ECU <b>160</b> closes the shutoff valve <b>122</b>, stops hydrogen supply for the anode flow passage <b>111</b>, and stops the compressor <b>131</b> to stop air supply for the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Thereafter, the ECU <b>160</b> closes the first valve <b>10</b> of the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second valve <b>10</b>A of the second valve device <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The first valve device <b>1</b> is described more specifically with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. The ECU <b>160</b> supplies current for the solenoid <b>53</b> of the first solenoid device <b>50</b> so as to retract the latch shaft <b>51</b> from the flange <b>26</b>. Holding the latch shaft <b>51</b> retracted, the ECU <b>160</b> supplies current for the first motor <b>40</b> to rotate the pinion <b>41</b> (see the arrow A<b>1</b>) so as to lower the second rod <b>25</b> (valve body <b>20</b>) (see the arrow A<b>2</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">To what extent the second rod <b>25</b> is to be lowered, that is, the rotational angle of the first motor <b>40</b> may be defined such that, with the first valve <b>10</b> in the close state, the seal member <b>22</b> is elastically deformed enough to exert its sealing effect, and the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> is moderately compressed so as to sufficiently urge the plate body <b>21</b> against the valve seat <b>14</b> even if the thickness of the seal member <b>22</b> becomes smaller by long-term use, so that the first valve <b>10</b> is securely and completely closed.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">In such a manner, the plate body <b>21</b> of the valve body <b>20</b> is seated to the valve seat <b>14</b> to block the inlet port <b>12</b> and the outlet port <b>13</b>, so that the first valve <b>10</b> comes into the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">After the first valve <b>10</b> comes in the close state, the ECU <b>160</b> stops current supply for the solenoid <b>53</b> of the first solenoid device <b>50</b>. Then, the latch shaft <b>51</b> moves forward to the flange <b>26</b> by the compressed coil spring <b>52</b> (see the arrow A<b>3</b>) to latch the upper face of the flange <b>26</b> so that the first valve <b>10</b> is maintained in the close state, that is, is locked. After the first valve <b>10</b> is maintained in the close state, the ECU <b>160</b> stops current supply for the first motor <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">In this way, while the power generation is out of operation (the system is out of operation) after the power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> is stopped (after the system is stopped), since the first valve <b>10</b> of the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second valve <b>10</b>A of the second valve device <b>2</b> are kept to be in the close state and the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> is blocked, external fresh air never flows through the first valve <b>10</b> or the second valve <b>10</b>A into the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Accordingly, rise in potential in the cathode or the anode constituting the MEA, or generation of OH radical and the like can be reduced, and deterioration of the cathode or the anode and decomposition of the electrolyte membrane can be suppressed. As a result, deterioration of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> can be reduced thereby to increase duration thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">After the first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) closes the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A), the latch shaft <b>51</b> of the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (second solenoid device <b>50</b>A) latches the flange <b>26</b>, so that the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) can be maintained in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Then, after the latch shaft <b>51</b> latches the flange <b>26</b>, and the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) is maintained in the close state, current supply for the first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) is stopped, so that power consumption in the first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) is stopped, so as to preserve the remaining amount of the battery (not shown) as a power source thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">In addition, while the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) is being maintained in the close state, current supply for the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (second solenoid device <b>50</b>A) is stopped, so that power consumption in the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (second solenoid device <b>50</b>A) can also be stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) includes the lost motion mechanism L and the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> urges the plate body <b>21</b> against the valve seat <b>14</b>. Therefore even if, for example, the thickness of the seal member <b>22</b> becomes smaller by long-term use, the plate body <b>21</b> can be securely seated to the valve seat <b>14</b>. Accordingly, the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) can securely come in the close state, thereby to enhance its reliability.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">While the system is kept stopped, in order to scavenge the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> of the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, the ECU <b>160</b> unlocks the first solenoid device <b>50</b> (second solenoid device <b>50</b>A), and after the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) is opened, the ECU <b>160</b> activates the compressor <b>131</b> to scavenge the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> with scavenging gas from the compressor <b>131</b>. Then, after the cathode flow passage <b>112</b> is scavenged, the ECU <b>160</b> closes the first valve <b>10</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A).</p>
<p id="h-0019" num="0000">&#x3c;System Start Up (Start Up of Power Generation in Fuel Cell Stack)&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Hereinafter, descriptions are provided on the start up of the fuel cell system <b>100</b> (start up of power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">When a driver switches on the IG <b>151</b>, the ECU <b>160</b> detects its signal and then opens the first valve device <b>1</b> and the second valve device <b>2</b>, in order to drive a fuel cell vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the first valve device <b>1</b> is specifically described. The ECU <b>160</b> supplies current for the solenoid <b>53</b> of the first solenoid device <b>50</b> to retract the latch shaft <b>51</b> from the flange <b>26</b> thereby to unlatch the second rod <b>25</b> (valve body <b>20</b>). Then, the compressed coil spring <b>31</b> pushes the flange <b>26</b> and the valve body <b>20</b> upward against the static torque of the first motor <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">As a result, the plate body <b>21</b> of the valve body <b>20</b> comes unseated from the valve seat <b>14</b>, and then the first valve device <b>1</b> (first valve <b>10</b>) comes in the open state (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Then, the ECU <b>160</b> stops current supply for the solenoid <b>53</b> of the first solenoid device <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">Thereafter, the ECU <b>160</b> opens the shutoff valve <b>122</b> to supply hydrogen for the anode flow passage <b>111</b>, and drives the compressor <b>131</b> to supply air for the cathode flow passage <b>112</b>. The ECU <b>160</b> starts up power generation in the fuel cell stack <b>110</b> in accordance with the power generation demand from the accelerator or the like.</p>
<p id="h-0020" num="0000">&#x3c;Failure in Close State of First Valve Device and Second Valve Device&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, descriptions are provided on a failure in the close state of the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b>, more specifically a case in which even though an open instruction is input from the ECU <b>160</b> to the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b>, these valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b> are not in the open state but still in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">Such a failure in the close state of the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b> may be caused if, for example, the first solenoid device <b>50</b> or the second solenoid device <b>50</b>A has a failure so that the second rod <b>25</b> cannot be unlocked, or the first motor <b>40</b> (second motor <b>40</b>A) operates improperly so that the valve body <b>20</b> moves in the close direction, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">For example, at the time of the system start up or of scavenging of the cathode <b>112</b>, since ECU <b>160</b> controls the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b> to be opened and determines that the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b> are opened, the ECU <b>160</b> activates the compressor <b>131</b> so that the air pressure at the upper reach of the first valve device <b>1</b> begins to increase. This increasing air pressure pushes the plate body <b>21</b> of the valve body <b>20</b> in the close state in the open state direction (upward).</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">When the air pressure at the upper reach of the first valve device <b>1</b> (first valve <b>10</b>) becomes equal to or greater than the first predetermined pressure, the compressed coil spring <b>32</b> is compressed with the second rod <b>25</b> in the lock state, the plate body <b>21</b> comes unseated from the valve seat <b>14</b> (see the arrow A<b>4</b>), and then the first valve <b>10</b> comes into the open state. In other words, the first valve <b>10</b> having the lost motion mechanism L functions as a relief valve, and the pressure at the upper reach of the first valve <b>10</b> is released.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">Therefore, damages and or failures in devices (such as the compressor <b>131</b> and an intercooler at the lower reach of the compressor <b>131</b>, etc.) at the upper reach of the first valve <b>10</b> and the pipe <b>131</b><i>a</i>, etc. due to abnormal rise in pressure can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">Note that the first predetermined pressure for defining the first valve <b>10</b> to come in the open state may be found through a pretest or the like, and may be defined to be a pressure at which devices at the upper reach of the first valve <b>10</b> experience no damages and or no failures.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Similarly, if the second valve device <b>2</b> (second valve <b>10</b>A) has a failure in the close state and the pressure at the upper reach thereof becomes equal to or greater than the second predetermined pressure, the second valve <b>10</b>A is controlled to come in the open state and functions as the relief valve (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), so that the pressure at the upper reach thereof is released. Accordingly, due to abnormal rise in pressure, damages and failures of devices such as the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, the pipes <b>131</b><i>b </i>and <b>132</b><i>a </i>and the humidifier (not shown) installed across the pipes <b>131</b><i>b </i>and <b>132</b><i>a </i>can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Note that the second predetermined pressure for defining the second valve <b>10</b>A to be in the open state may be obtained through a pretest or the like, and may preferably be defined to be a pressure at which devices at the upper reach of the second valve <b>10</b>A (such as the fuel cell stack <b>110</b>, etc.) experience no damages and or no failures, and may preferably be defined to be equal to or smaller than the first predetermined pressure for defining the first valve <b>10</b> to be in the open state, as well.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">As described above, the embodiment of the present invention has been explained, but the present invention is not limited to this, and may be modified as follows, without departing from the spirit of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The above described embodiment exemplifies that the valve body <b>20</b> is controlled to be from the open state into the close state by the rotational force of the motor <b>40</b>, and it may also be controlled to supply current for either solenoid to operate the valve body <b>20</b> to be in the close state, or alternatively a hydraulic motor may be used to operate the valve body <b>20</b> to be in the close state.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">The above embodiment exemplifies that the solenoid <b>53</b> retracts the latch shaft <b>51</b>, and alternatively a rack may be formed on the latch shaft <b>51</b> and the latch shaft <b>51</b> may be retracted by an electrical motor having a pinion meshed with this rack.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">The above embodiment exemplifies that the latch shaft <b>51</b> latches the flange <b>26</b> of the second rod <b>25</b>, and alternatively the latch shaft <b>51</b> may latch the upper face of the plate body <b>21</b> if the first and second valves <b>10</b> and <b>10</b>A include no lost motion mechanism L.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The above embodiment exemplifies that the latch shaft <b>51</b> latches the upper face of the flange <b>26</b> of the second rod <b>25</b>, but the above latching mechanism is not limited to this, for example, the latching mechanism may be embodied by inserting the latch shaft <b>51</b> into a latch hole provided in the second rod <b>25</b>. Or, a cam or the like may be used to latch the second rod <b>25</b>, instead.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">The above embodiment exemplifies that the first valve device <b>1</b> includes the first solenoid device <b>50</b> and the second valve device <b>2</b> includes the second solenoid device <b>50</b>A respectively, but only either of the first and second valve devices <b>1</b> and <b>2</b> may include a solenoid.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">The above embodiment exemplifies that the first and second valves <b>10</b> and <b>10</b>A include the lost motion mechanism L respectively, but only either the valves <b>10</b> and <b>10</b>A may include the lost motion mechanism L.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">The above embodiment exemplifies that the fuel cell system <b>100</b> is mounted in a fuel cell vehicle, but may also be a fuel cell system that is mounted in a two-wheeled motor vehicle, a railway train or a vessel. In addition, the present invention may be applicable to a stationary fuel cell system for household use, or to a fuel cell system for a hot water supply system.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">According to the present invention, there can be provided a fuel cell system that blocks the oxidant gas flow passage, as well as reducing energy consumption such power consumption.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">The embodiments according to the present invention have been explained as aforementioned. However, the embodiments of the present invention are not limited to those explanations, and those skilled in the art ascertain the essential characteristics of the present invention and can make the various modifications and variations to the present invention to adapt it to various usages and conditions without departing from the spirit and scope of the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fuel cell system comprising:
<claim-text>a fuel cell including a fuel gas flow passage and an oxidant gas flow passage, and generating power with fuel gas supply for the fuel gas flow passage and oxidant gas supply for the oxidant gas flow passage, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an oxidant gas supply passage in which oxidant gas flows toward the oxidant gas flow passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an oxidant gas exhaust passage in which oxidant gas discharged from the oxidant gas flow passage flows;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first valve that is normally open and has a first valve body, provided in the oxidant gas supply passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second valve that is normally open and has a second valve body, provided in the oxidant gas exhaust passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first electric drive device for operating the first valve, and energized to drive the first valve that is opened to be closed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electric drive device for operating the second valve, and energized to drive the second valve that is opened to be closed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller for controlling the first electric device and the second electric drive device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first valve body including a first plate body; and a first rod which is formed integrally with the first plate body and has a first latched portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second valve body including a second plate body; and a second rod which is formed integrally with the second plate body and has a second latched portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>during power generation in the fuel cell, the controller controlling the first electric device to operate the first valve to be in an open state, and controlling the second electric device to operate the second valve to be in an open state, thereby to open the oxidant gas flow passage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the power generation in the fuel cell is stopped, the controller controlling the first electric device to operate the first valve to be in a close state, and the controller controlling the second electric device to operate the second valve to be in a close state, thereby to close the oxidant gas flow passage, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fuel cell system further comprising a first close state maintaining member; a second close state maintaining member; and a power source for the first electric device, the second electric device, a first solenoid and a second solenoid,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first close state maintaining member comprising a first latch shaft movable forward or backward in a radial direction of the first rod; a first latch-shaft urging-spring pressing against the first latch shaft in a forward direction; and the first solenoid to have the first latch shaft moved backward on being energized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second close state maintaining member comprising a second latch shaft movable forward or backward in a radial direction of the second rod; a second latch-shaft urging-spring pressing against the second latch shaft in a forward direction; and the second solenoid to have the second latch shaft moved backward on being energized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>after the power generation in the fuel cell is stopped; after the first valve is closed, the first latch shaft latching the first latched portion to maintain the first valve in a close state; after the second valve is closed, the second latch shaft latching the second latched portion to maintain the second valve in a close state; and after the first valve and second valve are maintained in a close state, the first electric device and the second electric device being stopped from being energized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the extendable and retractable first rod comprising a first A rod formed integrally with the first plate body; and a first B rod being movable relative to the first A rod and having the first latched portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the extendable and retractable second rod comprising a second A rod formed integrally with the second plate body; and a second B rod being movable relative to the second A rod and having the second latched portion,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fuel cell system further comprising a first urging spring to press against the first A rod and the first B rod to extend while the first valve is open and to press against the first plate body to be kept closed while the first valve is closed, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fuel cell system further comprising a second urging spring to press against the second A rod and the second B rod to extend while the second valve is open and to press against the second plate body to be kept closed while the second valve is closed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
