<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622077-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622077</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12872317</doc-number>
<date>20100831</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2009 041 159</doc-number>
<date>20090914</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>533</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>13731503</main-classification>
<further-classification>25112904</further-classification>
<further-classification>32420715</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Position sensor unit and valve arrangement</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4984549</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mesenich</name>
<date>19910100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123472</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5494255</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pearson et al.</name>
<date>19960200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>25112915</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7093613</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hofling et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>137554</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0052289</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jansen</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>251 635</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0257422</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fack et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1374875</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>35 06 053</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19860800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>196 43 976</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Rainer et al., DE3506053, Published Aug. 21, 1986, Description Translated by EPO and Google on Dec. 27, 2012, http://translationportal.epo.org/emtp/translate/?ACTION=description-retrieval&#x26;COUNTRY=DE&#x26;ENGINE=google&#x26;FORMAT=docdb&#x26;KIND=A1&#x26;LOCALE=en<sub>&#x2014;</sub>EP&#x26;NUMBER=3506053&#x26;OPS=ops.epo.org&#x26;SRCLANG=de&#x26;TRGLANG=en.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Martin, DE19643976A1, Published May 7, 1998, Description Translated by EPO and Google on Dec. 27, 2012, http://translationportal.epo.org/emtp/translate/?ACTION=description-retrieval&#x26;COUNTRY=DE&#x26;ENGINE=google&#x26;FORMAT=docdb&#x26;KIND=A1&#x26;LOCALE=en<sub>&#x2014;</sub>EP&#x26;NUMBER=19643976&#x26;OPS=ops.epo.org&#x26;SRCLANG=de&#x26;TRGLANG=en.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>13731503</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137554</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112904</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112915</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2511291</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>25112918</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32420713</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>32420715</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110062356</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110317</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>P&#xf6;gel</last-name>
<first-name>Oliver</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lohr am Main</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morawski</last-name>
<first-name>Dieter</first-name>
<address>
<city>Marktheidenfeld</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Heinzmann</last-name>
<first-name>J&#xfc;rgen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Babenhausen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lesk</last-name>
<first-name>Hans-Kersten</first-name>
<address>
<city>Immenstadt</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>P&#xf6;gel</last-name>
<first-name>Oliver</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lohr am Main</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morawski</last-name>
<first-name>Dieter</first-name>
<address>
<city>Marktheidenfeld</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Heinzmann</last-name>
<first-name>J&#xfc;rgen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Babenhausen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lesk</last-name>
<first-name>Hans-Kersten</first-name>
<address>
<city>Immenstadt</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oliff &#x26; Berridge, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Robert Bosch GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Stuttgart</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Magnet-Schultz GmbH &#x26; Co. KG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Memmingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Fristoe, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>John K</first-name>
<department>3753</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Jellett</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew W</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed are a position sensor unit and a valve arrangement comprising such a position sensor unit, wherein a sensor housing of the position sensor unit is fixed in position with respect to a housing of an actuating magnet or a valve by an adjusting nut and a counter nut. The counter nut is mounted on the sensor housing and supported at the housing.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="179.92mm" wi="232.83mm" file="US08622077-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.17mm" wi="177.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622077-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.34mm" wi="184.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622077-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a position sensor unit according to the preamble of claim <b>1</b>, and to a valve arrangement comprising such a position sensor unit.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Such a position sensor unit is, for instance, disclosed in DE 196 43 976 A1. This document shows a switching magnet for a hydraulic valve, wherein the switching position of the hydraulic valve actuated by the switching magnet is sensed by a position sensor that is attached laterally to a switching magnet housing. In this known solution an axially movable armature of the switching magnet is connected with a measuring bar that immerses from the switching magnet housing into a housing of the position sensor and is sealed via a pressure pipe. The axial displacement of the measuring bar causes a field change in a coil winding of the position sensor, so that this field change gives an indication of the switching position of the armature and thus of the actuating magnet. In such solutions it is essential that the position of the measuring bar is adjusted relative to the coil winding and to the armature to enable an exact measurement.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the known solution, adjusting is performed by an adjusting nut via which the coil winding that is guided on the pressure pipe is displaced in axial direction against the force of an adjusting spring. The coil winding is then fixed in the desired relative position, on the one hand, by the adjusting spring and, on the one hand, by the adjusting nut that is, for instance, designed as a self-locking nut.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The fastening of the position sensor at the switching magnet housing is, in this solution, performed by a slide-on casing encompassing the housing of the position sensor unit, by which a flanged end portion of a pole tube is connected with a fixing member of the position sensor unit in a force-fit manner.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A disadvantage of this known solution is, on the one hand, the relatively complex structure and, on the other hand, a comparatively defective adjustment since the clamping between the adjusting spring, on the one hand, and the adjusting nut, on the other hand, does not ensure an exact adjusting position&#x2014;for instance, in the case of temperature changes&#x2014;, so that the position sensor may tend to temperature drifting, and thus the risk of a defective position sensing exists.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">DE 35 06 053 A1 discloses a position sensor unit of a switching magnet in which the position sensor unit is also attached laterally to a switching magnet housing, wherein the relative positioning of the measuring bar that is connected with the armature of the switching magnet to the coil winding of the position sensor unit is&#x2014;similar to the afore-described solution&#x2014;adapted to be adjusted by an adjusting nut, wherein the fixing in the adjusting position is then performed by a counter nut arranged in the transition area between the switching magnet housing. Via this counter nut, the position sensor unit is also connected with the switching magnet. Such a solution requires substantial constructive adaptations at the switching magnet housing since it is necessary to form the thread of the counter nut at the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In contrast to this, it is an object of the invention to provide a position sensor unit and a valve arrangement comprising such a position sensor unit, wherein the adjustment and the fastening of the position sensor unit is possible with little effort.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">This object is solved with respect to the position sensor unit by the features of claim <b>1</b> and with respect to the valve arrangement by the feature combination of claim <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The position sensor unit according to the invention is provided to be attached to a housing, preferably a valve or actuating magnet housing, and comprises a coil with a measuring bar that is movable relative thereto. These components are accommodated in a sensor housing that is adapted to be displaced by means of an adjusting nut in the direction of the sensor axis for adjusting the relative position. In accordance with the invention, the position fixing of the sensor housing is performed by a counter nut that is, on the one hand, supported at the housing and, on the other hand, encompasses the sensor housing in sections and is in thread engagement therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">This variant requires comparatively little constructional modifications of the housing, for instance, a valve housing or an actuating magnet housing, since the counter nut merely has to be supported at this housing. By the thread engagement between the counter nut and the sensor housing it is possible to adjust the latter also by twisting the counter nut in axial direction, so that the adjustment and the position fixing are possible in an extremely simple and exact manner.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In a variant according to the invention, the housing and the sensor housing are indirectly or directly connected with each other by means of an anti-twist protection, so that a relative twisting is not possible when the counter nut is adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">This anti-twist protection is, for instance, formed by a notched internal toothing that is, on the one hand, formed at a locking collar of the coil housing and, on the other hand, as an external toothing at a hub projection of the housing. In particular, the housing-side toothing may be formed on a stroke limitation of the pole tube of an actuating magnet. The toothing may be designed as a notched toothing or as a knurling, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one embodiment of the invention, the counter nut comprises an internal thread that is adapted to be brought in engagement with an external thread of a fastening flange encompassing the locking collar.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In order to further simplify the adjustment, the coil housing is adapted to be biased via the adjusting nut against a spring that is supported at the housing, so that the adjusting position is defined even if the counter nut is released.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In a particularly compact variant of the position sensor unit, the sensor-side fastening flange is guided on a coil fastening nut of the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In a simple embodiment, the sensor coil and the coil housing are connected with each other by injection molding. In a further development of this embodiment, the current supply and signal connections of the coil may also be injected.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In a preferred embodiment of the invention, the housing is a magnet coil housing of an actuating magnet, preferably a switching magnet, wherein the measuring bar is actuated by an armature of the actuating magnet.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The construction of the position sensor unit is particularly simple if the above-mentioned hub projection is formed at a stroke limitation of a pole tube of the actuating magnet.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In an alternative variant, the housing may also be a valve housing to which the position sensor unit is directly attached to sense a position of a valve element.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The structure of the position sensor unit is particularly simple if the sensor housing is guided on a pressure pipe which is anchored at the side of the housing and into which the measuring bar immerses and onto which the adjusting nut is adapted to be screwed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The actuating magnet may be designed as a switching magnet and/or as a proportional solenoid. As a matter of principle, the afore-described structure may also be used with other sensors.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The counter nut may be supported directly at the housing (valve housing/actuating magnet housing) or at the coil fastening nut via which, for instance, a magnet coil of the actuating magnet is fixed in axial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Other advantageous further developments of the invention are the subject matter of further subclaims.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A preferred embodiment of the invention will be described in detail by means of schematic drawings. There show:</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> a longitudinal section through an assembly with an actuating magnet and a position sensor unit attached thereto, and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> an enlarged partial representation of the assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an actuating magnet <b>1</b>, for instance, a switching magnet of a valve for controlling a pressure agent flow, and a position sensor unit <b>2</b> attached thereto for detecting a position of a valve body of this valve. The basic structure of the actuating magnet <b>1</b> corresponds to that of conventional solutions, so that only the components that are essential for the understanding of the invention will be explained here. The actuating magnet <b>1</b> comprises a pole tube <b>4</b> in which an armature <b>6</b> is guided to be displaced axially. The operating displacement of the armature <b>6</b> is, on the one hand, formed by a stroke limitation <b>8</b> that is screwed into the pole tube <b>4</b> at the front side and, on the other hand, by a pole piece <b>10</b> of the pole tube <b>4</b>. The front-side pole piece <b>10</b>, an intermediate ring <b>12</b> of a non-magnetizable material which is attached thereto laterally, and a pole tube ring <b>14</b> that is welded therewith, as well as the stroke limitation <b>8</b> mentioned confine an armature chamber <b>16</b> for the armature <b>6</b>. The armature <b>6</b> is, via a spring <b>18</b> that is supported at the stroke limitation <b>8</b>, biased in the direction of a basic position that is not illustrated, in which the armature <b>6</b> rests against an anti-stick pad <b>20</b> that is attached to the inner front face of the pole piece <b>10</b>. Into the adjacent end portion of the armature <b>6</b>, a valve lifter <b>22</b> is inserted which is in operative connection with a valve body of a valve to which the actuating magnet <b>1</b> is attached via a fastening flange <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A coil housing <b>26</b> comprising a coil carrier <b>28</b>, a magnet coil <b>30</b> supported by it, and a coil casing <b>32</b> encompassing these components is slid onto the pole tube <b>4</b>. The coil casing <b>32</b> is biased via a coil fastening nut <b>34</b> against a support ring <b>36</b> that is connected with the pole piece <b>10</b>. The coil fastening nut <b>34</b> comprises an internal thread <b>38</b> that is in engagement with an external thread <b>40</b> at a radially projecting thread flange <b>42</b> of the stroke limitation <b>8</b>. The current feed of the magnet coil <b>30</b> is performed via connections <b>44</b> formed at the coil housing <b>26</b>. By powering off the magnet coil <b>30</b>, the armature <b>6</b> may be moved from its illustrated switching position to the left by the force of the spring <b>18</b>, so that the valve lifter <b>22</b> performs a corresponding stroke that is transmitted to the valve body of the assigned valve. Into the end portion of the armature <b>6</b> which is remote from the valve lifter <b>22</b>, a measuring bar <b>46</b> is inserted which penetrates the spring <b>18</b> in axial direction as well as a through bore <b>48</b> of the stroke limitation <b>8</b> and immerses into the position sensor <b>1</b>. A pressure pipe <b>52</b> with a support flange <b>54</b> is supported at a radial shoulder <b>50</b> of the through bore <b>38</b> and is sealed by means of a seal <b>56</b> in this region. The measuring bar <b>46</b> immerses into a blind bore <b>58</b> of the pressure pipe <b>52</b>, wherein the axial length thereof is chosen such that the armature <b>6</b> and hence also the measuring bar <b>46</b> are adapted to perform the predetermined switching stroke.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">By means of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, further details of the position sensor unit are explained. Accordingly, a sensor housing <b>60</b> of the position sensor unit <b>2</b> is mounted on the pressure pipe <b>52</b>. The sensor housing <b>60</b> comprises an external housing <b>62</b> to which plug connections <b>64</b> for the contacting of signal and current supply connections are injected integrally. The external housing <b>62</b> encompasses a sensor coil housing <b>66</b> into which a sensor coil <b>68</b> is injected by injection molding. In accordance with the invention it is provided to sheathe the unit of sensor coil housing <b>66</b> and sensor coil <b>68</b> by injection molding with the external housing <b>62</b>, so that the entire sensor housing <b>60</b> constitutes a structural unit. As a matter of principle, the individual components (external housing <b>62</b>, connections <b>64</b>, sensor coil housing <b>66</b>, and sensor coil <b>68</b>) may also be designed as separate components that are assembled in the known manner. The afore-described structural unit produced by injection molding has, however, the advantage that the pre-assembled sensor housing <b>60</b> can be produced with little effort and high precision.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In accordance with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the sensor coil housing <b>66</b> comprises at the right end portion thereof a support hub <b>70</b> projecting along the pressure pipe <b>52</b> and being penetrated by the end portion of the pressure pipe <b>52</b>, so that it projects from the support hub <b>70</b>. At that end portion of the pressure pipe <b>52</b>, an external thread <b>72</b> is formed onto which an adjusting nut <b>74</b> is screwed which rests with the front side thereof against the support hub <b>70</b>. By adjusting this adjusting nut <b>74</b>, it is thus possible to adjust the relative position of the sensor housing <b>60</b> with the sensor coil <b>68</b> in relation to the pressure pipe <b>52</b> and hence also to the measuring bar <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The sensor housing <b>60</b> is biased via an adjusting spring <b>76</b> in the direction of the adjusting nut <b>74</b>, wherein the adjusting spring <b>76</b> is supported at a front face <b>77</b> of a radial expansion of the through bore <b>48</b>. This means that the adjustment of the adjusting screw <b>74</b> to the left in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is performed against the force of the adjusting spring <b>76</b>, so that the sensor housing <b>60</b> is pre-positioned by the adjusting nut <b>74</b>, on the one hand, and the adjusting spring <b>76</b>, on the other hand, as a function of the position of the adjusting nut <b>74</b>. The external housing <b>62</b> is, with its left end portion in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, designed with an annular locking collar <b>78</b> that encompasses the adjacent hub-shaped end portion of the stroke limitation <b>8</b> (at the right of the thread flange <b>42</b>), so that this region of the sensor housing <b>60</b> is guided to slide on the stroke limitation <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">For anti-twist protection between the pole tube <b>4</b> and the sensor housing <b>60</b>, the locking collar <b>78</b> is provided with an internal toothing <b>80</b>, and the outer circumference of the stroke limitation <b>8</b> which cooperates therewith is provided with a corresponding external toothing <b>82</b>, so that the coil housing <b>60</b> is guided along the toothing engagement both in axial direction and in radial direction as well as in circumferential direction (twisting).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">At the actuating magnet-side end portion of the external housing <b>62</b>, a fastening flange <b>84</b> encompassing the locking collar <b>78</b> is further formed, said fastening flange <b>84</b> being guided with an inner circumference face <b>86</b> on a circumference step <b>88</b> of the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>. Thus, the left end portion of the sensor housing <b>60</b> is, on the one hand, guided along the toothing <b>80</b>, <b>82</b> and, on the other hand, along the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>. At the outer circumference of the fastening flange <b>84</b>, an external thread <b>89</b> is formed which combs with an internal thread <b>90</b> of a sleeve-like counter nut <b>92</b>. It encompasses with the&#x2014;in FIG. <b>2</b>&#x2014;right end portion the fastening flange <b>84</b>, so that the counter nut <b>92</b> is guided thereon, and rests with its&#x2014;in FIG. <b>2</b>&#x2014;left front face <b>94</b> against an adjacent abutment face <b>96</b> of the coil housing <b>26</b> or, more exactly, of the coil casing <b>32</b>. The counter nut is guided with a guiding portion <b>91</b> on the outer circumference of the coil fastening nut. At the outer circumference of the counter nut <b>92</b>, longitudinal grooves are formed to improve the handling thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the contact area between the coil casing <b>32</b>, the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>, and the pole tube piece <b>14</b> as well as the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>, the counter nut <b>92</b>, and the coil casing <b>32</b>, respective seals <b>98</b>, <b>100</b> are positioned. Corresponding seals are also positioned&#x2014;as usual&#x2014;in the area between the pole tube piece <b>14</b> and the stroke limitation <b>8</b> as well as in the contact area between the connecting flange <b>84</b> and the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>. For attaching or adjusting the coil housing <b>60</b> with respect to the position of the measuring bar <b>46</b>, the counter nut <b>92</b> is screwed to the right, so that it gets in a distance to the coil casing <b>32</b>. Subsequently, the entire coil housing <b>60</b> is displaced via the adjusting nut <b>74</b> against the force of the adjusting spring <b>76</b>, wherein it is guided along the outer circumferential face of the pressure pipe <b>52</b>, the toothing <b>80</b>, <b>82</b>, as well as the sliding guide between the fastening flange <b>84</b> and the coil fastening nut <b>34</b>. After the adjustment of the predetermined adjusting position, the counter nut <b>92</b> is pulled tight again until it gets into contact with the coil casing <b>32</b> and thus fastens and counters the coil housing <b>60</b>, so that the adjusted position is reliably fixed.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the illustrated embodiment, the housing portions, preferably the external housing <b>62</b>, the housing-side regions of the plug connections, and the sensor coil housing <b>66</b> are manufactured of plastics.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the illustrated embodiment, the counter nut <b>92</b> is supported at the coil casing <b>32</b> at the front side. In another embodiment, the counter nut <b>92</b> may also engage in the circumference step <b>88</b> with the left end portion thereof which is shortened vis-&#xe0;-vis the afore-described solution, and then be supported at the support shoulder designated with reference sign <b>102</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Disclosed are a position sensor unit and a valve arrangement comprising such a position sensor unit, wherein a sensor housing of the position sensor unit is fixed in position with respect to a housing of an actuating magnet or a valve by an adjusting nut and a counter nut. The counter nut is mounted on the sensor housing and supported at the housing.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">LIST OF REFERENCE SIGNS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0038"><b>1</b> actuating magnet</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0039"><b>2</b> position sensor unit</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0040"><b>4</b> pole pipe</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0041"><b>6</b> armature</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0042"><b>8</b> stroke limitation</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0043"><b>10</b> pole piece</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0044"><b>12</b> intermediate ring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0045"><b>14</b> pole ring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0046"><b>16</b> armature chamber</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0047"><b>18</b> spring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0048"><b>20</b> anti-stick pad</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0049"><b>22</b> valve lifter</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0050"><b>24</b> fastening flange</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0051"><b>26</b> coil housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0052"><b>28</b> coil carrier</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0053"><b>30</b> magnet coil</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0054"><b>32</b> coil casing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0055"><b>34</b> coil fastening nut</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0056"><b>36</b> support ring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0057"><b>38</b> internal thread</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0058"><b>40</b> external thread</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0059"><b>42</b> thread flange</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0060"><b>44</b> connections</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0061"><b>46</b> measuring bar</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0062"><b>48</b> through bore</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0063"><b>50</b> radial shoulder</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0064"><b>52</b> pressure tube</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0065"><b>54</b> support flange</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0066"><b>56</b> seal</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0067"><b>58</b> blind bore</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0068"><b>60</b> sensor housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0069"><b>62</b> external housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0070"><b>64</b> plug connections</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0071"><b>66</b> sensor coil housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0035" num="0072"><b>68</b> sensor coil</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0036" num="0073"><b>70</b> support hub</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0037" num="0074"><b>72</b> external thread</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0038" num="0075"><b>74</b> adjusting nut</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0039" num="0076"><b>76</b> adjusting spring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0040" num="0077"><b>77</b> front face</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0041" num="0078"><b>78</b> locking collar</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0042" num="0079"><b>80</b> toothing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0043" num="0080"><b>82</b> toothing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0044" num="0081"><b>84</b> fastening flange</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0045" num="0082"><b>86</b> inner circumference face</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0046" num="0083"><b>88</b> circumference step</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0047" num="0084"><b>89</b> external thread</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0048" num="0085"><b>90</b> internal thread</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0049" num="0086"><b>91</b> guide section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0050" num="0087"><b>92</b> counter nut</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0051" num="0088"><b>94</b> front face</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0052" num="0089"><b>96</b> contact face</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0053" num="0090"><b>98</b> seals</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0054" num="0091"><b>100</b> seals</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0055" num="0092"><b>102</b> support shoulder</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A position sensor unit for attaching to a housing, comprising:
<claim-text>a sensor coil; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a measuring bar that is movable relative to the housing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said sensor coil and said measuring bar are accommodated in a sensor housing that is adapted to be displaced in a direction of a sensor axis by means of an adjusting nut for adjusting the relative position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a counter nut is supported in an axial direction indirectly or directly at the housing, said counter nut encompasses the sensor housing in sections, and said counter nut is in thread engagement with said sensor housing to fix the adjusted relative position, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a fastening flange of said sensor housing is guided radially inside on a coil fastening nut of said housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said housing and said sensor housing are connected with each other indirectly or directly by means of an anti-twist protection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a locking collar comprising a toothing is formed at said sensor housing, said locking collar being in engagement with a corresponding toothing at the outer circumference of a house-side hub projection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said counter nut comprises an internal thread that is in engagement with an external thread of a fastening flange encompassing said locking collar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said sensor housing is biased via said adjusting nut against an adjusting spring supported at said housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said sensor coil and/or the connections thereof are molded into said sensor housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said housing is assigned to an actuating magnet, and wherein said measuring bar is in operative connection with an armature of said actuating magnet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said measuring bar is in operative connection with an armature of an actuating magnet, wherein said house-side hub projection is formed at a stroke limitation of a pole pipe of said actuating magnet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said sensor coil and/or the connections thereof are molded into said sensor housing, wherein said counter nut is supported at said coil fastening nut of an actuating magnet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said sensor housing is guided in axial direction on a house-side anchored pressure tube onto which said adjusting nut is screwed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A valve arrangement comprising a position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing is a valve housing or an actuating magnet housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the toothing is an internal toothing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The position sensor unit according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein said housing is a valve housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
