<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622192-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622192</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13306468</doc-number>
<date>20111129</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>28</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>41</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198312</main-classification>
<further-classification>198318</further-classification>
<further-classification>198317</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Conveyor shift assembly and product cart with conveyor shift assembly</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5178253</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fix</name>
<date>19930100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198317</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5913369</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bodie et al.</name>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>172311</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6910586</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>McCloskey</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>209241</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7267519</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Cresswell et al.</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7488149</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Waldner</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414532</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7500814</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Meyer</name>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414327</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7740189</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Meyer et al.</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>239159</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8408377</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Werlinger</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198313</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130134013</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130530</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Borkgren</last-name>
<first-name>Stanley R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneseo</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Borkgren</last-name>
<first-name>Stanley R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Geneseo</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Deere &#x26; Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Moline</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Burgess</last-name>
<first-name>Ramya</first-name>
<department>3651</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Randazzo</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A product cart has a frame and one or more tanks forming compartments each having an opening at the upper end for receiving product. The cart includes a conveyor support having a swing arm with a first end pivotally mounted to the frame for motion generally horizontally between storage and use positions, a shift assembly mounted to a second end of the swing arm, and a mounting bracket assembly coupled to the shift assembly. Finally a conveyor is coupled to the mounting bracket assembly. The swing arm is constructed as a parallel linkage having first and second links which form a four-bar parallel linkage with the frame and with the shift assembly to maintain the shift assembly in a fixed orientation relative to the frame as the swing arm is moved. The shift assembly is operable to move the mounting bracket assembly between lowered and raised positions.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="156.38mm" wi="267.21mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="270.00mm" wi="171.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622192-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="240.20mm" wi="180.34mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="248.33mm" wi="162.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622192-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="227.92mm" wi="172.80mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622192-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="228.60mm" wi="175.51mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="216.41mm" wi="180.34mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="261.62mm" wi="177.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622192-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="246.30mm" wi="149.69mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="185.08mm" wi="173.48mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="236.14mm" wi="178.99mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="162.64mm" wi="173.48mm" file="US08622192-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">A product cart is disclosed together with a conveyor support for mounting a conveyor to the cart for use in filling and emptying the cart. The cart can take any of a variety of forms, including an air cart of an air seeder.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND AND SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">A product cart is disclosed having a frame and one or more tanks forming a plurality of compartments each having an opening at the upper end thereof for receiving product into the compartments. The cart further includes a conveyor support having a swing arm with a first end pivotally mounted to the frame for motion generally horizontally between a storage position and a use position, a shift assembly mounted to a second end of the swing arm, and a mounting bracket assembly coupled to the shift assembly. Finally a conveyor is coupled to the mounting bracket assembly. The swing arm is constructed as a parallel linkage having first and second links which together with a frame and with the shift assembly form a four-bar parallel linkage to maintain the shift assembly in a fixed orientation relative to the frame as the swing arm is moved. The shift assembly is operable to move the mounting bracket assembly between lowered and raised positions.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The conveyor support is described as having a swing arm with a first end adapted to be pivotally mounted to a frame for motion between a conveyor storage position and a conveyor use position, a shift assembly mounted to a second end of the swing arm and a mounting bracket assembly coupled to the shift assembly and adapted to be coupled to a conveyor housing. The swing arm is constructed as a parallel linkage having first and second links which together with a frame and with the shift assembly form a four-bar parallel linkage to maintain the shift assembly in a fixed orientation relative to the frame as the swing arm is moved. The shift assembly is operable to move the mounting bracket between lowered and raised positions.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The shift assembly and mounting bracket assembly for a conveyor are described as having an attachment bracket that mounts the shift assembly to a support and forms a ground link of a four-bar linkage. A parallel linkage having first and second parallel links each are coupled at a first end to the attachment bracket while a coupler is connected to the other end of each of the first and second links such that the coupler maintains a fixed attitude relative to the attachment bracket as the first and second links are moved. The mounting bracket assembly is connected to the coupler and is adapted to mount a conveyor thereto. The parallel linkage of the shift assembly is movable in a generally vertical plane so that the mounting bracket assembly is moved between a lowered position and a raised position.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view of a product cart having a conveyor support as described herein;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the conveyor support and conveyor of the cart shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are enlarged perspective views of the conveyor support in the cart shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</figref> are enlarged perspective views of the shift assembly and mounting bracket assembly of the conveyor support;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a plan view of the cart of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrating the conveyor in the storage position;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a side view of the conveyor support shift assembly with the conveyor in the storage position;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a side view of the conveyor shift assembly like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> with the shift assembly in a raised center position;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a plan view of the cart like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> with the conveyor in a conveyor use position to fill one or more compartments of the cart;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a plan view of the cart like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> with the conveyor in another use position;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a side view of the shift assembly in a forward shifted position corresponding to the conveyer fill position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a plan view of the cart like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrating the conveyor in a use position to clean out a compartment of the cart.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A product cart <b>20</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> having product tanks <b>22</b>, <b>24</b> and <b>26</b> each forming a compartment for carrying a granular product. The tanks have openings <b>32</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> respectively at their upper ends through which the compartments can be filled with a granular product. The tanks are supported on a frame <b>34</b> which in turn is supported by tires <b>36</b> for moving the cart. The frame <b>34</b> includes a tongue <b>38</b> to enable the cart <b>20</b> to be connected to a hitch of a towing vehicle, not shown. As shown, cart <b>20</b> is an air cart of an air seeder with the compartments intended to hold seed and fertilizer or other chemicals to be applied in the ground. Other carts may be grain carts to carry harvested grain products from a field, fertilizer or other chemical carts, rail cars or any other vehicle used to transport granular material. While the cart <b>20</b> shown is a towed cart, a self-propelled cart or truck can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The illustrated cart, being an air cart for seeding has meters <b>40</b> and <b>42</b> at the lower end of each of the compartments formed by tanks <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> respectively. Tank <b>26</b> likewise has a meter that is not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Product from the compartments is delivered by the meters to pneumatic conduits <b>46</b> for delivery of product to a tool, not shown. The meters <b>40</b>, <b>42</b> further have clean out openings <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> respectively through which product from the compartments is drained to empty the compartments.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">To facilitate both filling of the compartments and clean out of the compartments, the cart <b>20</b> includes a conveyor <b>54</b>. The conveyor includes a fill hopper <b>56</b> at one end and a discharge spout <b>58</b> at the other end. The conveyor can be used to fill the compartments with product through the upper openings <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> by positioning the conveyor in a cart use position in which the discharge spout <b>58</b> can be aligned with the desired opening <b>28</b>, <b>30</b> or <b>32</b> and then receiving product into the hopper <b>56</b> for conveying to the discharge spout. Additionally, the conveyor can be positioned with the hopper beneath one or the other of the clean out openings <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> in a cart clean out position to receive product from the compartments and conveying the product to the discharge spout <b>58</b> for delivery into another container. The cart includes front and rear support brackets <b>60</b>, <b>62</b> to hold the conveyor in a storage position in which the conveyor extends parallel to the cart fore and aft direction as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The conveyor is attached to the cart frame <b>34</b> by a conveyor support <b>68</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-6</figref>. Conveyor support <b>68</b> includes a swing arm <b>70</b> constructed as a parallel linkage having first and second parallel links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b>. The links are coupled at first ends thereof to the frame <b>34</b> by pivots <b>76</b>, <b>78</b> that define generally vertical axes <b>80</b>, <b>82</b> respectively. The pivots <b>76</b>, <b>78</b> allow the swing arm <b>70</b> to move in an arc horizontally as shown by the arrow <b>84</b>. The first and second links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b> are coupled at second ends thereof to a shift assembly <b>90</b>. Shift assembly <b>90</b> includes an attachment bracket <b>86</b> with pivots <b>92</b> and <b>94</b> connected to the first and second links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b>. The pivots allow for rotation about generally vertical axes <b>96</b>, <b>98</b> respectively. The attachment bracket <b>86</b> includes a plate <b>102</b> and an L-shaped bracket <b>104</b> forming the pivots <b>92</b>, <b>94</b>. A linear actuator <b>88</b> extending between the links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b> moves the linkage and controls the position of the swing arm. Alternatively, the actuator <b>88</b> could be coupled at one end to the frame <b>34</b> and at the other end to one of the links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The first and second parallel links <b>72</b>, <b>74</b> of the swing arm <b>70</b>, together with the frame <b>34</b> of the cart and the shift assembly, form a four-bar parallel linkage to maintain the shift assembly in a fixed orientation relative to the frame <b>34</b> as the swing arm is moved horizontally as shown by the arc <b>84</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The shift assembly also includes a four-bar parallel linkage. Shift assembly first and second links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> are pivotally mounted to the plate <b>102</b> on the side of the plate opposite the L-shaped bracket <b>104</b>. The shift assembly links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> rotate about pivots <b>110</b>, <b>112</b> defining axes <b>114</b>, <b>116</b>. The axes <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> are generally horizontal. A coupler <b>118</b>, in the form of a plate <b>120</b> with a bracket <b>122</b> on the bottom of the plate <b>120</b> is coupled to the other ends of the links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>. Pivots <b>124</b> and <b>126</b> connect the links to the coupler <b>118</b> and define axes <b>128</b>, <b>130</b>. The links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b>, together with the plate <b>102</b> and coupler <b>118</b> form a four-bar parallel linkage to maintain the coupler <b>118</b> in a fixed attitude relative to the ground as the shift assembly links move. The links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> move generally in a vertical plane in an arc shown by the arrow <b>132</b>. A guide <b>134</b> carried by the link <b>106</b> has a channel that receives the upper edge of the plate <b>102</b> to support the links and reduce the bending load on the pivots <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>. A shift assembly linear actuator <b>136</b> extends between the plate <b>102</b> and the first link <b>106</b> of the shift assembly to control the position of the linkage.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A mounting bracket assembly <b>140</b> is attached to the plate <b>120</b> by a pivot <b>142</b> that allows the mounting bracket assembly <b>140</b> to rotate about a vertical axis <b>144</b>. The mounting bracket assembly <b>140</b> is a hinge like structure having a first member <b>146</b> and a second member <b>148</b> pinned together at a pivot <b>150</b> for rotation about a horizontal pivot axis <b>152</b>. The first member <b>146</b> is held to the plate <b>120</b> while the second member is allowed to rotate relative to the first member about the axis <b>152</b>. The mounting bracket assembly <b>140</b> is used to mount the conveyor <b>54</b> onto the conveyor support <b>68</b>. The housing <b>160</b> of the conveyor is rotatably coupled to the pivot <b>154</b> of the mounting bracket assembly second member <b>148</b> and defines an axis <b>156</b>. A linear actuator <b>158</b> extends from the mounting bracket assembly <b>140</b> to the conveyor housing, spaced from the pivot <b>154</b> to control the inclination of the conveyor.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a top view of the cart <b>20</b> with the conveyor <b>54</b> in a storage position. The swing arm <b>68</b> is generally parallel to the fore and aft direction of the cart as is the conveyor <b>54</b>. In the storage position, the shift assembly <b>90</b> is shifted to the rear of the cart with the links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> extending upward and rearward at about the 2 o'clock position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. The first movement of the conveyor support <b>68</b> in deploying the conveyor to a use position is moving the shift assembly by rotating the links <b>106</b>, <b>108</b> counter clockwise to a more upward position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. This raises the conveyor off the front and rear support brackets <b>60</b> and <b>62</b> while moving the conveyor forward slightly. Due to the four-bar parallel linkage of the shift assembly, the attitude, that is the angle of inclination of the conveyor, remains the same during this movement. The linear actuator <b>158</b> is not actuated during this movement of the shift assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Deployment of the conveyor continues with pivoting of the swing arm <b>70</b> from the fore and aft extending position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> to a laterally projecting position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. The swing arm pivots by operation of the actuator <b>88</b>. The deployed use position of the swing arm can be any position in the pivot range of the swing arm. In the embodiment shown, the swing arm has more than 135 degrees of travel. Any position within that range can be a &#x201c;conveyor use position&#x201d; of the swing arm. While actuating the linear actuator <b>88</b>, the shift assembly, and therefore the conveyor, maintains a fore and aft extending orientation relative to the cart <b>20</b>. Once the swing arm is pivoted to the desired conveyor use position, the conveyor is rotated about the axis <b>144</b> by manual manipulation. Alternatively, the conveyor can be rotated about the axis <b>144</b> as the swing arm is pivoted outwardly. The linear actuator <b>158</b> is also extended to raise the discharge spout end of the conveyor and lower the hopper <b>56</b> to the ground. The shift assembly may also be moved slightly rearwardly by rotation along the arc <b>132</b>. In a first conveyor use position, the upper end of the conveyor is located where the discharge spout <b>58</b> can be placed in each the openings <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> of the two rearmost compartments of the cart. This position corresponds to a rearward position of the shift assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The conveyor is moved to a second tank fill position by actuating the shift assembly to move to a forward position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> while the hopper <b>56</b> remains in position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. This moves the upper end of the conveyor forward to a position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> where the discharge spout can be placed in each of the openings <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> of the two forward most compartments. It will be appreciated by those in the art that different tank configurations, including more or less than three tanks can be used with appropriate changes to the geometry of the shift assembly and/or swing arm. As one example, a cart having five tanks can use the conveyor support <b>68</b> with one conveyor fill position used to fill the rear two compartments with the shift assembly in a rearward position, another conveyor fill position to fill the center compartment with the shift assembly in a center upright position and third conveyor fill position to fill the front two compartments with the shift assembly in the forward position.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The conveyor <b>54</b> is also used to empty the compartments after use. This is accomplished by moving the swing arm <b>70</b> and shift assembly <b>90</b> as needed to place the hopper <b>56</b> beneath the clean out opening of each compartment. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the conveyor is positioned with the hopper <b>56</b> beneath the clean out opening <b>48</b> of the forward most compartment.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">As shown, the swing arm <b>70</b> has multiple conveyor use positions. Similarly, the shift assembly <b>90</b> has multiple use positions as well. The swing arm moves the conveyor <b>54</b> away from and toward the cart and also moves the conveyor fore and aft relative to the cart. The shift assembly moves the conveyor up and down and fore and aft. Furthermore, with the conveyor fill hopper on the ground, the shift assembly moves the discharge hopper end of the conveyor fore and aft to reach different compartments for filling. The mounting bracket assembly together with the linear actuator <b>158</b> controls the inclination of the conveyor. Pivot <b>142</b> adjusts the angle of the conveyor relative to the cart and is manually adjustable; however, a rotational drive can be added if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As noted above, the cart can have any number of compartments with the size of the conveyor and length of the conveyor support varied as necessary to reach each compartment. The illustrated cart has individual tanks each forming a compartment. Alternatively, a single tank can be divided internally into multiple compartments. In the cart <b>20</b> as illustrated, the tanks <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b> are shown supported by a separate frame <b>34</b>. Alternatively, the tank or tanks can be constructed as a structural member not in need of a separate frame. With this in mind, the claims that follow are not to be understood as requiring a separate frame structure from the tank or tanks. The various linear actuators are shown as being hydraulic cylinders. However, they could be other types of actuators including electronic actuators. They need not be linear but could be rotary actuators couple to a pivot about which a driven component is rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Various axes are described as being horizontal or vertical and movements of components in the conveyor support are described as being horizontal or vertical. In an alternative arrangement, the pivots need not be horizontal or vertical but could be inclined. For example, the pivots <b>76</b>, <b>78</b> attaching the swing arm <b>70</b> to the frame <b>34</b> may be inclined to the vertical such that as the swing arm pivots from a storage position to a use position, the swing arm moves forwardly and upwardly. Other arrangements are also possible. Unless specifically noted in the following claims, the orientation of the pivot axes should not be limited to the embodiment shown and described.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">While the swing arm <b>70</b> and shift assembly <b>90</b> are shown together in a single conveyor support <b>68</b>, they can each be used separately. In other words, the swing arm <b>70</b> can be used without the shift assembly <b>90</b> and the shift assembly <b>90</b> can be used without the swing arm <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The conveyor support shown and described provides efficient and complete control over the movement of the conveyor for both filling the tanks and emptying the tanks.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Having described the product cart and conveyor support, it will become apparent that various modifications can be made without departing from the scope of the accompanying claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A shift assembly and mounting bracket assembly for mounting a conveyor to a mobile cart, the cart having tires for moving the cart in a fore and aft direction, the shift assembly comprising:
<claim-text>an attachment bracket to mount the shift assembly to a support and forming a ground link;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a parallel linkage movable having first and second parallel links each coupled at a first end to the attachment bracket; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupler connected to the other end of each of the first and second links whereby the coupler maintains a fixed attitude relative to the attachment bracket as the first and second links are moved; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting bracket assembly connected to the coupler and adapted to mount a conveyor thereto;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the parallel linkage is limited to movement in a generally vertical plane in the fore and aft direction whereby the mounting bracket assembly is movable between a lowered position and a raised position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The shift assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the parallel linkage is movable to move the mounting bracket assembly between at least two conveyor use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The shift assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a shift assembly linear actuator coupled to the attachment bracket and the parallel linkage to move the parallel linkage between positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The shift assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a pivot between the parallel linkage and the mounting bracket assembly to rotate the mounting bracket assembly about a generally vertical axis.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A product cart comprising:
<claim-text>a frame;</claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more tanks forming a plurality of compartments each having an opening at the upper end thereof for receiving product into the compartments;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveyor support having a swing arm with a first end pivotally mounted to the frame for motion generally horizontally between a storage position and a use position, a shift assembly mounted to a second end of the swing arm, a mounting bracket assembly coupled to the shift assembly and a conveyor coupled to the mounting bracket assembly; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the shift assembly includes a parallel linkage having first and second parallel links and is operable to move the mounting bracket assembly between lowered and raised positions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the shift assembly is further operable to move the mounting bracket assembly between two or more conveyor use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the conveyor has a lower end with a hopper for receiving product and an upper end with a discharge spout for discharging product;
<claim-text>wherein the shift assembly, in a first conveyor use position, places the discharge spout of the conveyor in a position to fill a first compartment and the shift assembly, in a second conveyor use position, places the discharge spout of the conveyor in a position to fill a second compartment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the shift assembly moves the mounting bracket assembly fore and aft when moving between the first and second conveyor use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the shift assembly includes a parallel linkage to maintain the mounting bracket assembly in a fixed orientation relative to a ground surface as the shift assembly moves between the first and second conveyor use positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the shift assembly has a transport position in which the conveyor rests on one or more support brackets and a raised release position in which the conveyor is raised off the one or more support brackets.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The product cart of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> wherein the shift assembly includes a parallel linkage to maintain the mounting bracket assembly in a fixed orientation relative to a ground surface as the shift assembly moves between the transport position and the raised release position whereby when the shift assembly moves between the transport and release positions the conveyor attitude remains constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
