<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622038-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622038</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13123125</doc-number>
<date>20090909</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2008 050 672</doc-number>
<date>20081007</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>275</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9017</main-classification>
<further-classification>138 31</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Device for variably adjusting the control times of gas exchange valves of an internal combustion engine</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2688984</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Snyder</name>
<date>19540900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>138 31</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6782856</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Aimone</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9034</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6871620</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Aimone</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7108016</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Moskalik et al.</name>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>138 31</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0188705</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Aimone</name>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0060159</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Moretz et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>195 29 277</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19970200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102 28 354</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20040100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10228354</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20040100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2007 041552</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11 153014</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19990600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9017</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9015</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9016</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9031</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9012</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9033- 9038</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 906</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>138 31</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110239966</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111006</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Strauss</last-name>
<first-name>Andreas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Forchheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Strauss</last-name>
<first-name>Andreas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Forchheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lucas &#x26; Mercanti, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Schaeffler Technologies AG &#x26; Co. KG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Herzogenaurach</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bomberg</last-name>
<first-name>Kenneth</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Harris</last-name>
<first-name>Wesley</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2009/061674</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20090909</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20110407</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2010/040617</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20100415</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention relates to a device (<b>11</b>) for variably adjusting the control times of gas exchange valves (<b>9, 10</b>) of an internal combustion engine (<b>1</b>) having a hydraulic phase shifting device (<b>12</b>), a camshaft (<b>6, 7</b>), and a pressure accumulator (<b>15</b>), wherein the phase shifting device (<b>12</b>) can be brought into a drive connection with a crankshaft (<b>2</b>) and is connected to the camshaft (<b>6, 7</b>) in a rotationally fixed manner, wherein a phase position of the camshaft (<b>6, 7</b>) relative to the crankshaft (<b>2</b>) can be variably adjusted by means of the phase shifting device (<b>12</b>) and wherein the interior of the camshaft (<b>6, 7</b>) comprises a cavity (<b>38</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="128.10mm" wi="221.83mm" file="US08622038-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="219.12mm" wi="136.74mm" file="US08622038-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.37mm" wi="136.40mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622038-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="208.28mm" wi="170.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622038-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="217.00mm" wi="115.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08622038-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a 371 of PCT/EP2009/061674 filed Sep. 9, 2009, which in turn claims the priority of DE 10 2008 050 672.9 filed Oct. 7, 2008, the priority of both applications is hereby claimed and both applications are incorporated by reference herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a device for variably adjusting the control times of gas exchange valves of an internal combustion engine having a hydraulic phase setting device, a camshaft and a pressure accumulator, it being possible for the phase setting device to be brought into a drive connection with a crankshaft, and said phase setting device being connected fixedly to the camshaft so as to rotate with it, a phase relation of the camshaft relative to the crankshaft being variably adjustable by means of the phase setting device, and the interior of the camshaft having a cavity.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In modern internal combustion engines, devices are used for variably adjusting the control times of gas exchange valves, in order for it to be possible to variably configure the phase relation between the crankshaft and the camshaft in a defined angular range, between a maximum early position and a maximum late position. The device usually comprises a camshaft and a hydraulic phase setting device, by means of which a phase relation between the crankshaft and the camshaft can be changed in a targeted manner by way of feeding in or discharging pressure medium. For this purpose, the phase setting device is integrated into a drive train, via which torque is transmitted from the crankshaft to the camshaft. Said drive train can be realized, for example, as a belt drive, chain drive or a gearwheel drive.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A device of this type is known, for example, from DE 195 29 277 A1. The device comprises a phase setting device and a camshaft. The phase setting device has an output element which is arranged such that it can be rotated with respect to a drive element. The drive element is drive connected to the crankshaft. The output element and the drive element delimit a pressure space which is divided by means of an axially displaceable piston into two pressure chambers which act counter to one another. The piston is displaced within the pressure space by feeding in or discharging pressure medium from the pressure chambers. The piston has a helical toothing system which meshes with a helical toothing system of the camshaft. A targeted rotation of the camshaft with respect to the crankshaft can therefore be brought about by the axial displacement of the piston.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Furthermore, the device has a pressure accumulator which is arranged in a crankcase or a cylinder head of the internal combustion engine. During the normal operation of the internal combustion engine, the pressure accumulator is filled with pressure medium, as a rule the engine oil, by a pressure medium pump. If the system pressure which is delivered by the pressure medium pump falls below a value which is required for the functionally reliable operation of the device, the pressure accumulator is emptied into the pressure medium circuit of the internal combustion engine. Brief minimum pressure undershoots within the pressure medium system can therefore be absorbed and/or the volumetric flow can be increased.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A disadvantage of this embodiment is the great space requirement of the pressure accumulator within the crankcase or the cylinder head.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The invention is based on the object of providing a device for variably adjusting the control times of gas exchange valves of an internal combustion engine, it being intended that the installation space requirement of the device is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to the invention, the object is achieved by virtue of the fact that the pressure accumulator is arranged in the cavity and communicates with the phase setting device.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The device has at least one hydraulic phase setting device, one camshaft and one pressure accumulator. The phase setting device comprises at least one drive element and one output element. In the mounted state of the device, the drive element is drive connected to the crankshaft via a flexible drive, for example a belt or chain drive or a gearwheel drive. The output element is arranged such that it can be pivoted relative to the drive element in an angular range and is fastened fixedly to the camshaft so as to rotate with it.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">At least one pressure chamber is provided within the device, by the pressure loading of which at least one pressure chamber the output element can be pivoted relative to the drive element and therefore the camshaft can be pivoted relative to the crankshaft. One or a plurality of pairs of pressure chambers which act counter to one another is/are advantageously provided.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The camshaft has a cavity. Said camshaft can be configured, for example, as a hollow shaft. Embodiments are likewise conceivable, in which the camshaft is configured as a tube, on the outer circumferential face of which cams are fastened in a nonpositive manner, a positive manner or with a material to material fit. However, camshafts of solid configuration are likewise also conceivable, in which a cavity is provided, for example in the form of a blind bore. The pressure accumulator is arranged in the cavity of the camshaft. The pressure accumulator can be connected in a stationary manner to the camshaft, for example in a positive manner, a nonpositive manner or with a material to material fit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Pressure medium can be fed to the interior of the camshaft, for example via a camshaft bearing. The pressure medium passes firstly to the hydraulic phase setting device; and secondly to the pressure accumulator which is filled with pressure medium during the normal operation of the internal combustion engine. At the beginning of a phase adjustment, a defined quantity of pressure medium is removed from the pressure medium system of the internal combustion engine. As a consequence of this, the system pressure drops to a lower level. The system pressure which is present before the adjustment is not available in its full extent for the phase adjustment. The adjusting speed of the phase adjustment and therefore the performance of the entire internal combustion engine drop. If the pressure accumulator is filled, this pressure drop is absorbed by it, and the adjusting speed is held at a high level. The installation space requirement of the internal combustion engine is significantly reduced by the arrangement of the pressure accumulator within the camshaft, an installation space which is otherwise unused.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one implementation of the invention, it is proposed that the pressure accumulator has a longitudinally displaceable piston. Furthermore, the pressure accumulator can have a spring element which loads the piston with a force counter to the force of the pressure medium. As an alternative, for example, gas cushions can be provided as force accumulators. The pressure accumulator can be configured, for example, as a piston accumulator, in particular as a piston spring accumulator. This represents a very robust solution.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">There is provision in one development of the invention for the pressure accumulator to have a housing which is arranged in the cavity and in which the piston is guided such that it can be displaced longitudinally. A wall of the cavity of the camshaft therefore does not have to be machined further in a complicated manner. The running face of the piston is provided by an inner circumferential face of the housing. The housing can be realized, for example, as a cylindrical or pot-shaped sheet metal part which can be manufactured, for example, by a chipless shaping process, for example by a deep drawing method. As a result, the weight and the manufacturing costs of the housing are kept low. As a result of the deep drawing method, the running face of the piston is automatically manufactured with the necessary accuracy. Complicated further machining steps are not necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Furthermore, there can be provision for the pressure accumulator to be arranged in a stationary manner in the cavity between the housing and a wall of said cavity by means of a nonpositive connection. As an alternative, material to material or positive connections can also be provided, such as adhesive, soldered or welded connections.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">There can be provision in one implementation for the housing to have a guide section and for the piston to have an outer circumferential face which is adapted to an inner circumferential face of the guide section. The piston is guided in an axially movable manner on a guide face of the guide section. Here, the length of the guide section corresponds to the stroke of the piston within the pressure accumulator. The guide section can extend, for example, over the entire length of the piston. There can be provision in this embodiment for the nonpositive connection between the housing and the wall of the cavity to be configured along the entire length of the guide section, as a result of which the connection is given a high stability. For this purpose, its outer circumferential face is to be adapted to the wall of the cavity. As an alternative, there can be provision, at both axial ends of the guide section, for the housing to have a region of increased diameter, the outer circumferential faces of which are adapted to the wall of the cavity. There is therefore a nonpositive connection only between the regions of increased diameter and the wall of the cavity. As a result, a deformation of the guide face is avoided during the mounting of the pressure accumulator in the cavity, which could lead to jamming of the piston in the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Furthermore, there can be provision for the housing to have at least one stop for limiting the travel of the piston at least in one displacement direction of the piston, advantageously in both. Furthermore, there can be provision for the camshaft to be of tubular configuration.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Further features of the invention result from the following description and from the drawings, in which exemplary embodiments of the invention are shown in simplified form. In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an internal combustion engine in an only very diagrammatic way,</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a longitudinal section through a first embodiment according to the invention of a device for changing the control times of gas exchange valves of an internal combustion engine,</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a cross section through the phase setting device from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> along the line III-III, the central screw not being shown,</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b> show the detail X from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an illustration of a further embodiment according to the invention of a device, analogously to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> outlines an internal combustion engine <b>1</b>, a piston <b>3</b> which is seated on a crankshaft <b>2</b> in a cylinder <b>4</b> being indicated. In the embodiment which is shown, the crankshaft <b>2</b> is connected via in each case one flexible drive <b>5</b> to an inlet camshaft <b>6</b> and outlet camshaft <b>7</b>, it being possible for a first and a second device <b>11</b> to ensure a relative rotation between the crankshaft <b>2</b> and the camshafts <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>. Cams <b>8</b> of the camshafts <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> actuate one or more inlet gas exchange valves <b>9</b> and one or more outlet gas exchange valves <b>10</b>. There can likewise be provision for only one of the camshafts <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> to be equipped with a device <b>11</b>, or for only one camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> to be provided which is provided with a device <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> show a first embodiment of a device <b>11</b> according to the invention in longitudinal and transverse cross section. The device <b>11</b> has a phase setting device <b>12</b>, a camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> and a pressure accumulator <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The phase setting device <b>12</b> comprises a drive element <b>14</b>, an output element <b>16</b> and two side covers <b>17</b>, <b>18</b> which are arranged on the axial side faces of the drive element <b>14</b>. The output element <b>16</b> is configured in the form of an impeller wheel and has a substantially cylindrically configured hub element <b>19</b>, from the outer cylindrical circumferential face of which five vanes <b>20</b> extend in the radial direction to the outside in the embodiment which is shown.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Starting from an outer circumferential wall <b>21</b> of the drive element <b>14</b>, five projections <b>22</b> extend radially to the inside. In the embodiment which is shown, the projections <b>22</b> and the vanes <b>20</b> are configured integrally with the circumferential wall <b>21</b> and the hub element <b>19</b>, respectively. The drive element <b>14</b> is arranged such that it can be rotated with respect to the output element <b>16</b> by means of radially inner circumferential walls of the projections <b>22</b> relative to said output element <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A chain sprocket <b>23</b> is formed on an outer circumferential face of the drive element <b>14</b>, via which chain sprocket <b>23</b> torque can be transmitted from the crankshaft <b>2</b> to the drive element <b>14</b> by means of a chain drive (not shown). The output element <b>16</b> is connected fixedly to the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> so as to rotate with it. For this purpose, in the embodiment which is shown, a central screw <b>13</b> reaches through a central opening <b>16</b><i>a </i>of the output element <b>16</b> and engages into a threaded section <b>25</b> of the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>. Here, a shoulder of the central screw <b>13</b> bears against that side face of the output element <b>16</b> which faces away from the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In each case one of the side covers <b>17</b>, <b>18</b> is arranged on one of the axial side faces of the drive element <b>14</b> and is fixed firmly on the latter so as to rotate with it. For this purpose, an axial opening <b>26</b> is provided in each projection <b>22</b>. Furthermore, in each case five openings are provided in the side covers <b>17</b>, <b>18</b>, which openings are arranged in such a way that they are aligned with the axial openings <b>26</b>. In each ease one screw <b>27</b> reaches through an opening of the second side cover <b>18</b>, an axial opening <b>26</b> and an opening of the first side cover <b>17</b>. Here, a threaded section of the screw <b>27</b> engages into a threaded section which is formed in the opening of the first side cover <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A pressure space <b>28</b> is formed within the device <b>11</b> between in each case two projections <b>22</b> which are adjacent in the circumferential direction. Each of the pressure spaces <b>28</b> is delimited in the circumferential direction by substantially radially extending bounding walls <b>29</b>, which lie opposite one another, of adjacent projections <b>22</b>, in the axial direction by the side covers <b>17</b>, <b>18</b>, radially to the inside by the hub element <b>19</b> and radially to the outside by the circumferential wall <b>21</b>. A vane <b>20</b> protrudes into each of the pressure spaces <b>28</b>, the vanes <b>20</b> being configured in such a way that they bear both against the side covers <b>17</b>, <b>18</b> and against the circumferential wall <b>21</b>. Each vane <b>20</b> therefore divides the respective pressure space <b>28</b> into two pressure chambers <b>30</b>, <b>31</b> which act counter to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The output element <b>16</b> is arranged such that it can be rotated with respect to the drive element <b>14</b> in a defined angular range. The angular range is delimited in one rotational direction of the output element <b>16</b> by virtue of the fact that the vanes <b>20</b> come to bear against in each case one corresponding bounding wall <b>29</b> (early stop <b>32</b>) of the pressure spaces <b>28</b>. In an analogous manner, the angular range in the other rotational direction is delimited by virtue of the fact that the vanes <b>20</b> come to hear against the other bounding walls <b>29</b> of the pressure spaces <b>28</b>, which bounding walls <b>29</b> act as late stop <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">By loading one group of pressure chambers <b>30</b>, <b>31</b> with pressure and relieving the other group of pressure, the phase relation of the drive element <b>14</b> with respect to the output element <b>16</b> (and therefore the phase relation of the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> with respect to the crankshaft <b>2</b>) can be varied. The phase relation can be kept constant by loading both groups of pressure chambers <b>30</b>, <b>31</b> with pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the region of a camshaft bearing <b>39</b>, the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> has a plurality of openings <b>35</b>, via which the pressure medium which is delivered by a pressure medium pump <b>48</b> passes into the interior of said camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>. A pressure medium path <b>36</b> which communicates firstly with the openings <b>35</b> and secondly with the control valve <b>34</b> is formed within the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>. A control valve <b>34</b> is arranged in the interior of the central screw <b>13</b> in order to supply the phase setting device <b>12</b> with pressure medium. By means of the control valve <b>34</b>, pressure medium can be guided optionally to the first or second pressure chambers <b>30</b>, <b>31</b> and can be discharged from the respectively other pressure chambers <b>30</b>, <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">A pressure medium channel <b>37</b> which communicates firstly with the pressure medium path <b>36</b> and secondly with a cavity <b>38</b> of the camshaft <b>6</b>, <b>7</b> of hollow configuration is provided in the interior of the central screw <b>13</b>. The pressure medium channel <b>37</b> is configured as an axial hole which reaches through the threaded section of the central screw <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The pressure accumulator <b>15</b> is arranged in the cavity <b>38</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> show the pressure accumulator in the filled (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) and in the emptied state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). The pressure accumulator <b>15</b> comprises a housing <b>40</b>, a piston <b>41</b> and a force accumulator, a spring element <b>42</b> in the embodiment which is shown. The housing <b>40</b> is arranged within the cavity <b>38</b> and is connected fixedly to a wall <b>43</b> of the cavity <b>38</b>. In the embodiment which is shown, the outer circumferential face of the housing <b>40</b> is adapted to the wall <b>43</b> and is connected nonpositively to the latter. Embodiments are also conceivable, in which the housing <b>40</b> is connected to the wall <b>43</b> with a material to material fit or in a positive manner. In addition, the housing <b>40</b> can be fixed by means of a securing ring <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The piston <b>41</b> is arranged in the interior of the housing <b>40</b> such that it can be displaced axially, said piston <b>41</b> being of cup-shaped configuration in the embodiment which is shown. The entire housing <b>40</b> serves as guide section <b>44</b>, an inner circumferential face of the guide section <b>44</b> being configured as guide face <b>45</b> for a cylindrical section of the piston <b>41</b>. Here, the cylindrical section of the piston <b>41</b> can bear entirely or in regions against the guide face <b>45</b>. The outer circumferential face of the piston <b>41</b> is adapted to the guide face <b>45</b> in such a way that it divides the housing <b>40</b> into two regions axially in front of and behind the head of the piston <b>41</b> in a manner which is sealed with respect to pressure medium. The piston <b>41</b> is loaded with a force by means of the spring element <b>42</b> which is arranged in the region of the cylindrical section. The spring element <b>42</b> is supported on one side on a stop <b>46</b> which is formed at that end of the housing <b>40</b> which faces away from the phase setting device <b>12</b>, and on the other side on the head of the piston <b>41</b>. The spring element <b>42</b> therefore loads the piston <b>41</b> with a force in the direction of the pressure medium channel <b>37</b>. Here, the displacement travel of the piston <b>41</b> in the direction of the pressure medium channel <b>37</b> is delimited by a stop <b>46</b> which is formed at the end which faces the phase setting device <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In the embodiment which is shown, the housing <b>40</b> and the piston <b>41</b> are configured as sheet metal parts which are manufactured, for example, by a chipless manufacturing method, for example a deep drawing method. This has the advantage that the guide face <b>45</b> and the cylindrical section of the piston <b>41</b> can be manufactured so precisely by this shaping process that they do not have to be machined further. Expensive further machining steps of the wall <b>43</b> of the cavity <b>38</b> are also dispensed with as a result of the use of the housing <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a second embodiment of a pressure accumulator <b>15</b>. This has the difference from the first embodiment that the guide section <b>44</b> does not extend over the entire axial length of the housing <b>41</b> and does not bear against the wall <b>43</b> of the cavity <b>38</b>. The guide section <b>44</b> is adjoined in the axial direction by in each case one region <b>47</b> of increased diameter. Here, the outer circumferential faces of the regions <b>47</b> of increased diameter are adapted to the wall <b>43</b>. The nonpositive connection between the housing <b>40</b> and the wall <b>43</b> therefore exists only in the area of the regions <b>47</b> of increased diameter. As a result, a deformation of the guide face <b>45</b> during the operation of pressing the housing <b>40</b> into the cavity <b>38</b> is avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">During the operation of the internal combustion engine <b>1</b>, pressure medium is guided from the pressure medium pump <b>48</b> via the openings <b>35</b>, the pressure medium path <b>36</b> and the control valve <b>34</b> to the phase setting device <b>12</b>. Furthermore, pressure medium is guided via the openings <b>35</b>, the pressure medium path <b>36</b>, the pressure medium channel <b>37</b> and a housing opening <b>50</b> into the housing <b>40</b>. The pressure medium loads the piston <b>41</b> with a force, as a result of which said piston <b>41</b> is displaced axially counter to the force of the spring element <b>42</b>. The pressure accumulator <b>15</b> is filled (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). If the system pressure which is delivered by the pressure medium pump <b>48</b> drops, the force of the pressure medium on the piston <b>41</b> drops, as a result of which said piston <b>41</b> is displaced by the spring element <b>42</b> in the direction of the pressure medium channel <b>37</b> and therefore feeds pressure medium to the system. On account of a nonreturn valve <b>49</b>, the pressure medium is prevented from flowing back into the pressure medium system and is therefore completely available to the phase setting device <b>12</b>, as a result of which its response sensitivity and its adjusting speed are kept at a high level.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">LIST OF DESIGNATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0040"><b>1</b> Internal combustion engine</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0041"><b>2</b> Crankshaft</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0042"><b>3</b> Piston</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0043"><b>4</b> Cylinder</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0044"><b>5</b> Flexible drive</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0045"><b>6</b> Inlet camshaft</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0046"><b>7</b> Outlet camshaft</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0047"><b>8</b> Cam</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0048"><b>9</b> Inlet gas exchange valve</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0049"><b>10</b> Outlet gas exchange valve</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0050"><b>11</b> Device</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0051"><b>12</b> Phase setting device</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0052"><b>13</b> Central screw</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0053"><b>14</b> Drive element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0054"><b>15</b> Pressure accumulator</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0055"><b>16</b> Output element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0056"><b>16</b><i>a </i>Central opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0057"><b>17</b> Side cover</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0058"><b>18</b> Side cover</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0059"><b>19</b> Huh element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0060"><b>20</b> Vane</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0061"><b>21</b> Circumferential wall</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0062"><b>22</b> Projection</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0063"><b>23</b> Chain sprocket</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0064"><b>24</b> Securing ring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0065"><b>25</b> Threaded section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0066"><b>26</b> Axial opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0067"><b>27</b> Screw</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0068"><b>28</b> Pressure space</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0069"><b>29</b> Bounding wall</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0070"><b>30</b> First pressure chamber</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0071"><b>31</b> Second pressure chamber</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0072"><b>32</b> Early stop</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0073"><b>33</b> Late stop</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0035" num="0074"><b>34</b> Control valve</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0036" num="0075"><b>35</b> Openings</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0037" num="0076"><b>36</b> Pressure medium path</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0038" num="0077"><b>37</b> Pressure medium channel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0039" num="0078"><b>38</b> Cavity</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0040" num="0079"><b>39</b> Camshaft bearing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0041" num="0080"><b>40</b> Housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0042" num="0081"><b>41</b> Piston</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0043" num="0082"><b>42</b> Spring element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0044" num="0083"><b>43</b> Wall</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0045" num="0084"><b>44</b> Guide section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0046" num="0085"><b>45</b> Guide face</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0047" num="0086"><b>46</b> Stop</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0048" num="0087"><b>47</b> Region</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0049" num="0088"><b>48</b> Pressure medium pump</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0050" num="0089"><b>49</b> Nonreturn valve</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0051" num="0090"><b>50</b> Housing opening</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device for variably adjusting control times of gas exchange valves of an internal combustion engine having a crankshaft, comprising:
<claim-text>a hydraulic phase setting device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camshaft; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure accumulator, the phase setting device being connectable with the crankshaft by a drive connection, and said phase setting device being fixedly connected to the camshaft so as to rotate with the camshaft, a phase relation of the camshaft relative to the crankshaft being variably adjustable by the phase setting device, an interior of the camshaft having a cavity, wherein the pressure accumulator is arranged in the cavity and communicates with the phase setting device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the pressure accumulator includes a housing arranged in the cavity and a longitudinally displaceable piston guided in the housing, the housing is arranged in a stationary manner in the cavity by a connection between the housing and a radially outer wall of the cavity.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pressure accumulator includes a spring element that loads the piston with a force counter to a force of a pressure medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing includes at least one stop for limiting travel of the piston at least in one displacement direction of the piston.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing is arranged in a stationary manner in the cavity by a nonpositive connection between the housing and the radially outer wall of the cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing has a guide section and the piston has an outer circumferential face that is adapted to an inner circumferential face of the guide section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the guide section extends over an entire length of the piston.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the housing has a region of increased diameter at both axial ends of the guide section, outer circumferential faces of the increased diameter regions being adapted to a wail of the cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the camshaft is tubular. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
