<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627214-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627214</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12968983</doc-number>
<date>20101215</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>170</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20130101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>048</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715758</main-classification>
<further-classification>715755</further-classification>
<further-classification>715756</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e55">Inviting temporary participants to a virtual meeting or other communication session for a fixed duration</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6839417</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Weisman et al.</name>
<date>20050100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7804948</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Turner</name>
<date>20100900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0028199</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Carlson</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>379 9321</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0238156</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Turner</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>37920201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0077311</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Renneberg</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0086564</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Putman et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709227</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0189238</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gupta</name>
<date>20100700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>37920201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>2005077592</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>2008019087</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>Tran Tuan Anh, et al., &#x201c;Push to Talk over Cellular Traffic Modeling,&#x201d; 2006.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715755</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715756</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>715758</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120159353</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120621</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Beerse</last-name>
<first-name>Chelsea</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairport</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Denne</last-name>
<first-name>Arno</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dublin</city>
<country>IE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Sullivan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dublin</city>
<country>IE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>IE</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sloyer</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fishersville</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Beerse</last-name>
<first-name>Chelsea</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairport</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Denne</last-name>
<first-name>Arno</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dublin</city>
<country>IE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Sullivan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dublin</city>
<country>IE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="004" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sloyer</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fishersville</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Patents on Demand P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Buchheit</last-name>
<first-name>Brian K.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Garrett</last-name>
<first-name>Scott M.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>International Business Machines Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Leggett</last-name>
<first-name>Andrea</first-name>
<department>2171</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A session invitation can be received from a first communicator for a first communication session. The session invitation can be for a temporary participant to join a sub-session of the first communication session for a sub-session duration specified by the first communicator. The sub-session duration can be less than a duration of the first communication session. The session information can be conveyed to the temporary participant within a session invitation so that the sub-session duration is able to be presented to the temporary participant. Thus, the temporary participant is able to accept or deny the session invitation with full knowledge of the sub-session duration.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="267.38mm" wi="206.08mm" file="US08627214-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="272.12mm" wi="204.98mm" file="US08627214-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="270.51mm" wi="209.21mm" file="US08627214-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="250.11mm" wi="203.28mm" file="US08627214-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to the field of real-time communications and virtual meetings.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Many communication solutions today leverage information technology (IT) and telephony assets to improve collaboration and business processes. Advances in communicating via voice, video, and data on IP networks are fundamentally transforming the way people work. For instance, use of virtual meetings, online collaboration, Instant Messaging, video conferencing, voice conferencing, and the like have proven to be efficient substitutes for in-person meetings. The convenience of today's communication tools can result in increased contacts among a set of remotely located people. If improperly used, these increased contacts and communications can represent a set of interruptions, which may hamper a person's ability to conduct daily business transactions.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">One aspect of the disclosure can include a method, computer program product, apparatus, and system. In this aspect, a session invitation can be received from a first communicator for a first communication session. The session invitation can be for a temporary participant to join a sub-session of the first communication session for a sub-session duration specified by the first communicator. The sub-session duration can be less than a duration of the first communication session. The session information can be conveyed to the temporary participant within a session invitation so that the sub-session duration is able to be presented to the temporary participant. Thus, the temporary participant is able to accept or deny the session invitation with full knowledge of the sub-session duration. The temporary participant can respond by accepting the session invitation. This invitation response can be received, where the response indicates that the temporary participant has elected to join the first communication for the sub-session duration. In response, the temporary participant can be joined to the first communication session. Duration information can be provided to at least the first communicator and the temporary participant so that a count-down for the sub-session duration is able to be presented upon user interfaces of the first communicator and the temporary participant. A time that the sub-session duration ends (and/or an event indicating the end of the sub-session duration) can be determined. Responsive to this determination, the temporary participant can be automatically removed from the first communication session.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">One aspect of the disclosure can include a computer program product and/or user device having a user interface. The user interface can be one through which a user is able to participate in real-time communication sessions conducted with sets of one or more remotely located people. The user interface can include an invitation acceptance screen, a bidirectional communication component, a countdown screen, an auto-termination component, and/or the like. As used herein, screen is used to present a user interface element, which can include a graphical user interface element, a text user interface element, a voice user interface element, and the like. A screen can be a specific division of a display or voice prompt, or can be integrated with other interface components.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the aspect, the invitation acceptance screen can present a session duration at a time of prompting a user to accept or deny an invitation to join an ongoing communication session. The session duration can represent a duration which the user is to be part of the ongoing communication session should the user accept the invitation. The bidirectional communication component can permit the user to bidirectionally communicate during the ongoing communication session. The user can be automatically joined to the ongoing communication session responsive to acceptance of an invitation via the invitation acceptance screen. The countdown screen can present a user with a continually decrementing countdown time representing an amount left in the session duration. The countdown screen can be presented to a user during the ongoing communication session conducted through the bidirectional communication component. The auto-termination component can automatically disconnect the user from the ongoing communication session at a time that the session duration expires.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a diagram in which an invitation to a virtual meeting or other real time communication is conveyed and accepted, where the invitation is subject to a fixed duration.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a flow chart of a method for communication sub-sessions of fixed durations in accordance with an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a system for implementing communication sub-sessions having fixed durations in accordance with an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">With advances in communication tools, such as unified telephony, video meeting, video conferencing, online collaboration, and the like, comes a downside of increased interruptions. That is, an improved ability to remotely communicate in a cost effective manner leads directly to increased interruptions during a workday. Improved tools are needed to manage communications that minimize interruptions. The need for these tools is only expected to increase as collaborative practices, virtual networking, social networking, and other communication technologies grow.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The disclosure presents a communication tool that adds an ability to include a fixed duration with a communication invitation for a virtual meeting or other real-time communication session. This fixed duration can be established by a person initiating the invitation and can be presented to the receiver of the invitation. In one embodiment, the receiver of the invitation can renegotiate the fixed duration. The fixed duration can be for less than the duration of the virtual meeting. In one embodiment, the invitation can be conveyed during the virtual meeting and/or at a time the invitee is engaged in a different conference, virtual meeting, or other real time communication. When the invitee accepts the fixed duration invitation, any pending communication can be placed on hold, to be automatically resumed at the end of the fixed duration. In one embodiment, a countdown of the fixed duration can be presented to the invitee and to participants of any affected communication.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It should be appreciated that the disclosure permits a temporary participant to be guaranteed a duration before agreeing to enter a communication session. This capability can be extremely beneficial in many scenarios, such as permitting an expert jump into a virtual meeting, provide needed expertise, and jump out of virtual meeting all while keeping interruptions to the flow of the meeting and to the interruptions to the expert's schedule to a minimum.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one embodiment, decisions can be made about whether or not an existing communication is to be interrupted based on a computed relative importance level (or priority) of each communication. For example, if an existing communication is determined to be more important than one for which an interruption is being requested, the interruption may be denied immediately by a system (e.g., never presented to a user). In another example, if an incoming communication is significantly more important that an existing one, an automated system may automatically accept the interruption for the designated duration. Moreover, one embodiment of the disclosure can leverage knowledge about a hierarchical organization to determine relative importance of communications. For example, a higher priority can be established based on organizational identity (e.g., a vice president of an organization having a greater priority than a mid-level manager) and a determination to interrupt an existing communication can be based on whether the incoming communication has a higher priority than the existing one.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art, aspects of the present invention may be embodied as a system, method or computer program product. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may take the form of an entirely hardware embodiment, an entirely software embodiment (including firmware, resident software, micro-code, etc.) or an embodiment combining software and hardware aspects that may all generally be referred to herein as a &#x201c;circuit,&#x201d; &#x201c;module&#x201d; or &#x201c;system.&#x201d; Furthermore, aspects of the present invention may take the form of a computer program product embodied in one or more computer readable medium(s) having computer readable program code embodied thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Any combination of one or more computer readable medium(s) may be utilized. The computer readable medium may be a computer readable signal medium or a computer readable storage medium. A computer readable storage medium may be, for example, but not limited to, an electronic, magnetic, optical, electromagnetic, infrared, or semiconductor system, apparatus, or device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing. More specific examples (a non-exhaustive list) of the computer readable storage medium would include the following: an electrical connection having one or more wires, a portable computer diskette, a hard disk, a random access memory (RAM), a read-only memory (ROM), an erasable programmable read-only memory (EPROM or Flash memory), an optical fiber, a portable compact disc read-only memory (CD-ROM), an optical storage device, a magnetic storage device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing. In the context of this document, a computer readable storage medium may be any tangible medium that can contain, or store a program for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A computer readable signal medium may include a propagated data signal with computer readable program code embodied therein, for example, in baseband or as part of a carrier wave. Such a propagated signal may take any of a variety of forms, including, but not limited to, electro-magnetic, optical, or any suitable combination thereof. A computer readable signal medium may be any computer readable medium that is not a computer readable storage medium and that can communicate, propagate, or transport a program for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Program code embodied on a computer readable medium may be transmitted using any appropriate medium, including but not limited to wireless, wireline, optical fiber cable, RF, etc., or any suitable combination of the foregoing. Computer program code for carrying out operations for aspects of the present invention may be written in any combination of one or more programming languages, including an object oriented programming language such as Java, Smalltalk, C++ or the like and conventional procedural programming languages, such as the &#x201c;C&#x201d; programming language or similar programming languages. The program code may execute entirely on the user's computer, partly on the user's computer, as a stand-alone software package, partly on the user's computer and partly on a remote computer or entirely on the remote computer or server. In the latter scenario, the remote computer may be connected to the user's computer through any type of network, including a local area network (LAN) or a wide area network (WAN), or the connection may be made to an external computer (for example, through the Internet using an Internet Service Provider).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Aspects of the present invention are described below with reference to flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams of methods, apparatus (systems) and computer program products according to embodiments of the invention. It will be understood that each block of the flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams, and combinations of blocks in the flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams, can be implemented by computer program instructions. These computer program instructions may be provided to a processor of a general purpose computer, special purpose computer, or other programmable data processing apparatus to produce a machine, such that the instructions, which execute via the processor of the computer or other programmable data processing apparatus, create means for implementing the functions/acts specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">These computer program instructions may also be stored in a computer readable medium that can direct a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to function in a particular manner, such that the instructions stored in the computer readable medium produce an article of manufacture including instructions which implement the function/act specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The computer program instructions may also be loaded onto a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to cause a series of operational steps to be performed on the computer, other programmable apparatus or other devices to produce a computer implemented process such that the instructions which execute on the computer or other programmable apparatus provide processes for implementing the functions/acts specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a diagram <b>100</b> in which an invitation <b>150</b> to a virtual meeting or other real time communication is conveyed and accepted, where the invitation is subject to a fixed duration. More specifically, in diagram <b>100</b>, a set of users <b>120</b>-<b>124</b> communicate with one another over a network through computing devices <b>110</b>-<b>114</b>. Each computing device <b>110</b>-<b>114</b> can provide a user interface <b>130</b>, <b>150</b>, <b>170</b>, <b>180</b> through which user (users <b>120</b>-<b>124</b>) to machine (device <b>110</b>-<b>114</b>) interactions occur. The communications can occur in real-time or near real time in one embodiment of the disclosure. Further, the different user interfaces <b>130</b>, <b>150</b>, <b>170</b>, <b>180</b> can utilize any of a plurality of different modalities when communicating, such as voice, graphical, textual, video, data, and the like. Communication modalities used by two different communicating users (<b>120</b>-<b>124</b>) may or may not be the same. In one embodiment, different options or actions can depend upon an importance level of a communication or set of communications. Thus, different reactions and actions can result, which bias the telephony system to favor more important communications over those of lesser import.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, user <b>120</b> (e.g., Alice) uses a unified telephony interface <b>130</b> functioning in an instant messaging mode. User <b>120</b> (e.g., Joe) uses a voice interface for communicating via voice and a visual display <b>172</b> for providing additional information. User <b>124</b> (e.g., Sue) uses a voice user interface <b>180</b>. It is contemplated in the disclosure that different interfaces and devices <b>110</b>-<b>114</b> than those shown in diagram <b>100</b> can be used by any of the users <b>120</b>-<b>124</b>, and the disclosure is not to be construed as limited in this regard.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The diagram <b>100</b> illustrates that an initial communication session (virtual meeting, voice conference, video conference, instant messaging session, chat session, co-browsing session, etc.) can be conducted with a set of people that includes user <b>120</b> (e.g., Alice) and that does not include user <b>122</b> (e.g., Joe) or <b>124</b> (e.g., Sue). During the meeting, a need or desire to temporarily include user <b>122</b> (e.g., Joe) to the session as a temporary participant can arise. User <b>120</b> can select an invite <b>131</b> option from interface <b>130</b>, which results in a pop-up window <b>132</b> being presented.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In window <b>132</b>, Joe Smith <b>134</b> is selected as an invitee. Different contact mechanisms for communicating with the invitee can be provided, as shown by graphical user interface (GUI) element <b>136</b>. For example, Joe Smith (invitee <b>134</b>) can be asked to join the communication session by phone, video conference, chat, voice chat, virtual meeting, and the like. In one embodiment, contact information for Joe Smith for specific devices and/or type of communication can be managed and utilized (e.g., from a master contact list) so that user <b>120</b> need not specify specific contact information (e.g., phone number, IM user name, video conference IP address, etc.). In another embodiment, user <b>120</b> may have to explicitly specify the address, phone number, or other identifier for a specific communication device <b>113</b>, <b>112</b> associated with the invitee (e.g., Joe Smith).</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">User <b>120</b> can further specify a fixed duration <b>138</b> for the Joe Smith <b>134</b> to join the session. Effectively the fixed duration <b>138</b> can represent a sub-session, which occurs as part of the main session. Another option within window <b>132</b> can be to provide overview data or not along with the invitation. Further, user <b>120</b> can provide additional manually specified comments <b>142</b>. A send <b>144</b> option can cause the invitation to be sent. Selection of the cancel option <b>146</b> can result in the invitation not being sent.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It should be understood that the options of window <b>132</b> are not intended to be comprehensive. For example, the window <b>132</b> can schedule a future time for the invitation. That is, the sub-session can begin at a user <b>120</b> designated start time and/or end at a user <b>120</b> designated start time (the end time can also be inferred from the duration <b>138</b>. In one embodiment, a default time for the duration <b>138</b> can be programmatically determined. For example, it can be based on the comments <b>142</b>, the purpose of the sub meeting, historical records, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The invited user <b>122</b> (e.g., Joe Smith) can receive the invitation via a user interface <b>150</b> of computing device <b>113</b>. The user interface can present (visually and/or audibly, depending on interface <b>150</b> modality) the comment <b>152</b> (corresponds to comment <b>142</b>) about the sub-meeting, a duration <b>152</b> (initially corresponds to duration <b>138</b>), as well as meeting details <b>156</b> (assuming option <b>140</b> for presenting session overview was elected).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In one embodiment, the invitee <b>122</b> can change the duration <b>154</b> or other sub-meeting specifics before accepting the invitation. Accepting the invitation can be an immediate acceptance (through a selection of option <b>160</b>, for example) or a delayed acceptance (through a selection of option <b>162</b>, for example). When acceptance is delayed, a delay time can be specified, such as by selecting or inputting a delay time in GUI element <b>164</b>. User <b>122</b> may also choose a refuse option <b>166</b> to refuse the invitation to the sub-session. User <b>122</b> provided comments <b>168</b> can be included in a refusal or an acceptance in one embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In one scenario, the user <b>122</b> can be engaged in a different communication session at an overlapping time with the sub-session. For example, Joe Smith can be talking via real-time voice with sue <b>124</b> at the time the invitation for an immediate sub-session with Alice <b>120</b> arrives. The device <b>113</b> upon which the invitation is presented may be the same or a different device <b>112</b> than that used to communicate with sue <b>124</b> or than the device <b>112</b> that is to be used to join the communication sub-session with Alice <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The participant(s) of the existing conversation (e.g., Sue <b>124</b>) can be presented with a message <b>182</b> that their session with Joe Smith <b>122</b> has been temporarily interrupted for the duration <b>184</b>. A count-down of the duration <b>184</b> can be shown in their interface <b>180</b>. This count-down <b>184</b> can be time-synched with a count-down <b>174</b>, <b>175</b> displayed to Joe Smith <b>122</b> and a count-down timer <b>184</b> displayed to each user <b>120</b> (e.g., Alice, Jake, etc.) of the sub-session. When the count-down timer ends, the Joe Smith <b>122</b> can be automatically disconnected from the sub-session (with Alice <b>120</b>, and Jake) and Joe Smith <b>122</b> can automatically rejoin the interrupted communication session with Sue <b>124</b>. In one embodiment, the count-down timer the sending of notification messages of the countdown, of the meeting interruption message, call (or communication session) establishment, halting, and resumption, and the like can be handled by a communication system with minimal to no manual user (<b>120</b>-<b>124</b>) actions being required.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Diagram <b>100</b> shows that a communication system can dynamically transcode or convert communication streams from one format to another during either of the communication sessions (the session with Sue <b>124</b> and/or the sub-session with Alice <b>120</b>), in one embodiment. For example, user <b>122</b> can hear text <b>182</b> input by Alice <b>120</b> via an interface <b>130</b> as audible output <b>177</b> from a speaker <b>176</b>. The user <b>122</b> can speak <b>178</b> into a microphone <b>179</b>, where the spoken content is displayed as text <b>185</b> in interface <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a flow chart of a method <b>200</b> for communication sub-sessions (e.g., the sub-session involving Alice <b>120</b>, Joe <b>122</b>, and Jake in diagram <b>100</b>) of fixed durations in accordance with an embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Method <b>200</b> can begin in step <b>210</b>, where a duration for a sub-session can be specified for a specific temporary participant (e.g., user <b>122</b> of diagram <b>100</b>). In step <b>212</b>, an invitation can be sent to the temporary participant for the sub-session. In step <b>214</b>, the invitation having the established duration can be presented to the temporary participant.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In step <b>216</b>, the temporary participant can opt to renegotiate specifics of the sub-session. The renegotiated specifics can include, for example, the sub-session duration, start time, participant set, modality or device with which the temporary participant joins the sub-session, and the like. In one embodiment, whenever specifics are renegotiated, these changes can be conveyed back to the inviter, who may agree, disagree, make further changes, and the like, which are eventually agreed upon by all necessary parties. In step <b>218</b>, sub-session specifics can be changed to reflect the renegotiated ones.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In step <b>220</b>, the invitation may or may not be denied by the temporary participant. If the invitation is denied, the refusal and any associated comments provided by the invitee can be provided to the inviter, as shown by step <b>222</b>. If the temporary participant does not accept the invitation in step <b>224</b> and has not denied the invitation in step <b>220</b>, a time-out period for responding can occur, as shown by step <b>228</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">If the invitation is accepted in step <b>224</b>, the method <b>200</b> can progress to step <b>230</b>, where the temporary participant may or may not be participating in an existing communication session. If there is an existing communication session, the parties of that session can be notified of the interruption, the duration of the interruption, and/or may be provided other information (e.g., the reason for the interruption), as represented by step <b>232</b>. In step <b>234</b>, the existing communication session can be halted for the duration or may continue without the temporary participant for the duration. A count-down expressing the duration can be optionally shown to participants of the existing communication session.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Regardless of whether an existing communication session is interrupted, the temporary participant can join the sub-session in step <b>236</b>. As the sub-session progresses, a count-down until the end of the duration of the sub-session can be updated and optionally shown, as shown by step <b>238</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">During this sub-session, one or more of the participants of the sub-session (e.g., sub-session moderator, temporary participant, etc.) may opt to change the duration of the sub-session, as shown by step <b>240</b>. Changing this duration, may or may not require authorization by affected users (such as the temporary participant, a sub-session moderator, a leader of the interrupted session, etc.) depending on implementation specifics. When the sub-session specifics are changed, suitable changes to the count-down timer can be made and messages concerning the change can be sent to affected parties, as represented by step <b>242</b>. Eventually, the count-down timer can expire (shown by progressing from step <b>244</b> to step <b>246</b>), at which time the sub-session can end and the temporary participant can be disconnected from the sub-session, as shown by step <b>246</b>. Other participants of the communication session, which the temporary participant joined, can continue with their session (which the temporary participant has been disconnected from) at this point. If there was an interrupted existing communication session (step <b>250</b>), the temporary participant can resume his/her participation in this interrupted session automatically, as shown by step <b>254</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In one embodiment of the invention, a relative importance level of a conversation can affect specifics performed by method <b>200</b>. The relative importance level of a conversation can be based on a variety of factors. One of these factors can include knowledge about hierarchical information of an organization. For example, if a vice-president invites a user to be a temporary participant in a conference, the method can show this invitation as having a high priority and indicate the user needs to join this conference regardless of other pending matters. Other factors can relate to specific content of the conversations, urgency levels established by conference initiators, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To elaborate, if a temporary participant is requested by a manager in his/her direct chain, options to renegotiate (step <b>216</b>) can be intentionally limited. The contrary is true, in that very expansive options to renegotiate (step <b>216</b>) can be provided to a user who is an organizational superior to the person issuing an invitation. Similarly, in one embodiment, automatically computed durations of a sub-session, a decision of whether to even show an invitation when a temporary participant is engaged in an existing communication, decisions regarding breadth and details of interruptions to present to others, and the like can vary based on relative importance values computed for communications and/or communication participants.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a system <b>300</b> for implementing communication sub-sessions having fixed durations in accordance with an embodiment of the disclosure. In one embodiment, system <b>300</b> can be a system that implements method <b>200</b>. For example, an application server <b>360</b> can implement a fixed duration for a communication sub-session in which a temporary participant communicates with other session participants.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In system <b>300</b>, a set of user devices <b>310</b> can be connected to a network <b>320</b>. A number of servers, including a wireless network server <b>330</b>, a telephony server <b>332</b>, communication server(s) <b>340</b>, and application server <b>360</b> can also be connected to the network <b>320</b>. Various users of devices <b>310</b> can communicate with one another via the user interfaces <b>312</b> of the devices. These communications can be facilitated by one or more of the servers <b>330</b>-<b>360</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The user device(s) <b>310</b> can include phones, mobile phones, personal computers, media players, internet applicants, two-way radios, instant messaging terminals, and the like. Basically, a user device <b>310</b> can be any device through which a user (e.g., Alice, Joe Smith, Jake, Sue, etc. from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) can interact. Different user devices <b>310</b> can include different types of user interfaces, such as a text user interface (TUI), a voice user interface (VUI), a graphical user interface (GUI), a multimodal interface, and the like. Thus, users can communicate via user interfaces <b>312</b> in different modalities, such as voice, text, video, interactive Web, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">To elaborate, zero or more of the devices <b>310</b> can directly connect to a wireless network <b>322</b>, such as a WIFI network, a WIMAX network, a mobile telephony network, a two-way-radio network, and the like. The wireless network server <b>330</b> can be connected to a backbone, such as Internet Protocol (IP) network <b>326</b>. In one embodiment, the wireless server <b>330</b> can include carrier grade equipment. In another embodiment, the wireless server can include home grade equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Zero or more of the devices <b>310</b> can be customer premise equipment (CPE) directly connected to the public switched telephone network (PSTN) <b>324</b>. In one embodiment, the telephony server <b>332</b> can include carrier grade equipment, which links calls and other communications conducted over the PSTN <b>324</b> to an IP backbone <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Zero or more of the devices <b>310</b> can be internet enabled devices, which connect directly to an IP network <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The different communication servers <b>340</b> can be used to conduct numerous types of different communication sessions, such as instant messaging (IM) sessions, chat sessions, telephony sessions, voice over internet protocol (VoIP) sessions, video teleconferencing, co-browsing, and the like. The communication sessions can include real-time communication sessions in one embodiment. The different communication servers <b>340</b> that facilitate communications between user devices <b>310</b> can include an instant messaging (IM) server <b>342</b>, a virtual meeting (or online meeting) server <b>344</b>, a video conferencing server <b>346</b>, a presence server <b>348</b>, a Web server, a unified telephony server, a chat server, and the like. The various servers <b>342</b>, <b>344</b>, <b>346</b>, <b>348</b> can each utilize information stored in a corresponding data store <b>343</b>, <b>345</b>, <b>347</b>, and <b>349</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The application server <b>360</b> can interact with a set of different communication servers <b>340</b> in order to connect user devices <b>310</b> to a communication session, to disconnect a user from a communication session, to establish a communication session, to halt a communication session, and to perform other such actions. In one embodiment, the application server <b>360</b> can utilize application program interfaces (APIs) or other interfaces to convey data and commands to and from the various communication servers <b>340</b>. In one embodiment, the application server <b>360</b> can be a JAVA 2 ENTERPRISE EDITION (J2EE) server and the functionality that permits duration specified sub-sessions for one or more of the communication servers <b>340</b> can be implemented as a software service (e.g., a Web service).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The application server <b>360</b> can include an invitation handler <b>362</b>, a session manager <b>364</b>, a notifier <b>366</b>, a duration engine <b>368</b>, and/or other components. Although the functionality of components <b>362</b>, <b>364</b>, <b>366</b>, and <b>368</b> is shown as being implemented within application server <b>360</b> this is not a limitation of the disclosure. That is, in various embodiments, the functionality of one or more of the components <b>362</b>, <b>364</b>, <b>366</b>, and <b>368</b> can be implemented by the communication servers <b>340</b> and/or a portion of the functionality can be implemented within one of the user devices <b>310</b> or within any device connected to network <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The invitation handler <b>362</b> can handle specifics for sending invitations from one user device <b>310</b> to another user device <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The session manager <b>364</b> can handle details and make changes to communication sessions managed by the communication server(s) <b>340</b>. For example, the session manager <b>364</b> can add a user device <b>310</b> or remove a user device <b>310</b> to an existing session without terminating the session. In one embodiment, the session manager <b>364</b> can automatically remove one of the user devices <b>310</b> from a communication session when a fixed duration expires. In one embodiment, the session manager <b>364</b> can halt a communication session, pause a communication session, establish a communication session, and the like for one or more of the communication servers <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The notifier <b>366</b> can convey messages to and from the communication servers <b>340</b> in a format that each communication server accepts. In one embodiment, different plug-ins can be required for at least a portion of the communication servers <b>340</b> to facilitate the communication of messages. In one embodiment, the notifier <b>366</b> can utilize pop-up messages, voice messages, or messages conveyed within communication applications (using APIs of the applications for message-conveyances).</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The duration engine <b>368</b> can establish a fixed duration for a sub-session. Further, the duration engine <b>368</b> can establish rules for extending a sub-session duration, such as requiring authorization before extensions of a sub-session are permitted. The duration engine <b>368</b> can establish a time at which a sub-session is to start and end. In one embodiment, the duration engine <b>368</b> can convey count-down notifications (with the cooperation of notifier <b>368</b>) related to the duration and/or changes to the duration of a sub-session.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Data store <b>370</b> can maintain information used by the application server <b>360</b>, which is related to the duration of a sub-session. For example, data store <b>370</b> can maintain information in a set of tables <b>380</b>, <b>390</b> or other data structure. This information can include a use-session table <b>380</b>, which includes records that relate users <b>382</b> to sessions <b>384</b>. The information can indicate whether a communication session is a sub-session <b>386</b> or not, where a sub-session indicates a participant is to be automatically removed after a duration <b>389</b>. Each record can further include a start time <b>388</b> for the session or sub-session.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Records of table <b>380</b> can be indexed against records maintained by other tables <b>392</b>-<b>395</b>. For example, a user-device table <b>392</b> can maintain which set of devices <b>310</b> correspond to which user names/identities. A session-server table <b>393</b> can indicate which communication server <b>340</b> manages which of the communication sessions (<b>384</b>) and can include server-specific information for communicating between application server <b>360</b> and the related communication server <b>340</b>. A conversion table <b>394</b> can indicate a manner in which communication data content (e.g., streams or other data) are to be converted when conveyed between user devices <b>310</b>. The conversation table <b>394</b> can, for example, indicate IP addresses of text-to-speech servers, speech-to-text servers, and callable services for performing conversions during communication sessions. The schedule table <b>395</b> can include information related to schedules of users of devices <b>310</b>. Schedules in any of the tables <b>395</b> can be affected by the interruptions represented by the sub-sessions. In one embodiment, sub-sessions can be scheduled in advance, such as using a meeting scheduling program, a task management program, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Each data store <b>343</b>, <b>345</b>, <b>347</b>, <b>349</b> and <b>370</b> can be physically implemented within any type of hardware including, but not limited to, a magnetic disk, an optical disk, a semiconductor memory, a digitally encoded plastic memory, a holographic memory, or any other recording medium. The data stores can be a stand-alone storage unit as well as a storage unit formed from a plurality of physical devices, which may be remotely located from one another. Additionally, information can be stored within each data store in a variety of manners. For example, information can be stored within a database structure or can be stored within one or more files of a file storage system, where each file may or may not be indexed for information searching purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The flowchart and block diagrams in the Figures illustrate the architecture, functionality, and operation of possible implementations of systems, methods and computer program products according to various embodiments of the present invention. In this regard, each block in the flowchart or block diagrams may represent a module, segment, or portion of code, which comprises one or more executable instructions for implementing the specified logical function(s). It should also be noted that, in some alternative implementations, the functions noted in the block may occur out of the order noted in the figures. For example, two blocks shown in succession may, in fact, be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved. It will also be noted that each block of the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, and combinations of blocks in the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, can be implemented by special purpose hardware-based systems that perform the specified functions or acts, or combinations of special purpose hardware and computer instructions.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A computer program product comprising a computer readable storage medium having computer usable program code embodied therewith, the computer usable program code comprising:
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to receive a session invitation from a first communicator for a first communication session, wherein said session invitation is for a temporary participant to join a sub-session of the first communication session for a sub-session duration specified by the first communicator, said sub-session duration being less than a duration of the first communication session;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to convey the session information within a session invitation to the temporary participant, so the temporary participant is able to accept or deny the session invitation with knowledge of the sub-session duration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to receive an invitation response from the temporary participant that indicates the temporary participant has elected to join the first communication for the sub-session duration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to, responsive to the invitation response and at a time that the sub-session is to start, join the temporary participant to the first communication session;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to provide sub-session duration information to at least the first communicator and the temporary participant so that a count-down for the sub-session duration is able to be presented upon user interfaces of the first communicator and the temporary participant during the sub-session;</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to determine a time at which the sub-session duration has ended; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to, responsive to determining that the sub-session duration has ended, automatically remove the temporary participant from the first communication session.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the temporary participant is participating in a second communication session at the time that the sub-session is to start, said computer program product comprising:
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to disconnect the temporary participant from the second communication session without terminating the second communication session; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to, in response to automatically removing the temporary participant from the first communication session, automatically reconnect the temporary participant to the second communication session.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said computer program product further comprising computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to manage the sub-session based, at least in part, upon an importance level of the sub-session, wherein the importance level of the sub-session depends on one or more of: content of the sub-session, participants in the sub-session, urgency level of the sub-session.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the session invitation received by the temporary participant indicates that the temporary participant is desired to immediately join the first communication session, wherein the joining of the temporary participant to the first communication session is able to result in an approximate immediate joining if the invitation response so indicates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation response comprises a time delay specified by the temporary participant, said computer program product further comprising:
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to convey the time delay to the first communicator so that it is able to be presented via a user interface to the first communicator to inform the first communicator of the time delay; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to join the temporary participant to the first communication session for the sub-session duration at a time at which the time delay occurs.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation response comprises a different sub-session duration from that contained in the session invitation, wherein the different sub-session duration is specified by the temporary participant, said computer program product further comprising:
<claim-text>computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to change the sub-session duration to the different sub-session duration, wherein the determination that the sub-session has ended occurs upon the different sub-session duration expiring.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said computer program product further comprising computer usable program code stored on a storage medium that upon being executed by a processor is operable to programmatically determine the sub-session duration.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A system comprising a processor, storage medium, a communication bus connecting the storage medium to the processor, and at least one computer program product digitally encoded on the storage medium and able to be executed by the processor, wherein the processor is operable to execute the at least one computer program product to cause the system to:
<claim-text>receive a session invitation from a first communicator for a first communication session, wherein said session invitation is for a temporary participant to join a sub-session of the first communication session for a sub-session duration specified by the first communicator, said sub-session duration being less than a duration of the first communication session;</claim-text>
<claim-text>convey the session information within a session invitation to the temporary participant, so the temporary participant is able to accept or deny the session invitation with knowledge of the sub-session duration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive an invitation response from the temporary participant that indicates the temporary participant has elected to join the first communication for the sub-session duration;</claim-text>
<claim-text>join the temporary participant to the first communication session responsive to the invitation response and at a time that the sub-session is to start;</claim-text>
<claim-text>provide sub-session duration information to at least the first communicator and the temporary participant so that a count-down for the sub-session duration is able to be presented upon user interfaces of the first communicator and the temporary participant during the sub-session;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine time at which the sub-session duration has ended; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>automatically remove the temporary participant from the first communication session responsive to determining that the sub-session duration has ended.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the temporary participant is participating in a second communication session at the time that the sub-session is to start, said processor further causes the system to:
<claim-text>disconnect the temporary participant from the second communication session without terminating the second communication session; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to automatically removing the temporary participant from the first communication session, automatically reconnect the temporary participant to the second communication session.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first communication session utilizes a first communication server and wherein the second communication session utilizes a second communication server.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A computer program product able to be stored upon a storage medium and to be executed by a processor, said computer program product comprising:
<claim-text>a user interface through which a user is able to participate in real-time communication sessions conducted with sets of one or more remotely located people, said user interface comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>an invitation acceptance screen operable to present a sub-session duration when prompting a user to accept or deny an invitation to join a sub-session of an ongoing communication session, wherein the sub-session duration represents a duration which the user is to be part of the ongoing communication session should the user accept the invitation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bidirectional communication component for permitting said user to bidirectionally communicate during the ongoing communication session, wherein the user is automatically joined to the ongoing communication session responsive to acceptance of an invitation via the invitation acceptance screen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a countdown screen operable to present a user with a continually decrementing countdown time representing an amount left in the sub-session duration, where the countdown screen is presented to a user during the sub-session conducted through the bidirectional communication component; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an auto-termination component configured to automatically disconnect the user from the ongoing communication session when the sub-session duration expires.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises an option to input a different duration from the sub-session duration for the invitation presented through the invitation acceptance screen, wherein a user is able to conditionally accept the invitation via the invitation acceptance screen with the different duration instead of the sub-session duration that was defined by a person who issued the invitation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises a default device that is to be joined to the communication session upon accepting the invitation via the invitation acceptance screen.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises a designated device for joining the ongoing communication session upon acceptance of the invitation, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises an option through which a user is able to select a different device than the designated one for joining the ongoing communication session upon acceptance of the invitation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises an option through which the user is able to specify a delay time representing a time for joining the user to the ongoing communication session upon acceptance of the invitation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is a unified telephony user interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is an online meeting user interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is one of a video conference user interface, a voice over internet protocol (VoIP) interface, and a teleconference interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the user interface is one of an instant messaging interface, an online chat interface, and a voice chat interface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The computer program product of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the invitation acceptance screen comprises an option to re-negotiate one or more participants of the ongoing communication session, wherein a user is able to conditionally accept the invitation via the invitation acceptance screen with a re-negotiated participant set. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
