<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626042-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626042</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13106360</doc-number>
<date>20110512</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-111239</doc-number>
<date>20100513</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>244</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>01</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399301</main-classification>
<further-classification>399 49</further-classification>
<further-classification>399 74</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Detecting apparatus and image forming apparatus including the same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5083161</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Borton et al.</name>
<date>19920100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>399 49</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-089540</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20000300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-055497</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 49</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 72</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 73</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399 74</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>399301</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>12</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110280595</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20111117</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Naito</last-name>
<first-name>Yuuta</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Naito</last-name>
<first-name>Yuuta</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rossi, Kimms &#x26; McDowell LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ngo</last-name>
<first-name>Hoang</first-name>
<department>2852</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Provided is a detecting apparatus including an illumination optical system for emitting an image bearing member with a light beam emitted from a light source unit, an imaging optical system including an imaging optical element for imaging an image on the surface of the image bearing member, a light receiving unit for detecting the image on the image bearing member which has been imaged by the imaging optical system, and a calculation unit for detecting image information on the image on the image bearing member from a detection signal received from the light receiving unit. In the detecting apparatus, at least one optical plane of the imaging optical element is configured to refract an imaging system principal ray after passing therethrough in a direction of farther becoming apart from the light source unit than the imaging system principal ray before passing through the optical plane.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="156.97mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="161.88mm" wi="162.56mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="127.42mm" wi="160.70mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="244.09mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="138.68mm" wi="142.07mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="164.17mm" wi="125.81mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="209.89mm" wi="128.02mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="245.62mm" wi="157.99mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="211.41mm" wi="159.77mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="134.11mm" wi="147.24mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="242.23mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="143.59mm" wi="174.75mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="220.30mm" wi="173.57mm" file="US08626042-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a detecting apparatus used for an image forming apparatus such as a copier, a printer, or a facsimile, to which an electrophotographic process or an electrostatic recording process is applied. In particular, the present invention relates to an image information detection apparatus, which is suited for detecting image information on a pattern image for position detection formed on an image bearing member.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In a conventional image forming apparatus for obtaining a multiple color image, images having different colors are formed in multiple image forming sections, paper is conveyed by a conveyer unit such as a conveyer belt, and the images are transferred onto the paper while being overlapped, to thereby perform multiple color image formation. In a case of obtaining a full color image by performing multiple color developing, even a slight overlap positional deviation of the paper deteriorates image quality. For example, in a case of a resolution of 400 dpi, one pixel is set to 63.5 &#x3bc;m, and even an overlap positional deviation of a fraction of this value appears as a change of a color misregistration or a color drift and significantly deteriorates an image.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the initial stage of development of a color image forming apparatus, the multiple color developing is performed by optical scanning with a single image forming section, that is, an image forming section having the same optical characteristic, thereby alleviating the overlap positional deviation of images. However, this method has a problem of requiring much time to output a multiplexed image or a full color image. In order to solve this problem, there is known a color image forming apparatus employing a method of forming images by using optical scanners for respective colors so as to separately obtain images of the respective colors and overlaying the images of the respective colors one on another on the paper conveyed by a conveyer section (see Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2000-089540 and Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2002-055497). However, in this method, a color misregistration has been a big problem, which is caused when overlaying the images of the respective colors one on another on the paper.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Conventionally, in many color image forming apparatuses, an image information detection apparatus for detecting the color misregistration at this time is mounted. In the image information detection apparatus, a light beam emitted from a light source unit is condensed at an illumination lens, and a pattern image for position detection depicted on a recording material (image bearing member) being a transferring belt is illuminated with the condensed light beam. Then, image information such as position information or density information on a recording member and a pattern image depicted thereon is detected by a light receiving unit via an imaging lens. The image information on the pattern image is detected according to detection signals detected by the light receiving unit and the driving of an image forming section (image forming unit) is controlled to output images of respective colors.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In recent years, there is an increasingly vocal demand for overall downsizing/simplification of a color image forming apparatus. This also increases a demand for overall downsizing/simplification of an image information detection apparatus. The color image forming apparatus disclosed in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2000-089540 achieves the downsizing/simplification by using an illumination optical element (illumination lens) and an imaging optical element (imaging lens) as the same part. Further, the detecting apparatus disclosed in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2002-055497 achieves the simplification by unitarily forming the illumination optical element and the imaging optical element as one member.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">As one method for achieving the downsizing and simplification of the image information detection apparatus, there is a method of reducing an angle (incident angle of an illumination optical system) between a principal ray of the illumination optical system for illuminating the pattern image and a surface normal to the recording member. This downsizes an illumination optical element and facilitates molding of an element. However, this method is subject to a large number of constraints in terms of layout because a substrate of a light source unit and a substrate of the light receiving unit are in so close vicinity to each other as to cause interference therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">On the other hand, it is possible to avoid the interference between the substrates by increasing a distance between the light source unit and the recording member, but an optical path length becomes longer, which causes the overall apparatus to become larger. Further, if the substrates are brought into close vicinity to each other with less space therebetween, it becomes difficult to appropriately adjust positions of respective members, which causes the occurrence of a large number of color misregistrations.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An object of the present invention is to provide a detecting apparatus capable of detecting a pattern image for position detection formed on a recording member (image bearing member) by securing sufficient space between both substrates of a light source unit and a light receiving unit in terms of layout and performing appropriate adjustment while achieving overall downsizing and simplification.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In order to achieve the above-mentioned object, the present invention provides a detecting apparatus including; a light source unit, an illumination optical system for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of the image bearing member, a light receiving unit for detecting the light beam reflected by the image formed on the surface of the image bearing member; and a light receiving optical system including a light receiving optical element for imaging the light beam reflected by the image formed on the surface of the image bearing member on the light receiving unit, in which, within a main scanning section, the light receiving optical element includes an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member and is to enter the light receiving unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the detecting apparatus, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the principal ray of the light beam before passing through the optical plane of the light receiving optical element, which has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member and is to enter the light receiving unit, and the principal ray of the light beam after passing through the optical plane of the light receiving optical element, which has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member and is to enter the light receiving unit, have an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> (deg.) satisfying 0&#x3c;&#x3b8;1&#x2266;15 therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the optical plane of the light receiving optical element include a refractive plane having such a curvature that an optical axis of the optical plane is tilted with respect to an optical axis of the light receiving optical system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Alternatively, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the optical plane of the light receiving optical element include a refractive plane having such a curvature that an optical axis of the optical plane is shifted with respect to an optical axis of the light receiving optical system.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Further, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the illumination optical system have an optical axis perpendicular to the surface of the image bearing member.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Further, the present invention provides a detecting apparatus including; a light source unit, an illumination optical system including an illumination optical element for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of the image bearing member, a light receiving unit for detecting the light beam reflected by the image formed on the surface of the image bearing member; and a light receiving optical system for imaging the light beam reflected by the image formed on the surface of the image bearing member on the light receiving unit, in which, within a main scanning section, the illumination optical element includes an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has exited from the light source unit and is to enter the light receiving unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light receiving unit.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Further, in the detecting apparatus, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the principal ray of the light beam before passing through the optical plane of the illumination optical element, which has exited from the light source unit and is to enter the light receiving unit, and the principal ray of the light beam after passing through the optical plane of the illumination optical element, which has exited from the light source unit and is to enter the light receiving unit, have an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> expressed in degrees satisfying 0&#x3c;&#x3b8;<b>2</b>&#x2266;15 therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Further, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the optical plane of the illumination optical element include a refractive plane having such a curvature that an optical axis of the optical plane is tilted with respect to an optical axis of the illumination optical system.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Alternatively, it is preferred that, within the main scanning section, the optical plane of the illumination optical element include a refractive plane having such a curvature that an optical axis of the optical plane is shifted with respect to an optical axis of the illumination optical system.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Further, in the detecting apparatus, it is more preferred that; the light receiving optical system include a light receiving optical element for imaging the image formed on the surface of the image bearing member on the light receiving unit; and within the main scanning section, the light receiving optical element include an optical plane for causing the principal ray of the light beam that has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member and is to enter the light receiving unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Further, the present invention provides an image forming apparatus including; the above-mentioned detecting apparatus; and multiple photosensitive drums.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Further, the present invention also provides an image forming apparatus including; the above-mentioned detecting apparatus; and multiple photosensitive drums.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">According to the present invention, the detecting apparatus capable of detecting the pattern image for position detection formed on the recording member (image bearing member) by securing sufficient space between both the substrates of the light source unit and the light receiving unit in terms of layout and performing appropriate adjustment while achieving overall downsizing and simplification can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Further features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of exemplary embodiments with reference to the attached drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view of a main portion of an image information detection apparatus according to Example 1 of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</figref>, <b>2</b>B and <b>2</b>C are diagrams each illustrating a light beam obtained when a conjugate plane is changed in the image information detection apparatus according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a graph illustrating an irradiation light intensity ratio obtained when the conjugate plane is changed in the image information detection apparatus according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an explanatory diagram of pattern images formed on a recording member when there is no formation positional deviation.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an explanatory diagram of the pattern images formed on the recording member when there is a formation positional deviation in a magenta (M) color.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an explanatory diagram of a light emitting surface conjugate image (<b>111</b>) and a light receiving surface conjugate image (<b>112</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an explanatory diagram of pattern images (<b>121</b> and <b>122</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an explanatory diagram of the pattern image (<b>121</b>), the light emitting surface conjugate image (<b>111</b>), and the light receiving surface conjugate image (<b>112</b>) that are formed on the recording member in a case where a straight line portion of the pattern image (<b>121</b>) has reached a light receiving surface conjugate image center position (<b>112</b><i>e</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a sectional view of Comparative Example 1 of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a sectional view of an imaging optical system according to Comparative Example 1.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic view of a layout of substrates.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a sectional view of an imaging optical system according to Example 1.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a sectional view of Comparative Example 2 of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a schematic view of the layout of the substrates.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a sectional view of a main portion of Example 2 of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a schematic view of a main portion of an image forming apparatus using the image information detection apparatus according to the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Preferred embodiments of the present invention will now be described in detail in accordance with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Hereinafter, an image information detection apparatus according to the present invention and an image forming apparatus including the same are described. The image information detection apparatus according to the present invention includes: a light source <b>31</b>; and an illumination optical system S<b>1</b> for illuminating a surface of an image bearing member (transferring belt) <b>34</b> that conveys an image with a light beam exiting from the light source <b>31</b>. Further, the image information detection apparatus includes: an imaging optical system S<b>2</b> including an imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>for imaging an image (pattern image) <b>34</b><i>a </i>formed on the image bearing member <b>34</b> and a diaphragm <b>35</b> for limiting a diameter of the light beam; and a light receiving element (light receiving unit) <b>36</b> for detecting the image <b>34</b><i>a </i>on the image bearing member <b>34</b> which has been imaged by the imaging optical system. In addition, the image information detection apparatus includes a calculation unit <b>101</b> for calculating position information on the image <b>34</b><i>a </i>formed on the image bearing member <b>34</b> based on a detection signal obtained from the light receiving element <b>36</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">EXAMPLE 1</heading>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view of a main portion of the image information detection apparatus according to Example 1 of the present invention. The image information detection apparatus according to Example 1 of the present invention is used for a color image forming apparatus. A configuration of the image information detection apparatus is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrating the illumination optical system S<b>1</b> and the light receiving optical system (imaging optical system) S<b>2</b>. The light source (light source unit) <b>31</b> constituting one part of an illumination unit is formed of an LED light source. The light source <b>31</b> includes a light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>whose shape is a square of 0.35 mm on one side and a condensing part <b>31</b><i>b </i>for condensing the light beam emitted from the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The diaphragm <b>32</b> constituting one part of the illumination optical system S<b>1</b> limits the light beam emitted from the light source <b>31</b>. An optical element <b>33</b> is obtained from the same material by unitarily molding an illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a </i>constituting one part of the illumination optical system S<b>1</b> and the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>constituting one part of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>. The transferring belt <b>34</b> serves as a recording member (image bearing member) that conveys pattern images (images) <b>34</b><i>a </i>for position detection formed of toner in respective colors. The diaphragm <b>35</b> constituting one part of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b> limits the light beam exiting from the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>serving as a light receiving optical element. The light receiving element <b>36</b> constitutes one part of a light receiving unit. The light receiving element <b>36</b> includes a light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>whose shape is a square of 1 mm on one side. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> also illustrates a light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k</i>, a substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit, a front surface (lens surface) <b>331</b><i>a </i>and a back surface (lens surface) <b>332</b><i>a </i>of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a</i>, and a front surface (lens surface) <b>331</b><i>b </i>and a back surface (lens surface) <b>332</b><i>b </i>of the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a direction perpendicular to the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is set as an X direction, a direction parallel to the drawing sheet and perpendicular to the X direction is set as a Y direction, and a direction perpendicular to the drawing sheet is set as a Z direction. The Y direction is a main scanning direction of an image forming apparatus. The Z direction is a sub scanning direction of the image forming apparatus, and is a conveyance direction of the pattern image <b>34</b><i>a </i>for position detection. The light beam exiting from the light source <b>31</b> is limited by the diaphragm <b>32</b>, and the pattern image <b>34</b><i>a </i>on a surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is illuminated through the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a </i>serving as an illumination optical element. At this time, a principal ray (central ray in terms of intensity) (illumination system principal ray) A<b>1</b> of the light beam exiting from the light source <b>31</b> perpendicularly enters the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b>. Light (irregularly reflected light) scattered by the pattern image <b>34</b><i>a </i>formed on the surface of the transferring belt (image bearing member) <b>34</b> is condensed by the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b</i>, has the light beam limited by the diaphragm <b>35</b>, and received by the light receiving element <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As the transferring belt <b>34</b> conveys the pattern image <b>34</b><i>a</i>, there is a change in a received light intensity of the light received by the light receiving element <b>36</b>. The calculation unit <b>101</b> detects a formation position (position information) of the pattern image <b>34</b><i>a </i>from the detection signal of the received light intensity and calculates a formation positional deviation amount from a preset reference position. Noise present in the detection signal causes a problem when the formation positional deviation amount is calculated. As a method for improving a signal-to-noise ratio, there is a method of increasing the received light intensity of the light received by the light receiving element <b>36</b>. In order to increase the received light intensity, in the illumination optical system S<b>1</b>, the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>and the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> are caused to have a substantially optical conjugate relation by the condensing part <b>31</b><i>b </i>and the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> are explanatory diagrams for describing effectiveness of the above-mentioned illumination in increasing the received light intensity. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</figref> illustrate optical paths of an illumination optical system obtained when a position of a conjugate plane of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is set as a position of the back surface of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a </i>in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> and set as a position of the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref>, respectively. In addition, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref> illustrates an optical path of the illumination optical system obtained when a gap between the back surface <b>332</b><i>a </i>of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a </i>and the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is set as a distance h and the position of the conjugate plane of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is set as a position spaced apart from the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> in a vertical direction by the distance h.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a light intensity ratio of the light beam emitted from the illumination optical system S<b>1</b>, at which a light receiving region on the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is illuminated in the above-mentioned cases. It is understood that an illumination light intensity within the light receiving region is largest when the conjugate plane is set as the transferring belt <b>34</b>. Here, having a &#x201c;substantially optical conjugate relationship&#x201d; described above refers to having such a relationship between the object point and the image plane that the following expression is established:
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>|&#x394;|&#x3c;0.3<i>L </i><?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
where L represents a distance between the object point and a paraxial image plane, and &#x394; represents a distance between the paraxial image plane and a real image plane. When the above-mentioned expression is established, a conjugate image of the object point is projected onto the image plane. When the above-mentioned relationship is established, a light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> serving as the conjugate image of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is projected onto the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b>. Therefore, the shape of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>affects a detection signal obtained at the time of detection by the light receiving element <b>36</b>. The light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is square, and hence light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> on the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is square. For the same purpose as the illumination optical system S<b>1</b>, also in the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>, the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> and the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>are caused to have a substantially optical conjugate relationship by the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b. </i>
</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">An imaging magnification &#x3bc;<sub>2 </sub>of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b> of this example is defined by assuming that the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is the object point and that the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is the image plane. Here, &#x3b2;<sub>2</sub>=&#x2212;1.4. A light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> is considered, which is a conjugate image obtained by assuming that the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is the object point and that the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> is the image plane. The light receiving element <b>36</b> receives scattered light from the region of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>. Therefore, the shape of the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>affects a detection signal.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b> of this example, the optical axis (principal ray) (imaging principal ray) A<b>2</b> thereof is located with an angle of 25&#xb0; with respect to the perpendicular direction (&#x2212;X direction) of the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b>. Therefore, the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> exhibiting different magnifications in the main scanning direction (Y direction) within its region does not have a precise square shape but has a distorted shape. However, this does not cause a problem in the description of the effect obtained from the present invention, and hence the description is made hereinbelow on the assumption that the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> is square.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an explanatory diagram illustrating pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> formed on the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b> for detecting the formation positional deviation amount of the respective colors. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an ideal case where no formation positional deviation occurs in the pattern images. The dots inside the pattern images each indicate a center position of the pattern image. Here, the center position of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> is set as a light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. A K-axis parallel to a Z-axis is assumed. The K-axis passes the light receiving surface conjugate image center positions <b>112</b><i>e </i>and coincides with the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b>. The pattern images have the center positions arrayed along the K-axis at predetermined intervals.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the pattern images are arranged in the order of yellow (Y), magenta (M), cyan (C), and black (Bk) and in the order of the pattern image <b>121</b> and the pattern image <b>122</b>, but the present invention is not limited thereto. Long side directions of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> are each located with an angle of 45 degrees with respect to the K-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The transferring belt <b>34</b> conveys the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> at a conveying speed V. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> also illustrates detection signals obtained when a corresponding K coordinate reaches the light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. The image information detection apparatus detects a time period t required for a straight line portion of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> to pass the light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. A detection time is obtained with reference to a detection time instant of a reference color (yellow in this example) pattern image. Further, the K coordinate determined at the time of detection is set as a detection position. The detection position is determined with reference to a detection position of the reference color pattern image Y. A detection position L of the pattern image is calculated from the detection time t and the conveying speed V as follows.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>L=t&#xd7;V</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 1)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">When no formation positional deviation occurs, the pattern images are arrayed at the predetermined intervals, and hence the detection position L takes a predetermined known value. This position is set as a &#x201c;estimated detection position&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Taking a magenta color of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> as an example, a detection position L<b>1</b> of the pattern image <b>121</b> is calculated from a detection time t<b>1</b> as L<b>1</b>=t<b>1</b>&#xd7;V. In the same manner, a detection position L<b>2</b> of the pattern image <b>122</b> is calculated from a detection time t<b>2</b> as L<b>2</b>=t<b>2</b>&#xd7;V. No formation positional deviation occurs, and hence the detection positions L<b>1</b> and L<b>2</b> are the same as the estimated detection positions, thereby taking the predetermined known values. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an explanatory diagram of the pattern images obtained when a formation positional deviation occurs. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates the pattern images obtained when a formation positional deviation occurs in the magenta pattern images M. The deviation amounts d<b>1</b> and d<b>2</b> of the center positions of the magenta pattern images M from that in the case where no formation positional deviation occurs are the formation positional deviation amounts of the magenta pattern images.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The detection signals at this time are also illustrated. The detection positions and the detection times in the case where no formation positional deviation occurs are indicated by the dotted lines. There are deviations between the detection positions and the estimated detection positions. The deviation amounts are set as &#x201c;detection deviation amounts&#x201d;. By obtaining detection positions L<b>3</b> and L<b>4</b> from detection times t<b>3</b> and t<b>4</b>, respectively, of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b>, detection deviation amounts d<b>1</b> and d<b>2</b> of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b>, respectively, are obtained as follows.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>d</i>1<i>=L</i>3<i>&#x2212;L</i>1=(<i>t</i>3<i>&#x2212;t</i>1)&#xd7;<i>V</i>&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 2)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">From the detection deviation amounts, a formation positional deviation amount &#x394;Y in the main scanning direction and a formation positional deviation amount &#x394;Z in the sub scanning direction are respectively calculated as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">
<maths id="MATH-US-00001" num="00001">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x394;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>Y</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>d</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>-</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>d</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>3</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>4</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
              <mi>V</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mtext>
</mtext>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>&#x394;</mi>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mstyle>
              <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
            </mstyle>
            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
            <mi>Z</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>d</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mn>1</mn>
                </mrow>
                <mo>+</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>d</mi>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mstyle>
                    <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                  </mstyle>
                  <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                  <mn>2</mn>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>=</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mfrac>
                <mrow>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>3</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>1</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>(</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>4</mn>
                      </mrow>
                      <mo>-</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mi>t</mi>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mstyle>
                          <mspace width="0.3em" height="0.3ex"/>
                        </mstyle>
                        <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>)</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
                <mn>2</mn>
              </mfrac>
              <mo>&#xd7;</mo>
              <mi>V</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Expression</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>3</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Results thereof are respectively color misregistration amounts of magenta in the main/sub scanning directions with reference to the reference color.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> and the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> on the transferring belt <b>34</b>. The light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> includes four straight line portions <b>111</b><i>a</i>, <b>111</b><i>b</i>, <b>111</b><i>c</i>, and <b>111</b><i>d </i>and a light emitting surface conjugate image center position <b>111</b><i>e</i>. The straight line portions <b>111</b><i>a </i>and <b>111</b><i>b </i>are parallel with the straight line portions <b>111</b><i>c </i>and <b>111</b><i>d</i>, respectively. Angles &#x3b8;a<b>1</b> and &#x3b8;a<b>2</b> formed between the straight line portions <b>111</b><i>d </i>and <b>111</b><i>c </i>and the Z direction (K direction) in the traveling direction (moving direction) are 45&#xb0; and 135&#xb0;, respectively. From one side of the light emitting surface being 0.35 mm with the optical magnification &#x3b2;<sub>1</sub>=&#x2212;2.6, one side of the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> is calculated as 0.91 mm (0.35&#xd7;2.6).</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> includes four straight line portions <b>112</b><i>a</i>, <b>112</b><i>b</i>, <b>112</b><i>c</i>, and <b>112</b><i>d</i>, and the light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. The straight line portion <b>112</b><i>a </i>and the straight line portion <b>112</b><i>b </i>are parallel with the straight line portion <b>112</b><i>c </i>and the straight line portion <b>112</b><i>d</i>, respectively. The light emitting surface conjugate image center position <b>111</b><i>e </i>coincides with the light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. Angles &#x3b8;b<b>1</b> and &#x3b8;b<b>2</b> formed between the straight line portions <b>112</b><i>d </i>and <b>112</b><i>c </i>and the Z direction in the traveling direction are about 45&#xb0; and about 135&#xb0;, respectively. From one side of the light receiving surface being 1 mm with the optical magnification &#x3b2;<sub>2</sub>=&#x2212;1.4, one side of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> is calculated as 0.71 (1/1.4) mm.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is an explanatory diagram of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> on the surface of the transferring belt <b>34</b>. Each of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> is rectangular, and its widths <b>121</b><i>b</i>, <b>121</b><i>d</i>, <b>122</b><i>a</i>, and <b>122</b><i>c </i>in a long side direction are sufficiently longer than the widths of the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> and the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>. The widths <b>121</b><i>a</i>, <b>121</b><i>c</i>, <b>122</b><i>b</i>, and <b>122</b><i>d </i>in a short side direction are substantially the same as the width of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>. There are two pattern images, that is, the pattern image <b>121</b>, and the pattern image <b>122</b>. The pattern image <b>121</b> includes four straight line portions <b>121</b><i>a</i>, <b>121</b><i>b</i>, <b>121</b><i>c</i>, and <b>121</b><i>d</i>, and a center position <b>121</b><i>e</i>. Further, the pattern image <b>122</b> includes four straight line portions <b>122</b><i>a</i>, <b>122</b><i>b</i>, <b>122</b><i>c</i>, and <b>122</b><i>d</i>, and a center position <b>122</b><i>e</i>. The straight line portion <b>121</b><i>a </i>is parallel with the straight line portion <b>121</b><i>c</i>, and the straight line portion <b>122</b><i>a </i>of the pattern image <b>122</b> is parallel with the straight line portion <b>122</b><i>c</i>. Angles &#x3b8;c<b>1</b> and &#x3b8;c<b>2</b> formed between the straight line portions <b>121</b><i>b </i>and <b>122</b><i>c </i>and the Z direction in the traveling direction are 45&#xb0; and 135&#xb0;, respectively. Therefore, the straight portions of the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b>, the straight portions of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>, and the straight portions of the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> are substantially parallel with one another.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an explanatory diagram illustrating a relationship among the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b>, the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>, and the pattern image <b>121</b> on the transferring belt <b>34</b> obtained when the straight line portion <b>121</b><i>b </i>of the pattern image <b>121</b> reaches the light receiving surface conjugate image center position <b>112</b><i>e</i>. When the transferring belt <b>34</b> conveys the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b>, scattering light occurs in an overlapped region <b>131</b> between the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> and the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b>. Of the scattering light, the light receiving element <b>36</b> receives the scattering light from an overlapped region <b>130</b> between the overlapped region <b>131</b> and the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>. Here, the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>emits light uniformly within the surface, and hence an illumination intensity distribution within the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b> being the conjugate image of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is also uniform. Further, the illumination intensity is extremely lowered outside the region of the light emitting surface conjugate image <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In the same manner, the sensitivity of the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is uniform within the light receiving surface, and hence a light receiving sensitivity distribution within the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> being the conjugate image of the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is also substantially uniform. Further, there is no light receiving sensitivity outside the region of the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b>. The word &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; is added here because the light receiving surface conjugate image <b>112</b> is substantially square as discussed above. In addition, the scattering by the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> is substantially isotropic scattering, and hence the light intensity toward the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is substantially proportional to the area of the scattered region. As a result, the received light intensity is substantially proportional to the area of the overlapped region <b>130</b>. As the pattern images <b>121</b> and <b>122</b> are conveyed, the area of the overlapped region <b>130</b> changes, thereby changing the received light intensity and generating a detection signal.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Before describing the image information detection apparatus of the present invention, the problems to be solved by the image information detection apparatus of the present invention are described by taking a system (Comparative Example 1) comparable with this example.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">COMPARATIVE EXAMPLE 1</heading>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> are explanatory diagrams of Comparative Example 1 corresponding to Example 1 of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a main scanning sectional view of an overall optical system of the image information detection apparatus. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a main scanning sectional view of the imaging optical system according to Comparative Example 1. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, the same members as the members illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A to 2C</figref> are denoted by the same reference symbols.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In the present invention, in a range from the light source <b>31</b> (hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;light source <b>31</b> for irregular reflection&#x201d;) to a recording member <b>34</b> of the illumination optical system S<b>1</b>, the center ray in terms of intensity of the light beam exiting from the light source <b>31</b> for irregular reflection is defined as an illumination system principal ray A<b>1</b>. Further, in a range from the recording member <b>34</b> to the light receiving element <b>36</b> of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>, a ray passing through the center of the diaphragm <b>35</b> within the imaging optical system and entering the center of the light receiving unit is defined as an imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Of lens surfaces of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a</i>, the surface on the light source <b>31</b> side is defined as the lens surface <b>331</b><i>a </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface&#x201d;), and the surface on the recording member <b>34</b> side is defined as the lens surface <b>332</b><i>a </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface&#x201d;). Further, of the lens surfaces of the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b</i>, the surface on the recording member <b>34</b> side is defined as the lens surface <b>331</b><i>b </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface&#x201d;), and the surface on a light source unit side is defined as the lens surface <b>332</b><i>b </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface&#x201d;).</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The illumination system principal ray A<b>1</b> has a direction perpendicular to the recording member <b>34</b>, and a lens surface normal of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>a </i>is also perpendicular to the recording member <b>34</b> as well as the lens surfaces <b>331</b><i>a </i>and <b>332</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> is set to have an angle of 25&#xb0; with respect to the X-axis immediately after being reflected by the recording member <b>34</b>. After that, the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> that has been refracted by the lens surface <b>331</b><i>b </i>has an angle of 16.5&#xb0; with respect to the X-axis. Here, in the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>, as indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, an X<b>2</b>-axis and a Y<b>2</b>-axis obtained by rotating the X-axis and the Y-axis, respectively, about the Z-axis clockwise on the drawing sheet by 16.5&#xb0; (hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;(X<b>2</b>, Y<b>2</b>, and Z) coordinate system&#x201d;) are introduced in addition to the X-, Y-, and Z-axes.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Here, in both the (X, Y, and Z) coordinate system and the (X<b>2</b>, Y<b>2</b>, and Z) coordinate system, an intersection point of the recording member (recording medium) <b>34</b> and the illumination system principal ray A<b>1</b> is set as an origin point. In Comparative Example 1, the lens surface <b>332</b><i>b </i>and the imaging system diaphragm <b>35</b> are set in a direction perpendicular to the X<b>2</b>-axis. Information related to the layout and surface shapes of the respective members according to Comparative Example 1 is shown in the following Table 1.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="315pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comparative Example 1</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface vertex</entry>
<entry>vertex normal</entry>
<entry>Refractive</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>index</entry>
<entry>Surface shape</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bb; = 880 nm)</entry>
<entry>R</entry>
<entry>K</entry>
<entry>C4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting point</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;27.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.550</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(31a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.450</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (31b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.200</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.000</entry>
<entry>3.986</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.8868</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0058</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.500</entry>
<entry>4.134</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.938</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>7.850</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>element surface (36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The (X, Y, and Z) coordinate system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is used for the surface vertex coordinates and the surface vertex normal direction cosines of the respective surfaces shown in the above Table-1. Further, the surface shape is defined according to the following Expression 4.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">
<maths id="MATH-US-00002" num="00002">
<math overflow="scroll">
<mtable>
  <mtr>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mtable>
          <mtr>
            <mtd>
              <mrow>
                <mi>x</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mfrac>
                    <mrow>
                      <msup>
                        <mi>h</mi>
                        <mn>2</mn>
                      </msup>
                      <mo>/</mo>
                      <mi>R</mi>
                    </mrow>
                    <mrow>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                      <mo>+</mo>
                      <msqrt>
                        <mrow>
                          <mn>1</mn>
                          <mo>-</mo>
                          <mrow>
                            <mrow>
                              <mo>(</mo>
                              <mrow>
                                <mn>1</mn>
                                <mo>+</mo>
                                <mi>k</mi>
                              </mrow>
                              <mo>)</mo>
                            </mrow>
                            <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                            <msup>
                              <mrow>
                                <mo>(</mo>
                                <mrow>
                                  <mi>h</mi>
                                  <mo>/</mo>
                                  <mi>R</mi>
                                </mrow>
                                <mo>)</mo>
                              </mrow>
                              <mn>2</mn>
                            </msup>
                          </mrow>
                        </mrow>
                      </msqrt>
                    </mrow>
                  </mfrac>
                  <mo>+</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <msub>
                      <mi>C</mi>
                      <mn>4</mn>
                    </msub>
                    <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>h</mi>
                      <mn>4</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
            </mtd>
          </mtr>
          <mtr>
            <mtd>
              <mrow>
                <mi>h</mi>
                <mo>=</mo>
                <msqrt>
                  <mrow>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>y</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                    <mo>+</mo>
                    <msup>
                      <mi>z</mi>
                      <mn>2</mn>
                    </msup>
                  </mrow>
                </msqrt>
              </mrow>
            </mtd>
          </mtr>
        </mtable>
        <mo>}</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
    <mtd>
      <mrow>
        <mo>(</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>Expression</mi>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mspace width="0.8em" height="0.8ex"/>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&#x2062;</mo>
          <mn>4</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mtd>
  </mtr>
</mtable>
</math>
</maths>
</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Here, as x, y, and z in the above-mentioned mathematical expression, the (X, Y, and Z) coordinate system is used for the illumination optical system S<b>1</b>, and the (X<b>2</b>, Y<b>2</b>, and Z) coordinate system including the X<b>2</b>-axis parallel with the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> is used for the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>. In the expression, R represents a curvature radius, and k and C<sub>4 </sub>each represent an aspheric coefficient. It is understood from the above mathematical expression that the illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>a</i>) is a spherical surface being rotationally symmetric about the X-axis, and the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is an aspheric surface being rotationally symmetric about the X<b>2</b>-axis. Further, the illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>a</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) each have a planar shape parallel with the recording member <b>34</b>. Further, the following Table 2 shows ray passing coordinates of the principal ray on the respective surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00002" num="00002">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comparative Example 1</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Ray passing</entry>
<entry>Principal ray</entry>
<entry>Exit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>angle</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b8;x</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;27.001</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.002</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>point (31a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.451</entry>
<entry>0.007</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.001</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (31b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.200</entry>
<entry>0.014</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.001</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R1 surface (331a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illuminaton lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.001</entry>
<entry>0.010</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.001</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R2 surface (332a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.002</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.907</entry>
<entry>0.421</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>24.9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.001</entry>
<entry>2.791</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.959</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.003</entry>
<entry>3.976</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.958</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.504</entry>
<entry>4.125</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.958</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.001</entry>
<entry>7.843</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.958</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>element surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">As shown above, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle (angle formed with respect to the surface normal of the recording member <b>34</b>; the same shall apply hereinafter) to the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 24.9 (deg.). Further, an exit angle (angle formed with respect to the surface normal of the recording member <b>34</b>; the same shall apply hereinafter) &#x3b8;i<b>1</b> from the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 16.6 (deg.), and an exit angle &#x3b8;e<b>1</b> from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is 16.6 (deg.). In other words, an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> (deg.) of the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> before and after passing through the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is defined as &#x3b8;<b>1</b>=|&#x3b8;e<b>1</b> (deg.)&#x2212;&#x3b8;i<b>1</b> (deg.)|, and &#x3b8;<b>1</b>=0.0 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a detailed view of a positional relationship between the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit according to Comparative Example 1. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the center of the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>is referred to as a point O<b>1</b>, the center of the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>is referred to as a point O<b>2</b>, the closest point to the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit within the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection is referred to as a point O<b>3</b>, and the closest point to the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection within the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit is referred to as a point O<b>4</b>. Here, a Y-direction (main scanning direction) distance between the light emitting surface <b>31</b><i>a </i>of the light source <b>31</b> for irregular reflection and the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>of the light receiving element <b>36</b> is set as Wy. In addition, by setting a Y-direction distance between the point O<b>1</b> and the point O<b>3</b> as Wy<b>1</b>, a Y-direction distance between the point O<b>3</b> and the point O<b>4</b> as Wy<b>2</b>, and a Y-direction distance between the point O<b>2</b> and the point O<b>4</b> as Wy<b>3</b>, the following relationship is established.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>Wy=Wy</i>1<i>+Wy</i>2<i>+Wy</i>3&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 5)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Further, this expression can be put another way as follows.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>Wy</i>2<i>=Wy&#x2212;Wy</i>1<i>&#x2212;Wy</i>3&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 6)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">If the Y-direction distance Wy<b>3</b> between the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit assumes only a small value, there arises a problem in terms of layout, design, and ease of assembly. In this comparative example, Wy=7.65 (mm), Wy<b>1</b>=2.3 (mm), and Wy<b>3</b>=5.1 (mm). Therefore, as small a value as Wy<b>2</b>=0.25 (mm) is obtained from Expression 6.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Further, if the value of the distance Wy<b>2</b> as a design value is small, in a case of assembling the unit of Comparative Example 1, a shift adjustment amount in the Y direction cannot be set large even when shift adjustment is performed on the substrate of at least one of the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit. As a result, there may be a fear that the adjustment is insufficient compared to an ideal adjustment amount.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">According to Example 1 of the present invention, in order to solve the above-mentioned problem, a countermeasure is taken against Comparative Example 1. In Example 1, the principal ray passing through the center of the diaphragm <b>35</b> within the imaging optical system and entering the center of the light receiving element <b>36</b> is defined as the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b>. The imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>being the light receiving optical element includes at least one optical plane for refracting an imaging system principal ray. The at least one optical plane of the imaging optical element is configured to refract the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> after passing therethrough in a direction of becoming farther apart from the light source <b>31</b> than the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> before passing through the optical plane. Next described is a specific configuration of Example 1.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">EXAMPLE 1</heading>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is referenced again to describe Example 1. As indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the X<b>2</b>-axis and the Y<b>2</b>-axis are introduced for the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b> in the same manner as in Comparative Example 1. Example 1 is different from Comparative Example 1 in that, compared to Comparative Example 1, the surface shape of the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is shift-decentered by 0.39 mm in the positive direction of the Y<b>2</b>-axis, the entire light receiving element <b>36</b> is shift-moved by 0.95 mm in the positive direction of the Y-axis.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a main scanning sectional view of the imaging optical system according to Example 1. Further, information related to the layout and surface shapes of the respective members is shown in the following Table 3. Further, the following Table 4 shows the ray passing coordinates of the principal ray on the respective surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00003" num="00003">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="329pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 3</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Example 1</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface vertex</entry>
<entry>vertex normal</entry>
<entry>Refractive</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>index</entry>
<entry>Surface shape</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bb; = 880 nm)</entry>
<entry>R</entry>
<entry>K</entry>
<entry>C4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting point</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;27.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.550</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(31a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.450</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(31b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.200</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>3.7</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium surface</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.889</entry>
<entry>4.360</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.8868</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0058</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.500</entry>
<entry>4.171</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.938</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving element</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>8.800</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00004" num="00004">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 4</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Example 1</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Ray passing</entry>
<entry>Principal ray</entry>
<entry>Exit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>angle</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b8;x</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;27.001</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.006</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>point (31a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.452</entry>
<entry>0.020</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.001</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>lens surface (31b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.201</entry>
<entry>0.039</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.002</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R1 surface (331a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.001</entry>
<entry>0.029</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.004</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R2 surface (332a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.007</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.908</entry>
<entry>0.419</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>24.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.001</entry>
<entry>2.778</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.959</entry>
<entry>0.282</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.980</entry>
<entry>3.950</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.937</entry>
<entry>0.348</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.510</entry>
<entry>4.147</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.937</entry>
<entry>0.348</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.001</entry>
<entry>8.789</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.937</entry>
<entry>0.348</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>element surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">As shown above, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle to the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 24.8 (deg.), and the exit angle (angle formed between the principal ray before the passing and the surface normal of the recording member <b>34</b> according to the present invention) &#x3b8;i<b>1</b> from the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 16.4 (deg.). Further, the exit angle (angle between the principal ray after the passing and the surface normal of the recording member <b>34</b> according to the present invention) &#x3b8;e<b>1</b> from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is 20.4 (deg.). In other words, the angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> (deg.) of the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> before and after passing through the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is defined as &#x3b8;<b>1</b>=|&#x3b8;e<b>1</b> (deg.)&#x2212;&#x3b8;i<b>1</b> (deg.)|, and &#x3b8;<b>1</b>=4.0 (deg.). Further, compared to Comparative Example 1, the angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> of the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is increased by 4.0 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">As a result, the positional relationship between the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit according to Example 1 is Wy=8.6 (mm), Wy<b>1</b>=2.3 (mm), and Wy<b>3</b>=5.1 (mm), and the distance Wy<b>2</b>=1.2 (mm) is obtained from Expression 6. As a result, compared to Comparative Example 1, the value of the distance Wy<b>2</b> can be increased by 0.95 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Broadly speaking, in Example 1, compared to Comparative Example 1, the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is shifted by 0.39 mm in the positive direction of the Y<b>2</b>-axis, thereby increasing the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) by 4.0 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">As a result, the distance Wy<b>2</b> between the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit can be increased by 0.95 mm. As a result, large space between the substrates or between supporting members that support the substrates are generated, and the shift adjustment amount of the light source <b>31</b> or the light receiving element <b>36</b> can be set larger, which allows assembly adjustment to be performed with higher precision. In addition, large space between the two substrates <b>31</b><i>k </i>and <b>36</b><i>k </i>can be obtained, which is also advantageous in improving workability of assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In Example 1, a surface vertex of the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is shifted in the positive direction of the Y<b>2</b>-axis with respect to the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> passing through the center of the diaphragm <b>35</b>. Accordingly, the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> being the principal ray exiting from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is bent at an angle larger by 4.0 (deg.) than in Comparative Example 1, but the same effect can be obtained even when the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is decentered in a tilted (inclined) direction.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">To put the above description another way, in the case of Comparative Example 1 where the surface normal at a point at which the optical plane having a curvature of the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>and the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> intersect each other is parallel with the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> after passing through the optical plane, the principal ray is not bent before and after passing through the optical plane.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">On the other hand, in Example 1, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>is optically located in such a manner that the shift-decentering at the lens surface and tilt-decentering at the lens surface are performed. In this case, the surface normal at the point at which the optical plane having the curvature of the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>and the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> intersect each other is non-parallel with the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> after passing through the optical plane. Accordingly, the principal ray exiting from the optical plane can be bent, and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>and the substrate <b>36</b><i>k </i>for a light receiving unit can be spaced farther apart. At this time, it is desired that the angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> (deg.) of the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> before and after passing through the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) satisfy the following condition.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>0 (deg.)&#x3c;&#x3b8;1(deg.)&#x2266;15(deg.)&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 7)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The lower limit value of the above-mentioned condition is an obvious numerical value because the optical path is bent. Further, the upper limit value indicates an amount in which allowance is made for deterioration in optical aberration exhibited by the fact that the principal ray does not pass through a vertex of the lens surface and for a bending angle within such a range that the entire apparatus does not become too large.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">In this example, &#x3b8;<b>1</b> (deg.)=4.0 (deg.), which satisfies Expression 7. In Example 1, the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) having a curvature is shift-decentered, but the present invention is not limited thereto. For example, the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) having a curvature may be shift-decentered or tilt-decentered. Alternatively, both the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) having a curvature and the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) having a curvature may be shift-decentered or tilt-decentered. Further, if the lens surface is tilt-decentered, even a planar shape having no curvature can produce the same effect.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Note that in Example 1, the lens R<b>2</b> surface for irregular reflection illumination (<b>332</b><i>a</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) are set to have a planar shape. This is because cleaning is easily performed on the lens R<b>2</b> surface for irregular reflection illumination (<b>332</b><i>a</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) that serve as a front surface portion of a detecting unit and are likely to be subject to toner stain. Further, in Example 1, the recording member (transferring belt) <b>34</b> is set as a flat-shaped member, but the present invention is not limited thereto, and the same effect can also be obtained by using a member having a curved surface shape. A possible example of having a curved surface shape is a case where the optical system is located above a roller that supports the recording member. In that case, a flapping amount of the recording member (transferring belt) can be suppressed to a low level to thereby increase detection precision.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">EXAMPLE 2</heading>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">An image information detection apparatus according to Example 2 of the present invention includes a system for detecting the density (reflected light intensity) of the pattern image by using the light beam obtained by regularly reflecting image information on the pattern image for position detection formed on the transferring belt <b>34</b> with respect to the incident light beam and a system for detecting a color misregistration (position information) by using scattered light (irregularly reflected light). One or both thereof are used as necessary to detect the image information on the pattern image. In the same manner as in Example 1, a system to be compared with Example 2 is taken to describe the problem to be solved by the present invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">COMPARATIVE EXAMPLE 2</heading>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a schematic view of a main portion of Comparative Example 2 corresponding to Example 2 of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a main scanning sectional view of the overall optical system of the image information detection apparatus. Here, the imaging optical system is configured to have the same layout as in Example 1 illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, and hence description thereof is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> illustrates an illumination optical system S<b>3</b> in a range from the light source <b>41</b> (hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;light source <b>41</b> for regular reflection&#x201d;) to a recording member <b>34</b>. In the illumination optical system S<b>3</b>, the center ray in terms of intensity of the light beam exiting from the light source <b>41</b> for regular reflection is defined as an illumination system principal ray A<b>3</b>. Further, as in Example 1, in a range from the recording member <b>34</b> to the light receiving element <b>36</b> of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>, a ray passing through the center of the diaphragm <b>35</b> within the imaging optical system and entering the center of the light receiving unit <b>36</b> is defined as an imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b>. The illumination system principal ray A<b>3</b> is regularly reflected by the recording member <b>34</b> to become the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Of lens surfaces of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>c</i>, the surface on the light source <b>41</b> side is defined as the lens surface <b>331</b><i>c </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface&#x201d;), and the surface on the recording member <b>34</b> side is defined as the lens surface <b>332</b><i>c </i>(hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface&#x201d;). Further, the lens surfaces of the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>are denoted similarly as in Example 1. Information related to the layout and surface shapes of the respective members according to Comparative Example 2 is shown in the following Table 5.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00005" num="00005">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="336pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 5</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comparative Example 2</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface vertex</entry>
<entry>vertex normal</entry>
<entry>Refractive</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>index</entry>
<entry>Surface shape</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bb; = 880 nm)</entry>
<entry>R</entry>
<entry>K</entry>
<entry>C4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting point (41a)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;18.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.362</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.550</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;14.597</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;5.351</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(41b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;3.986</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium surface</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.889</entry>
<entry>4.360</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.8868</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0058</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.500</entry>
<entry>4.171</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.938</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving element</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>8.800</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">An illumination optical system S<b>3</b> is laid out in the following manner. That is, the incident angle to the recording member <b>34</b> is 16.5 (deg.) in a range from the light source <b>41</b> for regular reflection to a illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>). Further, the incident angle to the recording member <b>34</b> is 25 (deg.) in a range after being refracted by a illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) being a flat-shaped portion. The configuration of the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b> is the same as Example 1.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Here, in the illumination optical system S<b>3</b>, as indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, an X<b>3</b>-axis and a Y<b>3</b>-axis obtained by rotating the X-axis and the Y-axis, respectively, about the Z-axis counterclockwise on the drawing sheet by 16.5&#xb0; (hereinafter, referred to as &#x201c;(X<b>3</b>, Y<b>3</b>, and Z) coordinate system&#x201d;) are introduced in addition to the X-, Y-, and Z-axes. In the (X<b>3</b>, Y<b>3</b>, and Z) coordinate system, an intersection point of the recording member (recording medium) <b>34</b> and the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> is set as an origin point.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In Comparative Example 2, the light source <b>41</b> for regular reflection and the illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) are set in a direction perpendicular to the X<b>3</b>-axis. The (X, Y, and Z) coordinate system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is used for the surface vertex coordinates and the surface vertex normal direction cosines of the respective surfaces shown in the above-mentioned Table-5. Further, the surface shape is defined according to Expression 5 described above. Here, as x, y, and z in Expression 5, the (X<b>3</b>, Y<b>3</b>, and Z) coordinate system is used for the illumination optical system S<b>3</b>, and the (X<b>2</b>, Y<b>2</b>, and Z) coordinate system including the X<b>2</b>-axis parallel with the imaging system principal ray A<b>2</b> is used for the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>. In the expression, R represents the curvature radius, and k and C<sub>4 </sub>each represent the aspheric coefficient. It is understood from the above-mentioned mathematical expression that the illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is a spherical surface being rotationally symmetric about the X<b>3</b>-axis, and the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is an aspheric surface being rotationally symmetric about the X<b>2</b>-axis. Further, the illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) each have a planar shape parallel with the recording member <b>34</b>. Further, the following Table 6 shows the ray passing coordinates of the principal ray on the respective surfaces according to Comparative Example 2.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00006" num="00006">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 6</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Comparative Example 2</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Ray passing</entry>
<entry>Principal ray</entry>
<entry>Exit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>angle</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b8;x</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;18.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.362</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.953</entry>
<entry>0.289</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;16.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>point (41a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;14.616</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;5.290</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.957</entry>
<entry>0.289</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;16.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (41b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.024</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;3.903</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.960</entry>
<entry>0.289</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;16.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R1 surface (331c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.725</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.909</entry>
<entry>0.417</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;24.7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R2 surface (332c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.028</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.909</entry>
<entry>0.417</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>24.7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.781</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.960</entry>
<entry>0.281</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>16.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.979</entry>
<entry>3.946</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.938</entry>
<entry>0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.510</entry>
<entry>4.143</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.938</entry>
<entry>0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>8.760</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.938</entry>
<entry>0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>element surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">As shown above, the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>c </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle &#x3b8;i<b>2</b> to the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is 16.8 (deg.), and the exit angle &#x3b8;e<b>2</b> from the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is 16.8 (deg.). Further, the exit angle from the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) is 24.7 (deg.). Further, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle to the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 24.7 (deg.), the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 16.3 (deg.), and the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is 20.3 (deg.). In other words, an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> (deg.) of the imaging system principal ray before and after passing through the illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is defined as &#x3b8;<b>2</b>=|&#x3b8;e<b>2</b> (deg.)&#x2212;&#x3b8;i<b>2</b> (deg.)|, and &#x3b8;<b>2</b>=0.0 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is an explanatory view of details of the positional relationship between a light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the closest point to the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection within the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection is referred to as a point O<b>5</b>, and the closest point to the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection within the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection is referred to as a point O<b>6</b>. The Y-direction distance between the point O<b>5</b> and the point O<b>6</b> is set as Wy<b>4</b>. If the distance Wy<b>4</b> being the Y-direction distance between the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection assumes only a small value, there arises a problem in terms of layout, design, and ease of assembly. In this comparative example, the value of the distance is as small as Wy<b>4</b>=0.2 (mm).</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">Further, the value of the distance Wy<b>2</b> as a design value is small, and hence in a case of assembling the unit of Comparative Example 2, the following drawback arises. That is, the shift adjustment amount in the Y direction cannot be set large even when the shift adjustment is performed on at least one of the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection, and hence, there may be a fear that the adjustment is insufficient compared to an ideal adjustment amount.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">EXAMPLE 2</heading>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">In order to solve the above-mentioned problem, Example 2 of the present invention obtained by taking a countermeasure against Comparative Example 2 is described below. In Example 2, a central ray of the light beam exiting from a light source unit <b>41</b> is defined as an illumination system principal ray A<b>3</b>. An illumination lens (illumination optical element) <b>33</b><i>c </i>includes at least one optical plane for refracting an illumination system principal ray. The at least one optical plane of the illumination optical element is configured so that the illumination system principal ray before passing therethrough enters the illumination optical element in a direction of becoming farther apart from the light receiving element <b>36</b> than the illumination system principal ray A<b>3</b> after passing through the optical plane.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">Also in this example, in the same manner as in Comparative Example 2 illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection for detecting the color misregistration and the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection for detecting the density (reflected light intensity) of the pattern image are provided and used as necessary. Note that the color misregistration (position information) may be detected by using the light beam emitted from the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a schematic view of a main portion of Example 2 of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> illustrates only the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection, but in the same manner as <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>, the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection is provided. In Example 2 illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, the X<b>3</b>-axis and the Y<b>3</b>-axis are introduced for the illumination optical system S<b>3</b>, and the X<b>2</b>-axis and the Y<b>2</b>-axis are introduced for the light receiving optical system S<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">In this example, the surface shape of the illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) of the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>c </i>is tilt-decentered by 10.8 (deg.) in a direction from the Y<b>3</b>-axis toward the X<b>3</b>-axis, and the entire light source unit <b>41</b> is shift-moved by 0.8 mm toward the negative direction of the Y-axis. Information related to the layout and surface shapes of the respective members according to Example 2 is shown in the following Table 7. Further, the following Table 8 shows the ray passing coordinates of the principal ray on the respective surfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00007" num="00007">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="336pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 7</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Example 2</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Surface vertex</entry>
<entry>vertex normal</entry>
<entry>Refractive</entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>index</entry>
<entry>Surface shape</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bb; = 880 nm)</entry>
<entry>R</entry>
<entry>K</entry>
<entry>C4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting point (41a)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;18.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;7.200</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.928</entry>
<entry>0.373</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.550</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;14.706</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;5.877</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.928</entry>
<entry>0.373</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(41b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;3.986</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.995</entry>
<entry>0.100</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>4.0</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (331c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium surface</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R1 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.798</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.484</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2 surface</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.889</entry>
<entry>4.360</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.959</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.285</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.8868</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0058</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.500</entry>
<entry>4.171</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.938</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.347</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving element</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>8.800</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>1.000</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>&#x221e;</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.0000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="11" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00008" num="00008">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 8</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Example 2</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="70pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Ray passing</entry>
<entry>Principal ray</entry>
<entry>Exit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>coordinates</entry>
<entry>direction cosine</entry>
<entry>angle</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>Z</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;x&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;y&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1;z&#x2032;</entry>
<entry>&#x3b8;x</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="14pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Light emitting</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;18.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;7.200</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.941</entry>
<entry>0.338</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;19.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>point (41a)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light source lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;14.662</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.001</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.931</entry>
<entry>0.364</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;21.3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (41b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.977</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;4.170</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.956</entry>
<entry>0.294</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;17.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R1 surface (331c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Illumination lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2.948</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.900</entry>
<entry>0.436</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;25.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R2 surface (332c)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recording medium</entry>
<entry>0.000</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.041</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.900</entry>
<entry>0.436</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>25.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (34)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6.000</entry>
<entry>2.866</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.956</entry>
<entry>0.294</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>17.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>R1 surface (331b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Imaging lens R2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;9.957</entry>
<entry>4.082</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.939</entry>
<entry>0.344</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>surface (332b)</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diaphragm (35)</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;10.464</entry>
<entry>4.267</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.939</entry>
<entry>0.344</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Light receiving</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;23.000</entry>
<entry>8.857</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;0.939</entry>
<entry>0.344</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>20.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>element surface</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(36a)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">As shown above, the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>c </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle &#x3b8;i<b>2</b> to the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is set to 21.3 (deg.). Further, the exit angle &#x3b8;e<b>2</b> from the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is 17.1 (deg.), and the exit angle from the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) is 25.8 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">Further, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the incident angle to the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 25.8 (deg.), and the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) is 17.1 (deg.), and the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is 20.1 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">In other words, an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> (deg.) of the illumination system principal ray before and after passing through the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is defined as &#x3b8;<b>2</b>=|&#x3b8;e<b>2</b> (deg.)&#x2212;&#x3b8;i<b>3</b> (deg.)|, and &#x3b8;<b>2</b>=|17.1&#xb0;&#x2212;21.3&#xb0;|. That is, &#x3b8;<b>2</b>=4.2 (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">Compared to Comparative Example 2, the incident angle to the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is &#x3b8;b<b>3</b>=21.3&#xb0; in Example 2 and &#x3b8;b<b>3</b>=16.8&#xb0; in Comparative Example 2, and hence the incident angle is increased by 4.5&#xb0; (deg.).</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">As a result, the positional relationship between the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection according to Example 2 is the distance Wy<b>4</b>=1.0 (mm), and hence, compared to Comparative Example 2, it is possible to increase the value of 0.2 of the distance Wy<b>4</b> by 0.8 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">In summary, in Example 2, compared to Comparative Example 2, the surface shape of the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is tilt-decentered by 10.8 (deg.) in a direction from the Y<b>3</b>-axis toward the X<b>3</b>-axis. Accordingly, the incident angle to the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) has increased by 4.5 (deg.), and the distance Wy<b>4</b> between the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection and the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> can be increased by 0.8 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">As a result, large space between the substrates <b>41</b><i>k </i>and <b>36</b><i>k </i>or between the supporting members that support the substrates is generated, and the shift adjustment amount of the light source unit for regular reflection or the light source unit for irregular reflection can be set larger, which allows the assembly adjustment to be performed with higher precision. In addition, large space between the two substrates is obtained, which is also advantageous in improved workability of assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">In Example 2, the surface shape of the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is tilt-decentered by 10.8 (deg.) in a direction from the Y<b>3</b>-axis toward the X<b>3</b>-axis. Accordingly, the incident angle to the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is bent at an angle larger by 4.5 (deg.) than in Comparative Example 2. In Example 2, the same effect can be obtained even when the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) is decentered in a shift direction (Y<b>3</b> direction) as performed in Example 1.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">To put the above description another way, in the case of Comparative Example 2, where the surface normal at a point at which the optical plane having a curvature of the illumination optical element and the illumination system principal ray intersect each other is parallel with the illumination system principal ray after passing through the optical plane, the principal ray is not bent before and after passing through the optical plane.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">On the other hand, in the case of performing the tilt-decentering at the lens surface and the shift-decentering at the lens surface as described in Example 2, the illumination lens <b>33</b><i>c </i>is located in the following manner. That is, the surface normal at the point at which the optical plane having a curvature of the illumination optical element and the illumination system principal ray intersect each other is non-parallel with the illumination system principal ray after passing through the optical plane. Accordingly, the principal ray exiting from the optical plane can be bent, and the light source substrate <b>41</b><i>k </i>for regular reflection can be spaced farther apart than the light source substrate <b>31</b><i>k </i>for irregular reflection of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">At this time, it is desired that the angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> (deg.) of the illumination system principal ray before and after passing through the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) satisfy the following condition.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>0(deg.)&#x3c;&#x3b8;2(deg.)&#x2266;15(deg.)&#x2003;&#x2003;(Expression 8)<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">The lower limit value of the above-mentioned condition is an obvious numerical value because the optical path is bent. Further, the upper limit value indicates an amount in which allowance is made for deterioration in optical aberration exhibited by the fact that an incident ray does not perpendicularly enter the lens surface and for the bending angle within such a range that the entire apparatus does not become too large.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">In this example, the angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> (deg.)=4.2 (deg.), which satisfies Expression 8.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">In Example 2, the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) having a curvature is tilt-decentered, but the present invention is not limited thereto, and the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) may be configured to have a curvature and may be shift-decentered or tilt-decentered. In addition, both the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>c</i>) having a curvature and the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) may be shift-decentered or tilt-decentered.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">In addition, in Example 2, by the fact that the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) is shift-decentered or tilt-decentered in the positive direction of the Y<b>2</b>-axis, the exit angle from the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) may be increased.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">That is, within a main scanning section, the imaging lens <b>33</b><i>b </i>includes the imaging lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>b</i>) for causing the principal ray of the light beam that has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member and is to enter the light receiving surface <b>36</b><i>a </i>to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Further, if the lens surface is tilt-decentered, even a planar shape having no curvature can produce the same effect.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">Note that in Example 2, the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) are configured to have a planar shape. This is because, in the same manner as in Example 1, such an advantage is taken into consideration that cleaning is easily performed on the regular reflection illumination lens R<b>2</b> surface (<b>332</b><i>c</i>) and the imaging lens R<b>1</b> surface (<b>331</b><i>b</i>) that serve as the front surface portion of the detecting unit and are likely to be subject to toner stain.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Further, in Example 2, the recording member (transferring belt) <b>34</b> is set as a flat-shaped member, but the present invention is not limited thereto, and the same effect can also be obtained by using a member having a curved surface shape. A possible example of having a curved surface shape is the case where the optical system is located above the roller that supports the recording member, and in that case, the flapping amount of the recording member (transferring belt) can be suppressed to a low level to produce an advantage of the increase in detection precision.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">As described above, according to each of the examples, large space between the substrates or between the supporting members that support the substrates is generated, and the shift adjustment amount of the light source unit or the light receiving unit can be set larger, which allows the assembly adjustment to be performed with higher precision. Further, large space between the substrates is obtained, which is advantageous in improved workability of assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">While the present invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed exemplary embodiments. The scope of the following claims is to be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent structures and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136">Described below is an image forming apparatus including the image information detection apparatus discussed so far. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a schematic view of a main portion of the image forming apparatus including the image information detection apparatus according to the present invention, which is applied to a digital full color copier. First, a construction and an operation of the digital full color copier of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> are described.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, in an original reader section <b>80</b>, image information on a color image placed on an original glass table <b>86</b> is read by being formed on a surface of a reading unit <b>81</b> of a CCD or the like by using mirrors <b>83</b>, <b>84</b>, and <b>85</b> and a reading lens <b>82</b>. Then, the color image information obtained from the reading unit <b>81</b> is input to a full color image forming section <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">In the full color image forming section <b>10</b>, four (first to fourth) image forming stations (image forming sections (image forming units) Pa to Pd) are arranged. The respective image forming stations (Pa to Pd) include photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>) serving as recording members. Further, respectively arranged around the photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>) are dedicated charging units (<b>3</b><i>a </i>to <b>3</b><i>d</i>), scanning optical devices (<b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>d</i>) for illuminating the surface of the photosensitive drum with a light beam corresponding to image information, developing units (<b>5</b><i>a </i>to <b>5</b><i>d</i>), drum cleaning units (<b>4</b><i>a </i>to <b>4</b><i>d</i>), and transferring units (<b>6</b><i>a </i>to <b>6</b><i>d</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">Developer containers <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>d </i>corresponding to the respective developing units (<b>5</b><i>a </i>to <b>5</b><i>d</i>) are provided immediately under horizontal portions of the scanning optical devices (<b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>d</i>) in alignment with vertical portions thereof. The developer containers <b>51</b><i>a </i>to <b>51</b><i>d </i>perform replenishment of developers by attaching and detaching developer cartridges having a cylindrical shape. Here, the image forming stations (Pa to Pd) form a cyan image, a magenta image, a yellow image, and a black image, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">Meanwhile, a transferring belt (recording member) having an endless belt shape is disposed below the photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>) in such manner as to pass the respective image forming stations (Pa to Pd). Further, the transferring belt <b>61</b> is stretched around a drive roller <b>62</b> and driven rollers <b>63</b> and <b>65</b>, and a cleaning unit <b>64</b> for cleaning a front surface thereof is also provided.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">The scanning optical devices (<b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>d</i>) each include a semiconductor laser serving as a light source unit, and an incident optical unit for introducing a light beam exiting from the semiconductor laser to a polygon mirror. The scanning optical devices (<b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>d</i>) each further include an imaging unit including a toric lens and optical elements such as a spherical lens and an aspherical lens, for causing a light beam deflected by the polygon mirror to image on the surface of the corresponding one of the photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>) serving as the recording members. The scanning optical devices (<b>1</b><i>a </i>to <b>1</b><i>d</i>) each further include a reflecting mirror serving as a reflecting member provided between the toric lens and the optical elements, and a receiving unit for integrally receiving those optical elements.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">In such a construction, first, a latent image of a cyan component corresponding to image information is formed on the surface of the photosensitive drum <b>2</b><i>a </i>by known electrophotographic process units of the first image forming station Pa such as the charging unit <b>3</b><i>a </i>and exposure performed by the scanning optical device la. After that, the latent image is visualized as a cyan pattern image by the developing unit <b>5</b><i>a </i>with the developer having cyan toner, and the cyan pattern image is transferred onto the front surface of the transferring belt <b>61</b> by the transferring unit <b>6</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">While the above-mentioned cyan pattern image is transferred onto the transferring belt <b>61</b>, in the second image forming station Pb, a latent image of a magenta component is formed, and a pattern image using magenta toner is subsequently obtained by the developing unit <b>5</b><i>b</i>. Then, the magenta pattern image is accurately transferred while being overlapped onto the transferring belt <b>61</b> on which the transfer has already been finished in the first image forming station Pa, by the transferring unit <b>6</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">After that, the image formation is performed on the yellow image and the black image by the same method. Thus, overlaying the pattern images of the four colors one on another on the transferring belt <b>61</b> is finished. Then, a four-color pattern image on the transferring belt <b>61</b> is again transferred (secondarily transferred) onto a sheet material S by a secondary transfer roller <b>66</b>. The sheet material S is conveyed from a sheet feeding cassette <b>70</b> by a sheet feeding roller <b>71</b>, a conveyance roller pair <b>72</b>, and a registration roller pair <b>73</b> at a good timing. Then, the transferred pattern image is heat-fixed by a fixing roller pair <b>74</b> on the sheet material S that has been subjected to the secondary transfer, and a full color image is obtained on the sheet material S. Then, the sheet material S on which the full color image has been formed is sent to a tray <b>77</b> via rollers <b>75</b> and <b>76</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">Note that, the respective photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>) in which the transfer has been finished have the cleaning units (<b>4</b><i>a </i>to <b>4</b><i>d</i>) remove residual toner from the respective photosensitive drums (<b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d</i>), and are prepared for subsequent image formation. When facing <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, image information detection apparatuses <b>69</b> having the same configuration are disposed in three positions at the back, the center, and the front of the transferring belt <b>61</b>. Note that, the surface of the transferring belt <b>61</b> is in a state close to a mirror surface.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">In this example, before the image forming process is performed, the respective image forming sections Pa, Pb, Pc, and Pd form pattern images <b>69</b><i>a </i>for position detection on the transferring belt <b>61</b> as four images corresponding to the image forming sections Pa, Pb, Pc, and Pd, respectively. That is, the four images are respectively formed as a whole. For the sake of simplicity, the pattern images for position detection on the left and right are handled as one.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">Before executing the above-mentioned process at the image forming sections, the image information detection apparatus <b>69</b> detects image information on the pattern images <b>69</b><i>a </i>for position detection that have been formed in a non-image forming region of the respective photosensitive drums <b>2</b><i>a </i>to <b>2</b><i>d </i>and transferred onto the transferring belt <b>61</b> in its conveyance direction. Based on detection signals obtained through the detection, the respective image forming sections Pa, Pb, Pc, and Pd are controlled by a control section.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">While the present invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed exemplary embodiments. The scope of the following claims is to be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent structures and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">This application claims the benefit of Japanese Patent Application No. 2010-111239, filed May 13, 2010, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00001" nb-file="US08626042-20140107-M00001.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00001" he="13.04mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626042-20140107-M00001.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-math idrefs="MATH-US-00002" nb-file="US08626042-20140107-M00002.NB">
<img id="EMI-M00002" he="14.14mm" wi="76.20mm" file="US08626042-20140107-M00002.TIF" alt="embedded image " img-content="math" img-format="tif"/>
</us-math>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A detecting apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a light source unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an illumination optical system for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of an image bearing member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light receiving unit for receiving the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging optical system for guiding the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member to the light receiving unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the imaging optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the principal ray of the light beam before passing through the optical plane of the imaging optical system, which has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member, and the principal ray of the light beam after passing through the optical plane of the imaging optical system, which has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member, have an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>1</b> expressed in degrees satisfying 0&#x3c;&#x3b8;1&#x2266;15 therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical plane of the imaging optical system comprises a curvature plane and the optical plane is tilt-decentered.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the optical plane of the imaging optical system comprises a curvature plane and the optical plane is shift-decentered.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the illumination optical system has an optical axis perpendicular to the surface of the image bearing member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the imaging optical system comprises a diaphragm for limiting the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member, and
<claim-text>a principal ray of the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member passes through a center of the diaphragm and enters into a center of the light receiving unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the illumination optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam exited from the light source unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light receiving unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a calculation unit for detecting an image information formed on the surface of the image bearing member based on an output from the light receiving unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the illumination optical system comprises a first optical element of which optical plane at a side of image bearing member has a planar shape, and the imaging optical system comprises a second optical element of which optical plane at a side of image bearing member has a planar shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A detecting apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a light source unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an illumination optical system for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of an image bearing member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light receiving unit for receiving the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging optical system for guiding the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member on the light receiving unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the illumination optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has exited from the light source unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light receiving unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the imaging optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a calculation unit for detecting an image information formed on the surface of the image bearing member based on an output from the light receiving unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the illumination optical system comprises a first optical element of which optical plane at a side of image bearing member has a planar shape, and the imaging optical system comprises a second optical element of which optical plane at a side of image bearing member has a planar shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a principal ray of the light beam exited from the light source unit is a central ray of the light beam exited from the light source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein, the principal ray of the light beam before passing through the optical plane of the illumination optical system, which has exited from the light source unit, and the principal ray of the light beam after passing through the optical plane of the illumination optical system, which has exited from the light source unit, have an angular difference &#x3b8;<b>2</b> expressed in degrees satisfying 0&#x3c;&#x3b8;2&#x2266;15 therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the optical plane of the illumination optical system comprises a curvature plane and the optical plane is tilt-decentered.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A detecting apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein, the optical plane of the illumination optical system comprises a curvature plane and the optical plane is sift-decentered.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. An image forming apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a detecting apparatus including:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an illumination optical system for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of an image bearing member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light receiving unit for receiving the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging optical system for guiding the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member to the light receiving unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the imaging optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has been reflected by the surface of the image bearing member to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light source unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming system for forming an image on the surface of the image bearing member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An image forming apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a detecting apparatus including:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an illumination optical system for emitting a light beam exiting from the light source unit on a surface of an image bearing member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light receiving unit for receiving the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging optical system for guiding the light beam reflected by the surface of the image bearing member on the light receiving unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the illumination optical system comprises an optical plane for causing a principal ray of the light beam that has exited from the light source unit to bend in a direction of becoming apart from the light receiving unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an image forming system for forming an image on the surface of the image bearing member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
