<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622509-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622509</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13474108</doc-number>
<date>20120517</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>165</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347 29</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Touch-free nozzle sealant removal</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6764170</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ardito</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7611222</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Cray et al.</name>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 29</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0221119</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bertelsen et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347 29</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12611986</doc-number>
<date>20091104</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8313164</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13474108</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120224004</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120906</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Olson</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen Todd</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>KY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Olson</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen Todd</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>KY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Amster, Rothstein &#x26; Ebenstein LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Funai Electric Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Luu</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Erica</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method for automatic removal of a sealant member from a nozzle plate that includes applying a sealant member to a surface of the nozzle plate, attaching the sealant member with a pull tab, one end of the pull tab being attached to a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism at a first position, the maintenance sled moves from a first position to a second position thereby removing the sealant member at a 180 degree angle and with a speed of about 10 mm/sec.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="80.86mm" wi="272.46mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="113.79mm" wi="172.38mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="192.11mm" wi="170.26mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="227.50mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="133.52mm" wi="177.80mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="192.79mm" wi="166.20mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="210.48mm" wi="186.01mm" file="US08622509-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority and benefit as a continuation of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/611,986, filed Nov. 4, 2009 now U.S. Pat. No. 8,313,164.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a print head with a sealant member and, more particularly, to a method for removing the sealant member automatically by a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism of an image forming apparatus when the image forming apparatus is powered on.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Thermal ink jet print heads that contain an ink supply from the factory utilize a low vacuum level to retain the various ink colors within their nozzles. Changes in atmospheric pressure, as well as shock and vibration, require that the nozzles be sealed against leakage during shipment. Prior to first use, the nozzle seals must be removed. Historically, manufacturers have relied upon their customers to remove the nozzle seals. Photo imageable nozzle plate (PINP) materials are more susceptible to mechanical damage during the removal of sealing means than their predecessors were. Mechanical stress applied during removal of sealing means can be minimized if the rate and angle of removal can be controlled. The nozzle seals can be made from pressure sensitive adhesive (PSA) materials as they maintain a level of tack sufficient to prevent ink leakage around each nozzle during storage and shipment to customers. The substrate upon which these acrylic adhesives are applied has been limited to polyimide, and specifically laser ablated Upilex. Within the printhead manufacturing facility, each head is inspected 24 hours after initial application of the PSA to ensure that no ink leakage has occurred. If ink leakage is detected, the PSA is removed from the nozzle plate, discarded, and a PSA tape is re-applied. The process of sealing and removal can be repeated up to three times before the entire print head is declared unsuitable for customer use. If the printhead passes the 24 hour leak inspection, another removal will be performed by the customer at the time of print head installation into a printer. New sealing materials and processes have been developed to comply with the aforementioned strength limitations and these materials include lower adhesion PSA as well as UV curable sealants. The new materials have addressed the problem of excessive stress during seal removal by lowering the adhesion, but have not addressed the inherent stress induced by the seal removal angle and speed.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, it would be desirable to provide a method to replace the variables associated with customer removal with automatic removal of a seal from the nozzle plate to ensure a specific removal angle and a specific removal speed when an image forming apparatus is powered on for the first time after the installation of an ink supply. Automated removal will allow for highly reliable removal of the seals thereby eliminating at least one source of error.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Disclosed herein is an image forming apparatus that includes an inkjet printhead including a nozzle plate, the nozzle plate having a plurality of nozzle holes formed therein, a sealant member arranged to cover the nozzle holes of the nozzle plate, a pull tab member attached to at least a portion the sealant member, a maintenance mechanism having a maintenance sled located below the print head, the pull tab being attached to the maintenance sled, the maintenance sled being positioned at a first position, wherein movement of the maintenance sled from the first position to a second position pulls the sealant member and the pull tab member from the nozzle plate.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In some embodiments, as the maintenance sled moves from the first position towards the second position, the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate at a peel angle of about 180&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another embodiment, as the maintenance sled moves from the first position to the second position, the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate at a speed of about 10 mm/sec.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In yet another aspect of the invention, disclosed is a method of providing a sealant member on a nozzle plate of a printhead that is automatically removed upon first use of the printhead, the method comprising applying a sealant member to a surface of the nozzle plate, attaching the sealant member to a pull tab, one end of the pull tab being attached to a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism at a first position, wherein the sealant member is removed by the maintenance sled as the maintenance sled moves from a first position to a second position upon first use of the printhead.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the sealant member and the pull tab drops to a bottom of the maintenance sled and remains tethered to the maintenance sled when the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In yet another aspect of the invention, disclosed herein is an image forming apparatus comprising inkjet printhead including a nozzle plate, the nozzle plate having a plurality of nozzle holes formed therein and attached to a carrier of the inkjet printhead, the carrier of the inkjet printhead being positioned at a first position, a sealant member arranged to cover the nozzle holes of the nozzle plate, and a frame member having an attachment point located below the carrier of the inkjet printhead, the frame member including mechanical barbs to retain one end of the sealant member, wherein movement of the carrier of the inkjet printhead from the first position to a second position pulls the sealant member from the nozzle plate.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In yet another embodiment, the carrier of the inkjet printhead moves from the first position to the second position when the image forming apparatus is powered on for a first time.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The above-mentioned and other features and advantages of the various embodiments of the invention, and the manner of attaining them, will become more apparent and will be better understood by reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a graph illustrating a relationship between peel strength of a PSA tape and a time period (aging time) at 60&#xb0;C.;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an elevational view of the side of one embodiment of an image forming apparatus with a printhead located over a maintenance sled and a sealant member attached to the nozzle plate of the printhead according to the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partial side view of the sealant member attached to the nozzle plate of the printhead and the maintenance sled;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial side view showing the sealant member during removal as the maintenance sled transitions from a first position to a second position;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a partial side view of the sealant member after it is pulled from the nozzle plate and drops to the bottom of the maintenance sled;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of another embodiment where the sealing means is a Pressure Sensitive Adhesive (PSA) tape that is secured to an attachment point on a frame member of the image forming apparatus after a printhead carrier is installed according to one embodiment of present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates an elevational view of the PSA tape of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> being removed from the nozzle plate when the maintenance sled moves from first position to a second position.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Reference will now be made in detail to the exemplary embodiment(s) of the invention as illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Whenever possible, the same reference numerals will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a plot of peel strength of pressure sensitive adhesive (PSA) versus aging time at 60&#xb0; C. on a nozzle plate substrate. The curve shows that there is an increase in peel strength over 4 weeks. A nozzle plate substrate has to be engineered to tolerate a minimum of one and, in one embodiment, up to four (PSA) removals. Secondly, the PSA removal by the customer is subject to significant variation as it is difficult to ensure a specific angle and/or speed of seal removal from the nozzle plate by the customer. Further, it is relevant from an engineering persepective to ensure a specific angle and/or speed of PSA removal from the nozzle plate substrate by the customer as the angle and speed impact the level of stress induced on the nozzle plate substrate material. For example, a peel angle of 180&#xb0; minimizes the amount of stress placed on the nozzle plate, whereas a peel angle of 90&#xb0; induces a maximum amount of stress placed on the nozzle plate. Similarly, a slow peel speed is better than a fast peel speed. To estimate the change in adhesion over time, samples are &#x2018;aged&#x2019; at an elevated temperature, which simulates an extended period of time. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, 60&#xb0; Celsius for a duration of 4 weeks was used to simulate a year of shelf life at room temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an elevational side view of part of an image forming apparatus <b>10</b> with a carrier assembly <b>12</b> and a print head <b>14</b>, the print head <b>14</b> includes a nozzle plate <b>16</b> having plurality of nozzles holes (not shown) formed therein. The print head <b>14</b> is installed in the carrier assembly <b>12</b> that is located over a maintenance mechanism <b>18</b>. The maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> includes a maintenance sled <b>20</b>. A sealant member <b>22</b> is placed such that it covers the nozzle holes of the nozzle plate <b>16</b> and is removed when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is powered on for the first time.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a sealant member <b>22</b> in home position covering the nozzle holes of the nozzle plate <b>16</b> with the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> in a home position. A pull tab <b>24</b> is attached to an attachment post <b>26</b> on the maintenance sled <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In some embodiments, the print head unit is permanently or semi-permanently integrated with the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> and the pull tab <b>24</b> may be secured to the attachment post <b>26</b> at the manufacturer site. In such case, the pull tab <b>24</b> is removed the first time the image forming apparatus is turned on. But in alternative embodiments, a disposable print head might be associated with an ink supply cartridge and the connection between the pull tab <b>24</b> and the attachment post <b>26</b> may need to occur at or near the time an ink supply is installed in the image forming device. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-5</figref>, a pull tab <b>24</b> is shown physically connected to the sealant member <b>22</b> by a looped portion that wraps around a corresponding grooved portion of the attachment post <b>26</b>. One option for making the connection between the pull tab <b>24</b> and the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> is to have an operator manually attach the pull tab <b>24</b> to the attachment post <b>26</b> as part of an ink supply installation process. Using the embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-5</figref> as an illustrative example, the installation process could require that an operator manually connect the pull tab <b>24</b> to the maintenance sled <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">But complicating the installation process can be problematic, so another possible option is to design a pull tab <b>24</b> such that when a supply item is installed, a looped portion of a pull tab is disposed within the image forming device such that the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> automatically grabs the pull tab <b>24</b> as it passes by the sealant member, and removes the sealant member the first time the ink supply unit is powered on after the ink supply installation occurs. One of ordinary skill in the art will readily recognize that there are multiple designs of the sealant member and/or pull tab that would allow a maintenance mechanism to connect to and remove the sealant member as the maintenance mechanism moves across the sealant member.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">When the maintenance sled <b>20</b> moves from left to right, as indicated by the arrow, the pull tab <b>24</b> also moves along with the maintenance sled <b>20</b> and given the height of the attachment post <b>26</b> being so close to the sealant member <b>22</b>, the sealant member <b>22</b> is removed at an angle of about 180&#xb0;. While the sealant member <b>22</b> and pull tab <b>24</b> are described as two pieces, they may be one integral piece and still fall within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates the sealant member <b>22</b> partially removed from the nozzle holes and the 180 degree removal angle. The sealant member <b>22</b> is removed from its fixed position on the nozzle plate <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) by the maintenance sled <b>20</b> of the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is powered up for the first time. At power-up, the maintenance sled <b>20</b> moves from left, i.e., home position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), to the right in the direction of the arrow to remove sealant member <b>22</b>. Due to the direction of travel of the maintenance sled <b>20</b> and the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b> and the attachment point of the pull tab <b>24</b> to the attachment post <b>26</b>, a peel angle of about 180&#xb0; is assured in removing the sealant member <b>22</b> from the nozzle plate <b>16</b>. The angle of removal may also be changed by changing the relative positions of the nozzle plate <b>16</b> and the attachment post <b>26</b>. Also, the speed of travel of the maintenance sled <b>20</b> and hence the removal speed of the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b>, is controlled to a maximum of 10 mm/sec to ensure a low stress sealing means removal. Similarly, the nozzle plate <b>16</b> may also move relative to the attachment post <b>26</b> in order to remove the sealant member <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the sealant member <b>22</b> after it is pulled free of the nozzle plate <b>16</b> and the sealant member <b>22</b> drops to the bottom of the maintenance sled <b>20</b>. The sealant member <b>22</b> falls over attachment post <b>26</b> of the maintenance sled <b>20</b> with the sealant member <b>22</b> landing nearby. The maintenance sled <b>20</b> of the maintenance mechanism <b>18</b>, the carrier assembly <b>12</b> and the print head <b>14</b> then returns to the home position once the sealant member <b>22</b> falls over attachment post <b>26</b> to initiate priming of the print head <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows another embodiment of a sealant member <b>28</b> which is a pressure sensitive adhesive (PSA) tape attached to the nozzle plate <b>16</b> that is attached to the print head carrier <b>34</b> according to the present invention. The PSA tape <b>28</b> is attached to the nozzle plate <b>16</b> in an initial position. One end of the PSA tape <b>28</b> is secured to an attachment point <b>32</b> on a frame member <b>30</b> of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> after a printhead carrier <b>34</b> is installed. The frame member <b>30</b> preferably includes mechanical barbs <b>36</b> that assist in retaining one end of the PSA tape <b>28</b> as the PSA tape <b>28</b> is a low tack PSA tape. In this regard, PSA tape <b>28</b> can be utilized without relying solely on adhesion to the frame member <b>30</b> to retain the PSA tape <b>28</b> depending on the adhesion to the frame member <b>30</b>. The printhead carrier <b>34</b> of the image forming apparatus removes the PSA tape <b>28</b> when the printhead carrier <b>34</b> moves from its original position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) to a second position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) when the image forming apparatus <b>10</b> is powered on for a first time.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The direction of travel of the printhead carrier <b>34</b> and the motion of the printhead carrier <b>34</b> are aligned in such a manner that when the printhead carrier <b>34</b> moves from the first position to the second position, the PSA tape <b>28</b> is removed by the print head carrier motion relative to the frame member <b>30</b> to ensure a peel angle of about 180&#xb0;. Further, the speed of the printhead carrier <b>34</b>, when moving from the first direction to the second direction, is controlled to a maximum of 10 mm/sec relative to the frame member <b>30</b> to ensure a low stress sealing member removal. Once the PSA tape <b>28</b> is pulled free of the nozzle plate <b>16</b> due to the relative motion of the printhead <b>14</b>, the PSA tape <b>28</b> drops to the bottom of the image forming apparatus <b>10</b>, where it remains tethered to the attachment point <b>32</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">By automatically removing the sealant member <b>22</b> as described above, there is a reduced risk of nozzle plate damage with the use of PSA tapes or UV curable sealants. The rate and angle of removal can also be optimized so the sealants are removed either parallel to vias (north-south) or orthogonal to the vias (east-west), depending on the configuration of the image forming apparatus. In both cases, the rate and angle can be controlled by design.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made to the present invention without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Thus it is intended that the present invention cover the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of providing a sealant member on a nozzle plate of a printhead that is automatically removed upon first use of the printhead, the method comprising:
<claim-text>applying a sealant member to a surface of the nozzle plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching the sealant member to a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism at a first position, wherein as the maintenance sled moves from a first position to a second position upon first use of the printhead, the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate with a peel angle of about 180&#xb0; , and wherein the sealant members drops to a bottom of the maintenance sled and remains tethered to the maintenance sled after removal from the nozzle plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further including applying the sealant member as a UV curable sealant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein as the maintenance sled moves from the first position towards the second position, further including removing the sealant member from the nozzle plate with a speed of about 10 mm/sec.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method of providing a sealant member on a nozzle plate of a printhead that is automatically removed upon first use of the printhead, comprising:
<claim-text>applying a sealant member to a surface of the nozzle plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixedly attaching an end of the sealant member to a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism at a first position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving the maintenance sled from the first position to a second position so that as the maintenance sled moves from the first position toward the second position, the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate by the maintenance sled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further including applying the sealant member as a UV curable sealant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein as the maintenance sled moves from the first position towards the second position, further including removing the sealant member from the nozzle plate with a speed of about 10 mm/sec.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the sealant member drops to a bottom of the maintenance sled and remains tethered to the maintenance sled after removal from the nozzle plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate with a peel angle of about 180&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of providing a sealant member on a nozzle plate of a printhead that is automatically removed upon first use of the printhead, the method comprising:
<claim-text>applying a sealant member to a surface of the nozzle plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching the sealant member to a maintenance sled of a maintenance mechanism at a first position, wherein as the maintenance sled moves from a first position to a second position upon first use of the printhead, the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate by the maintenance sled.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further including applying the sealant member as a UV curable sealant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein as the maintenance sled moves from the first position towards the second position, further including removing the sealant member from the nozzle plate with a speed of about 10 mm/sec.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the sealant member drops to a bottom of the maintenance sled and remains tethered to the maintenance sled after removal from the nozzle plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the sealant member is removed from the nozzle plate with a peel angle of about 180&#xb0;. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
