<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624489-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624489</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13538228</doc-number>
<date>20120629</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>94113941 A</doc-number>
<date>20050429</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>98104418 A</doc-number>
<date>20090211</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>6</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>62</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313506</main-classification>
<further-classification>313498</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e90">Light-emitting diode die packages and illumination apparatuses using same</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0123148</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Park</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>257 94</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313498</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313502</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313506</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313509</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313512</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 98</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>257 99</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>15</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>31</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12703369</doc-number>
<date>20100210</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8242690</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13538228</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12492606</doc-number>
<date>20090626</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7858416</doc-number>
<date>20101228</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12703369</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11302127</doc-number>
<date>20051214</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7635876</doc-number>
<date>20091222</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12492606</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120267648</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121025</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shen</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Nung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shen</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Nung</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Jackson IPG PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Evergrand Holdings Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tortola</city>
<country>VG</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Vip</first-name>
<department>2889</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention relates to an LED die package, which has a light-emitting diode die having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer. A surface of the sapphire layer opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer is disposed is formed with generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses and overlaid with a phosphor powder layer. Each of the first and the second doped layers has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode, on which an insulation layer is disposed and formed with exposure holes for exposing the electrodes. The exposure holes are each filled with an electrically conductive linker.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="114.55mm" wi="312.34mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="244.18mm" wi="136.74mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="252.73mm" wi="167.05mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="249.43mm" wi="184.49mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="240.54mm" wi="176.28mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="251.71mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="212.51mm" wi="159.77mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="243.16mm" wi="153.84mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="216.49mm" wi="150.28mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="178.22mm" wi="185.50mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="166.71mm" wi="114.98mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="213.87mm" wi="126.15mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="216.83mm" wi="160.44mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="243.50mm" wi="172.30mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="195.75mm" wi="137.08mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="236.56mm" wi="122.26mm" file="US08624489-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional application of U.S. Ser. No. 12/703,369, filed Feb. 10, 2010, which is a continuation-in-part application of U.S. Ser. No. 12/492,606, filed Jun. 26, 2009 and issued as U.S. Pat. No. 7,858,416, which is a divisional application of U.S. Ser. No. 11/302,127, filed Dec. 14, 2005 and issued as U.S. Pat. No. 7,635,876, the disclosures of all of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to light-emitting diode (LED) die packages and illumination apparatuses using the same, and more particularly, to highly reliable LED die packages and illumination apparatuses using the same.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As the global trend of energy saving continuously progresses, light-emitting diodes play an increasingly important role in this regard, in view of the fact that they have been used more and more in the replacement of traditional light sources. However, the thermal dissipation ability of LEDs should still be improved to realize a more ideal light source.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In view of the above, the inventor has devised LED die packages, as well as illumination apparatuses using the same, to fulfill the need in this respect.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, an object of the invention is to provide an LED die package and an illumination apparatus using the same.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In order to achieve this object, a light-emitting diode die package according to a technical feature of the invention is provided, which comprises a light-emitting diode die having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer disposed on the sapphire layer and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer disposed on the first doped layer and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer, wherein a surface of the sapphire layer opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer is disposed is formed with a plurality of generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses, and wherein each of the first doped layer and the second doped layer has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode; a phosphor powder layer disposed on the surface of the sapphire layer formed with the recesses; an insulation layer disposed on the electrode-forming surfaces and formed with a plurality of exposure holes for exposing the electrodes corresponding thereto; and a plurality of electrically conductive linkers, each being formed within one of the exposure holes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to another technical feature of the invention, a light-emitting diode die package is provided, which comprises at least two light-emitting diode dies, each having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer disposed on the sapphire layer and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer disposed on the first doped layer and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer, wherein each of the first doped layers and the second doped layers has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode, and wherein a gap is provided between the first doped layers of two light-emitting diode dies, so that a continuous metal layer present between the first doped layers of neighboring LED dies is divided; a first insulation layer disposed on the electrode-forming surfaces of the first doped layers and the second doped layers, the first insulation layer being formed with a plurality of exposure holes for exposing the corresponding electrodes of the first doped layers and the second doped layers; a second insulation layer disposed on the first insulation layer, the second insulation layer being formed with a plurality of communication holes and a plurality of through holes, wherein each of the communication holes is adapted for communicating two exposure holes with each other, with the two exposure holes exposing two electrodes that have opposite polarity and reside in neighboring light-emitting diode dies, and wherein each of the through holes is registered with an exposure hole for exposing an electrode that need not be electrically connected to any electrode located in neighboring light-emitting diode dies; conductors formed within the exposure holes, the communication holes and the through holes, so that the light-emitting diode dies are electrically connected in series; a cover layer disposed on the second insulation layer and formed with a plurality of open holes, each being registered with a through hole; and a plurality of electrically conductive linkers formed within the open holes and adapted for electrically connecting the conductors located within the through holes to an external circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to still another technical feature of the invention, a light-emitting diode die package is provided, which comprises a light-emitting diode die having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer disposed on the sapphire layer and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer disposed on the first doped layer and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer, wherein a surface of the sapphire layer opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer is disposed is formed with a plurality of generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses, and wherein each of the first doped layer and the second doped layer has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode, and wherein the recesses comprise inclined walls coated with metal layers; a support plate having a supporting surface, on which conductive contacts are disposed; a heat-dissipating film layer overlaid on the supporting surface of the supporting layer; a thermal conductive film layer overlaid on the heat-dissipating film layer; and a circular seat disposed on the thermal conductive film layer and having an upper edge, the upper edge of the circular seat being provided with conductive contacts, wherein the light-emitting diode die is positioned at a central portion of the circular seat by being secured to the thermal conductive film layer with a metal connecting layer, and wherein the electrodes provided on the first doped layer and the second doped layer are electrically connected to the conductive contacts provided on the circular seat via wires and the conductive contacts provided on the circular seat are electrically connected to the corresponding conductive contacts provided on the support plate via wires.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to still another technical feature of the invention, a light-emitting diode die package is provided, which comprises a light-emitting diode die having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer disposed on the sapphire layer and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer disposed on the first doped layer and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer, wherein a surface of the sapphire layer opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer is disposed is formed with a plurality of generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses, and wherein each of the first doped layer and the second doped layer has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode; a phosphor powder layer disposed on the surface of the sapphire layer formed with the recesses; an insulation layer disposed on the electrode-forming surfaces and formed with a plurality of exposure holes for exposing the electrodes corresponding thereto; a plurality of electrically conductive linkers, each being formed within one of the exposure holes; a support plate having a supporting surface, on which conductive contacts are disposed; a heat-dissipating film layer overlaid on the supporting surface of the support plate and formed with at least two through holes that communicate between an upper surface and a lower surface thereof, wherein the light-emitting diode die is secured to the heat-dissipating film layer, so that the electrically conductive linkers are electrically connected to the conductive contacts of the support plate via the corresponding through holes provided in the heat-dissipating film layer; and a circular seat, placed on the heat-dissipating film layer, so that the light-emitting diode die is located at a central portion of the circular seat.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to still another technical feature of the invention, an illumination apparatus is provided, which comprises an elongated housing provided at both ends with an electrode adapted for being connected to an external socket, the housing having a base part and a transparent part, wherein the base part has a chamber and a mounting surface; a power supplying circuit unit disposed within the chamber of the base part and provided with an input terminal and an output terminal which are electrically connected to the electrodes located at both ends of the housing; and a light-emitting unit including a mounting substrate disposed on the mounting surface of the base part and a plurality of light-emitting diode die packages according to the invention placed on a mounting surface of the mounting substrate, wherein the mounting surface of the mounting substrate is overlaid with predetermined circuit traces electrically connected to the output terminal of the power supplying circuit unit, and wherein the electrically conductive linkers of the light-emitting diode die packages are electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces overlaid on the mounting substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to still another technical feature of the invention, an illumination apparatus is provided, which comprises an elongated housing provided at both ends with an electrode adapted for being connected to an external socket, the housing having a base part and a transparent part, wherein the base part has a chamber and a mounting surface mounted with predetermined circuit traces; a power supplying circuit unit disposed within the chamber of the base part and provided with an input terminal and an output terminal which are electrically connected to the electrodes located at both ends of the housing; and a light-emitting unit including a plurality of light-emitting diode die packages according to the invention placed on the mounting surface of the base part, wherein the electrodes of the light-emitting diode die packages are electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces overlaid on the mounting surface of the base part.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to yet still another technical feature of the invention, an illumination apparatus is provided, which comprises a housing including a body, a transparent cap and an adapter, wherein the body has an upper surface and an accommodating chamber accessible through a lower open end of the body, and wherein the transparent cap is fixed to an upper end of the body, and wherein the adapter is mounted at the lower open end of the body; a power supplying circuit unit having a power supplying module which is placed into the accommodating chamber through the lower open end of the body, wherein the power supplying module includes input terminals electrically connected to a positive-voltage electrode and a negative-voltage electrode of the adapter; and a light-emitting unit including a substrate mounted on the upper surface of the body and a plurality of light-emitting diode die packages according to the invention operatively mounted on the substrate, wherein a surface of the substrate on which the light-emitting diode die packages are mounted is overlaid with predetermined circuit traces electrically connected to the electrodes of the light-emitting diode die packages, and wherein the power supplying module has an output terminal which is electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces overlaid on the substrate via a wire, so that the light-emitting diode die packages can receive electric power from the power supplying module.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The above and other objects, features and effects of the invention will become apparent with reference to the following description of the preferred embodiments taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of a method for packaging an LED die package according to the first preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of a method for packaging an LED die package which includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 to 10</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of an alternative method to that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref> for packaging an LED die package which includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an equivalent circuit diagram for an LED die package which includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 to 13</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of a method for packaging an LED die package according to the second preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the third preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the four preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the fifth preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 to 19</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of alternative examples of the phosphor layer <b>103</b> in the first preferred embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 20 and 21</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of an alternative method for packaging an LED die package according to the first preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of an illumination apparatus that uses an LED die package according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> is schematic cross-sectional view of an alternative example of the illumination apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 25 to 27</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of another illumination apparatus that uses an LED die package according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 28 and 29</figref> are schematic diagrams illustrating a light-emitting unit of an illumination apparatus that uses an LED die package according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an alternative example of the illumination apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an alternative example of the illumination apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Before the present invention is described in greater detail, it should be noted that the same or like elements are denoted by the same reference numerals throughout the disclosure. Moreover, the elements shown in the drawings are not illustrated in actual scale, but are expressly illustrated to explain in an intuitive manner the technical feature of the invention disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of a method for packaging an LED die package according to the first preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, a light-emitting diode (LED) die <b>1</b> is provided. It should be noted that the packaging method according to the invention is carried out on an intact wafer and the LED die <b>1</b> remains undiced from the wafer. For clarity, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> omit the LED dies neighboring to the LED die <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The LED die <b>1</b> has a sapphire layer <b>10</b>, a first doped layer <b>11</b> disposed on the sapphire layer <b>10</b> and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer <b>12</b> disposed on the first doped layer <b>11</b> and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Next, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer <b>11</b> is disposed is subjected to an etching process, so that the surface <b>100</b> is formed with a plurality of generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses <b>101</b> and turned into a roughened surface <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">It should be noted that the formation of the recesses <b>101</b> is not limited to by performing an etching process. Any process adapted for roughening the surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> can be used in the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a phosphor powder layer <b>103</b> is formed on the surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> in such a manner that the phosphor powder layer <b>103</b> extends into the recesses <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Since the first and second doped layers <b>11</b> and <b>12</b> have a refractive index of 2.4, the sapphire layer <b>10</b> has a refractive index of 1.7 and the phosphor layer <b>103</b> has a refractive index of 1.4, the structure described above achieves a multiple refraction effect and increases the light extraction efficiency by a factor of 24-50%.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the first doped layer <b>11</b> and the second doped layer <b>12</b> have electrode-forming surfaces <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> formed with electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>, on which an insulation layer <b>104</b> is disposed after formation of the phosphor layer <b>103</b>. The insulation layer <b>104</b> is subjected to exposure and development processes to be formed with several exposure holes <b>1040</b> for exposing corresponding electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b>. Each of the exposure holes <b>1040</b> is then formed inside with an electrically conductive linker <b>2</b> for electrically connecting the electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> to external circuit components (not shown). Finally, the resultant structure is subjected to a dicing process to give an LED die package according to the first preferred embodiment of the invention as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">It should be noted that the insulation layer <b>104</b> can be made of a transparent material doped with phosphor powder. In addition, the electrically conductive linker <b>2</b> is preferably fabricated by laminating <b>1</b> to <b>6</b> metal layers together using a vapor depositing process and/or an electro-plating process. For example, the electrically conductive linker <b>2</b> is preferably made of a combination of a silver layer, a diamond film layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer, a combination of a silver layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer, or a combination of a chromium layer, a diamond film layer, a silver layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Now referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref>, in the case where the LED die package according to the invention includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series, an LED wafer W, prior to being processed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> or subsequent to being processed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is subjected to a dicing process along a dicing line CL, so as to generate a gap S between the first doped layers <b>11</b> of two neighboring LED dies <b>1</b>, thereby dividing a continuous metal layer (not shown) present between the first doped layers <b>11</b> of neighboring LED dies <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> demonstrates that the dicing process is carried out to a depth that reaches the sapphire layer <b>10</b>, it should be noted that the dicing process may be performed to a less extent, so long as the continuous metal layer present between the first doped layers <b>11</b> of neighboring LED dies <b>1</b> is divided.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Next, a first insulation layer <b>104</b> is formed on the surfaces <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> of the first doped layers <b>11</b> and the second doped layers <b>12</b>, with the insulative material being filled into the gaps S. The first insulation layer <b>104</b> is subjected to exposure and development processes to be formed with a plurality of exposure holes <b>1040</b> for exposing corresponding electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> on the first doped layers <b>11</b> and the second doped layers <b>12</b>. A second insulation layer <b>106</b> is then formed on the first insulation layer <b>104</b>. The second insulation layer <b>106</b> is subjected to exposure and development processes to be formed with a plurality of communication holes <b>1060</b> and a plurality of through holes <b>1061</b>. Each of the communication holes <b>1060</b> is adapted for communicating two exposure holes <b>1040</b> with each other, with the two exposure holes <b>1040</b> exposing two electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> that have opposite polarity and reside in neighboring LED dies <b>1</b>. The through hole <b>1061</b> are adapted for exposing the electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> that need not be electrically connected to any electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> located in the neighboring LED dies <b>1</b>. For example, in the case where the LED die package includes ten LED dies electrically connected in series, an electrode <b>121</b> located in the first LED die <b>1</b> and an electrode <b>111</b> located in the tenth LED die <b>1</b> are exposed through the exposure holes <b>1040</b> and the through holes <b>1061</b> registered therewith, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Then, conductors <b>108</b> are formed within the exposure holes <b>1040</b>, the communication holes <b>1060</b> and the through holes <b>1061</b>, so that the LED dies <b>1</b> are electrically connected in series. A cover layer <b>107</b> is then disposed on the second insulation layer <b>106</b> and is subjected to exposure and development processes to be formed with a plurality of open holes <b>1070</b>, each being registered with a through hole <b>1061</b>. Electrically conductive linkers <b>2</b> are then formed within the open holes <b>1070</b> and used for electrically connecting to external circuit components. Finally, the resultant structure is subjected to a dicing process to give individual LED die packages having predetermined amounts of LED dies connected in series or in parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Similar to those described in the embodiments above, the insulation layers <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, <b>107</b> are preferably made of transparent material doped with phosphor powder, and the conductors <b>108</b> and the electrically conductive linkers <b>2</b> are preferably formed by laminating <b>1</b> to <b>6</b> metal layers together using a vapor depositing process and/or an electro-plating process.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of an alternative method to that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref> for packaging an LED die package which includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, an LED wafer W, prior to being processed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> or subsequent to being processed as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, is formed with a cover layer <b>105</b> on the electrode-mounting surfaces <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> of the first doped layers <b>11</b> and the second doped layers <b>12</b>. The cover layer <b>105</b> is subjected to exposure and development processes to be formed with a plurality of via holes <b>1050</b> for exposing portions of the surfaces <b>110</b> of the first doped layers <b>11</b> that are proximal to the dicing lines CL. The portions of the first doped layers <b>11</b> which are exposed by the via holes <b>1050</b> are then removed by chemical etching, so as to divide a continuous metal layer (not shown) present between the first doped layers <b>11</b> of neighboring LED dies <b>1</b>. Similarly, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> demonstrates that the dicing process is carried out to a depth that reaches the sapphire layer <b>10</b>, the dicing process may be performed to a less extent, so long as the continuous metal layer present between the first doped layers <b>11</b> of neighboring LED dies <b>1</b> is divided.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Next, the cover layer <b>105</b> is removed and the processes shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 to 8</figref> are performed afterwards to result in a structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. Finally, the resultant structure is subjected to a dicing process to give individual LED die packages having predetermined amounts of LED dies electrically connected in series or in parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Similar to those described in the embodiments above, the insulation layers <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, <b>107</b> are preferably made of transparent material doped with phosphor powder, and the conductors <b>108</b> and the electrically conductive linkers <b>2</b> are preferably formed by laminating <b>1</b> to <b>6</b> metal layers together using a vapor depositing process and/or an electro-plating process.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an equivalent circuit diagram for the LED dies connected in series shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, each of the LED dies <b>1</b> may be electrically connected in parallel to a fuse unit <b>6</b> made of SiOH<sub>4</sub>. When an LED die <b>1</b> fails to work and causes an open circuit, the fuse unit <b>6</b> corresponding thereto melts down due to overvoltage and is therefore short-circuited to turn into an electrically connected state. Hence, even if one of the LED dies <b>1</b> connected in series fails to function normally, the rest of them would remain operating. The conventional problem in this respect is overcome accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 to 13</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of a method for packaging an LED die package according to the second preferred embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Contrary to the first preferred embodiment, this embodiment as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is featured by, after formation of recesses <b>101</b> on a sapphire layer <b>10</b>, coating a metal layer <b>102</b> on inclined walls of the recesses <b>101</b>. The LED wafer is then subjected to a dicing process to obtain a plurality of LED dies shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Next, a support plate <b>3</b> is prepared as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>. The support plate <b>3</b> has a supporting surface <b>30</b>, on which a plurality of conductive contacts <b>31</b> and predetermined circuit traces (not shown) for being electrically connected to the conductive contacts <b>31</b> are disposed. The supporting surface <b>30</b> of the support plate <b>3</b> is overlaid with a heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> made by a material having a thermal conductivity between 900 W/(m&#xb7;K) to 1200 W/(m&#xb7;K), such as a diamond material. The heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> is overlaid with a thermal conductive film layer <b>33</b> made by a material having a thermal conductivity between 400 W/(m&#xb7;K) to 700 W/(m&#xb7;K), such as pyrolytic graphite.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">A circular seat <b>34</b> made of silicon is then placed on the thermal conductive film layer <b>33</b>. An upper edge of the circular seat <b>34</b> is provided with conductive contacts <b>340</b>. The LED die shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is then positioned at a central portion of the circular seat <b>34</b> by being secured to the thermal conductive film layer <b>33</b> with a metal connecting layer <b>35</b>. The electrodes <b>111</b>, <b>121</b> provided on the first doped layer <b>11</b> and the second doped layer <b>12</b> are electrically connected to the conductive contacts <b>340</b> provided on the circular seat <b>34</b> via wires <b>36</b>, whereas the conductive contacts <b>340</b> provided on the circular seat <b>34</b> are electrically connected to the corresponding conductive contacts <b>31</b> provided on the support plate <b>3</b> via wires <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Finally, a phosphor layer <b>38</b> is formed at the central portion of the circular seat <b>34</b> in a manner covering the LED die.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the third preferred embodiment of the invention. An LED die shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and a support plate <b>4</b> are first provided. The support plate <b>4</b> has a supporting surface <b>40</b>, on which a plurality of conductive contacts <b>41</b> and predetermined circuit traces (not shown) are disposed. The supporting surface <b>40</b> of the support plate <b>4</b> is overlaid with a heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> described in the second preferred embodiment. Contrary to the second preferred embodiment, the heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> used herein is formed with at least two through holes <b>320</b> that communicate between the upper and lower surfaces of the layer <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The LED die shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is secured to the heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> by a suitable process, such as reflow soldering, so that the electrically conductive linkers <b>2</b> are electrically connected to the conductive contacts <b>41</b> of the support plate <b>4</b> via the corresponding through holes <b>320</b> in the heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b>. A circular seat <b>34</b> described in the second preferred embodiment is then placed on the heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b>, so that the LED die is located at a central portion of the circular seat <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Finally, a phosphor layer <b>38</b> is formed at the central portion of the circular seat <b>34</b> in a manner covering the LED die. It should be noted, however, that a phosphor layer <b>103</b> is optional in this embodiment and can be omitted due to the provision of the phosphor layer <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the fourth preferred embodiment of the invention. Contrary to the second preferred embodiment, this embodiment includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series or in parallel. It should be noted that the LED dies according to this embodiment may be electrically connected in series, in parallel, or partly in series and partly in parallel. Since this embodiment merely differs from the second preferred embodiment in the amount of LED dies mounted in an LED die package, the details thereof are omitted for brevity.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of an LED die package according to the fifth preferred embodiment of the invention. Contrary to the third preferred embodiment, this embodiment includes two or more LED dies electrically connected in series or in parallel. It should be noted that the LED dies according to this embodiment may be electrically connected in series, in parallel, or partly in series and partly in parallel. Since this embodiment merely differs from the third preferred embodiment in the amount of LED dies mounted in an LED die package, the details thereof are omitted for brevity.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 to 19</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of alternative examples of the phosphor layer <b>103</b> in the first preferred embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref>, the phosphor layer <b>103</b> disposed on the surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> is a yellow phosphor layer. It should be noted that the phosphor layer <b>103</b> is provided to extensively cover side surfaces of the sapphire layer <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, the phosphor layer <b>103</b> disposed on the surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> is composed of a red phosphor layer <b>103</b>-<b>1</b> and a green phosphor layer <b>103</b>-<b>2</b>. It should be noted that the phosphor layer <b>103</b> is provided to extensively cover side surfaces of the sapphire layer <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>, the phosphor layer <b>103</b> disposed on the surface <b>100</b> of the sapphire layer <b>10</b> is composed of a red phosphor layer <b>103</b>-<b>1</b>, a green phosphor layer <b>103</b>-<b>2</b> and a blue phosphor layer <b>103</b>-<b>3</b>. It should be noted that the phosphor layer <b>103</b> is provided to extensively cover side surfaces of the sapphire layer <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 20 and 21</figref> are schematic, cross-sectional flowcharts of an alternative method for packaging an LED die package according to the first preferred embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref>, contrary to the first preferred embodiment, a heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> or a thermal conductive film layer <b>33</b> described in the second preferred embodiment is disposed on portions of the electrode-mounting surfaces <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> that are exposed by the exposure holes <b>1040</b>, after the formation of the exposure holes <b>1040</b> in the insulation layer <b>104</b>. The heat-dissipating film layer <b>32</b> or the thermal conductive film layer <b>33</b> is then overlaid with a high thermal conductive metal layer <b>34</b> composed of a nickel layer combined with a gold layer, or an aluminum layer combined with a copper layer. It should be noted, however, that the metal layer <b>34</b> may be a copper layer. Alternatively, the metal layer <b>34</b> may be made of any suitable metal or alloy, such as Al, AlN<sub>3</sub>, Cu, BN<sub>3 </sub>and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">A protective layer <b>109</b> is then formed on the insulation layer <b>104</b>. The protective layer <b>109</b> is then subjected to exposure and development processes, so that the protective layer <b>109</b> is removed other than the portion located between the electrode <b>111</b> of the first doped layer <b>11</b> and the electrode <b>121</b> of the first doped layer <b>12</b>. Finally, the metal layers <b>34</b> are each overlaid with an electrically conductive linker <b>2</b> for connection to external circuits. According to this embodiment, when the LED die package is mounted, for example, on a printed circuit board by using a reflow soldering process, the residual portion of the protective layer <b>109</b> functions to prevent the melted electrically conductive linkers <b>2</b> disposed on the electrode <b>111</b> of the first doped layer <b>11</b> and the electrode <b>121</b> of the first doped layer <b>12</b>, respectively, from contacting each other and causing a short circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Similarly, the insulation layer <b>104</b> and the protective layer <b>109</b> are preferably made by a transparent material doped with phosphor powder.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of an illumination apparatus that uses an LED die package according to the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The illumination apparatus includes an elongated housing <b>5</b>, a power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b> and a light-emitting unit <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The housing <b>5</b> is composed of a base part <b>5</b><i>a </i>and a transparent part <b>5</b><i>b</i>. The base part <b>5</b><i>a </i>has a chamber <b>50</b> for accommodating the power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b> and a mounting surface <b>52</b> for receiving the light-emitting unit <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b> disposed within the chamber <b>50</b> is provided with an input terminal <b>81</b> and an output terminal <b>82</b>, which are electrically connected to electrodes <b>51</b> located at both ends of the housing <b>5</b> and acting like the electrodes provided at both ends of a conventional fluorescent lamp tube.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The light-emitting unit <b>7</b> includes a mounting substrate <b>70</b> disposed on the mounting surface <b>52</b> of the base part <b>5</b><i>a </i>and a plurality of LED die packages <b>71</b> placed on amounting surface <b>700</b> of the mounting substrate <b>70</b>. The mounting surface <b>700</b> of the mounting substrate <b>70</b> is overlaid with predetermined circuit traces (not shown) electrically connected to the output terminal <b>82</b> of the power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b>. The electrically conductive linkers (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the LED die packages <b>71</b> are electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces overlaid on the mounting substrate <b>70</b>. It should be noted that the LED die packages <b>71</b> used herein are not limited to those described in the embodiments according to the invention but include any suitable LED die packages for the purpose of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> is schematic cross-sectional view of an alternative example of the illumination apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref>, this embodiment differs from the illumination apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</figref> in that circuit traces <b>701</b> are mounted on amounting surface <b>51</b> of the base part <b>5</b><i>a</i>, and in that the LED die packages <b>71</b> are directly mounted on the mounting surface <b>51</b> and electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces. As a result, the mounting substrate <b>70</b> is omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 25 to 27</figref> are schematic cross-sectional views of another illumination apparatus that uses an LED die package according to the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 25 to 27</figref>, the illumination apparatus includes a housing <b>5</b>&#x2032;, a power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b>&#x2032; and a light-emitting unit <b>7</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The housing <b>5</b>&#x2032; includes a body <b>53</b>, a transparent cap <b>54</b> and an adapter <b>55</b>. The body <b>53</b> has an upper surface <b>530</b> for receiving a substrate <b>70</b> of the light-emitting unit <b>7</b>&#x2032; and an accommodating chamber <b>531</b> for accommodating a power supplying module <b>80</b> of the power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b>&#x2032;. The accommodating chamber <b>531</b> is accessible through a lower open end of the body <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The transparent cap <b>54</b> is fixed to an upper end of the body <b>53</b>, so as to allow the transmission of light from the light-emitting unit <b>7</b>&#x2032; disposed on the upper surface <b>530</b> of the body <b>53</b> to outside of the apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">According to the embodiment, the adapter <b>55</b> is configured as an E27-type adapter and mounted at the lower open end of the body <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The power supplying circuit unit <b>8</b>&#x2032; has a power supplying module <b>80</b> which is placed into the accommodating chamber <b>531</b> through the lower open end of the body <b>53</b>. The power supplying module <b>80</b> includes input terminals <b>81</b> electrically connected to a positive-voltage electrode and a negative-voltage electrode of the adapter <b>55</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The light-emitting unit <b>7</b>&#x2032; includes a substrate <b>70</b> mounted on the upper surface <b>530</b> of the body <b>53</b> and a plurality of LED die packages <b>71</b> operatively mounted on the substrate <b>70</b>. A surface of the substrate <b>70</b> on which the LED die packages <b>71</b> are mounted is overlaid with predetermined circuit traces (not shown) for electrical connection to the electrodes of the LED die packages <b>71</b>. The power supplying module <b>80</b> has an output terminal <b>82</b> which is electrically connected to the corresponding circuit traces overlaid on the substrate <b>70</b> via a wire <b>83</b>, so that the LED die packages <b>71</b> can receive electric power from the power supplying module <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">It should be noted that the LED die packages <b>71</b> used herein may be any of the LED die packages described in the embodiments above. In addition, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 28 and 29</figref>, the light-emitting unit <b>7</b>&#x2032; may further include a circular ring <b>72</b> disposed on the substrate <b>70</b> in a manner surrounding the LED die packages <b>71</b> and a phosphor powder <b>73</b> disposed in the circular ring <b>72</b> in a manner covering the LED die packages <b>71</b>. Further, the transparent cap <b>54</b> of the housing <b>5</b>&#x2032; may be configured into other shapes, such as those shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 30 and 31</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In conclusion, the LED die packages and the illumination apparatuses using the same as disclosed herein can surely achieve the intended objects and effects of the invention by virtue of the structural arrangements and operating steps described above.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">While the invention has been described with reference to the preferred embodiments above, it should be recognized that the preferred embodiments are given for the purpose of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention and that various modifications and changes, which will be apparent to those skilled in the relevant art, may be made without departing from the spirit of the invention and the scope thereof as defined in the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A light-emitting diode die package, comprising:
<claim-text>at least two light-emitting diode dies, each having a sapphire layer, a first doped layer disposed on the sapphire layer and doped with a p- or n-type dopant, and a second doped layer disposed on the first doped layer and doped with a different dopant from that doped in the first doped layer, wherein each of the first doped layers and the second doped layers has an electrode-forming surface formed with an electrode, and wherein a gap is provided between the first doped layers of two light-emitting diode dies, so that a continuous metal layer present between the first doped layers of neighboring LED dies is divided;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first insulation layer disposed on the electrode-forming surfaces of the first doped layers and the second doped layers, the first insulation layer being formed with a plurality of exposure holes for exposing the corresponding electrodes of the first doped layers and the second doped layers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second insulation layer disposed on the first insulation layer, the second insulation layer being formed with a plurality of communication holes and a plurality of through holes, wherein each of the communication holes is adapted for communicating two exposure holes with each other, with the two exposure holes exposing two electrodes that have opposite polarity and reside in neighboring light-emitting diode dies, and wherein each of the through holes is registered with an exposure hole for exposing an electrode that need not be electrically connected to any electrode located in neighboring light-emitting diode dies;</claim-text>
<claim-text>conductors formed within the exposure holes, the communication holes and the through holes, so that the light-emitting diode dies are electrically connected in series;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover layer disposed on the second insulation layer and formed with a plurality of open holes, each being registered with a through hole; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of electrically conductive linkers formed within the open holes and adapted for electrically connecting the conductors located within the through holes to an external circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The light-emitting diode die package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a surface of the sapphire layer opposite to the surface on which the first doped layer is disposed is formed with a plurality of generally inverted-pyramidal-shaped recesses, and wherein the light-emitting diode die package further comprises a phosphor powder layer disposed on the surface of the sapphire layer formed with the recesses.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The light-emitting diode die package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the phosphor layer is selected from the group consisting of a yellow phosphor layer, a combined phosphor layer of a red phosphor layer with a green phosphor layer, and a combined phosphor layer of a red phosphor layer, a green phosphor layer with a blue phosphor layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The light-emitting diode die package according to claim <b>1</b>, which further comprises:
<claim-text>a thermal conductive film layer disposed on portions of the electrode-mounting surfaces that are exposed by the exposure holes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a high thermal conductive metal layer disposed on the thermal conductive film layer and composed of a metal material selected from the group consisting of a nickel layer combined with a gold layer, and an aluminum layer combined with a copper layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a protective layer disposed on the insulation layer, wherein the protective layer is patterned, so that only a portion of the protective layer located between the electrode of the first doped layer and the electrode of the first doped layer remains, and wherein the electrically conductive linkers are disposed on the high thermal conductive metal layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The light-emitting diode die package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the electrically conductive linkers is fabricated by laminating <b>1</b> to <b>6</b> metal layers together using a vapor depositing process and/or an electro-plating process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The light-emitting diode die package according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the electrically conductive linkers are composed of a silver layer, a diamond film layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer; or a silver layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer; or a chromium layer, a diamond film layer, a silver layer, a copper layer, a nickel layer and a gold layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
