<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627457-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627457</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10608137</doc-number>
<date>20030630</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>10</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>3260</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>726 22</main-classification>
<further-classification>726 23</further-classification>
<further-classification>726 24</further-classification>
<further-classification>726 25</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Integrated security system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6519703</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Joyce</name>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>726 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6785732</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bates et al.</name>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709232</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6941467</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Judge et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>726 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0087882</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schneier et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0145228</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Suuronen et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713201</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20040268147</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20041230</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wiederin</last-name>
<first-name>Shawn E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cedar Rapids</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hoefelmeyer</last-name>
<first-name>Ralph S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Colorado Springs</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Phillips</last-name>
<first-name>Theresa E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairfax</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wiederin</last-name>
<first-name>Shawn E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cedar Rapids</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hoefelmeyer</last-name>
<first-name>Ralph S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Colorado Springs</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Phillips</last-name>
<first-name>Theresa E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fairfax</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Verizon Business Global LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Basking Ridge</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lanier</last-name>
<first-name>Benjamin</first-name>
<department>2432</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A network device used to provide network security includes an interface configured to receive data transmitted over a network. The network device also includes a firewall, intrusion detection logic and forwarding logic. The firewall, intrusion detection logic and forwarding logic process the received data to determine whether the data contains malicious content. When the data contains malicious content, the data may be dropped before it reaches a user device to which the received data was sent. Optionally, the network device may interact with an external device in order to make the forwarding decision. In addition, the network device may subscribe to services offered by the external device to receive updated security information.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="158.58mm" wi="226.14mm" file="US08627457-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.13mm" wi="157.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627457-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.66mm" wi="159.60mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627457-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="217.34mm" wi="164.68mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08627457-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="251.21mm" wi="178.31mm" file="US08627457-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="196.77mm" wi="160.02mm" file="US08627457-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to security systems and, more particularly, to providing an integrated security system for users receiving and transmitting information via a network.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The number of user communicating over public networks, such as the Internet, has increased significantly over the last several years. As a result, companies are providing more products and services over the Internet. Customers may access these products/services using a personal computer (PC). The customer's PC may include anti-virus software that protects the PC from malicious viruses.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">One problem with using conventional commercial off the shelf anti-virus software is that such software is often unable to detect sophisticated attacks and/or prevent unauthorized users from accessing personal data stored on the customer's PC. In addition, the use of non-PC based devices, such as network appliances, televisions, etc., to access products/services via the Internet has become increasingly common. Typically, these non-PC based devices include no security mechanisms to combat viruses or other malicious attacks. Therefore, the customer is often left unprotected when accessing products/services over the Internet.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">There exists a need for systems and methods that provide security for users accessing a public network.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">These and other needs are met by the present invention where an integrated security device may be connected to an Internet access device to provide security features. The security device may be modular and may perform a number of security functions to provide/enhance security.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to one aspect of the invention, a device including at least one interface, a firewall, intrusion detection logic and forwarding logic is provided. The interface is configured to receive data transmitted via a network and the firewall is configured to receive data from the interface. The firewall is also configured to determine whether the data potentially contains malicious content and identify first data in the received data that potentially contains malicious content. The intrusion detection logic is configured to receive the first data and generate report information based on the first data. The forwarding logic is configured to receive the report information and determine whether to forward the first data for processing by a user application based on the report information.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Another aspect of the present invention provides a computer-readable medium having stored instructions which when executed by a processor, cause the processor to receive data transmitted via a network and receive at least one set of rules from an external device, where the at least one set of rules is associated with processing the received data. The instructions also cause the processor to determine whether the data may contain malicious content using a first set of rules and identify first data that may contain malicious content based on the determining. The instructions further cause the processor to determine whether to forward the first data to a user device based on a second set of rules.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A further aspect of the present invention provides a method for providing security information to a number of user devices. The method includes storing, by a security provider, rules-based security information. The method also includes providing, by the security provider, a number of subscription levels, where each subscription level is associated with a different security level and has a different set of rules-based security information. The method further includes, downloading, by the security provider, a first set of rules-based security information to a first one of the user devices. The downloading is performed in response to at least one of a request from the first user device and a subscription associated with the first user device.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become readily apparent to those skilled in this art from the following detailed description. The embodiments shown and described provide illustration of the best mode contemplated for carrying out the invention. The invention is capable of modifications in various obvious respects, all without departing from the invention. Accordingly, the drawings are to be regarded as illustrative in nature, and not as restrictive.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Reference is made to the attached drawings, wherein elements having the same reference number designation may represent like elements throughout.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of an exemplary system in which methods and systems consistent with the present invention may be implemented.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary configuration of an interface device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an implementation consistent with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary configuration of a user device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an implementation consistent with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating exemplary processing by an interface device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an implementation consistent with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating exemplary processing performed by an interface device and central management system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an alternative implementation consistent with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The following detailed description of implementations consistent with the present invention refers to the accompanying drawings. The same reference numbers in different drawings may identify the same or similar elements. Also, the following detailed description does not limit the invention. Instead, the scope of the invention is defined by the appended claims and equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Systems and methods consistent with the present invention provide a network security device that integrates a number of security functions in a modular unit. The security services/processing performed by the network security device may include, for example, firewall services, intrusion detection services, data forwarding services and virtual private network (VPN) related processing.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">Exemplary System</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an exemplary system <b>100</b> in which methods and systems consistent with the present invention may be implemented. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, system <b>100</b> includes a network <b>110</b> that interconnects a group of user devices <b>130</b>, a central management system (CMS) <b>140</b> and a server <b>150</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each user device <b>130</b> is coupled to network <b>110</b> via an interface device <b>120</b>. Each interface device <b>120</b> may provide security-related processing for its respective user device <b>130</b>, as described in more detail below. While interface device <b>120</b> is illustrated as being connected to a single user device <b>130</b>, it will be appreciated that interface device <b>120</b> may connect to and provide security-related processing for more than one user device <b>130</b>. The number of devices illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is provided for simplicity. It will be appreciated that a typical system may include more or fewer devices than illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Moreover, system <b>100</b> may include additional devices (not shown) that aid in the transfer, processing, and/or reception of data.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Network <b>110</b> may include, for example, the Internet, an intranet, a local area network (LAN), a metropolitan area network (MAN), a wide area network (WAN), a public switched telephone network (PSTN), and/or some other similar type of network that is capable of transmitting data, such as voice and data communications. In fact, network <b>110</b> may include any type of network or combination of networks that permits routing of information from a particular source to a particular destination.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Interface device <b>120</b> may be a modular device that provides security-related processing for user device <b>130</b>. Interface device <b>120</b>, consistent with the present invention, may provide firewall processing, intrusion detection processing, data forwarding processing, VPN-related processing, etc., as described in more detail below. Interface device <b>120</b> may connect to network <b>110</b> via any conventional technique, such as wired, wireless, or optical connections.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary configuration of interface device <b>120</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an implementation consistent with the present invention. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, interface device <b>120</b> includes a processor <b>210</b>, a storage device <b>220</b>, a communication interface <b>230</b>, a firewall <b>240</b>, a virtual private network (VPN) gateway <b>250</b>, intrusion detection logic <b>260</b>, forwarding logic <b>270</b>, an input/output device <b>280</b> and a bus <b>290</b>. Bus <b>290</b> may include one or more conventional buses that permit communication among the components of interface device <b>120</b>. It will be appreciated that the interface device <b>120</b> may include other components (not shown) that aid in receiving, processing, and/or transmitting data.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Processor <b>210</b> may include any type of conventional processor or microprocessor that interprets and executes instructions. Storage device <b>220</b> may include a random access memory (RAM) or another type of dynamic storage device that stores information and instructions for execution by processor <b>210</b>. Storage device <b>220</b> may also be used to store temporary variables or other intermediate information during execution of instructions by processor <b>210</b>. Storage device <b>220</b> may also include a read only memory (ROM) device and/or another type of static storage device that stores static information and instructions for processor <b>210</b>. Storage device <b>220</b> may further include a magnetic disk or optical disk and its corresponding drive and/or some other type of magnetic or optical recording medium and its corresponding drive for storing information and/or instructions. In an exemplary implementation consistent with the present invention, processor <b>210</b> may execute operating system software stored in storage device <b>220</b>. The operating system may provide the platform for integrating the various components/modules of interface device <b>120</b> and enable interface device <b>120</b> to manage, configure and provision services in real-time or near real-time.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Communication interface <b>230</b> may include any transceiver-like mechanism that enables interface device <b>120</b> to communicate with other devices and/or systems, such as user device <b>130</b> and network <b>110</b>. For example, communication interface <b>230</b> may include a modem or an Ethernet interface to a network. Communication interface <b>230</b> may also include an application programming interface (API) that provides an interface between interface device <b>120</b> (e.g., the operating system being executed by processor <b>210</b>) and an application program being executed by user device <b>130</b>. Any conventional API may be used based on the particular system's requirements and/or the particular application program being executed by user device <b>130</b>. Communication interface <b>230</b> may present a received data stream to user device <b>130</b> via the API. Alternatively, communication interface <b>230</b> may include other mechanisms for communicating via a data network.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Firewall <b>240</b> provides packet filtering capabilities for interface device <b>120</b>. In one implementation, this filtering may be based on a set of rules that causes firewall <b>240</b> to perform an action on incoming traffic based on, for example, the Internet Protocol (IP) source address, IP destination address, and/or other fields/information included in the data stream. For example, firewall <b>240</b> may permit the received traffic to be forwarded to user device <b>130</b> or may drop or block the traffic from reaching user device <b>130</b> when the incoming traffic fails to satisfy the set of rules stored by firewall <b>240</b>. Firewall <b>240</b> may also include an anti-virus module that scans the incoming data streams for viruses. The anti-virus module may use signature-based rules or heuristic-based techniques to detect a virus. Firewall <b>240</b> may also detect other forms of malicious content or unwanted data. The term &#x201c;malicious content&#x201d; may encompass, for example, unsolicited messages or e-mails, also referred to as &#x201c;spam,&#x201d; and other types of malicious data, such as viruses. Firewall <b>240</b> may use conventional techniques to detect spam or similar information received by interface device <b>120</b> and may also discard this type of unwanted data.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Firewall <b>240</b>, consistent with the present invention, may also apply different sets of rules based on the particular type of data it receives (e.g., video data, music data, etc.), the particular type of application being executed by user device <b>130</b>, the provider of the received data (i.e., the source) or other factors. Firewall <b>240</b> may receive the rules from an external device, such as CMS <b>140</b>. CMS <b>140</b>, consistent with the present invention, may provide the particular rules to interface device <b>120</b> on a subscription basis. That is, a user associated with user device <b>130</b> and interface device <b>120</b> may subscribe to security services with CMS <b>140</b>, as described in more detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">VPN gateway <b>250</b> may include logic for setting up secure tunnels to other devices in system <b>100</b> over network <b>110</b>, such as CMS <b>140</b>. VPN gateway <b>250</b> may encrypt data for transmission over the secure tunnel. VPN gateway <b>250</b> may also decrypt encrypted payloads and assemble the decrypted payloads for use by other devices in interface device <b>120</b>, such as firewall <b>240</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may receive information from other devices in interface device <b>120</b> indicating the detection of anomalous events. For example, intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may receive data packets from firewall <b>240</b> which match a particular viral signature. Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may correlate the data packets to the particular viral signatures and provide a normalized, filtered report for use by other devices/systems. For example, intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may provide a report that indicates the number of packets, number of bytes, source address, destination address, etc., associated with the anomalous packets that match the viral signature. Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may also take the incoming data streams and correlate events associated with the data streams into a normalized or standardized form. For example, all events associated with the data streams may be stored in a database utilizing uniform records and fields. Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may then filter the events by combining a number of similar events into a single event, thereby reducing the overall data set size.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Forwarding logic <b>270</b> may receive information from other devices, such as intrusion detection logic <b>260</b>. Forwarding logic <b>270</b> may determine whether to pass received information to other devices, such as user device <b>130</b>. Forwarding logic <b>270</b> may make the determination on whether to pass a data stream to user device <b>130</b> based on a set of stored rules. Based on the stored rules, forwarding logic <b>270</b> may pass the data stream or defer the decision on whether to forward the data stream to the application (i.e., user device <b>130</b>) to CMS <b>140</b>. For example, forwarding logic <b>270</b> may include a set of IF-THEN-ELSE statements, such as a set a computer aided software engineering (CASE) statements in C, where all decision trees may lead to passing the data stream to user device <b>130</b> or deferring the decision to CMS <b>140</b>. In some implementations, forwarding logic <b>270</b> may perform an error recovery procedure on the received data stream by removing the malicious content.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Input/output device <b>280</b> may include any conventional mechanism that permits an operator to input information to interface device <b>120</b>, such as a keyboard, a mouse, a microphone, a pen, a biometric input device, such as voice recognition device, etc. Input/output device <b>280</b> may also include any conventional mechanism that outputs information to the operator, including a display, a printer, a speaker, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each user device <b>130</b> may include any type of computer system, such as a personal computer (PC), laptop, etc., that is capable of transmitting and receiving voice and/or data communications via network <b>110</b>. User devices <b>130</b> may also include non-computer or non-PC based devices, such as a network appliance, a set top box for interfacing between a monitor (e.g., a television) and a network, a television-type Internet access device, or some other type of device that is capable of transmitting and receiving information to/from network <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an exemplary configuration of user device <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in an implementation consistent with the present invention. As illustrated, user device <b>130</b> includes a bus <b>310</b>, a processor <b>320</b>, a memory <b>330</b>, an input device <b>340</b>, an output device <b>350</b>, and a communication interface <b>360</b>. Bus <b>310</b> permits communication among the components of user device <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Processor <b>320</b> may include any type of conventional processor or microprocessor that interprets and executes instructions. Memory <b>330</b> may include a RAM or another type of dynamic storage device that stores information and instructions for execution by processor <b>320</b>; a ROM or another type of static storage device that stores static information and instructions for use by processor <b>320</b>; and/or some type of magnetic or optical recording medium and its corresponding drive.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Input device <b>340</b> may include any conventional mechanism that permits an operator to input information to user device <b>130</b>, such as a keyboard, a mouse, a pen, voice recognition and/or biometric mechanisms, and the like. Output device <b>350</b> may include any conventional mechanism that outputs information to the operator, including a display, a printer, a speaker, etc. Communication interface <b>360</b> may include any transceiver-like mechanism that enables user device <b>130</b> to communicate with other devices and/or systems, such as interface device <b>120</b>, integrated applications, traditional telephony systems, etc., via wired, wireless, and/or optical connections.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In alternative implementations, user device <b>130</b> and interface device <b>120</b> may be integrated into a single device. For example, some or all of the functions performed by user device <b>130</b>, such as executing application programs associated with receiving and transmitting information via network <b>110</b>, may be performed by interface device <b>120</b> and vice versa. In other words, the security functions described above with respect to interface device <b>120</b> may be built into a user device <b>130</b>, such as a PC-based device, a network appliance, a set top box, a TV-type device, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, CMS <b>140</b> may provide security related information to users and their corresponding interface devices <b>120</b>. For example, CMS <b>140</b> may analyze patterns of attacks to create rules and signatures associated with attacks.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">CMS <b>140</b>, consistent with the present invention, may provide the particular rules to interface devices <b>120</b> on a subscription basis. That is, a user associated with user device <b>130</b> and interface device <b>120</b> may subscribe to security services with CMS <b>140</b>. The security services provided by CMS <b>140</b> may include multiple service levels. The user may select the particular service level based on the particular user's requirements. In this manner, a user may determine the desired level of security he/she wishes to obtain and may subscribe to the corresponding service level with CMS <b>140</b>. In addition, CMS <b>140</b> may adjust/modify the rules applied by firewall <b>240</b> in a real-time or near real-time manner, as described in more detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Users may also request security information/services from CMS <b>140</b> on an as-needed basis instead of subscribing for security services with CMS <b>140</b>. In this case, the user may pay for security-related services when requesting information from CMS <b>140</b>. In either case (i.e., subscription-based or request-based), CMS <b>140</b> may download the security related information for use by interface devices <b>120</b>. The security information may include rules that may be used by firewall <b>240</b>, intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> and forwarding logic <b>270</b> to perform the functions described above. CMS <b>140</b> may periodically update these rules. For example, when new viruses are detected, CMS <b>140</b> may modify or provide new rules to firewall <b>240</b> that may then be used to detect the new virus. CMS <b>140</b> may provide these updated rules at predetermined intervals or as needed.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">CMS <b>140</b>, as discussed above, may support a number of service levels. For example, a user may subscribe to any one of a number of security levels, e.g., up to four or more service levels, such as &#x201c;bronze,&#x201d; &#x201c;silver,&#x201d; &#x201c;gold&#x201d; and &#x201c;platinum.&#x201d; Each service level may have its own set of rules and CMS <b>140</b> may download the appropriate rules to interface devices <b>120</b> based on their respective subscription levels. For example, the platinum level may represent the highest security level and include the most stringent rules associated with allowing received data to be forwarded to user devices <b>130</b>. CMS <b>140</b> may provide these rules to interface devices <b>120</b> using VPN tunnels established with the respective interface devices <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">CMS <b>140</b> may also represent a service point of decision for making routing decisions on behalf of interface devices <b>120</b>. For example, CMS <b>140</b> may receive information from an interface device <b>120</b> and determine whether a particular data stream received by interface device <b>120</b> should be forwarded to a user application being executed by user device <b>130</b>. CMS <b>140</b> may be a provider-based point of decision associated with a particular service provider associated with routing data via network <b>110</b>. CMS <b>140</b> may also be associated with multiple service providers or may be associated with no particular service provider. In each case, CMS <b>140</b> may gather information and assess service wide patterns, such as attack patterns, using known correlation techniques. CMS <b>140</b> may include any combination of software/hardware based systems to assist the provider in gathering and assessing the information. A human operator of CMS <b>140</b> may also aid in determining the appropriate action, as described in more detail below. It should also be understood that CMS <b>140</b> may process data received from a number of interface devices <b>120</b> at the same time.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Server <b>150</b> may include any conventional server or computer-based system that provides information to user device <b>130</b> via its corresponding interface device <b>120</b>. Server <b>150</b> may, for example, represent a company providing products such as video-on-demand, video-based training, downloadable music files or games, on-line gaming, on-line shopping or any other service/product over network <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">As discussed previously, interface device <b>120</b> may perform a number of security-related functions associated with receiving data over network <b>110</b>. In implementations consistent with the present invention, the functions performed by the components/modules of interface device <b>120</b> may be performed by one or more processors executing sequences of instructions contained in a computer-readable medium, such as storage device <b>220</b>. In alternative embodiments, each of the modules/components may include hardwired circuitry and/or any combination of hardware, firmware and software. Thus, the present invention is not limited to any specific combination of hardware circuitry and software.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Exemplary Processing</heading>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow diagram, consistent with the present invention, illustrating exemplary processing associated with system <b>100</b>. Processing may begin with interface device <b>120</b> receiving data intended for user device <b>130</b> via communication interface <b>230</b> (act <b>410</b>). For example, the data may be received from an external device, such as server <b>150</b> or another user device <b>130</b>, via network <b>110</b>. The data may represent a response to a request for information made by user device <b>130</b> to server <b>150</b>. For example, server <b>150</b> may represent a provider offering a service or product, such as video-on-demand, music files, on-line games, interactive shopping, downloadable games, etc. In response to a request from user device <b>130</b>, server <b>150</b> may provide the requested information to interface device <b>120</b> via network <b>110</b>. Communication interface <b>230</b> may forward the data to firewall <b>240</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Firewall <b>240</b> may receive the data and apply a predetermined set of rules to determine whether the data contains anomalies or malicious content (act <b>420</b>). For example, as described previously, firewall <b>240</b> may include an anti-virus module. The anti-virus module may scan the incoming data to determine whether the received data includes a virus or other attack-related data. The anti-virus module may use signature-based techniques and/or heuristic techniques to detect viruses and/or other malicious content. For example, heuristic-based techniques may look for common text, transmission characteristics or content patterns that were previously shown to be related to a virus or malicious content.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The anti-virus module may also use &#x201c;rough set logic&#x201d; to detect viruses and/or other malicious content. As understood by those of ordinary skill in this art, rough set logic may look at every piece of content it receives to develop an artificial intelligence (AI) type engine to analyze data received at a later time. For example, the rough set logic may examine all the bytes of a received data stream and &#x201c;score&#x201d; the data stream to determine whether the data is appropriate for the user. As additional data streams are received, the rough set logic continues to refine its scoring process based on information gained from previous data streams. In this manner, the rough set logic continues to update and refine its processing to identify malicious content. In any of the above cases (i.e., using rules-based techniques, heuristic-based techniques, rough set logic or any combination of these or other techniques), if the anti-virus module does not detect anomalies or malicious content, firewall <b>240</b> forwards the data stream to user device <b>130</b> (act <b>430</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">However, if the anti-virus module detects anomalies or malicious content, firewall <b>240</b> may forward the data stream to intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> (act <b>440</b>). Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> receives the data stream from firewall <b>240</b> and may filter/normalize the received data (act <b>440</b>). For example, intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may count the number of packets, number of bytes, etc., of the received data stream that includes anomalies. Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may also provide the normalized data in a concise report format. Intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> may then forward the filtered/normalized report data to forwarding logic <b>270</b> (act <b>450</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Forwarding logic <b>270</b> receives the report data from intrusion detection logic <b>260</b> and determines if the data steam associated with the report data should be forwarded to its intended destination (e.g., user device <b>130</b>) (act <b>460</b>). Forwarding logic <b>270</b> may use a pre-stored set of rules to determine if the data should be passed to user device <b>130</b>. In the event that the data is to be forwarded to user device <b>130</b> (i.e., indicating that the anomalies are not related to malicious content), forwarding logic <b>270</b> forwards the data to user device <b>130</b> (act <b>470</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">If forwarding logic <b>270</b> determines that the data is not to be forwarded to user device <b>130</b> (i.e., indicating that the anomalies are related to malicious intent and are not for legitimate purposes), the data may be discarded (act <b>480</b>). That is, forwarding logic <b>270</b> may delete the received data stream. In implementations consistent with the present invention, the received data stream may be stored or buffered in a memory, such as storage device <b>220</b>, while the data stream is being examined for malicious content. In an exemplary implementation, the data stream may be &#x201c;quarantined&#x201d; in a memory while the data is being examined. That is, the data stream may be stored for a temporary period of time until the examination determines whether the data contains malicious content. While the data is quarantined, the data may be separated from other &#x201c;good&#x201d; data.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In an alternative implementation consistent with the present invention, forwarding logic <b>270</b> may defer the decision on whether to forward the data to user device <b>130</b> to an external entity, such as CMS <b>140</b>. In this case, forwarding logic <b>270</b> forwards the report information to CMS <b>140</b> (act <b>510</b>; <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). Interface device <b>120</b> may use a secure tunnel/connection established by VPN gateway <b>250</b> when communicating with CMS <b>140</b>. It should be understood that CMS <b>140</b> may not receive the actual data stream from interface device <b>120</b>, but may receive report information with pertinent data that may be used by CMS <b>140</b> to determine whether the data stream contains malicious content. The actual data stream may by stored on interface device <b>120</b>. In some implementations, however, the actual data stream may be forwarded to CMS <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">CMS <b>140</b> may then analyze the report data based on predetermined rules to determine whether the data should be forwarded to user device <b>130</b> (act <b>520</b>). CMS <b>140</b> may automatically make this determination based on predetermined rules stored in CMS <b>140</b>. A human operator of CMS <b>140</b> may also assist in determining whether the data should be forwarded to user device <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">If CMS <b>140</b> determines that the data should not be forwarded to user device <b>130</b>, CMS <b>140</b> signals interface device <b>120</b> to discard the data (act <b>530</b>). If CMS <b>140</b> determines that the data may be forwarded to user device <b>130</b>, CMS <b>140</b> signals interface device <b>120</b> to forward the data to user device <b>130</b> (act <b>540</b>). Interface device <b>120</b> receives the indication from CMS <b>140</b> and acts accordingly (act <b>550</b>). That is, interface device <b>120</b> either forwards the data to user device <b>130</b> or drops the data, based on the instructions from CMS <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In summary, interface device <b>120</b> provides a number of security functions in a single, modular device. The services provided may include firewall services, intrusion detection services, data forwarding services and VPN related services. In addition, interface device <b>120</b> operates in an efficient, seamless manner with respect to user device <b>120</b>. Therefore, the end user experiences no loss in satisfaction associated with receiving information via network <b>110</b> and executing applications.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Systems and methods consistent with the present invention provide a flexible system and method for providing increased network security. An advantage of the invention is that interface device <b>120</b> has the capability to identify and respond to widespread attack vectors across the Internet. In addition, the invention is scalable across a large number of customers (i.e., interface devices <b>120</b>). Further, multiple central management systems <b>140</b> may be distributed to provide load balancing for a large number of customers. The invention also provides a layered security defense for set top applications or programs that process data on a peer-to-peer basis, a distributed network, a grid-based network, a LAN, a wireless network, or any other similar network. Another advantage of the invention is that interface device <b>120</b> and CMS <b>140</b> provide for cost-effective mechanisms to update and maintain security for users as new security threats are identified.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In this disclosure, there is shown and described only the preferred embodiments of the invention, but, as aforementioned, it is to be understood that the invention is capable of use in various other combinations and environments and is capable of changes or modifications within the scope of the inventive concept as expressed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">For example, the present invention has been described mainly with respect to a separate interface device <b>120</b> being used to process data for a user device <b>130</b>. However, as discussed above, the functions of the interface device <b>120</b> and user device <b>130</b> may be combined in implementations consistent with the present invention. In addition, it should be understood that the present invention is not limited to any particular combination of hardware/software/firmware. Further, actions described as being performed by a particular device, module or logic in interface device <b>120</b> may alternatively be performed by another device/module/logic or may be performed by a single element. Lastly, aspects of the present invention have been described as series of acts in relation to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>. It should be understood that the order of these acts may vary in other implementations of the present invention. Moreover, non-dependent acts may be performed in parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">No element, act or instruction used in the description of the present application should be construed as critical or essential to the invention unless explicitly described as such. Also, as used herein, the article &#x201c;a&#x201d; is intended to include one or more items. Where only one item is intended, the term &#x201c;one&#x201d; or similar language is used.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The scope of the invention is defined by the claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device, comprising:
<claim-text>at least one interface configured to receive data transmitted via a network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a firewall configured to:
<claim-text>receive data from the at least one interface,</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine whether the data potentially contains malicious content, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identify first data in the received data that potentially contains malicious content;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>intrusion detection logic configured to:
<claim-text>receive the first data, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generate report information based on the first data; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forwarding logic configured to:
<claim-text>receive the report information,</claim-text>
<claim-text>forward the first data for processing by a user application when the report information indicates that the first data does not contain malicious content; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forward the report information to a remote central management system when the report information indicates that the first data potentially contains malicious content, the report information allowing the remote central management system to make a forwarding decision on behalf of the device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a virtual private network gateway configured to establish a secure connection with the remote central management system.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the firewall comprises anti-virus logic configured to examine a data stream for viral signatures using at least one of a signature-based technique, a heuristic technique or a rough set logic technique.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the anti-virus logic is further configured to identify unsolicited messages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a processing device executing the user application, the user application being associated with at least one of video-on-demand, video-based training, on-line gaming, on-line shopping, downloading music files or downloading games.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the firewall, the intrusion detection logic or the forwarding logic is configured to receive rule-based processing information from an external device via the network.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the firewall, intrusion detection logic or forward logic is further configured to receive updated rule-based processing information from the external device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. In a network device configured to receive data transmitted over a network, a method, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving data transmitted via the network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying first data that may contain malicious content;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating report information based on the first data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forwarding the report information to an external device when the report information indicates that the first data potentially contains malicious content, the report information allowing the external device to make a forwarding decision on behalf of the network device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forwarding the first data to the user device when it is determined that the first data does not contain malicious content.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>establishing a virtual private network connection to the external device, and wherein the forwarding the report information includes:
<claim-text>forwarding the report information over the virtual private network connection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, from the external device, information indicating whether the first data is to be forwarded to the user device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>dropping the first data when the information indicates that the first data is not to be forwarded.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the identifying comprises:
<claim-text>examining the received data for viruses using at least one of a signature-based technique, a heuristic technique or a rough set logic-based technique.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the identifying comprises:
<claim-text>identifying spam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A non-transitory computer-readable medium having stored thereon a plurality of sequences of instructions, said sequences of instructions including instructions which, when executed by a processor, cause the processor to:
<claim-text>receive data transmitted via a network;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive at least one set of rules from an external device, the at least one set of rules being associated with processing the received data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determine whether the data may contain malicious content using a first set of rules;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identify first data that may contain malicious content based on the determining;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generate report information based on the first data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forward the first data for processing by a user application when the report information indicates that the first data does not contain malicious content; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forward the report information to an external device when the report information indicates that the first data potentially contains malicious content, the report information allowing the external device to make a forwarding decision on behalf of the processor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The computer-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the instructions further cause the processor to:
<claim-text>establish a virtual private network tunnel with the external device and send the report information over the virtual private network tunnel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The computer-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein when identifying first data that may contain malicious content, the instructions cause the processor to identify a virus using at least one of a signature-based technique, a heuristic technique or a rough set logic-based technique.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The computer-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein when identifying first data that may contain malicious content, the instructions cause the processor to identify spam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The computer-readable medium of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the instructions further cause the processor to execute the received data, the data being associated with at least one of video-on-demand, video-based training, on-line gaming, on-line shopping, downloading music files or downloading games.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
