<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626298-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626298</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13893253</doc-number>
<date>20130513</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 42</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e51">Methods and apparatus for deep brain stimulation</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5505700</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Leone et al.</name>
<date>19960400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>60410103</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5634899</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Shapland et al.</name>
<date>19970600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>604507</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7081115</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Taimisto</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>606 41</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 45</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>600544</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>606 41</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>60410103</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>604507</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12507135</doc-number>
<date>20090722</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13893253</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12394972</doc-number>
<date>20090227</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8401650</doc-number>
<date>20130319</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12507135</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12338191</doc-number>
<date>20081218</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8209034</doc-number>
<date>20120626</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12394972</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61043805</doc-number>
<date>20080410</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>61043802</doc-number>
<date>20080410</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130253625</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130926</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>ElectroCore, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<city>Morris Plains</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Simon</last-name>
<first-name>Bruce J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mountain Lakes</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dentons US LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Electrocore, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Basking Ridge</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Wieland</last-name>
<first-name>Robert N</first-name>
<department>3762</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention provides systems, apparatus and methods for treating nerve disorders in the brain. An electrode is introduced into a patient's sinus cavity and an electrical impulse is applied to the electrode to modulate one or more target nerves in the brain to treat the disorder. In preferred embodiments, the electrode is positioned within a sinus cavity adjacent to or near the frontal cortex of the brain and the electrical signal is sufficient to modulate, stimulate and/or inhibit nerves within the frontal cortex. The electrode may be movable between a collapsed or compact configuration for introduction into the sinus cavity and an expanded configuration for contacting tissue within the sinus cavity to deliver the electrical impulse through the tissue to the target nerves in the brain.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="55.96mm" wi="258.06mm" file="US08626298-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="258.57mm" wi="180.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08626298-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="227.33mm" wi="137.33mm" file="US08626298-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="234.87mm" wi="178.56mm" file="US08626298-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="193.72mm" wi="194.65mm" file="US08626298-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application is a Continuation of U.S. Ser. No. 12/507,135 filed 22 Jul. 2009, which is a Continuation in Part of U.S. Ser. No. 12/394,972 filed 27 Feb. 2009, now U.S. Pat. No. 8,401,650 issued 19 Mar. 2013, which is a Continuation in Part of U.S. Ser. No. 12/338,191 filed 18 Dec. 2008, now U.S. Pat. No. 8,209,034 issued 26 Jun. 2012, which claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application Ser. No. 61/043,805 filed 10 Apr. 2008 and U.S. Provisional Application Ser. No. 61/043,802 filed 10 Apr. 2008; each of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to the delivery of electrical energy to bodily tissues for therapeutic purposes, and more specifically to devices and methods for treating various disorders resulting from nerve transmissions in the brain.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The use of electrical stimulation for treatment of medical conditions has been well known in the art for nearly two thousand years. Electrical stimulation of the brain and the peripheral nervous system and/or direct stimulation of malfunctioning tissue is generally a completely reversible and non-destructive treatment and holds significant promise for the treatment of many ailments.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Deep brain stimulation (DBS) is a surgical treatment involving the implantation of a medical device called a brain pacemaker, which sends electrical impulses to specific parts of the brain. DBS in select brain regions, such as the frontal cortex, has provided remarkable therapeutic benefits for otherwise treatment-resistant movement and affective disorders, such as chronic pain, Parkinson's disease, obsessive-compulsive disorder, major depression, essential tremor and dystonia. Although the exact principles and mechanisms of DBS are still not clear, DBS apparently changes brain activity directly in a controlled manner.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In addition to currently recognized neural circuits associated with behavioral disorders, there is an increasing awareness that abnormal neural activity in the brain may be associated with a variety of deleterious behavior patterns. For example, while obesity is not uniformly recognized as a class of psychiatric behavioral disorder, there is recent clinical evidence demonstrating that hyperphagia (excessive appetite and consumption of food) can be associated with excessive activity in certain neural circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Deep brain stimulation systems typically consist of three components, the implanted pulse generator (IPG), the lead and the extension. The IPG is a battery-powered neurostimulator encased in a titanium housing, which sends electrical pulses to the brain to interfere with neural activity at the target site. The lead is a coiled wire insulated in polyurethane with four platinum iridium electrodes connected to the IPG by the extension, an insulated wire that runs from the head, down the side of the neck and behind the ear to the IPG. The IPG is typically placed subcutaneously below the clavicle, or in some cases, the abdomen.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">DBS leads are placed in the brain according to the type of symptoms to be addressed. For non-Parkinsonian essential tremor, the lead is typically placed in the ventrointermedial nucleus (VIM) of the thalamus. For dystonia and symptoms associated with Parkinson's disease (rigidity, bradykinesia/akinesia and tremor), the lead is typically placed in either the globus pallidus or subthalamic nucleus.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Unfortunately, deep brain stimulation generally involves the invasive placement of electrodes into deep brain structures, along with the subcutaneous implantation of the electrical generator with batteries. Such approaches are expensive and generally accompanied by risks associated with surgery. In particular, implantation of the electrodes have risks associated with surgically accessing tissues of the brain, such as bleeding and infection. In addition, these approaches suffer from device-related risks, including device failure, battery-life limits and the like</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Deeper areas of the brain are difficult to reach with current DBS techniques without damaging otherwise healthy areas of the brain. A recent improvement over DBS is to stimulate the brain noninvasively. Newer techniques like transcranial magnetic stimulation have attempted to accomplish this and have shown efficacy in treating depression. However, they have not been able to target small regions of the brain and require large, expensive devices to deliver currents sufficient to induce electric fields in the brain capable of depolarizing nerve membranes.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In light of the above, improved systems, devices and methods for the treatment of disorders associated with nerve transmissions in the brain are desired. In particular, it would be desirable if these systems and methods could help mitigate the debilitating effects of behavioral and other disorders without imposing excessive surgical trauma on the patient, and without having to damage or kill healthy neural tissues.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention provides systems, apparatus and methods for selectively applying electrical energy to body tissue. In one aspect of the invention, a method for treating nerve disorders in the brain includes introducing an electrode into a patient's sinus cavity and applying an electrical impulse to the electrode that is sufficient to modulate one or more target nerves in the brain to treat the disorder. In preferred embodiments, the electrode is positioned within a sinus cavity adjacent to or near the frontal cortex of the brain and the electrical signal is sufficient to modulate, stimulate and/or inhibit nerves within the frontal cortex. The electrode is preferably movable between a collapsed or compact configuration for advancement into the sinus cavity and an expanded configuration for contacting tissue within the sinus cavity to deliver the electrical impulse through said tissue to the target nerves in the brain.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A key advantage of the invention is that deep brain stimulation (DBS) to treat certain nerve disorders can be accomplished minimally invasively, i.e., without requiring direct access to the brain through the patient's skull. In addition, the proximity of the sinus cavities to the frontal cortex allows precise positioning of the electric field to stimulate the appropriate nerve tissue. Thus, deeper areas of the brain can be directly stimulated without damaging otherwise healthy areas of the brain. Nerve disorders that can be treated according to the present invention include epilepsy, Parkinson's disease, depression, eating disorders, Tourette syndrome, obesity, mood disorders, obsessive-compulsive disorders, hyperphagia, addiction, dystonia, essential tremor, chronic pain or any other disorder associated with nerve transmissions in the frontal cortex.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In a preferred method according to the present invention, an expanded enclosure, such as a balloon, is introduced into a sinus cavity and conductive fluid is delivered within the interior of the balloon. Electrical energy is applied to the conductive fluid such that the electrical energy passes through an ion-permeable section of the outer wall of the balloon to the target tissue. In one embodiment, the electrical energy is applied to an electrode positioned within the balloon and surrounded by the conductive fluid. The conductive fluid allows for the passage of electrical energy from the electrode through the fluid and the outer wall of the enclosure for treatment of tissue on or in a patient. In an alternative embodiment, the electrode comprises part or all of the balloon's outer wall and the electrical energy is applied directly to the conductive fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In the preferred embodiment, the electrode does not directly contact the tissue of the sinus cavity, which reduces the potential for collateral tissue damage or necrosis and/or excessive electric fields in the tissue. In addition, the enclosure physically shields the electrode from the patient's tissue which substantially inhibits Faradic products (e.g., OH<sup>&#x2212;</sup>, H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) of the electrode from reaching the target site. In this manner, a direct or low frequency current can be applied to the electrode(s) without the danger of such Faradic products reaching excessively high concentrations at the tissue site. In addition, direct or low frequency current can be delivered for a longer period of time and/or at higher power levels than is conventionally considered safe. Faradic products may be minimized in the present invention either by spacing the electrode from the outer wall of the balloon (so that diffusion is the rate limiting step) or by using a buffered conductive solution as the fluid that expands the balloon.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In an alternative embodiment, a method for diagnosing a patient's hearing deficiency is also disclosed. In this method, an electrode is introduced into the sinus cavity of the patient near or adjacent the cochlea, preferably adjacent the voice canal in the nasal cavity. An electrical impulse is then applied to the electrode that is sufficient to replicate electrical signals that would naturally be generated by one or more nerves of a healthy cochlea. The patient is then monitored to determine if he/she is able to process these electrical signals in the brain and &#x201c;hear&#x201d; them. This enables the physician to determine if the patient's hearing deficiency originates in the cochlea and consequently whether a cochlear implant would improve the patient's hearing deficit.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Systems according to the present invention include an enclosure, such as a balloon, that is movable from a deflated position for introduction through one of the patient's nostrils into a sinus cavity to an inflated position wherein at least a portion of the outer wall of the balloon contacts target tissue within sinus. The balloon is preferably inflated by introducing an electrically conductive fluid into the balloon. The conductive fluid serves to inflate the balloon to allow the balloon to contact target tissue, and to electrically couple the electrode to the outer wall of the balloon. The material of the balloon is preferably very soft and flexible, e.g., elastic, such that it gently conforms to the surrounding tissue, which allows the electrically energy to be applied uniformly to the target tissue. In addition, one skilled in the art will recognize that this configuration allows the balloon to conform to tissue within the sinus cavity. Another advantage of the invention is that the balloon, in the inflated position, has a larger tissue contact area than the electrode, which allows the device to be applied to a larger tissue treatment area.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In another aspect of the invention, the device includes an introducer for introducing the device to a target location within the patient's nose. The electrode and the balloon are coupled to a distal portion of the introducer. In a preferred embodiment, the electrode is coupled to the introducer such that, when the balloon is inflated, the electrode is substantially centrally located within the interior of the balloon. This configuration ensures that the electrode is spaced sufficiently from the patient's tissue to minimize tissue necrosis and collateral tissue damage. In certain embodiments, the introducer is a tube designed for passage through the patient's nostril to a target location within the sinus cavities, such as the ethmoid, sphenoid or frontal sinus.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In a particularly preferred embodiment, the balloon is formed substantially from an ion-permeable and/or hydrophilic material. As the balloon is filled with a conductive fluid, such as saline, the outer surface of the balloon wets and permits good contact with the surrounding tissue of the patient, which may otherwise be dry. In certain embodiments, the balloon may include one or more sections formed from an ion-permeable material with other sections formed from an electrically insulating material, or the entire wall of the balloon may be formed from such a material. In the former embodiment, the balloon may be constructed to selectively apply electrical energy through certain sections of its outer wall to selectively apply such energy to specific tissue locations on the body. For example, the balloon may be constructed such that the electrical energy is directly focused from the sinus cavity to the target nerve in the brain, thereby avoiding unwanted stimulation of non-target nerves in the nasal cavity and/or brain.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Preferably, electrical properties of the electrode, the fluid, and the material of the balloon are such that a resistance through the electrode, the fluid, and the balloon outer wall is less than about 1,000 Ohms, more preferably less than about 400 Ohms, and preferably less than 200 Ohms. In one embodiment, the return electrode is a return pad located on a surface of the patient's skin, such as the back or hip, and the electrode within the balloon acts as the tissue treatment or active electrode. In this embodiment, an electro-magnetic field emanates from the active electrode through the tissue in a substantially radial pattern. In alternative embodiments, the return electrode may be located closer to the active electrode, e.g., within the balloon, coupled to the introducer outside of the balloon or within a second balloon. In these embodiments, the electrical energy will not flow completely through the patient's body, i.e., the current will generally flow from the active electrode through the conductive fluid and the outer wall of the balloon, through the patient's tissue at the target site and to the return electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one embodiment, the device further includes a vacuum source for aspirating the electrically conductive fluid from the interior of the balloon. The vacuum source may be a positive source of aspiration with an aspiration passage coupled to the interior of the balloon or the device may be designed to simply allow the fluid to evacuate the balloon through the same fluid passage it entered through pressure differential, gravity, or the like. Evacuating the conductive fluid deflates the balloon and allows any excess Faradic products and/or heat to be evacuated from the device. In this manner, the balloon may be periodically evacuated to allow for periodic evacuation of excess Faradic products and heat, which allows for higher power levels and/or longer continuous use of the device in the patient. In some embodiments, the device may be adapted for continuous circulation of the electrically conductive fluid to reduce any build-up of heat or Faradic products and ensure uniform temperatures at the outer surface of the balloon. These embodiments will allow the device to use much higher power levels as the heat generated around the electrode and within the conductive fluid from the higher power levels will be continuously evacuated from the interior of the balloon.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The source of electrical energy is an electrical signal generator that preferably operates to generate an electrical signal having a frequency between about 1 Hz to 10,000 Hz, a pulse duration of between about 10-1000 us, and an amplitude of between about 1-20 volts. The electrical signal may be one or more of: a full or partial sinusoid, a square wave, a rectangular wave, and triangle wave. By way of example, the at least one electrical signal may be of a frequency between about 15 Hz to 35 Hz. Alternatively, the at least one electrical signal may be of a frequency of about 25 Hz. By way of example, the at least one electrical signal may have a pulsed on-time of between about 50 to 1000 microseconds, such as between about 100 to 300 microseconds, or about 200 microseconds. By way of example, the at least one electrical signal may have an amplitude of about 5-15 volts, such as about 12 volts.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Other aspects, features, advantages, etc. will become apparent to one skilled in the art when the description of the invention herein is taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">For the purposes of illustrating the various aspects of the invention, there are shown in the drawings forms that are presently preferred, it being understood, however, that the invention is not limited by or to the precise arrangements and instrumentalities shown.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a schematic view of an esophageal electrode device in accordance with one or more aspects of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken through the balloon of the esophageal electrode device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is an illustration of a deflated balloon of the esophageal electrode device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is an illustration of an inflated balloon of the esophageal electrode device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of an electrical signal generating system for use with the esophageal electrode device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary electrical voltage-current profile for a blocking and/or modulating impulse in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a method of treating nerve disorders in the brain according to the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the present invention, electrical energy is applied to one or more electrodes in the presence of an electrically conductive fluid to deliver an electromagnetic field to a patient. For convenience, the remaining disclosure will be directed specifically to stimulation of the nerves within the frontal cortex and/or the cochlea with a device introduced into one of the sinus cavities of a patient, but it will be appreciated that the systems and methods of the present invention can be applied equally well to other tissues and nerves of the body, including but not limited to parasympathetic nerves, such as the vagus nerve, sympathetic nerves, spinal or cranial nerves, e.g., optic nerve, facial nerves, vestibulocochlear nerves and the like. In addition, the present invention can be applied to treat other ailments, such as asthma, COPD, sepsis, dialytic hypotension, epilepsy, depression or obesity and other procedures including open procedures, intravascular procedures, interventional cardiology procedures, urology, laparoscopy, general surgery, arthroscopy, thoracoscopy or other cardiac procedures, cosmetic surgery, orthopedics, gynecology, otorhinolaryngology, spinal and neurologic procedures, oncology procedures and the like. In particular, the present invention can be used to practice the treatments described in the following commonly assigned patent applications: US Patent Publication Numbers: 2009/0183237, 2008/0009913, 2007/0191902, 2007/0191905, 2007/0106339, 2007/0106338 and 2007/0106337, the full disclosures of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</figref>, <b>1</b>B, an exemplary device <b>100</b> for delivering an electromagnetic field to a patient will now be described. Device <b>100</b> is designed to be introduced into the esophagus and/or the sinus cavity of the patient and located therein at a position that (when activated) achieves a therapeutic result. The device <b>100</b> includes an inflatable balloon <b>102</b> and a catheter, or an introducer tube <b>104</b>, sized and shaped (when the balloon <b>102</b> is deflated) to slide into the patient's esophagus and/or one of the sinus cavities.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The balloon <b>102</b> has at least one section formed from an electrically-permeable material, preferably a hydrophilic or ion-permeable material. By way of example, balloon <b>102</b> may be substantially formed from an ion-permeable, soft, flexible, and/or distensible material with a thickness of about 0.001 inches. Suitable balloon materials for use in the present invention include Pebax&#xae;, aromatic polyether polyurethane grades, such as Dureflex&#xae; from, for example, Deerfield Urethane in Whately, Mass., thermally conductive polymers or thermoplastic elastomers (TPE) such as those found at Cool Polymers, Inc. in Warwick, R.I. and the like. However, it will be recognized by those skilled in the art that a variety of commercially available balloon materials may be used to carry out the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The balloon preferably has a length of between about 1-3 cm (such as 2 cm), a diameter of between about 1.5-4.0 cm (such as 2-3 cm), and a fluid pressure therein of between about 1-10 pounds per square inch (such as 2 psi) when inflated. Obviously, under the stresses experienced during insertion, extraction and inflation, the balloon <b>102</b> should not separate from tube <b>104</b>, tear or leak. The tube <b>104</b> may be of a standard type formed out of polyurethane, measuring about 36 cm long, and having inside and outside diameters of 1.6 mm and 2.5 mm, respectively (although other lengths, diameters, and materials may be employed). In order to assist in the placement of the balloon <b>102</b> at a desired location, the tube <b>104</b> may include markers along its length, such as one marker about every 1 cm.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>, tube <b>104</b> includes an internal passageway <b>106</b> and an external surface <b>108</b>. At least one electrode <b>110</b> is coupled to the external surface <b>108</b> of the tube <b>104</b> (such as by a UV curable adhesive, such as Dymax 204-CTH). By way of example, the at least one electrode <b>110</b> may be of a general cylindrical shape and may extend around the external surface <b>108</b> of tube <b>104</b>. Although there are a number of sizes and shapes that would suffice to implement the electrode <b>110</b>, by way of example, the at least one electrode <b>110</b> may be between about 1.0-1.5 mm long (such as 1.27 mm), may have an outside diameter of between about 2.6-2.85 mm (such as 2.77 mm), and may have an inside diameter of between about 2.5-2.75 mm (such as 2.67 mm). A suitable electrode <b>110</b> may be formed from Pt-IR (90%/10%), although other materials or combinations or materials may be used, such as platinum, tungsten, gold, copper, palladium, silver or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Those skilled in the art will also recognize that a variety of different shapes and sizes of electrodes may be used. By way of example only, electrode shapes according to the present invention can include ball shapes, twizzle shapes, spring shapes, twisted metal shapes, annular, solid tube shapes or the like. Alternatively, the electrode(s) may comprise a plurality of filaments, rigid or flexible brush electrode(s), coiled electrode(s) or the like. Alternatively, the electrode may be formed by the use of formed wire (e.g., by drawing round wire through a shaping die) to form electrodes with a variety of cross-sectional shapes, such as square, rectangular, L or V shaped, or the like. Alternatively, the electrode may comprise a breakaway electrode on the end of a small gauge needle (e.g., 22 GA). In this embodiment, the electrode is hollow to allow for aspiration through the needle while being inserted ensuring that no blood vessels are compromised. Once in place, the needle is withdrawn over a fine conducting wire which is attached to the electrode, leaving just the electrode near the vagus nerve. The wire is then connected to the negative terminal of source of electrical energy. In yet another embodiment, the syringe itself is the electrode. The needle is coated with a thin insulating material leaving only 1-2 mm of the distal end of the needle bare, which acts as the electrode.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A conductor <b>112</b> extends through the internal passageway <b>106</b> of tube <b>104</b> and electrically connects to the electrode <b>110</b>. By way of example, the conductor <b>112</b> may be a solid silver wire of about 0.25 mm diameter insulated with a PTFE material of about 0.33 mm diameter. The diameter of the insulating material of the conductor <b>112</b> should be less than the internal diameter of tube <b>104</b> such that fluid may freely flow therein despite the presence of the conductor <b>112</b>. The conductor <b>112</b> may be laser welded to the electrode <b>110</b> using known procedures.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a schematic illustration of the balloon <b>102</b> in an inflated state, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is a reproduction of a photograph illustrating a prototype of the device <b>100</b> with the balloon <b>102</b> inflated. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is a reproduction of a photograph illustrating the prototype of the device <b>100</b> with the balloon <b>102</b> deflated. A fluid, preferably a saline solution, passes into the balloon <b>102</b> through tube <b>104</b> to inflate same. In some embodiments, the fluid may be a buffered conductive solution that will further minimize Faradic products from the electrode contacting the patient's tissue (as discussed below). The balloon <b>102</b> is sized, shaped and located about the electrode <b>110</b> and a portion of tube <b>104</b> such that when the balloon is inflated with fluid, the electrode <b>110</b> is substantially centrally located within an interior volume of the balloon <b>102</b>. This configuration has several advantages over conventional electrode configurations, such as: (i) the metal of the electrode <b>110</b> is not too close to, and never comes in contact with, the patient's tissue, which means that there is no concern about tissue necrosis or excessive electric fields in the tissue; (ii) the electrode <b>110</b> may be used with direct current signal sources since any Faradic Products (e.g. OH<sup>&#x2212;</sup>, H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) would not reach excessively high concentrations at the tissue site; (iii) as the balloon <b>102</b> is filled with saline, the surface of the balloon <b>102</b> wets and permits good contact with the surrounding tissue of the patient, which may otherwise be dry; and (iv) the material of the balloon <b>102</b> is preferably very soft and flexible such that it gently conforms to the surrounding tissue.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To inflate the balloon <b>102</b>, a number of features are provided with the device <b>100</b>. A pilot balloon assembly <b>130</b>, which may be of a standard type, is located at a proximal end of the device <b>100</b>. The pilot balloon assembly <b>130</b> is in fluid communication with tube <b>104</b> via fluid tube <b>132</b>. The fluid tube <b>132</b> may enter tube <b>104</b> along with the conductor <b>112</b>, and the entry point may be sealed with an adhesive, such as Dymax 204-CTH UV curable adhesive. The pilot balloon assembly <b>130</b> includes a spring loaded valve that opens when introducing fluid into the pilot and the fluid tube <b>132</b>, and/or when removing fluid therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Tube <b>104</b> may include a first aperture <b>114</b> through which the conductor <b>112</b> passes from the internal passageway <b>106</b> to the at least one electrode <b>110</b>. The tube <b>104</b> may include second and third apertures <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> extending from the internal passageway <b>106</b> to the external surface <b>108</b>, and through which fluid may pass to inflate and deflate the balloon <b>102</b> (as will be discussed in more detail later herein). Preferably, the second and third apertures <b>116</b>, <b>118</b> are disposed at proximal and distal ends <b>120</b>, <b>122</b> of the balloon <b>102</b>, respectively, and the first aperture <b>114</b> is located between the second and third apertures <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The inflation process preferably includes a priming phase followed by an inflation phase. The priming phase preferably takes place prior to introducing the device <b>100</b> into the patient. In the priming phase, a source of fluid, such as saline, is coupled to the pilot balloon assembly <b>130</b>. The source of fluid may be a fluid filled syringe or the like. With the balloon <b>102</b> in a generally vertical orientation (with distal end <b>120</b> up), fluid is preferably introduced into the pilot, the fluid tube <b>132</b>, tube <b>104</b> and the balloon <b>102</b> via the syringe. The fluid will enter the balloon <b>102</b> mostly via the second and third apertures <b>116</b>, <b>118</b>. Air will tend to collect at the distal end <b>120</b> of the balloon <b>102</b> as the fluid enters the device and urges the air in that direction. Again, keeping the balloon upright, at least some of the fluid is drawn out of the balloon <b>102</b> by reversing the fluid flow at the pilot balloon assembly <b>130</b> and source of fluid. This reversal of fluid flow will create a vacuum and draw all the air out of the balloon <b>102</b> via the second aperture <b>116</b>. Of course, there may be other ways to prime the device <b>100</b>; however, the above approach is believed to be suitable.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">After the device <b>100</b> is inserted into the patient's esophagus and/or one of the sinus cavities (preferably through the nostril), the inflation phase begins. The inflation phase includes causing the fluid to flow into the device <b>100</b> from the source (e.g., the syringe) until a desired balloon size and/or pressure is reached, such as the aforementioned 1-3 cm length, 1.5-4.0 cm diameter, and/or 1-10 psi pressure.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The electrical properties of the electrode <b>110</b>, the fluid, and the material of the balloon <b>102</b> are preferably designed such that a resistance therethrough is no more than about 1000 Ohms, preferably no more than 500 Ohms and more preferably 200 Ohms or less. In an exemplary embodiment, the impedance through the electrode <b>110</b>, the fluid, and the material of the balloon <b>102</b> should be no more than about 200 Ohms at 1000 Hz. The electrical properties of the fluid may be as important as those of the electrode <b>110</b> in this regard. The electrically conducting fluid should have a threshold conductivity to provide a suitable conductive path between electrode <b>110</b> and the outer wall of the balloon <b>102</b>. The electrical conductivity of the fluid (in units of milliSiemans per centimeter or mS/cm) will typically be between about 1 mS/cm and 200 mS/cm and will usually be greater than 10 mS/cm, preferably will be greater than 20 mS/cm and more preferably greater than 50 mS/cm. In one embodiment, the electrically conductive fluid is isotonic saline, which has a conductivity of about 17 mS/cm. Applicant has found that a more conductive fluid, or one with a higher ionic concentration, will usually provide optimal results. For example, a saline solution with higher levels of sodium chloride than conventional saline (which is on the order of about 0.9% sodium chloride) e.g., on the order of greater than 1% or between about 3% and 20%, may be desirable. A fluid of about 5% saline (e.g., approximately 100 mS/cm) is believed to work well, although modifications to the concentration and the chemical make-up of the fluid may be determined through simple experimentation by skilled artisans.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As noted above, the material of the balloon <b>102</b> is preferably slightly water-permeable or hydrophilic so that when the balloon <b>102</b> is filled with saline, the surface of the balloon <b>102</b> wets. Preferably, when filled with 10 cc of saline, the flux of saline out of the balloon <b>102</b> (into a similar saline solution) should not exceed about 1 cc per hour. Lubrizol Tecophilic HP93A-100 is a material with these properties.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In an alternative embodiment, the electrode <b>110</b> may be implemented via the fluid itself within the balloon <b>102</b>. Although a 5% saline solution would have a relatively high resistance compared to a metal electrode <b>110</b> implementation, those skilled in the art would appreciate that higher conductivity fluid solutions may be employed for such purposes or a larger diameter and/or shorter tube may be utilized to increase the conductivity. Additionally or alternatively, the conductor <b>112</b> may be implemented using the conductive fluid used to fill the balloon <b>102</b>; indeed, such fluid is within the passage <b>106</b> anyway. Again, relatively high conductivity fluid would be desirable.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a complete system for using the device <b>100</b> includes an electrical signal generator (or source) <b>300</b>. Source <b>300</b> operates to apply at least one electrical signal to the conductor <b>112</b> (via lead <b>340</b>) such that, when the inflated balloon <b>102</b> (and electrode <b>110</b>) is positioned at the target region within a patient, an electro-magnetic field emanates from the electrode <b>110</b> to the anatomy of the patient in the vicinity of the target region to achieve a therapeutic result. Unlike some known techniques, which target a specific location of the patient's anatomy, such as a very specific location of a nerve, the return electrode <b>350</b> placement is preferably such that when applied to the patient, the electro-magnetic field emanating from the electrode <b>110</b> is a substantially radial pattern&#x2014;in other words, the pattern of the electro-magnetic field emanating from the electrode <b>110</b> is not focused on any particular point, or small, localized region of the patient's anatomy. This is preferably achieved by applying the return electrode <b>350</b> to an external portion of the patient, such as to at least one of the upper-back, the chest, and/or the stomach.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The source <b>300</b> may be tailored for the treatment of a particular ailment and may include an electrical impulse generator <b>310</b>, a power source <b>320</b> coupled to the electrical impulse generator <b>310</b>, and a control unit <b>330</b> in communication with the electrical impulse generator <b>310</b> and the power source <b>320</b>. Electrodes <b>340</b> provide source and return paths for the at least one electrical signal to/from the electrode <b>110</b> and return electrode <b>350</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The control unit <b>330</b> may control the electrical impulse generator <b>310</b> for generation of the signal suitable for amelioration of the ailment when the signal is applied via the electrodes <b>340</b> to the device <b>100</b>. It is noted that source <b>300</b> may be referred to by its function as a pulse generator.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary electrical voltage/current profile for a stimulating, blocking and/or modulating impulse applied to a portion or portions of the patient's anatomy, in accordance with one or more embodiments of the present invention. A suitable electrical voltage/current profile <b>400</b> for the stimulating, blocking and/or modulating impulse <b>410</b> to the portion or portions of one or more nerves and/or muscles may be achieved using the pulse generator <b>310</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the pulse generator <b>310</b> may be implemented using the power source <b>320</b> and control unit <b>330</b> having, for instance, a processor, a clock, a memory, etc., to produce a pulse train <b>420</b> to the electrode(s) <b>340</b> that deliver the blocking and/or modulating fields to the nerve resulting from impulses <b>410</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The parameters of the modulation signal <b>400</b> are preferably programmable, such as the frequency, amplitude, duty cycle, pulse width, pulse shape, etc. The blocking and/or modulating impulse signal <b>410</b> preferably has a frequency, an amplitude, a duty cycle, a pulse width, a pulse shape, etc. selected to influence the therapeutic result, such as stimulating, blocking and/or modulating some or all of one or more nerve transmissions.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">For example, assuming the aforementioned impedance characteristics of the device <b>100</b>, the at least one electrical signal may be of a frequency between about 1 Hz to 3000 Hz, a pulse duration of between about 10-1000 us, and an amplitude of between about 1-20 volts. For example, the at least one electrical signal may be of a frequency between about 15 Hz to 35 Hz, such as about 25 Hz. The at least one electrical signal may have a pulsed on-time of between about 50 to 1000 microseconds, such as between about 100 to 300 microseconds, such as about 200 microseconds. The at least one electrical signal may have an amplitude of about 5-15 volts, such as about 12 volts. The at least one electrical signal may include one or more of a full or partial sinusoid, a square wave, a rectangular wave, and triangle wave.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Although the specific implementation of the signal source <b>300</b> is not of criticality to the invention, by way of example, the source <b>300</b> may be purchased commercially, such as a Model 7432 available from Medtronic, Inc. Alternatively, U.S. Patent Application Publications 2005/0075701 and 2005/0075702, both to Shafer, both of which are incorporated herein by reference, contain descriptions of pulse generators that may be applicable for implementing the signal source <b>300</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">An alternative implementation for the signal source <b>300</b> of the present invention may be obtained from the disclosure of U.S. Patent Publication No.: 2005/0216062, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. U.S. Patent Publication No.: 2005/0216062 discloses a multi-functional electrical stimulation (ES) system adapted to yield output signals for effecting faradic, electromagnetic or other forms of electrical stimulation for a broad spectrum of different biological and biomedical applications. The system includes an ES signal stage having a selector coupled to a plurality of different signal generators, each producing a signal having a distinct shape such as a sine, a square or saw-tooth wave, or simple or complex pulse, the parameters of which are adjustable in regard to amplitude, duration, repetition rate and other variables. The signal from the selected generator in the ES stage is fed to at least one output stage where it is processed to produce a high or low voltage or current output of a desired polarity whereby the output stage is capable of yielding an electrical stimulation signal appropriate for its intended application. Also included in the system is a measuring stage which measures and displays the electrical stimulation signal operating on the substance being treated as well as the outputs of various sensors which sense conditions prevailing in this substance whereby the user of the system can manually adjust it or have it automatically adjusted by feedback to provide an electrical stimulation signal of whatever type he wishes and the user can then observe the effect of this signal on a substance being treated.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In a preferred embodiment, an electrode is introduced into one of the sinus cavities of a patient to treat nerve disorders in the brain and/or to evaluate hearing deficiencies. In preferred embodiments for treating nerve disorders, the electrode is positioned within a sinus cavity adjacent to or near the frontal cortex of the brain and the electrical signal is sufficient to modulate, stimulate and/or inhibit nerves within the frontal cortex. The electrode is preferably movable between a collapsed or compact configuration for introduction through one of the nostrils into the target sinus cavity and an expanded configuration for contacting tissue within the sinus cavity to deliver the electrical impulse through said tissue to the target nerves in the brain.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">A key advantage of the invention is that deep brain stimulation (DBS) to treat certain nerve disorders can be accomplished minimally invasively, i.e., without requiring direct access to the brain through the patient's skull. In addition, the proximity of the sinus cavities to the frontal cortex allows precise positioning of the electric field to stimulate the appropriate nerve tissue. Thus, deeper areas of the brain can be directly stimulated without damaging otherwise healthy areas of the brain. Nerve disorders that can be treated according to the present invention include epilepsy, Parkinson's disease, depression, eating disorders, Tourette syndrome, obesity, mood disorders, obsessive-compulsive disorders, hyperphagia, addiction, dystonia, essential tremor, chronic pain or any other disorder associated with nerve transmissions in the frontal cortex.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">One example of a nerve disorder that can be treated according to the present invention is Parkinson's disease. Parkinson's disease is a neurodegenerative disease whose primary symptoms are tremor, rigidity, bradykinesia and postural instability. Deep brain stimulation can be used to control or mitigate the symptoms of Parkinson's disease by sending high frequency electrical impulses into specific areas of the brain. Traditionally, the two most common target sites for nerve stimulation are the subthalamic nucleus (STN) and the globus pallidus internal (GPi), but other sites such as the caudal zona incerta and the pallidofugal fibers medial to the STN, are being evaluated and show promise.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Another example of a nerve disorder that can be treated according to the present invention is major depression. Researchers have shown that electrical stimulation of a small area of the frontal cortex, the subgenual cingulated region, can bring about sustained remissions in patients suffering from major depression. In addition, the nucleus accumbens, the region associated with pleasure and reward mechanisms, has shown promising results with patients suffering from profound depression.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the nasal cavity <b>900</b> is a large air-filled space above and behind the nose <b>902</b> in the middle of the face. The paranasal sinuses (maxillary, frontal, ethmoid and sphenoid) are air-filled spaces within the bones of the skull and face that communicate with the nasal cavity via small openings or ostia. The frontal sinuses <b>904</b> are superior to the eyes in the frontal bone which forms the hard part of the forehead. The maxillary sinuses (only the opening <b>910</b> of the maxillary sinus is shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) are under the eyes in the maxillary bone. The ethmoid sinuses <b>906</b> are formed from several discrete air cells within the ethmoid bone between the nose and eyes. Finally, the sphenoid sinuses <b>908</b> are located in the sphenoid bone at the center of the skull base under the pituitary gland.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In use, an electrode is introduced through the nostril <b>922</b> of the patient and advanced into one of the sinus cavities such as the front sinus <b>904</b> or the sphenoid sinus <b>908</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the electrode may be a balloon-electrode device <b>100</b> similar to the one shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> or any suitable electrode device that can be used in the method described below. For example, an expandable electrode may be used that is designed for insertion through the nostril <b>922</b> and then for expansion into a large configuration at the target site within the sinus cavities. Alternatively, any standard bipolar or monopolar electrode suitable for delivering the appropriate electrical impulse from the sinus cavities to the target location in the brain may be used to practice the method of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The exact location of placement of the electrode(s) will depend on the targeted region of the patient's frontal cortex according to the desired treatment of the nerve disorder. Once in position, a fluid, preferably a saline and/or a buffered conductive solution, passes into balloon <b>102</b> through an introducer tube <b>104</b> such that when balloon <b>102</b> is inflated, electrode <b>110</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) is substantially centrally located within the interior of balloon <b>102</b>. An electrical impulse is then applied to electrode <b>110</b> by a suitable impulse generator <b>310</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) such that the electrical impulse passes through the conductive fluid and the outer surface of balloon <b>102</b> into the tissue of the sinus cavity and to the targeted nerve in the patient's brain. The electrical signal may be of a frequency between about 1-3000 Hz, pulse duration between about 10-1000 us, and an amplitude between about 1-20 volts. The exact amplitude will largely depend on the distance between the electrode <b>110</b> and the targeted nerve.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The electrical signal is preferably selected to substantially block the nerve signals that cause the disorder to be treated. For example, if the physician is treating non-Parkinsonian essential tremor, the placement of balloon <b>102</b> and the amplitude of the signal will both be selected to apply a suitable electrical impulse to block nerves signals emanating from the ventrointermedial nucleus of the thalamus. If the physician is treating dystonia and symptoms associated with Parkinson's disease (rigidity, bradykinesia/akinesia and/or tremor), the balloon <b>102</b> is placed and the amplitude is selected to apply the electrical impulse to block nerve signals emanating from either the globus pallidus or subthalamic nucleus.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Balloon-electrode device <b>100</b> may be introduced into the sinus cavities for multiple treatments, depending on the nerve disorder. Alternatively, the device may be implanted in one of the sinus cavities. In this embodiment, balloon <b>102</b> is detachable from introducer tube <b>104</b>. In one embodiment, tube <b>104</b> includes a one-way valve along its length proximal to balloon <b>102</b> such that conductive fluid can be delivered to the interior of the balloon <b>102</b> without passing back through tube <b>104</b> when the distal portion of tube <b>104</b> is detached from balloon <b>102</b>. When it is desired to apply the electrical impulse, tube <b>104</b> may be reattached to balloon <b>102</b> to deliver sufficient conductive fluid to expand balloon <b>102</b>. A wireless transmitter outside of the patient's body may be used to apply the electrical impulse to electrode <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In another embodiment, an electrode, such as balloon electrode device <b>100</b>, may be used to evaluate a patient's hearing deficiency, such as a deficiency related to the cochlea. The cochlea is a spiraled hollow conical chamber of bone that functions as the auditory portion of the inner ear. It is filled with a water liquid, which moves in response to the vibrations coming from the middle ear via the oval window. As the fluid moves, thousands of &#x201c;hair cells&#x201d; are set in motion, and this motion is converted into electrical signals that are communicated via neurotransmitters to many thousands of nerve cells. These primary auditory neurons transform the signals into electrical impulses known as action potentials, which travel along the auditory nerve to structures in the brainstem for further processing.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">A cochlear implant is a surgically implanted electronic device that provides a sense of sound to a person who is profoundly deaf or severely hard of hearing. The cochlear implant is often referred to as a bionic ear. Unlike hearing aids, the cochlear implant does not amplify sound, but works by directly stimulating any functioning auditory nerves inside the cochlea with an electric field. External components of the cochlear implant may include a microphone, speech processor and an RF transducer or primary headpiece coil. A secondary coil is implanted beneath the skull's skin and inductively coupled to the primary headpiece coil. The headpiece coil has a magnet by which it attaches to another magnet placed on the secondary coil often beside the cochlear implant. The implant relays the incoming signal to the implanted electrodes in the cochlea. The speech processor allows an individual to adjust the sensitivity of the device. The implant gives recipients additional auditory information including sound discrimination fine enough to understand speech in quiet environments.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">A cochlear implant will not cure deafness or hearing impairment, but is a prosthetic substitute for hearing. Some recipients find them very effective, others somewhat effective and some feel worse overall with the implant than without. For people already functional in spoken language who lose their hearing, cochlear implants can be a great help in restoring functional comprehension of speech, especially if they have only lost their hearing for a short time. However, some effects of implantation are irreversible; while the device promises to provide new sound information for a recipient, the implantation process inevitably results in damage to nerve cells within the cochlea, which often results in a permanent loss of most residual natural hearing. While recent improvements in implant technology, and implantation techniques, promise to minimize such damage, the risk and extent of damage still varies. Thus, it is important to accurately assess the potential effectiveness of a cochlea implant prior to surgery (to the extent possible).</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The present invention provides a system and method of stimulating auditory nerves within the cochlea to determine which nerves are functional and thereby diagnose the patient's hearing deficiency. This allows the physician to more accurately assess the potential effectiveness of a cochlea implant prior to implantation. In a preferred embodiment, balloon <b>102</b> is introduced through one of the nostrils <b>922</b> of the patient and into a sinus cavity adjacent the pharyngeal orifice <b>920</b> of the auditory tube (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). Once in position, a fluid such as isotonic saline passes into balloon <b>102</b> through an introducer tube <b>104</b> such that when balloon <b>102</b> is inflated, electrode <b>110</b> is substantially centrally located within the interior of balloon <b>102</b>. An electrical impulse is then applied to electrode <b>110</b> by a suitable impulse generator <b>310</b> such that the electrical impulse passes through the conductive fluid and the outer surface of balloon <b>102</b> into the tissue of the sinus cavity and to the targeted auditory nerve(s) in the patient's cochlea (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">In this embodiment, the electrical signal(s) will preferably be selected to mimic one or more electrical signals that would be produced by a functioning cochlea. The patient's response to these signals is then monitored to determine whether a cochlea implant would be effective. The electrical signals may be of a frequency between about 1-10,000 Hz, pulse duration between about 10-1000 us, and an amplitude between about 1-20 volts.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Although the invention herein has been described with reference to particular embodiments, it is to be understood that these embodiments are merely illustrative of the principles and applications of the present invention. It is therefore to be understood that numerous modifications may be made to the illustrative embodiments and that other arrangements may be devised without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for treating a nerve disorder in a patient, comprising:
<claim-text>introducing an electrode into a sinus cavity of the patient by advancing an expandable enclosure into the sinus cavity, wherein the electrode is housed within the expandable enclosure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying an electrical impulse through the electrode to a target region in the patient's brain, the electrical impulse being sufficient to modulate one or more nerves in the target region to treat the nerve disorder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the target region is the frontal cortex of the brain.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical impulse is sufficient to inhibit nerve activity in the target region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical impulse is sufficient to depolarize nerve membranes in the target region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the introducing step is carried out by advancing the expandable enclosure through a nostril of the patient and into the sinus cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sinus cavity is at least one of the frontal sinus, the sphenoidal sinus and the ethmoid sinus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the nerve disorder is at least one of epilepsy, Parkinson's disease, depression, eating disorder, obesity, mood disorder, obsessive-compulsive disorder, hyperphagia, addiction, dystonia, essential tremor and chronic pain.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising expanding the expandable enclosure after introducing the electrode into the sinus cavity of the patient, and contacting a tissue of the sinus cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising contacting a tissue of the sinus cavity with an electrically-permeable portion of an outer wall of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the electrode is housed within the enclosure, and further comprising delivering electrically conductive fluid into the enclosure such that the conductive fluid electrically couples the electrode with the electrically-permeable portion of the outer wall of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the outer wall is the electrode, and further comprising delivering fluid into the enclosure to expand the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid is electrically conductive, and further comprising applying the electrical impulse through the electrically conductive fluid to the outer wall of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein contacting a tissue of the sinus cavity with an electrically-permeable portion of an outer wall of the enclosure comprises expanding the enclosure from a deflated position to an inflated position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein expanding the enclosure is carried out by delivering the electrically conductive fluid into an interior of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, further comprising inflating the enclosure with the electrically conductive fluid such that the electrode is substantially centrally located within an interior volume of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A system for treating a nerve disorder comprising:
<claim-text>an electrode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an introducer coupled to the electrode and configured for advancing the electrode into a sinus cavity adjacent to or near a target region in a brain of the patient;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source of electrical energy coupled to the electrode and configured for applying an electrical impulse through the electrode to the target region, the electrical impulse being sufficient to modulate one or more nerves in the target region to treat the nerve disorder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an enclosure coupled to the source of electrical energy and the introducer, the enclosure having an outer wall surrounding an interior, the outer wall having at least one section that is formed from an electrically-permeable material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the electrode is movable between a compact configuration for introduction into the sinus cavity and an expanded configuration for contacting tissue within the sinus cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a fluid delivery device fluidly coupled to the interior of the enclosure for delivering electrically conductive fluid to said interior such that the electrically-permeable section of the outer wall is electrically coupled to the electrical energy source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the electrode is housed within the interior of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the introducer comprises a hollow tube having an internal passageway with a proximal opening coupled to the fluid delivery device and a distal opening coupled to the interior of the enclosure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the enclosure is a balloon movable between a deflated position for introduction through a nostril into the sinus cavity of the patient and an inflated position for contacting tissue within the sinus cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the electrode is substantially centrally located within the balloon in the inflated position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a return electrode adapted for contact with the patient, wherein the electrode and the return electrode are adapted such that the electro-magnetic field emanating from the electrode is in a substantially radial pattern.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the source of electrical energy is an electrical signal generator and the electrical impulse is of a frequency between about 1 Hz to about 3000 Hz, a pulse duration of between about 10 us to about 1000 us, and an amplitude of between about 1 volt to about 20 volts. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
