<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08625205-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08625205</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13364692</doc-number>
<date>20120202</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-021613</doc-number>
<date>20110203</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359703</main-classification>
<further-classification>359694</further-classification>
<further-classification>359700</further-classification>
<further-classification>359826</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Zoom type lens barrel and image pickup apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4822153</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tomori et al.</name>
<date>19890400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359700</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6829103</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kobayashi et al.</name>
<date>20041200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359700</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0128931</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Matsumoto</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359823</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-078537</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-114531</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359676-693</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359694-706</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>359823-826</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120200941</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120809</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kudoh</last-name>
<first-name>Tomoyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kudoh</last-name>
<first-name>Tomoyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rossi, Kimms &#x26; McDowell LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Canon Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Mack</last-name>
<first-name>Ricky</first-name>
<department>2872</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>O'Neill</last-name>
<first-name>Gary</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A lens barrel which can increase the relative movement interval of lens units in the direction of an optical axis without increasing the dimension of a translating cylinder, which inhibits the rotation of the lens units, in the direction of the optical axis. The movement of a second lens unit holding second group lenses is switched from linear guide by a first translating guide unit to linear guide by a second translating guide unit when the second lens unit moves in a direction relatively away from a first lens unit holding first group lenses.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="150.88mm" wi="141.99mm" file="US08625205-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="164.34mm" wi="142.16mm" file="US08625205-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="149.10mm" wi="166.12mm" file="US08625205-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="246.89mm" wi="173.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625205-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="170.18mm" wi="143.00mm" file="US08625205-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="179.66mm" wi="159.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08625205-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="169.76mm" wi="140.97mm" file="US08625205-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a zoom type lens barrel mounted on an image pickup apparatus such as a digital camera, and an image pickup apparatus having the lens barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Conventionally, in a zoom-type lens barrel mounted on an image pickup apparatus such as a digital camera, a plurality of lens units holding lenses are moved in the direction of an optical axis by rotation of a cam cylinder, while the movement of the lens units in the rotational direction is inhibited by a translating cylinder.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In recent years, with the demand for an increase in shooting magnification, the number of lens units have increased, and the length over which lens units are extended have increased, and thus the size of a lens barrel tends to increase. On the other hand, there has been the demand for slimming down of digital cameras, and accordingly, the dimension of a lens barrel in the direction of an optical axis when the lens barrel is retracted has been required to be reduced to the extent possible.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, for example, there has been proposed a lens barrel in which cam grooves are provided on an inner peripheral side and an outer peripheral side of one cam cylinder, and a plurality of lens units following the respective cam grooves are relatively moved in the direction of an optical axis to change shooting magnifications (see Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication (Kokai) No. 2006-078537). Also, there has been proposed a lens barrel in which a front set of lens units and a rear set of lens units are cam-engaged with and held on respective cam grooves formed on cam members in the third row (see Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication (Kokai) No. 2006-078537).</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Further, there has been proposed a method by which followers are provided before and after a lens unit in the direction of an optical axis, and the followers are moved on the same cam cylinder with movement of a zoom lens to ensure movement strokes of the lens unit (see Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication (Kokai) No. 2007-114531).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, according to both Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication (Kokai) No. 2006-078537 and Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication (Kokai) No. 2007-114531, if relative movement intervals of lens units in the direction of an optical axis are increased so as to increase the shooting magnification, the dimension of a translating cylinder, which inhibits the rotation of the lens units, in the direction of the optical axis will be increased. As a result, the dimension of a lens barrel in the direction of the optical axis when the lens barrel is retracted will be increased, which inhibits slimming-down of an image pickup apparatus.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention provides a lens barrel capable of increasing the relative movement interval of lens units in the direction of an optical axis without increasing the dimension of a translating cylinder, which inhibits the rotation of the lens units, in the direction of the optical axis, and an image pickup apparatus having the lens barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Accordingly, a first aspect of the present invention provides a lens barrel comprising a first lens unit configured to hold first group lenses, a second lens unit configured to hold second group lenses, a first cam member with which the first lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move the first lens unit in a direction of an optical axis, a second cam member with which the second lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move the second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis, a translating cylinder configured to inhibit rotation of the first lens unit, a first translating guide unit configured to be provided between the first lens unit and the second lens unit, and linearly guide the second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis with rotation of the second lens unit being inhibited, and a second translating guide unit configured to be provided between the second lens unit and the translating cylinder, and linearly guide the second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis with rotation of the second lens unit being inhibited, wherein the movement of the second lens unit is switched from linear guide by the first translating guide unit to linear guide by the second translating guide unit when the second lens unit moves in a direction relatively away from the first lens unit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Accordingly, a second aspect of the present invention provides an image pickup apparatus having a zoom-type lens barrel that changes shooting magnifications by moving in the direction of the optical axis between a shooting position and a retracting position, comprising, as the lens barrel, a lens barrel as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to the present invention, the relative movement interval of lens units in the direction of the optical axis can be increased without increasing the dimension of the translating cylinder, which inhibits the rotation of the lens units, in the direction of the optical axis. Therefore, the shooting magnification of the lens barrel can be increased, while slimming down of the image pickup apparatus can be realized by reducing the dimension of the lens barrel in the direction of the optical axis when the lens barrel is retracted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of exemplary embodiments (with reference to the attached drawings).</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of a digital camera, which is an exemplary image pickup apparatus according to the present invention, as viewed from the front.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view showing the digital camera in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as viewed from the rear.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram useful in explaining a control system of the digital camera.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a lens barrel being at a wide position.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing the lens barrel being at a telephoto position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing the relationship among a first lens unit, a second lens unit, and a first translating cylinder.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The present invention will now be described in detail with reference to the drawings showing an embodiment thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view showing the appearance of a digital camera, which is an exemplary image pickup apparatus according to the present invention, as viewed from the front, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view showing the digital camera in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as viewed from the rear.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the digital camera <b>15</b> according to the present embodiment is configured such that a finder <b>20</b>, an auxiliary light source <b>19</b> for use in photometry and ranging, a strobe <b>21</b>, and a lens barrel <b>30</b> are disposed in front. The lens barrel <b>30</b> is of a zoom type which changes shooting magnifications by moving in the direction of an optical axis between a shooting position and a retracting position.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A release button <b>16</b>, a power switch button <b>18</b>, and a zoom switch <b>17</b> are disposed on the top of the digital camera <b>15</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, operation buttons <b>24</b> to <b>29</b>, a display <b>23</b> such as an LCD, and a finder eyepiece <b>22</b> are disposed on the back of the digital camera <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram useful in explaining a control system of the digital camera <b>15</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a CPU <b>46</b>, a ROM <b>45</b>, a RAM <b>47</b>, a release button <b>16</b>, and operation buttons <b>24</b> to <b>29</b>, and a display <b>23</b> are connected to a bus <b>44</b>. Also, the power switch button <b>18</b>, the zoom switch <b>17</b>, a memory <b>40</b>, a compression/expansion unit <b>41</b>, a memory card drive <b>42</b>, and a drive circuit <b>43</b> are connected to the bus <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A zoom mechanism <b>31</b> that zoom-drives the lens barrel <b>30</b>, a focus drive mechanism <b>32</b> that drives a focus lens <b>5</b>, a shutter drive mechanism <b>34</b> that drives a shutter <b>33</b>, and a diaphragm drive mechanism <b>36</b> that drives a diaphragm <b>35</b> are connected to a drive circuit <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">An image pickup device <b>11</b> such as a CCD sensor or CMOS sensor and a strobe <b>21</b> are connected to the drive circuit <b>43</b>. The operation of the units connected to the drive circuit <b>43</b> is controlled via the drive circuit <b>43</b> based on signals from the CPU <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Various control programs and others are stored in the ROM <b>45</b>, and data required for various control programs is stored in the RAM <b>47</b>. An analog signal processing unit <b>37</b> carries out analog processing on image data output from the image pickup device <b>11</b>, and outputs the image data to an A/D converter <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The A/D converter <b>38</b> converts analog data taken from the image pickup device <b>11</b> into digital data, and outputs the digital data to a digital signal processing unit <b>39</b>. The digital signal processing unit <b>39</b> carries out predetermined processing on the digital data obtained as a result of the conversion by the A/D converter <b>38</b>, and outputs the resulting data as image data to the memory <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Image data stored in the memory <b>40</b> is subjected to compression processing such as JPEG or TIFF by the compression/expansion unit <b>41</b> and then output to a memory card mounted on the memory card drive <b>42</b> and stored.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Also, image data stored in the memory <b>40</b> and image data stored in the memory card drive <b>42</b> can be subjected to expansion processing by the compression/expansion unit <b>41</b> and then displayed on the display <b>23</b> via the bus <b>44</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring next to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 to 6</figref>, a detailed description will be given of the lens barrel <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing the lens barrel <b>30</b> being at a wide position, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing the lens barrel <b>30</b> being at a telephoto position, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing the relationship among a first lens unit <b>1</b>, a second lens unit <b>2</b>, and a first translating cylinder <b>7</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the lens barrel <b>30</b> has the first lens unit <b>1</b> holding first group lenses, the second lens unit <b>2</b> holding second group lenses, and a third lens unit <b>3</b> holding third group lenses.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Also, the lens barrel <b>30</b> has a fourth lens unit <b>4</b> holding fourth group lenses and a fifth lens unit <b>5</b> holding fifth group lenses. The fifth group lenses of the fifth lens unit <b>5</b> are focus lenses.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A device holder <b>12</b> holds the image pickup device <b>11</b>, and a fixed cam cylinder <b>10</b> is disposed on the subject side of the device holder <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A fixed cam groove <b>10</b><i>a </i>is formed on an inner peripheral portion of the fixed cam cylinder <b>10</b>, and a follower pin of a second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> following the fixed cam groove <b>10</b><i>a </i>is cam-engaged with the fixed cam groove <b>10</b><i>a</i>. The second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> is rotatively driven, so that the follower pin follows the fixed cam groove <b>10</b><i>a </i>and moves in the direction of the optical axis while rotating with respect to the fixed cam cylinder <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">A second translating cylinder <b>9</b> is disposed on an inner peripheral portion of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and the second translating cylinder <b>9</b> is bayonet-joined to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> so as to be rotatable relatively to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> and moves with the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> in the direction of the optical axis. A key groove joined to a translating key <b>10</b><i>b </i>provided on an inner peripheral portion of the fixed cam cylinder <b>10</b> is formed on an outer peripheral portion of the second translating cylinder <b>9</b>, thus inhibiting the rotation of the second translating cylinder <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A first cam groove <b>8</b><i>a </i>is formed on an inner peripheral portion of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and a follower pin of the first translating cylinder <b>7</b> is cam-engaged with the first cam groove <b>8</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b> is disposed on an outer peripheral side of the first translating cylinder <b>7</b>, and the first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b> is rotatably bayonet-joined to the first translating cylinder <b>7</b>. The first translating cylinder <b>7</b> has a key groove that is joined to a translating key provided in the second translating cylinder <b>9</b>, and thus, in the state of being inhibited from rotating, the first translating cylinder <b>7</b> can move in the direction of the optical axis relatively to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> due to cam-engagement with the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b> is key-joined to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and moves in the direction of the optical axis together with the first translating cylinder <b>7</b> while rotating with rotation of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>. A cam groove is formed on an inner peripheral portion of the first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b>, and a follower pin of the first lens unit <b>1</b> following the cam groove is cam-engaged with the cam groove.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Thus, the rotation of the first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b> causes the first lens unit <b>1</b> to move in the direction of the optical axis. When the first lens unit <b>1</b> is moving in the direction of the optical axis, the first lens unit <b>1</b> is key-joined to the first translating cylinder <b>7</b>, and hence the rotation thereof is inhibited. Here, the first moving cam cylinder <b>6</b> corresponds to an exemplary first cam member according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">An inner cam cylinder <b>13</b> is disposed on an inner peripheral side of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and an inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> is disposed on an inner peripheral side of the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> is rotatably bayonet-joined to the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b>. A second cam groove <b>8</b><i>b </i>is formed on an inner peripheral portion of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and a follower pin of the inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> following the second cam groove <b>8</b><i>b </i>is cam-engaged with the second cam groove <b>8</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> has a key groove that is engaged with a translating key provided in the second translating cylinder <b>9</b>, and as a result, in the state of being inhibited from rotating, the inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> can relatively move in the direction of the optical axis relatively to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b> due to cam-engagement with the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The inner cam cylinder <b>13</b> is key-joined to the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>, and moves in the direction of the optical axis together with the inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> while rotating with rotation of the second moving cam cylinder <b>8</b>. Also, a cam groove followed by a follower pin <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the second lens unit <b>2</b> is formed on an outer peripheral portion of the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b>, and cam grooves followed by respective follower pins of the third lens unit <b>3</b> and the fourth lens unit <b>4</b> are formed on an inner peripheral portion of the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Thus, the rotation of the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b> causes the second lens unit <b>2</b>, third lens unit <b>3</b>, and fourth lens unit <b>4</b> to move in the direction of the optical axis. The third lens unit <b>3</b> and the fourth lens unit <b>4</b> are key-joined to the inner translating cylinder <b>14</b> and inhibited from rotating. Here, the inner cam cylinder <b>13</b> corresponds to an exemplary second cam member according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">When the lens barrel <b>30</b> is extended from the wide position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the telephoto position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the second lens unit <b>2</b> moves in a direction relatively away from the first lens unit <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">At this time, the amount of the relative movement of the second lens unit <b>2</b> relative to the first lens unit <b>1</b> in the direction of the optical axis is particularly large as compared to the other lens units.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Here, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, at the wide position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a translating groove <b>2</b><i>b </i>provided on an outer peripheral portion of the second lens unit <b>2</b> is engaged with a first guide projection <b>1</b><i>a </i>provided on an inner peripheral portion of the first lens unit <b>1</b> so as to linearly guide the second lens unit <b>2</b> while inhibiting the rotation thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Also, at the telephoto position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the translating groove <b>2</b><i>b </i>provided on the outer peripheral portion of the second lens unit <b>2</b> is engaged with a second guide projection <b>7</b><i>a </i>provided on an inner peripheral portion of the first translating cylinder <b>7</b>. Here, the translating groove <b>2</b><i>b </i>and the first guide projection <b>1</b><i>a </i>correspond to an exemplary first linear guide unit according to the present invention, and the translating groove <b>2</b><i>b </i>and the second guide projection <b>7</b><i>a </i>correspond to an exemplary second linear guide unit according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">While the lens barrel <b>30</b> is moving from the wide position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> to the telephoto position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the translating groove <b>2</b><i>b </i>switches from the state of being engaged with the first guide projection <b>1</b><i>a </i>to the state of being engaged with the second guide projection <b>7</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As a result, the relative movement interval of the first lens unit <b>1</b> and the second lens unit <b>2</b> in the direction of the optical axis can be increased without increasing the dimension of the first translating cylinder <b>7</b>, which inhibits the rotation of the second lens unit <b>2</b>, in the direction of the optical axis.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As described above, in the present embodiment, the stroke of the second lens unit <b>2</b> can be increased without increasing the dimension of the first translating cylinder <b>7</b> in the direction of the optical axis. As a result, the shooting magnification of the lens barrel <b>30</b> can be increased, while the slimming down of the digital camera <b>15</b> can be realized by decreasing the dimension of the lens barrel <b>30</b> in the direction of the optical axis when the lens barrel is retracted.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">OTHER EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Aspects of the present invention can also be realized by a computer of a system or apparatus (or devices such as a CPU or MPU) that reads out and executes a program recorded on a memory device to perform the functions of the above-described embodiment(s), and by a method, the steps of which are performed by a computer of a system or apparatus by, for example, reading out and executing a program recorded on a memory device to perform the functions of the above-described embodiment(s). For this purpose, the program is provided to the computer for example via a network or from a recording medium of various types serving as the memory device (e.g., computer-readable medium).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">While the present invention has been described with reference to exemplary embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the disclosed exemplary embodiments. The scope of the following claims is to be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent structures and functions.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">This application claims the benefit of Japanese Patent Application No. 2011-021613 filed Feb. 3, 2011, which is hereby incorporated by reference herein in its entirety.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A lens barrel comprising:
<claim-text>a first lens unit configured to hold a first lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lens unit configured to hold a second lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cam member with which said first lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said first lens unit in a direction of an optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cam member with which said second lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a translating cylinder configured to inhibit rotation of said first lens unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first translating guide unit provided between said first lens unit and said second lens unit, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second translating guide unit provided between said second lens unit and said translating cylinder, and linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein linear guide by said first translating guide unit is switched to linear guide by said second translating guide unit when said second lens unit moves in a direction relatively away from said first lens unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A lens barrel according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said first translating guide unit comprises a first guide projection that is provided on an inner periphery of said first lens unit, and a translating groove that is provided on an outer periphery of said second lens unit to engage the first guide projection, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second translating guide unit comprises the translating groove and a second guide projection that is provided on an inner periphery of said translating cylinder and engages said translating groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An image pickup apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image sensing device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a zoom-type lens barrel that changes shooting magnifications by moving in the direction of an optical axis of the image pickup apparatus between a shooting position and a retracting position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the zoom-type lens barrel includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lens unit configured to hold a first lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lens unit configured to hold a second lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cam member with which said first lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said first lens unit in a direction of an optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cam member with which said second lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a translating cylinder configured to inhibit rotation of said first lens unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first translating guide unit provided between said first lens unit and said second lens unit, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second translating guide unit provided between said second lens unit and said translating cylinder, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein linear guide by said first translating guide unit is switched to linear guide by said second translating guide unit when said second lens unit moves in a direction relatively away from said first lens unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A lens barrel comprising:
<claim-text>a first lens unit configured to hold a first lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lens unit configured to hold a second lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cam member with which said first lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said first lens unit in a direction of an optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cam member with which said second lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a translating cylinder configured to inhibit rotation of said first lens unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first translating guide unit provided between said first lens unit and said second lens unit, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second translating guide unit provided between said second lens unit and said translating cylinder, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first lens unit and said second lens unit are displaceable along the direction of the optical axis between a first position where said first lens unit and said second lens unit are closest to each other and a second position where said first lens unit and said second lens unit are farthest from each other,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first translating guide unit linearly guides said second lens unit to the first position, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second translating guide unit, instead of said first translating guide unit, linearly guides said second lens unit to the second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A lens barrel according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said first translating guide unit comprises a first guide projection that is provided on an inner periphery of said first lens unit, and a translating groove that is provided on an outer periphery of said second lens unit to engage the first guide projection, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second translating guide unit comprises the translating groove and a second guide projection that is provided on an inner periphery of said translating cylinder and engages said translating groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An image pickup apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>an image sensing device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a zoom-type lens barrel that changes shooting magnifications by moving in the direction of an optical axis of the image pickup apparatus between a shooting position and a retracting position,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the zoom-type lens barrel includes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lens unit configured to hold a first lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lens unit configured to hold a second lens group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first cam member with which said first lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said first lens unit in a direction of an optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second cam member with which said second lens unit is cam-engaged and which is configured to rotate to move said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a translating cylinder configured to inhibit rotation of said first lens unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first translating guide unit provided between said first lens unit and said second lens unit, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second translating guide unit provided between said second lens unit and said translating cylinder, and configured to linearly guide said second lens unit in the direction of the optical axis while inhibiting rotation of said second lens unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first lens unit and said second lens unit are displaceable along the direction of the optical axis between a first position where said first lens unit and said second lens unit are closest to each other and a second position where said first lens unit and said second lens unit are farthest from each other,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first translating guide unit linearly guides said second lens unit to the first position, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second translating guide unit, instead of said first translating guide unit, linearly guides said second lens unit to the second position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
