<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624627-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624627</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13538200</doc-number>
<date>20120629</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>25</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>326 41</main-classification>
<further-classification>326 62</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Method and device for low power control</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6240521</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Barber et al.</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7080341</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Eisenstadt et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 81</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7884640</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Greene et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 38</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8040151</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Speers</name>
<date>20111000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 38</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8103975</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lewis et al.</name>
<date>20120100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 38</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0091629</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Eisenstadt et al.</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>716 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0136767</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ma</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0247189</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Phil et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 41</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0156458</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Speers</name>
<date>20100600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>326 39</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jarrar</last-name>
<first-name>Anis M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moyer</last-name>
<first-name>William C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dripping Springs</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nash</last-name>
<first-name>Jim C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Jarrar</last-name>
<first-name>Anis M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Moyer</last-name>
<first-name>William C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dripping Springs</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nash</last-name>
<first-name>Jim C.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Freescale Semiconductor, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hammond</last-name>
<first-name>Crystal L</first-name>
<department>2819</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present application discloses an integrated circuit having a power controller that can manage power modes of a system when the system is in a low power mode. According to an embodiment, a power controller is built into an input/output (I/O) region of and integrated circuit die, wherein the I/O region is outside the main logic area of the die. The same supply voltage that powers the I/O region of the device can power the power controller. The power controller can operate to transition the integrated circuit die between power modes by transitioning logic modules of the integrated circuit between power states without intervention by the logic modules.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="175.77mm" wi="214.04mm" file="US08624627-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="219.63mm" wi="177.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624627-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="259.00mm" wi="160.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624627-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="245.96mm" wi="156.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624627-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="252.31mm" wi="177.72mm" file="US08624627-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="269.58mm" wi="192.53mm" file="US08624627-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="266.78mm" wi="184.74mm" file="US08624627-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="125.65mm" wi="168.57mm" file="US08624627-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates generally to electronic devices and more particularly to electronic devices having various power modes of operation.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Many integrated circuits can operate in various power modes that are used to reduce power consumption. A central power mode controller is commonly used in integrated circuit designs to transition a device through its various power modes. The central power mode controller can be a function implemented by a CPU core of the integrated circuit, which means that software has to execute at the CPU core of the integrated circuit to transition the integrated circuit between power modes. Thus, once the CPU core has been placed in a standby state during which it cannot execute instructions, there is no way to transition the integrated circuit to a higher or lower power mode without executing a wakeup sequence that returns the CPU core to a power state that allows execution of software that is used to transition integrated circuit between power states. Typically, the lower the integrated circuit power consumption during a power mode, the longer the wakeup time associated with transitioning the integrated circuit to an operational power mode. Thus, the process of waking up a CPU core of an integrated circuit and then transitioning the integrated circuit into a different standby mode has impact on the overall performance and power consumption profile of the system.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present disclosure may be better understood, and its numerous features and advantages made apparent to those skilled in the art by referencing the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a system in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a power subsystem of the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a communication subsystem of the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a specific embodiment of a power control module of the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, storage locations storing information used in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a specific embodiment of a portion of the power control module of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates, a timing diagram associated with the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates, a state diagram associated with the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates, a diagram illustrated power mode transition associated with the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates a cross-section view of transistors associated with the integrated circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in accordance with a particular embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present application discloses an integrated circuit having a power controller that can manage power modes of a system when the system is in a low power mode. According to an embodiment, a power controller is built into an input/output (I/O) region of an integrated circuit die, wherein the I/O region is outside the main logic area of the die. The power controller can be powered by the same supply voltage as the I/O region of the die, which can be different than the supply voltage that powers other portions of the die. The power controller can operate to transition the integrated circuit die between power modes by transitioning one or more logic modules of the integrated circuit between power states without intervention by the logic modules. Various aspects of a particular embodiment will be better understood with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a portion of a system <b>10</b> that includes a voltage supply <b>20</b> connected to an integrated circuit device (IC <b>30</b>) in accordance with a specific embodiment of the present disclosure. System <b>10</b> can be a portable or non-portable device. Examples of portable and non-portable devices include consumer goods, such as consumer electronics and durable consumer goods. In an embodiment, the system <b>10</b> can represent various devices, such as an automobile having an electronic engine controller, a printed circuit board having one or more integrated circuit die, a handheld computing device, a personal computer, a computer server, or components within any of these types of systems.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">IC <b>30</b> is represented in a block diagram and floor-plan perspective at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, wherein the relative location of various features of IC <b>30</b> are indicative of a physical layout relative to other features as indicated further herein. IC <b>30</b> is a semiconductor die that is defined by a common substrate, and that is capable of operating in one of a plurality of power modes. An illustrated a left most edge of the common substrate is indicated by dashed line <b>39</b>. IC <b>30</b> includes a plurality of I/O pads (I/Os) <b>31</b>, and a plurality of logic modules. The plurality of logic modules include the plurality of logic modules <b>50</b> and a logic module <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The plurality of logic modules <b>50</b> are illustrated to reside at the main logic area of IC <b>30</b>, referred to herein as the logic core region <b>41</b>. The plurality of I/Os <b>31</b> and the logic module <b>32</b> are illustrated to reside at the periphery region <b>40</b> of the IC <b>30</b>, which is an I/O region. By virtue of having I/O pads along each edge of IC <b>30</b>, the periphery region can be referred to as a padring. Each I/O pad includes a contact area <b>35</b>, to which an external interconnect can be attached, and can also include an I/O buffer <b>36</b> connected to the contact area for conditioning information, e.g., digital and analog information, communicated between its I/O contact and the logic core <b>41</b>. IC <b>30</b> includes an interconnect <b>33</b>, which can be referred to as an &#x201c;I/O power bus&#x201d;, that provides power to the I/Os <b>31</b>. According to an embodiment, only a portion of the logic module <b>32</b> resides within the periphery regions, such as at least 25 percent of the logic module <b>32</b> or at least 50 percent of the logic module <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The term &#x201c;interconnect&#x201d; as used herein refers to various features that are used to provide signals, such as voltage or current references and digital/analog information, between various modules either directly or indirectly. For example, an interconnect can be implemented as a passive device, such as one or more conductive nodes, e.g., metal traces, that transmit information signals directly between various modules, or as an active device, whereby information being transmitted is buffered, e.g., stored and retrieved, in the processes of being communicated between devices, such as at a first-in first-out memory or other memory device. For convenience, the present disclosure may use a common reference number or label to refer to both an interconnect and to the signal transmitted by the interconnect. For example, a clock signal transmitted via an interconnect labeled CLK can be referred to herein as the CLK signal.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the illustrated embodiment, the I/Os <b>31</b> are formed at each of the four sides of the IC <b>30</b> to define an annular region of the IC <b>30</b>, e.g., the padring. Note that devices other than I/Os <b>31</b> can reside within the I/O region defined by the padring of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The term &#x201c;annular,&#x201d; as used herein, is intended to mean a region of any geometric shape that is defined by an inside perimeter and an outside perimeter. Therefore, it will be appreciated that an annular region can have an inside perimeter that is a circle, a polygon, such as a rectangle or an octagon, or any other shape that has an opening in the interior. The outside perimeter of the annular region can be the same or different geometric shape as the outside perimeter of the annular region. According to one embodiment, the inner perimeter of the annular region is a distance <b>37</b> from the edge of the die <b>30</b> (dashed line <b>39</b>) to an inner-most edge of an I/O pad (dashed line <b>38</b>). Similarly, each side of the periphery region <b>40</b> has an I/O region that extends the distance <b>37</b> from the edge of the die <b>30</b>. In other configurations I/Os are not formed at each of the four sides of the IC <b>30</b>, and an annular region defined by the length of an I/O pad would not necessarily have I/O pads formed along each edge.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The voltage supply <b>20</b> receives a supply voltage labeled &#x201c;Vsupp&#x201d; and provides a plurality of voltage signals to the IC <b>30</b> via interconnects &#x201c;V_PR&#x201d; and &#x201c;V_CORE&#x201d;. Voltage V_PR is illustrated as being provided to I/O power bus <b>33</b> of IC <b>30</b> to provide power to the I/Os <b>31</b> and to the logic module <b>32</b>. The portion of the IC <b>30</b> powered by the I/O power bus <b>33</b> is referred to herein as the &#x201c;I/O power domain&#x201d;, and can include those portions of IC <b>30</b> located at periphery region <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The voltage V_CORE is connected to interconnect <b>34</b> of the IC <b>30</b>, referred to herein as a &#x201c;logic core power bus&#x201d;, and provides power to the logic modules <b>50</b> at logic core <b>41</b>. The portion of the IC <b>30</b> powered by the logic core power bus <b>34</b> is referred to herein as the &#x201c;logic core power domain&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">During operation, the IC <b>30</b> can operate in one of a plurality of power modes, wherein each one of the power modes is characterized by a different combination of power states of the logic modules <b>50</b>. By way of example, it is presumed that seven power modes (PM<b>1</b>-PM<b>7</b>) are defined for IC <b>30</b> and that three power states (PS<b>1</b>-PS<b>3</b>) are defined for each logic module of the logic modules <b>50</b>. A highest power mode (PM<b>7</b>) of IC <b>30</b> corresponds to each of the logic modules <b>50</b> being at their respective highest power states (PS<b>3</b>). During a next lower power mode (PM<b>6</b>), from full power mode, one or more of the logic modules <b>50</b> are operated at corresponding power states that are lower than PS<b>3</b>. Lower power states of a logic module can be implemented by reducing an operating voltage provided to the logic module, gating a power signal used by the logic module, back-biasing logic gates within a module, reducing an operating frequency of the logic module, the like, and combinations thereof. For example, the logic modules <b>50</b> can include a Central processor Unit logic module (CPU) that can be placed in a sleep state by providing a sufficiently low voltage to prevent it from executing instructions.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to a particular embodiment, a CPU of the plurality of logic modules <b>50</b> can communicate with a power controller, which may be centralized or distributed throughout the logic core <b>41</b>, to control when the logic modules <b>50</b> transition between their available power states, thereby effectuating a desired power mode of the IC <b>30</b>. According to an embodiment, the CPU can communicate directly with various logic modules or with a slave power controller to provide information that is used to transition the various logic modules between power states to implement a desired power mode of IC <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In response to the CPU being placed in a sufficiently low power state, presumed to be sleep state or lower, the CPU cannot execute instructions and the power mode of the IC <b>30</b> cannot be modified by the CPU unless the CPU is first transitioned to a higher power state that allows it to execute instructions. However, according to an embodiment, the power mode of IC <b>30</b> can be transitioned by the logic module <b>32</b> even when the CPU is non-operational, e.g., in a sleep mode. The logic module <b>32</b> is referred to herein as the Power Mode Control module <b>32</b> (PMC <b>32</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In an embodiment, the PMC <b>32</b> is enabled to implement a power management plan in response to the CPU transitioning to a sufficiently low power state that prevents the CPU from implementing a power management plan. As such, it is not necessary to return the CPU to an operational power state, e.g., full power mode operation, in order to transition the IC <b>30</b> between power modes. For example, the PMC <b>32</b> can be used to transition logic modules <b>50</b> between their respective power states without intervention by a CPU of the logic region <b>50</b>, eliminating the need to return the CPU to an operational state. Specific embodiments of the present disclosure will be better understood with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-9</figref></p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a particular embodiment of a power subsystem of IC <b>30</b> accordance with a specific embodiment. The plurality of logic modules <b>50</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> include: a voltage regulator module <b>51</b>; a central processing unit <b>52</b> (CPU <b>52</b>); a non-volatile memory module <b>53</b>; a volatile memory module <b>54</b>; a volatile memory module <b>55</b>; a digital peripheral <b>56</b>; an analog peripheral <b>57</b>; and an I/O control module <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The power subsystem of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates power domains including an I/O power domain <b>140</b> and a logic core power domain <b>150</b>. The I/O power domain <b>140</b> includes those portions of IC <b>30</b> that are powered by the voltage V_PR, which includes the external I/Os <b>31</b> and the PMC module <b>32</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the individual external I/Os <b>31</b> are collectively represented by a single box, and referred to, as external I/Os <b>131</b>, which include segments <b>138</b>-<b>139</b> that represent portions of the external I/Os <b>131</b>, wherein each one of the segments <b>138</b>-<b>139</b> can include one or more I/O pads <b>31</b> that are connected to different power nodes (V_PR<b>1</b>-V_PRn) of the I/O power bus <b>33</b>, each of which receives the voltage V_PR via a different I/O pad (not illustrated).</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The voltage V_PR received at the I/O power bus <b>33</b> can be used to directly power the external I/Os <b>131</b> and the PMC <b>32</b>, or the voltage V_PR can be further regulated at the IC <b>30</b> to provide voltages needed to power to the external I/Os <b>131</b> and the PMC module <b>32</b>. According to an embodiment, the voltage V_PR directly powers the external I/Os <b>131</b> and the PMC <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The logic core power domain <b>150</b> includes those portions of IC <b>30</b> that are powered by the voltage V_CORE, via the logic core power bus <b>34</b>, which includes the plurality of logic modules <b>50</b>. The voltage V_CORE can directly power the logic modules <b>50</b> or can be further regulated at the IC <b>30</b> to provide one or more regulated voltages. According to an embodiment illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each of the logic modules <b>50</b> is illustrated to receive one or more regulated voltage(s) from voltage regulator <b>51</b> via power interconnect <b>134</b>. In particular, CPU <b>52</b> is connected to receive a voltage V_CPU, nonvolatile memory <b>53</b> is connected to receive a voltage V_NVM, volatile memory <b>54</b> is connected to receive a voltage V_VM<b>1</b>, volatile memory <b>55</b> is connected to receive a voltage V_VM<b>2</b>, the peripheral <b>56</b> receives a voltage V_P<b>56</b>, peripheral <b>57</b> receives a voltage V_P<b>57</b>, and I/O control module <b>58</b> is connected to receive voltage V_IOCTL. Note that according to an embodiment, the analog peripheral <b>57</b> can monitor the voltage V_CORE, wherein the voltage V_CORE is also is provided to the analog peripheral <b>57</b>. In other embodiment, other signals, such as V_PR can be monitored by the analog peripheral <b>57</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a particular embodiment of a communication subsystem of IC <b>30</b> in accordance with a specific embodiment that can be implemented along with the power subsystem of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In addition to the modules illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates interconnects <b>230</b>, and interconnects <b>271</b>-<b>274</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Interconnect <b>230</b> is an external interface of the IC <b>30</b> and includes an interconnect PCTL and an interconnect <b>231</b>. Interconnect <b>231</b> is connected to portions of the external I/O module <b>131</b> to communicate information, such digital and analog information, to and from the logic modules <b>50</b> via the interconnect <b>274</b>. Various digital information can include address, data and control information. Interconnect PCTL is connected to a portion of the external I/O module <b>131</b> to communicate information to and from the PMC <b>32</b> via interconnect <b>273</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Interconnect <b>271</b>, referred to herein as &#x201c;a system interconnect&#x201d;, is an interconnect that communicates information during normal operation amongst the logic modules to which it is connected, including internal I/O control module <b>58</b>, voltage regulator <b>51</b>, CPU <b>52</b>, nonvolatile memory module <b>53</b>, volatile memory module <b>54</b>, volatile memory module <b>55</b>, peripheral <b>56</b>, and peripheral <b>57</b>. According to an embodiment, the I/O control module <b>58</b> is master of the system interconnect <b>271</b>, and each of the other modules is a slave. According to an embodiment, the CPU <b>52</b> communicates information used to transition logic modules between their available power states via the interconnect <b>271</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Interconnect <b>272</b>, referred to herein as &#x201c;a power control interconnect&#x201d;, is an interconnect that is used to communicate information between the power mode control module <b>32</b> and logic modules <b>50</b> in order to transition the various logic modules between power states. According to an embodiment, the power mode control module <b>32</b> is the only master of the power control interconnect <b>272</b>, and each of the other modules are slaves. According to an alternate embodiment, other modules can be master of interconnect <b>272</b>. For example, the power mode control module <b>32</b> or the CPU <b>52</b> can be master of the power control interconnect <b>272</b>, wherein the CPU <b>52</b> can communicate information used to transition modules between their available power states via interconnect <b>272</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Interconnect <b>273</b> is used to communicate information between PMC <b>32</b> and external the IC <b>30</b>. According to an embodiment, PMC <b>32</b> communicates external the IC <b>30</b> via the interconnect PCTL of interconnect <b>230</b>. Interconnect <b>274</b> is used to communicate information between the external I/Os <b>131</b> and the I/O control module <b>58</b>, e.g. via interconnect <b>231</b> of interconnect <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In addition to communicating over interconnects <b>271</b>-<b>274</b>, various modules of the plurality of modules <b>50</b> can communicate with other portions of the IC <b>30</b> via other interconnects. For example, various logic modules can be capable of providing interrupt signals to the PMC <b>32</b> via a separate interconnect, such as specifically illustrated by interconnect labeled P<b>57</b>_INT that provides an interrupt from analog peripheral <b>57</b> to the power mode control module <b>32</b>. Also illustrated as part of the communication subsystem is an interconnect that provides the voltage V_CORE to the analog peripheral <b>57</b> so that the analog peripheral can monitor a voltage level of V_CORE.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">According to one embodiment, command requests are communicated via the PCTL interconnects from external the IC <b>30</b> to the PMC module <b>32</b>. According to an embodiment, information received at interconnect PCTL can be provided to PMC module <b>32</b> without being provided to, or processed by, logic associated with the logic core <b>41</b>. According to an embodiment, information received at interconnect PCTL can be provided to PMC module <b>32</b> without being processed by logic associated with power domain <b>150</b>. It will be appreciated, that according to an alternate embodiment, PMC <b>32</b> is not connected to external I/O pads <b>31</b>, and therefore does not communicate directly external IC <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Internal I/O control module <b>58</b> is connected to interconnect <b>274</b>, power control interconnect <b>272</b>, and to system interconnect <b>271</b>. As indicated previously, according to an embodiment, the internal I/O control module <b>58</b> can operate as a bus master of the system interconnect <b>271</b> and of the interconnect <b>274</b>. The internal I/O control module <b>58</b> can belong either to the power domain <b>140</b> or to the power domain <b>150</b>. For purposes of discussion, it is presumed that the internal I/O control module <b>58</b> is a member of the power domain <b>150</b>, and is capable of being placed in various power states. In various embodiments, PMC module <b>32</b> either can or cannot request servicing by the internal I/O control module <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Power control interconnect <b>272</b> can communicate information amongst each of the following: PMC <b>32</b>; internal I/O control module <b>58</b>; voltage regulator <b>51</b>; CPU <b>52</b>; nonvolatile memory module <b>53</b>; volatile memory module <b>54</b>; volatile memory module <b>55</b>; digital peripheral <b>56</b>; and analog peripheral <b>57</b>. For purposes of discussion, it is presumed that power control interconnect <b>272</b> comprises different interconnects (PS_IO, PS_CPU, PS_NVM, PS_VM<b>1</b>, PS_VM<b>2</b>, PS_P<b>56</b>, and PS_P<b>57</b>) between the PMC <b>32</b> and each respective logic module <b>51</b>-<b>58</b>. Note that each of the logic modules <b>51</b>-<b>58</b> can include respective power control ports <b>151</b>-<b>158</b> that represent interface and control logic through which power state transition control information is communicated and handled by the respective logic modules. Thus, power control ports <b>151</b>-<b>158</b> can include specific control logic, including logic that remains powered during a lowest power state, referred to as &#x201c;always on&#x201d; logic, which is used to facilitate transitioning its corresponding logic module between its available power states.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">According to embodiment, in response to the CPU <b>52</b> being placed in a sufficiently low-power state that prevents it from implementing various power modes of the system <b>30</b>, the PMC module <b>32</b> is enabled to execute a power management plan that is implemented by communicating information over the power control interconnect <b>272</b> that transitions logic modules of logic core <b>50</b> between their available power states. Thus, when CPU <b>52</b> is in a sufficiently high power mode to be operational, the CPU <b>52</b> implements a power mode control plan and provides power state control information to the logic modules <b>50</b> via one or both of the power control interconnect <b>272</b> and the system interconnect <b>271</b>. In response to the CPU <b>52</b> being transitioned into a nonoperational low-power mode, a command is provided to PMC <b>32</b> to enable PMC <b>32</b> to implement a power control plan autonomous from the CPU <b>52</b>. The command provided from the CPU <b>52</b> to the PMC module <b>32</b> can include an OP code, an interrupt, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates, in block diagram form, a specific embodiment of PMC <b>32</b>, which includes a command interpreter <b>313</b> that is connected to each of a command memory <b>311</b>, a storage module (CTL REG) <b>312</b>, a timer <b>314</b>, a transition control module <b>315</b>, interconnect <b>271</b>, interconnect <b>272</b>, and interconnect <b>273</b>. The storage module <b>312</b> is further connected to timer <b>314</b>. The transition control module <b>315</b> is further connected to power control interconnect <b>272</b>. For purposes of discussion, the storage module <b>312</b> is presumed to be a register and referred to as control register <b>312</b>. The various portions of PMC <b>32</b> can be implemented by state machines, one or more instruction based data processors, and combinations thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Command interpreter <b>313</b> can receive and decode commands from a variety of sources and that can be of a variety of types. For example, commands can be received from command memory <b>311</b>, interconnects <b>271</b>, <b>273</b>, from timer <b>314</b>. Commands can be in the form of OP codes, interrupts, the like, and combinations thereof. According to an embodiment, the command interpreter <b>313</b> can itself be implemented as a state machine or as an instruction-based processor that facilitates execution of various commands associated with power management as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">According to an embodiment, commands executed by command interpreter <b>313</b> can include: a CALL command that is a request for the command interpreter <b>313</b> to begin execution of commands at a particular memory location, such as a memory location of command memory <b>311</b>; a PSTR command that is a power state transition request to transition a particular logic module <b>50</b> from one power state to another; a PMTR command that is a power mode transition request to transition the IC <b>30</b> from one power mode to another; a DELAY command that indicates how long until a next power mode transition; an ENABLE command to enable execution of a power mode control plan by the PMC <b>32</b>; a DISABLE command to disable operation execution of the power mode control plan by PMC <b>32</b>; conditional commands to control which commands are executed; READ/WRITE commands, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">According to an embodiment, a user can store commands at command memory <b>311</b> using a write command interpreted by the command interpreter <b>313</b>, or through the use of write commands that access command memory <b>311</b> via a different read write path other than that illustrated. Command memory <b>311</b> can be integrated at: the power mode control module <b>32</b>; a memory module of integrated circuit <b>30</b>, such as NVM <b>53</b>, the like, and combinations thereof. For purposes of discussion, it is presumed that information stored at command memory <b>311</b> resides local to the power mode control module <b>32</b>, and can reside within an I/O region.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">According to an embodiment, commands stored at command memory <b>311</b> include commands used to implement a power control plan that is used to control when IC <b>30</b> transitions between various power modes. For example, in response to the CPU <b>52</b> entering a sufficiently low power state, a power management plan stored at command memory <b>311</b> can be executed at PMC <b>32</b>, wherein PSTR and PMTR commands of the management plan are provided to command interpreter <b>313</b> to effectuate power mode transition requests in accordance with the plan.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates information stored at various register locations <b>370</b> of control register <b>312</b> for access by command interpreter <b>313</b> in response to interpreting and executing various commands. The register locations <b>370</b> include: a storage location <b>371</b> that stores an indicator ENABLE_INT that when asserted enables execution of a power management plan by the command PMC module <b>32</b>; a storage location <b>372</b> that stores an indicator ENABLE_EXT that when asserted enables execution of commands received from external IC <b>30</b>, e.g., commands received via interconnect <b>273</b>; a storage location <b>373</b> that stores an indicator CPM_IC<b>30</b> that indicates a current power mode of IC <b>30</b>; and a storage location <b>374</b> that stores an indicator NPM_COUNT that indicates the length of a delay.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">During execution of a power management plan, timer <b>314</b> can be loaded with the value NMP_COUNT to indicate when a next power mode transition is to be requested. For example, according to an embodiment, the NPM_COUNT is used to set a counter at timer <b>314</b>, which when expired results in timer <b>314</b> providing a PSTR command or a PMTR command to command interpreter <b>313</b>. For example, the routines stored at command memory <b>311</b> can set the value NPM_COUNT based upon a user's power plan requirements. It will be appreciated that the value NPM_COUNT can be fixed or user programmable.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">According to an embodiment, a PSTR received at the command interpreter <b>313</b> includes information indicating a particular logic module to be transitioned to a different power state and whether the particular logic module is to be transitioned to a next higher or next lower next state. According to another embodiment, a PSTR can indicate the particular logic module to be transitioned and an indication of a target power state that the particular logic module is to be transitioned to. Note that in this embodiment, the target power state may or may not be the next higher or lower power state. For purposes of discussion, it is presumed that the PSTR command indicates a particular logic module and whether it should be transitioned to a next higher or lower power state. It will be appreciated that PSTR commands need not be implemented in an embodiment of IC <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In response to receiving a PSTR command to transition a particular logic module between power states, the command interpreter <b>313</b> will access the indicator CPM_IC<b>30</b> from register <b>371</b> to determine the current power mode of IC <b>30</b>, which corresponds to a particular power state of the logic module to be transitioned. The command interpreter <b>313</b> will then provide transition control information to the transition control module <b>315</b> (a state transition request) indicating the desired logic module state transition to be implemented. In response to receiving a state transition request, the transition control module <b>315</b> provides control information, e.g., a set of signal transitions meeting particular timing requirements, over the power control interconnect <b>272</b> to one or more of the logic module <b>50</b> to implement the requested power state transition. In the embodiment being described, the target power state is presumed to be either the next higher or lower power state, thus only information identifying the particular logic module being transition, its current or target power state, and an indicator that indicates whether the logic module is transitioning to a higher or lower power state is needed to be provided to the transition control module <b>315</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In response to the command interpreter <b>313</b> receiving a PMTR command to transition the IC <b>30</b> between power states, the command interpreter <b>313</b> will access the indicator CPM_IC<b>30</b> from register <b>371</b> to determine the current power mode of IC <b>30</b> and will provide information to the transition control module <b>315</b> (a power mode transition request) indicating the desired power mode transition to be implemented. In response, the transition control module <b>315</b> provides control information, e.g., a set of signal transitions meeting particular timing requirements over the power control interconnect <b>272</b> to one or more logic modules <b>50</b> to implement the requested power mode transition. A PMTR can result in one or more multiple logic modules of the logic modules <b>50</b> changing power states. In the embodiment being described, a PMTR can request a target power mode that is either the next higher or lower power mode, thus only information identifying the current or target power mode, and whether the IC <b>30</b> is being transitioned to a next higher or lower power state needs to be provided to the transition control module <b>315</b>. It will be appreciated that in other embodiments additional information may need to be provided; for example, additional information may be needed to transition the IC <b>30</b> to a target power mode that is not a next higher or lower power mode. Transition control module <b>315</b> will be better understood with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates a particular embodiment of the transition control module <b>315</b> that includes a timing/edge control module <b>411</b>, a bus master <b>412</b>, and translation control module <b>413</b>. According to an embodiment, the state of each of each logic module <b>50</b> during a given power mode can be fixed by design or user programmable, e.g., defined by a user. By way of discussion, it is presumed that each one of the power modes PM<b>1</b>-PM<b>7</b> is fixed by design. As such, the translation control logic <b>413</b> stores information identifying the signal transitions, and their relationships to each other, that need to be provided via the power interconnect <b>272</b> to the logic modules <b>50</b> to implement a desired power mode transition between power modes. This information can be stored in tabular form that can be fixed or user programmable. Upon interpreting control information from interpreter <b>313</b>, translation control logic <b>413</b> provides signal and timing information to the timing/edge control logic <b>411</b> that indicates the various signal state and timing information to be communicated to one or more logic modules of the logic core via interconnect <b>271</b> to effectuate the desired power mode transition. Based upon the information received from translation control logic <b>413</b>, the timing/edge control logic <b>411</b> determines when to provide access requests to the bus master module <b>412</b> to assure appropriate time intervals between individual signal transitions used to transition the logic module <b>50</b> between logic state. In one embodiment, the PMC <b>32</b> operates based upon a clock having a very low clock rate, such as 32 kHz. However, in order to transition between power modes more quickly, and to accommodate timing constraints between transitioning signals that can be imposed by the logic modules, the very low frequency can be multiplied, e.g., by a PLL of edge control module <b>411</b>, to generate a sufficiently fast clock.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The translation logic module <b>315</b> can be a state machine or instruction based processor that implements specific timing and control information that is used to effectuate a requested power state transition of the logic module or a requested power mode transition of the IC <b>30</b>, without the need to first transition the CPU <b>52</b> to a higher power mode, e.g., without transitioning CPU <b>52</b> from a non-operational power mode to an operational power mode. A defined power mode transition can affect states of one or more logic modules as will be described in greater detail with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a timing diagram that includes a clock signal labeled CK_LPM that is received at PMC <b>32</b>, various signals transmitted from PMC <b>32</b> via low power interconnect <b>272</b>, including: PI_PR; PI_CPU; PI_NVM; VI_VMI; PI_P<b>1</b>; and signal information at system bys <b>271</b>, labeled SI_<b>271</b>. The transitions of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> are referred to in the plural, e.g., transitions <b>501</b>, transitions <b>502</b>, etc., because each transition illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> can represent one or more signals transitioning at one or more individual interconnects, and at one or more times.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">CK_LPM represents the very low-frequency clock that is provided to PMC <b>32</b>, which has a very low clock rate relative a system clock of the IC <b>30</b>. The clock CK_LPM can be multiplied to a higher frequency (not shown) in order to facilitate the various other transitions illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, or to implement requested power mode transitions faster.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Signal PI_VR represents one or more individual control signals provided from the power mode control module <b>32</b>, via the interconnect PI_VR, that are used to set one or more of the signals, e.g., voltages, that are provided from the voltage regulator <b>51</b> to various logic modules <b>52</b>-<b>57</b>. Signal PI_CPU represents one or more individual control signals provided from the PMC module <b>32</b>, via the interconnect PI_CPU, that are used to transition the CPU <b>52</b> between power states. Signal PI_NVM represents one or more individual control signals provided from the power mode control module <b>32</b>, via the interconnect PI_NVM, that are used to transition the NVM <b>53</b> between power states. Signal PI_VM<b>1</b> represents one or more individual control signals provided from the PMC module <b>32</b>, via the interconnect PI_VM<b>1</b>, that are used to transition the virtual memory module <b>54</b> between power states. Signal PI_P<b>56</b> represents one or more individual control signals provided from the PMC module <b>32</b>, via interconnect PI_P<b>56</b>, that are used to transition the peripheral module <b>56</b> between power states. Signal SI_<b>271</b> represents one or more individual signals provided from PMC <b>32</b>, via system interconnect <b>271</b>, that are used to communicate information between logic modules. It will be appreciated that the transitions illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> can occur over a period of time as needed to implement a specific operation as described.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Immediately prior to time T<b>0</b> of the timing diagram of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the IC <b>30</b> is in a sufficiently high power mode, presumed to be PM<b>6</b>, whereby the CPU <b>52</b> is at its highest power state (PS<b>3</b>), and, therefore, is operational and responsible for implementing a power control plan by communicating with other logic modules to manage power modes of the IC <b>30</b>. At time T<b>0</b> execution of a transition request, which can be a PSTR or a PMTR, is begun at CPU <b>52</b> that transitions the CPU <b>52</b> from the power state PS<b>3</b> to a next lower power state PS<b>2</b>. Transitions <b>501</b> represent an enable command received at command interpreter <b>313</b> that indicates the PMC <b>32</b> is to execute its own power management plan. Note that while the transitions <b>501</b> are illustrated at interconnect PI_CPU of interconnect <b>271</b>, in other embodiments, the enable command can be provided via an alternate interconnect, such as via an interrupt signal provided directly from CPU <b>52</b> to PMC <b>32</b> (not shown). In response to transitions <b>501</b>, the command interpreter <b>313</b> will access control register <b>312</b> to assert ENABLE_INT, which enables PMC <b>32</b> to execute a power management plan, and the CPU <b>52</b> places itself into a next lower power state (PS<b>2</b>) from which it can no longer communicate over system bus <b>271</b>. The inability of CPU <b>52</b> to communicate via bus <b>271</b> is indicated by signal SB_<b>271</b> transitioning to a high-impedance state (Z).</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In response to being enabled by transitions <b>501</b>, a power mode management plan is implemented by the PMC <b>32</b>. For example, asserting the indicator ENABLE_INT can result in a routine stored at command memory <b>311</b> being executed by the command interpreter <b>313</b>. As part of the power management plan, for example, the accessed commands can load the timer <b>314</b> with the value NPM_COUNT to indicate how long until a next power mode transition is to occur. When the timer expires, the timer <b>314</b> will send a PMTR request to interpreter <b>313</b>, all without intervention by the CPU <b>52</b>. Note that the transition to be requested by the timer <b>314</b> can be fixed, e.g., always request a next lower power mode, or user programmable.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Immediately prior to time T<b>1</b>, the IC <b>30</b> is in a power mode PM<b>5</b>, which is between the highest power mode (PM<b>7</b>) and the lowest power mode (PM<b>1</b>). By way of example, it is presumed that each of the logic modules having signals illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is at their middle power state (PS<b>2</b>) during power mode PM<b>5</b>. Note that in the power mode PM<b>5</b> that the CPU <b>52</b> is at a sufficiently low power mode that prevents it from transitioning itself or other logic modules between power states.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">At time T<b>1</b>, the command interpreter <b>313</b> has received a PMTR request to transition the IC <b>30</b> to a next lower power mode, e.g., from PM<b>5</b> to power mode PM<b>4</b>. For example, the requested transition to power mode PM<b>4</b> can be provided to the command interpreter <b>313</b> from the timer <b>314</b>, in response to a specified amount of time having elapsed at timer <b>314</b>. In response, the command interpreter <b>313</b> determines the current power state of IC <b>30</b> by accessing storage location CPM_IC<b>30</b> of control register <b>312</b>. Based upon this information, the command interpreter <b>313</b> determines a desired power mode transition, and provides control information, e.g., transition request information, to the transition control module <b>315</b> indicating the desired power mode transition.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Upon interpreting transition request information from interpreter <b>313</b>, translation control logic <b>413</b> provides signal and timing information to the timing/edge control logic <b>411</b> that indicates the various signal state and timing information to be communicated to one or more logic modules of the logic core via interconnect <b>271</b> to effectuate the desired power mode transition from PM<b>5</b> to PM<b>4</b>. Based upon the information received from translation control logic <b>413</b>, the timing/edge control logic <b>411</b> determines when to provide access requests to the bus master module <b>412</b> to assure appropriate time intervals between individual signal transitions used to transition the logic module <b>50</b> between logic state. Transitions <b>511</b> through <b>515</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> represent signal transitions that transition the IC <b>30</b> from power mode PM<b>5</b> to power mode PM<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">By way of example, power mode PM<b>5</b> varies from the power mode PM<b>4</b> in the following manner: CPU <b>52</b> is in power state PS<b>1</b> instead of power state PS<b>2</b>; voltage regulator <b>51</b> provides a voltage V_CPU<b>1</b> to CPU <b>52</b> instead of voltage V_CPU<b>2</b>; and peripheral <b>56</b> is in power mode PM<b>1</b> instead of PM<b>2</b>. Therefore, as described in greater detail below, the transitions <b>511</b>-<b>515</b> represent the signal changes needed to transition IC <b>30</b> from power mode PM<b>1</b> to power mode PM<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Signal PI_CPU includes signal transitions <b>511</b>, <b>513</b>, and <b>515</b> that are used to transition CPU <b>52</b> from power state PS<b>2</b> to power state PS<b>1</b>. Signal PI_P<b>61</b> includes signal transitions <b>512</b> that are used to transition the peripheral <b>56</b> from power state PS<b>2</b> to power mode PS<b>1</b>. Signal PI_VR includes signal transitions <b>514</b> that are used to transition the voltage provided to the CPU <b>52</b> from voltage V_CPU<b>2</b> to a lower voltage V_CPU<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">According to a particular embodiment, system requirements of IC <b>30</b> can be such that certain transitions need to occur in a certain sequence relative to other transitions. For example, the voltage provided to the CPU <b>52</b> may need to remain at voltage CPU<b>2</b> until after certain initial state changes at CPU <b>52</b> that are implemented by transitions <b>511</b>,<b>513</b>, but prior to certain other state changes at CPU <b>52</b> implemented by transitions <b>515</b>. Thus, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the signal transitions <b>514</b>, which change the voltage provided CPU <b>52</b> from CPU<b>2</b> to CPU<b>1</b>, occurring after transitions <b>513</b> and prior to transitions <b>515</b>. Signal transitions <b>512</b>, which place the peripheral <b>56</b> in a lowest power state (P<b>51</b>), are shown to occur between transition <b>511</b> and <b>513</b>. As a result of transitions <b>511</b>-<b>515</b> the IC is transitioned from power mode PM<b>5</b> to PM<b>4</b> without having to transition CPU <b>52</b> to a higher power mode.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Prior to time T<b>2</b>, the IC <b>30</b> is in a lowest power mode (PM<b>1</b>), and at time T<b>2</b> the command interpreter <b>313</b> has received a PMTR request to transition the IC <b>30</b> to a next higher power mode, e.g., from PM<b>1</b> to power mode PM<b>2</b>. In response, the command interpreter <b>313</b> determines the current power state by accessing storage location CPM_IC<b>30</b> of control register <b>312</b>, and provides control information to the transition control module <b>315</b> indicating the desired transition from PM<b>1</b> to PM<b>2</b>. Signal transitions <b>516</b> through <b>518</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> represent information being transmitted to various logic modules of the logic core <b>41</b> to transition the IC <b>30</b> from power mode PM<b>1</b> to PM<b>2</b>. By way of example, power mode PM<b>2</b> varies from the power mode PM<b>1</b> in the following manner: CPU <b>52</b> is in power state PS<b>2</b> instead of power state PS<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">PMC <b>32</b> provides signal transitions <b>517</b> and <b>518</b> to CPU <b>52</b> via interconnect PI_CPU to transition IC <b>30</b> from power state PS<b>1</b> to power state PS<b>2</b>. PMC <b>32</b> also provides signal transitions <b>516</b> that are used to transition the voltage provided to the CPU <b>52</b> from voltage V_CPU<b>1</b> to voltage regulator <b>51</b> via interconnect PI_VR to provide a higher voltage (V_CPU<b>2</b>) to the CPU <b>52</b>. According to a particular embodiment, system requirements of IC <b>30</b> can be such that transitions <b>516</b>-<b>518</b> need to occur in a particular sequence. For example, the voltage V_CPU<b>2</b> may need to be provided to the CPU <b>52</b> prior to certain state changes at CPU <b>52</b> implemented by transitions <b>518</b>. Thus, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the signal transitions <b>516</b>, which change the voltage provided to CPU <b>52</b>, occurring prior to transitions <b>518</b>. Note that the transitions <b>516</b> may or may not have particular timing requirements with respect to the transitions <b>217</b>, and are illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> as being contemporaneous with the transitions <b>217</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> represents a state diagram associated with IC <b>30</b>. The state diagram includes a state node <b>611</b> that represents a state of the IC <b>30</b> during which power mode management is controlled by the CPU <b>52</b>, and a state node <b>612</b> during which power mode management is controlled by PMC <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Upon reset, such as during startup, the IC <b>30</b> transitions via state transition <b>601</b> to state node <b>611</b> by virtue of the IC <b>30</b> being placed in a power mode that includes CPU <b>52</b> having an operational power state. At state node <b>611</b>, the CPU is responsible for executing a desired power mode transition plan. Thus, so long as the power mode of integrated circuit <b>30</b> remains sufficiently high, and in particular, so long as the power state of CPU <b>52</b> remains sufficiently high to execute the power mode transition plan, the IC <b>30</b> will remain in state node <b>611</b> as indicated by state transition <b>602</b>, and will implement a management power plan. However, the IC <b>30</b> will transition to state node <b>612</b>, as indicated by state transition <b>603</b>, in response to the CPU <b>52</b> transitioning to a power mode that is not sufficiently high to allow execution of the power mode management plan by CPU <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">While operating at state node <b>612</b>, the PMC <b>32</b> is responsible for implementing a power mode management plan in a manner that is autonomous from the CPU <b>52</b>. The power management plan executed by PMC <b>32</b> may be the same or different as the power management plan implemented by CPU <b>52</b> at state node <b>611</b>. According to an embodiment, one of a plurality of specific management plans can be identified for execution by the PMC <b>32</b> prior to CPU <b>52</b> completing its transition to a non-operative state. For example, a particular memory location can be identified by the CPU <b>52</b> that indicates to the PMC <b>32</b> where a power management plan to be implemented resides.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The PMC <b>32</b> continues to implement its power mode management plan as indicated by the state transition <b>605</b> so long as power mode transitions are not sufficiently high to place the CPU <b>52</b> in an operational power state. Otherwise, in response to the PMC <b>32</b> transitioning the IC <b>30</b> to a power mode that places the CPU <b>52</b> in an operational power state, the IC <b>30</b> will return to state node <b>611</b>, via state transition <b>604</b>, and the power mode management plan is implemented by CPU <b>52</b>, and the value ENABLE_INT <b>371</b> is disabled to stop execution of the power management plan by PMC <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">According to embodiment, the PMC <b>32</b> can interpret and execute commands received from external locations when the power management plan is being executed at PMC <b>32</b> or when the power management plan being executed at CPU <b>52</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, in response to receiving an external command while operating in state <b>611</b>, the IC <b>30</b> transitions via state transition <b>621</b> to state node <b>631</b>, wherein the external command is executed by the PMC <b>32</b>. The IC <b>30</b> returns to state node <b>611</b> the estate transition <b>622</b>, after executing the command, and the power mode management plan implemented by CPU <b>52</b> continues. Note it will be appreciated, that transitioning to node <b>631</b> to execute an external command does not necessarily require the power mode management plan being executed at CPU <b>52</b> to be halted. Similarly, in response to receiving an external command while IC <b>30</b> is operating at state <b>612</b>, PMC <b>32</b> transitions via state transition <b>623</b> to state node <b>632</b>, wherein the external command is executed by the PMC <b>32</b>. Upon completion, operation of IC <b>30</b> returns to state node <b>612</b>, wherein the power mode management plan being executed by PMC <b>32</b> continues.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">According to an embodiment, the analog peripheral <b>57</b> monitors an external voltage, such as V_CORE as illustrated at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, to determine whether to send an interrupt (P<b>57</b>_INT) to the PMC <b>32</b> based upon the detected voltage. For example, in response to being in a lowest power mode of operation, the voltage V_CORE can be at a reduced voltage that does not support full power operation of IC <b>30</b>, wherein upon detecting that V_CORE has returned to a power level that support a higher power mode of operation, the analog peripheral <b>57</b> will assert an interrupt, e.g., signal P<b>57</b>_INT, which is interpreted as a PMTR command by PMC <b>32</b> to transition the IC <b>30</b> to a higher power mode, such as full power mode.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> graphically illustrates each of the power modes PM<b>1</b>-PM<b>7</b> of the IC <b>30</b> and a demarcation line <b>630</b>. The power modes PM<b>6</b> and PM<b>7</b> are above the demarcation line <b>630</b> and the power modes PM<b>1</b>-PM<b>5</b> are below the demarcation line <b>630</b>. The power modes above the demarcation line <b>630</b> are power modes of the IC <b>30</b> during which the CPU <b>52</b> is in a sufficiently high power state to execute a power management plan, e.g., CPU <b>52</b> is operational, while the power modes below the demarcation line <b>630</b> are power modes of the IC <b>30</b> during which the CPU <b>52</b> is not in a sufficiently high power state to execute a power management plan. Therefore, the PMC <b>32</b> is responsible for executing the power management plan at IC <b>30</b> during power modes PM<b>1</b>-PM<b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">Arrows <b>631</b>-<b>635</b>, <b>641</b>-<b>644</b>, and <b>651</b>-<b>655</b> at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> represent power mode transitions that can be implemented by the management plan of the PMC <b>32</b> according to an embodiment. In particular, the management plan of the PMC <b>32</b> is capable of transitioning the IC <b>30</b> from a current power mode to full power mode PM<b>7</b> from any power mode, as indicated by arrows <b>651</b>-<b>654</b>, or from a current power mode to an immediately adjacent target power mode, as indicated by arrows <b>631</b>-<b>634</b> and arrows <b>641</b>-<b>643</b>, so long as the CPU <b>52</b> is not operational in the current power mode. According to an embodiment, the only transitions that can be implemented by PMC <b>32</b> include transitions to immediately adjacent power modes. According to another embodiment, the only transitions that can be implemented by PMC <b>32</b> include transitions to immediately adjacent power modes and transitions to a highest power mode. According to an embodiment, the only transitions that can be implemented by PMC <b>32</b> include transitions to immediately adjacent power modes, and state transitions for individual modules. It will be appreciated that in another embodiment, the PMC <b>32</b> can be capable of implementing additional transitions between power modes that are not immediately adjacent. For example, the PMC <b>32</b> can be capable of transitioning from any one of PM<b>2</b>-PM<b>5</b> to a lowest power mode (PM<b>1</b>). According to an embodiment, all power mode transitions that can be implemented by PMC <b>32</b> are implemented by the command interpreter <b>313</b> implementing a sequence of separate state transitions for one or more logic modules.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">It will be appreciated, that in an embodiment, that the power mode control module <b>32</b> can process requests to transition the IC <b>30</b> even when the CPU <b>52</b> is in an operational mode. For example, PMC <b>32</b> can execute transition request specifically requested by an external resource via interconnect <b>273</b>, so long as the value at register ENABLE_EXT is asserted. Alternatively, in response to the value ENABLE_EXT being negated, the PMC <b>32</b> is not be enabled to process external requests to transition the IC <b>30</b> when the CPU <b>52</b> is in a nonoperational mode, instead such requests would need to be made directly to the CPU <b>52</b>. In yet another embodiment, the low-power control module can transfer any received external requests to transition the IC <b>30</b> to the CPU <b>52</b> when the CPU <b>52</b> is operational in response to ENABLE_EXT being asserted.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">According to an embodiment, to reduce static power (leakage power) transistors used to implement logic at PMC <b>32</b> have a thicker gate oxide then transistors used to implement logic at the logic modules <b>50</b>. For example, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, a transistor <b>901</b> represents a transistor at PMC <b>32</b>, and includes a gate electrode <b>911</b> and a gate dielectric <b>912</b>; and a transistor <b>902</b> represents a transistor at CPU <b>52</b>, and includes a gate electrode <b>921</b> and a gate dielectric <b>922</b>. The gate dielectric <b>912</b> is thicker than gate dielectric <b>922</b>. For example, the gate dielectric <b>912</b> can have a thickness that is 2 to 15 times greater than that of gate dielectric <b>922</b>, such as approximately three times greater. According to an embodiment, gate dielectric <b>912</b> has a thickness of greater than 30 nm, such as in a range of 30-200 nm, while the gate dielectric <b>922</b> has a thickness of less than 20, such as in a rage of 15 to 20 nm. In addition, the gate width of transistor <b>901</b> can be larger than the gate width of transistor <b>902</b>. For example, the gate width of transistor <b>902</b> can be 2 to 5 times longer, such as approximately three times longer.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">In a first aspect, a device can include a logic core of an integrated circuit (IC) die comprising a plurality of logic modules including a first logic module, the first logic module to operate in one of a plurality of indicated power states including a first power state and a second power state. The device can also include a periphery region of the IC die defined by a plurality of I/O pads abutting an edge of the IC die, wherein the plurality of I/O pads of the IC die are to provide a signal interface between the plurality of logic modules and external the IC die, and a power control module, residing within the periphery region, to control transition the first logic module between the plurality of power states, including from the first power state to the second power state.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In one embodiment of the first aspect, the device is to enable the power control module to implement a power control plan that manages power states of the first and second logic modules in response to the first logic module transitioning to a power state that is not sufficiently high. In another embodiment, the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions. In a particular embodiment, the plurality of logic modules further includes a second logic module to operate in one of a plurality of indicated power states including a first power state and a second power state and the first logic module, when in a sufficiently high power state, is to control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state, otherwise, when the first logic module is not in the sufficiently high power state, the first logic module cannot control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state. In another particular embodiment, the power control module is to control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state, autonomous of the first logic module, when the first logic module is not in the sufficiently high power state.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In a further embodiment of the first aspect, the power control module cannot control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state when the first logic module is in the sufficiently high power state. In another embodiment, the power control module can control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state when the first logic module is in the sufficiently high power state. In an even further embodiment, the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions only when in a sufficiently high power state of the plurality power states, and neither the first power state nor the second power state of the data processor core are sufficiently high power states. In still another embodiment, the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions only when in a sufficiently high power state of the plurality power states, the first logic module's first power state is not a sufficiently high power state, and the first logic module's second power state is a sufficiently high power state.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">In another embodiment of the first aspect, the first logic module is execute a first power management plan for the IC die in response to the first power state being a sufficiently high power state, otherwise, in response to the first power state not being a sufficiently high power state, the power control module is to implement a second power management plan for the IC die to transition the plurality of logic modules between their respective power states autonomous of the first logic module. In a further embodiment, the second power management plan is user programmable. In particular embodiment, the power mode control module includes a storage region to store the second power management plan, the storage regions within the periphery regions. In an even more particular embodiment, the power mode control module is further to execute a command received from external the IC die via at least one I/O pad of the plurality of I/O pads.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">In a further embodiment of the first aspect, the logic core further includes a second logic module, and the power control module is further to transition the first logic module between first logic module's power states in response to receiving an interrupt indicator from the second logic module. In another embodiment, the power control module is further to transition the first logic module in response to receiving an interrupt indicator from an I/O port of the plurality of I/O pads. In still another embodiment, a system interconnect coupled to the plurality of logic modules to communicate information between the plurality of logic modules, and a power control interconnect coupled to the plurality of logic modules and to the power mode control module, the power control interconnect module to communicate information from the power mode control module to the plurality of logic modules to transition the IC die between a plurality of power modes.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In a particular embodiment of the first aspect, transistors of the logic module have a thinner gate dielectric than transistors of the power control module. In an even more particular embodiment, a logic core power bus, that is to provide power to the first logic module, to receive a first logic supply voltage from external the IC die, and an I/O power bus, that is to provide power to the plurality of I/O pads and to the power control module, to receive an I/O supply voltage from external the IC die. In a further embodiment, a voltage regulator at the integrated circuit die to receive a first supply signal from external the integrated circuit die and to generate one or more regulated supply signals to be provided to the plurality of logic modules via a logic core power bus, including a first regulated supply signal to be provided to the first logic module, and an I/O power bus to receive a second supply signal from external the IC die and to provide the second supply signal to the plurality of I/O pads and to the power control module.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In a second aspect, a method can include executing a first power management plan at a power mode control module that is substantially disposed at an I/O region of an integrated circuit die, and in response to executing the first power management plan, providing information from the power mode control module to transition a first set of one or more logic modules disposed within a logic core of the IC die between respective logic states to implement a first indicated power mode of the IC die.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In one embodiment of the second aspect, the I/O region includes a periphery region that is within a first distance of an edge of the I/C die, the first distance equal to a height of an I/O pad that borders the first edge. In another embodiment, executing the first power management plan includes the power mode control module executing a plurality of instructions stored within the I/O region. In still another embodiment, executing the first power management plan includes the power mode control module executing a plurality of instructions stored within the logic core.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In another embodiment of the second aspect, prior to executing the first power management plan, executing a second power management plan at a first logic module of the one or more logic modules, in response to executing the second power management plan, providing information from the first logic module to transition the first set of one or more logic modules between respective power states, to implement a second indicated power mode of the IC die, and wherein executing the first power management plan is in response to execution of the second power management plan enabling the power mode control module to execute the first power management plan.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In a third aspect, a method can include providing a voltage to a plurality of input/output (IO) pads at an I/O region of an integrated circuit die, and to a power mode control module at the I/O region, providing a logic core power supply signal to a plurality of logic modules of a logic region of the integrated circuit die to provide power to the plurality of logic modules, and receiving a command at the power mode control module, and in response to receiving the command, providing control information from the power mode control module to the first logic module to transition the first logic module to a different power mode.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Note that not all of the activities or elements described above in the general description are required, that a portion of a specific activity or device may not be required, and that one or more further activities may be performed, or elements included, in addition to those described. Still further, the order in which activities are listed is not necessarily the order in which they are performed.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Also, the concepts have been described with reference to specific embodiments. However, one of ordinary skill in the art appreciates that various modifications and changes can be made without departing from the scope of the present disclosure as set forth in the claims below. Accordingly, the specification and figures are to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense, and all such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">For example, according to an embodiment where it is desirable to reduce the size of the PMC <b>32</b>, only a defined set of PMTR transitions are supported. Therefore, in an embodiment the PMC <b>32</b> need not support PSTR commands. In other embodiments, such as embodiments where it would be desirable for a resource external the IC <b>30</b> to have a greater level of power mode control, the PMC <b>32</b> can support PSTR commands enabling greater flexibility to the external resource. Thus it will be appreciated that the power management plan implemented by PMC <b>32</b> can transition the IC <b>30</b> between the same or different set of power modes and states as can the CPU. Alternatively, the PMC <b>32</b> can transition the IC <b>30</b> between a subset of the power modes supported by the CPU. Also, while the PMC <b>32</b> has been described as maintaining transition information relating to power modes at the translation control logic <b>413</b>, in another embodiment, the translation control logic <b>413</b> can include only information related to timing needed to execute PSTRs, which transition individual logic modules between their power states, and the command interpreter <b>313</b> is responsible for effectively executing multiple PSTR commands sequentially to effectuate a PMTR request logic mode changes of IC <b>30</b>. In another example, the PMC <b>32</b> need not be connected to the system interconnect <b>271</b>. For example, instead of command interpreter <b>313</b> communicating information via the system interconnect <b>271</b>, the command interpreter <b>313</b> can communicate through the low-power interconnect <b>272</b>, by writing information to the control register <b>312</b>, which can be accessed via the system interconnect <b>271</b>, and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Benefits, other advantages, and solutions to problems have been described above with regard to specific embodiments. However, the benefits, advantages, solutions to problems, and any feature(s) that may cause any benefit, advantage, or solution to occur or become more pronounced are not to be construed as a critical, required, or essential feature of any or all the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device comprising:
<claim-text>a logic core of an integrated circuit (IC) die comprising a plurality of logic modules including a first logic module, the first logic module to operate in one of a plurality of indicated power states including a first power state and a second power state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a periphery region of the IC die defined by a plurality of I/O pads abutting an edge of the IC die, wherein the plurality of I/O pads of the IC die are to provide a signal interface between the plurality of logic modules and external the IC die; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power control module, residing within the periphery region, to control transition the first logic module between the plurality of power states, including from the first power state to the second power state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the device is to enable the power control module to implement a power control plan that manages power states of the first and second logic modules in response to the first logic module transitioning to a power state that is not sufficiently high.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of logic modules further comprises a second logic module to operate in one of a plurality of indicated power states including a first power state and a second power state; and
<claim-text>the first logic module, when in a sufficiently high power state, is to control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state, otherwise, when the first logic module is not in the sufficiently high power state, the first logic module cannot control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the power control module is to control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state, autonomous of the first logic module, when the first logic module is not in the sufficiently high power state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the power control module cannot control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state when the first logic module is in the sufficiently high power state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the power control module can control transitioning the second logic module from the second logic module's first power state to its second power state when the first logic module is in the sufficiently high power state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions only when in a sufficiently high power state of the plurality power states, and neither the first power state nor the second power state of the data processor core are sufficiently high power states.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first logic module is a data processor core that is to execute instructions only when in a sufficiently high power state of the plurality power states, the first logic module's first power state is not a sufficiently high power state, and the first logic module's second power state is a sufficiently high power state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first logic module is execute a first power management plan for the IC die in response to the first power state being a sufficiently high power state, otherwise, in response to the first power state not being a sufficiently high power state, the power control module is to implement a second power management plan for the IC die to transition the plurality of logic modules between their respective power states autonomous of the first logic module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the second power management plan is user programmable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the power mode control module includes a storage region to store the second power management plan, the storage regions within the periphery regions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the logic core further comprises a second logic module, and the power control module is further to transition the first logic module between first logic module's power states in response to receiving an interrupt indicator from the second logic module.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the power control module is further to transition the first logic module in response to receiving an interrupt indicator from an I/O port of the plurality of I/O pads.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a system interconnect coupled to the plurality of logic modules to communicate information between the plurality of logic modules; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power control interconnect coupled to the plurality of logic modules and to the power mode control module, the power control interconnect module to communicate information from the power mode control module to the plurality of logic modules to transition the IC die between a plurality of power modes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>a logic core power bus, that is to provide power to the first logic module, to receive a first logic supply voltage from external the IC die; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an I/O power bus, that is to provide power to the plurality of I/O pads and to the power control module, to receive an I/O supply voltage from external the IC die.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method comprising:
<claim-text>executing a first power management plan at a power mode control module that is substantially disposed at an I/O region of an integrated circuit die; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to executing the first power management plan, providing information from the power mode control module to transition a first set of one or more logic modules disposed within a logic core of the IC die between respective logic states to implement a first indicated power mode of the IC die.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the I/O region includes a periphery region that is within a first distance of an edge of the I/C die, the first distance equal to a height of an I/O pad that borders the first edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein executing the first power management plan includes the power mode control module executing a plurality of instructions stored within the I/O region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising
<claim-text>prior to executing the first power management plan, executing a second power management plan at a first logic module of the one or more logic modules;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in response to executing the second power management plan, providing information from the first logic module to transition the first set of one or more logic modules between respective power states, to implement a second indicated power mode of the IC die; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein executing the first power management plan is in response to execution of the second power management plan enabling the power mode control module to execute the first power management plan.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a voltage to a plurality of input/output (IO) pads at an I/O region of an integrated circuit die, and to a power mode control module at the I/O region;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a logic core power supply signal to a plurality of logic modules of a logic region of the integrated circuit die to provide power to the plurality of logic modules; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a command at the power mode control module, and in response to receiving the command, providing control information from the power mode control module to the first logic module to transition the first logic module to a different power mode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
