<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08626898-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08626898</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12640665</doc-number>
<date>20091217</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>674</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>16</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709224</main-classification>
<further-classification>709206</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">System and method for application alert tracking in an Internet protocol television system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6345288</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Reed et al.</name>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6957199</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Fisher</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7254645</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nishi</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7437446</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bailey et al.</name>
<date>20081000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0004830</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lora et al.</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>707102</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0106768</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Frietsch et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>709223</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0155564</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shcherbina et al.</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>719318</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0158096</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ali et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>714 43</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0161530</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yang et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370216</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0045841</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kuhlke et al.</name>
<date>20110200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4554561</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0141921</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Reese et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>370252</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>709224</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110153749</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110623</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Howcroft</last-name>
<first-name>Jerald R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beverly Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Howcroft</last-name>
<first-name>Jerald R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beverly Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Guntin &#x26; Gust, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schnabel</last-name>
<first-name>Douglas</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>AT&#x26;T Intellectual Property I, LP</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hussain</last-name>
<first-name>Tauqir</first-name>
<department>2452</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Golabbakhsh</last-name>
<first-name>Ebrahim</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A maintenance system for an IPTV network includes a logging module, a ticketing module, and an operations module. The logging module receives a fault alert from a service provider and sends the alert to the ticketing module. The ticketing module determines the urgency of the fault, generates a ticket, assigns priority to the ticket based upon the urgency, and sends the ticket to the operations module. The operations module allocates the ticket and sends a message to a mobile device regarding the ticket. A method includes receiving a fault alert from a service provider, sending the alert to a ticketing module, determining the urgency of the event, generating a ticket, assigning priority to the ticket based upon the urgency, sending the ticket to an operations module, allocating the ticket, and sending a message to a mobile device the ticket.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="238.00mm" wi="193.38mm" file="US08626898-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.00mm" wi="215.22mm" file="US08626898-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="204.55mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US08626898-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="239.78mm" wi="159.17mm" file="US08626898-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="233.85mm" wi="164.51mm" file="US08626898-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure generally relates to an Internet protocol television system, and more particularly relates to application alert tracking in an Internet protocol television system.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">An Internet protocol television (IPTV) service provider can transmit an IPTV signal to a user of the IPTV system via a central office, a serving area interface, and a residential gateway. The IPTV service provider can offer the user a variety of different content and services. For example, the IPTV service provider can supply users with real-time television programs that are typically available for the users to watch only at a specific date and time, or on-demand movies that are available for an extended amount of time and that are provided to the users upon request of the on-demand movie. The IPTV service provider can also supply users with service applications that enhance the users' enjoyment of the IPTV service. Third parties can source content and services to the IPTV service provider.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It will be appreciated that for simplicity and clarity of illustration, elements illustrated in the Figures have not necessarily been drawn to scale. For example, the dimensions of some of the elements are exaggerated relative to other elements. Embodiments incorporating teachings of the present disclosure are shown and described with respect to the drawings presented herein, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating an embodiment of an IPTV system;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an illustration of a system for processing third party content and service provisioning for the IPTV system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an illustration of a maintenance network in the IPTV system of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flowchart illustrating a method for alert tracking in an IPTV system; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram showing an illustrative embodiment of a general computer system.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The use of the same reference symbols in different drawings indicates similar or identical items.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The numerous innovative teachings of the present application will be described with particular reference to the presently preferred exemplary embodiments. However, it should be understood that this class of embodiments provides only a few examples of the many advantageous uses of the innovative teachings herein. In general, statements made in the specification of the present application do not necessarily limit any of the various claimed inventions. Moreover, some statements may apply to some inventive features but not to others.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an embodiment of an IPTV system <b>100</b> including a client facing (CF) tier <b>102</b>, an application tier <b>104</b>, an acquisition tier <b>106</b>, an operations and management (OM) tier <b>108</b>, and one or more sets of client equipment <b>110</b>. Client equipment <b>110</b> is typically located at the home or business premises of a subscriber to the IPTV system <b>100</b>. IPTV system <b>100</b> includes an access network <b>192</b>, a private network <b>194</b>, and a public network <b>196</b>. Each tier <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, and <b>108</b> is coupled to one or more of access network <b>192</b>, private network <b>194</b>, and public network <b>196</b>. In an embodiment, CF tier <b>102</b> is coupled to access network <b>192</b> and to private network <b>194</b>, application tier <b>104</b> is coupled to private network <b>194</b> and to public network <b>196</b>, acquisition tier <b>106</b> is coupled to private network <b>194</b> and to public network <b>196</b>, and OM tier <b>108</b> is coupled to public network <b>196</b>. Client equipment <b>110</b> is coupled to access network <b>192</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Networks <b>192</b>, <b>194</b> and <b>196</b> communicate information between tiers <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, and <b>108</b>, and client equipment <b>110</b>. Access network <b>192</b> communicates information between CF tier <b>102</b> and client equipment <b>110</b>. Private network <b>194</b> communicates information between CF tier <b>102</b> and application tier <b>104</b>, between application tier <b>104</b> and acquisition tier <b>106</b>, and between acquisition tier <b>106</b> and CF tier <b>102</b>. Public network <b>196</b> communicates information between application tier <b>104</b> and acquisition tier <b>106</b>, between acquisition tier <b>106</b> and OM tier <b>108</b>, and between OM tier <b>108</b> and application tier <b>104</b>. Information is also communicated directly between CF tier <b>102</b> and application tier <b>104</b>, as described below. The information communicated between tiers <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, <b>106</b>, and <b>108</b>, and client equipment <b>110</b> includes encoded television programs, audio files, data files, commands, procedures, other information, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">CF tier <b>102</b> communicates with multiple sets of client equipment <b>110</b> over a wide geographic area, such as a regional area, a metropolitan area, a viewing area, or any other suitable geographic area that is supported by access network <b>192</b>. Client equipment <b>110</b> includes a modem <b>112</b>, a set-top box <b>114</b>, a display device <b>116</b>, and a remote control <b>118</b>. The set-top box <b>114</b> includes a digital video recorder (DVR) <b>120</b> and a control module <b>125</b>. Modem <b>112</b> is coupled to access network <b>192</b>, and translates information from a form suitable for transmission over access network <b>192</b> to a form suitable for use by set-top box <b>114</b>, and vice versa. In a non-limiting example, modem <b>112</b> is coupled to access network <b>192</b> via fiber-optic cables, a digital subscriber line (DSL), another network fabric, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The information that CF tier <b>102</b> communicates to modem <b>112</b> is sent to set-top box <b>114</b>, which processes the information into a form suitable for display by display device <b>116</b> or for recording by DVR <b>120</b>. Set-top box <b>114</b> receives digitally encoded content from CF tier <b>102</b> for display on display device <b>116</b>, or for recording by DVR <b>120</b>. Set-top box <b>114</b> can also receive data from CF tier <b>102</b>, and render or display the data on display device <b>116</b>. Further, set-top box <b>114</b> can send data to CF tier <b>102</b>. Such data can include service requests, or commands from the subscriber, received by set-top box <b>112</b> via remote control <b>118</b>. For example, control module <b>125</b> can include a remote control interface module (not illustrated) for receiving inputs to set-top box <b>112</b> from remote control <b>118</b>. In this way, the subscriber can request services or information or respond to a request for information from IPTV system <b>100</b>. Control module <b>125</b> includes instructions that are executable by set-top box <b>114</b> to control the data flow between the subscriber and IPTV system <b>100</b>. Control module <b>125</b> can include an IPTV software platform such as Microsoft&#xae; TV IPTV Edition.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Control module <b>125</b> can facilitate data communication between set-top box <b>114</b> and IPTV system <b>100</b>. For example, control module <b>125</b> can include a procedure whereby set-top box <b>114</b> receives a request to record content on DVR <b>120</b>, or sends a status to IPTV system <b>100</b> that the content has been recorded. Likewise, control module <b>125</b> can include a procedure whereby the subscriber can interact with IPTV system <b>100</b> to receive and execute a viewing preference that the subscriber has created in IPTV system <b>100</b>. Such preferences can be created via remote control <b>118</b>, or through a subscriber account that is accessible through public network <b>196</b>, such as through a subscriber's personal computer <b>198</b>. A non-limiting example of remote control <b>118</b> includes a hand-held controller device, a game controller device, a keyboard/mouse device, another control device, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">CF tier <b>102</b> includes a client-facing tier (CFT) switch <b>130</b>, a data server <b>132</b>, a terminal server <b>134</b>, and a video-on-demand (VOD) server <b>136</b>. CFT switch <b>130</b> manages communication with client equipment <b>110</b> through access network <b>192</b> and with application tier <b>104</b> and acquisition tier <b>106</b> through private network <b>194</b>. CFT switch <b>130</b> is coupled to data server <b>132</b> that stores data transmitted in response to subscriber requests. CFT switch <b>130</b> is also coupled to terminal server <b>134</b> that provides terminal devices, such as a game application server, or other devices with a common connection point to private network <b>194</b>. CFT switch <b>130</b> is also coupled to VOD server <b>136</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Application tier <b>104</b> includes application tier (APP) switches <b>140</b> and <b>141</b>, an application server <b>142</b>, an operation systems and support/billing systems and support (OSS/BSS) server <b>144</b>, a subscriber and system store <b>145</b>, a domain controller <b>146</b>, and a client gateway <b>147</b>. APP switches <b>140</b> and <b>141</b> manage communication with CF tier <b>102</b> and acquisition tier <b>106</b> through private network <b>194</b>. APP switch <b>141</b> also manages communication with acquisition tier <b>106</b> and OM tier <b>108</b> through public network <b>196</b>. APP switch <b>140</b> is coupled to APP switch <b>141</b>. APP switch <b>140</b> is also coupled to application server <b>142</b> and to OSS/BSS gateway <b>144</b>. Application server <b>142</b> provides applications to set-top box <b>114</b> through a set-top box application <b>143</b>, so that set-top box <b>114</b> can provide functions such as recording and displaying content, messaging, and processing of IPTV data and VOD material. OSS/BSS gateway <b>144</b> includes operation systems and support (OSS) data, and billing systems and support (BSS) data.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">APP switch <b>141</b> is coupled to domain controller <b>146</b> and to subscriber and system store <b>145</b>. Domain controller <b>146</b> provides web access, for example, to subscribers via public network <b>196</b>. Subscriber and system store <b>145</b> includes account information that is associated with subscribers who access IPTV system <b>100</b> via private network <b>194</b> or public network <b>196</b>. Application tier <b>104</b> also communicates data directly to CF tier <b>102</b> through client gateway <b>147</b>. In this embodiment, client gateway <b>147</b> is coupled directly to CFT switch <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Client gateway <b>147</b> provides subscriber access to private network <b>194</b> and tiers coupled thereto. In particular, set-top box <b>114</b> accesses IPTV system <b>100</b> via access network <b>192</b> using information received from client gateway <b>147</b>. Access network <b>192</b> provides security for private network <b>194</b>. Client equipment <b>110</b> accesses client gateway <b>147</b> via access network <b>192</b>, and client gateway <b>147</b> allows client equipment <b>110</b> to access private network <b>194</b> once client equipment <b>110</b> is authenticated or verified. Similarly, client gateway <b>147</b> prevents unauthorized client equipment (not illustrated), such as hacker computers or stolen set-top box devices, from accessing private network <b>194</b> by denying access to these devices beyond access network <b>192</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">For example, when set-top box device <b>114</b> accesses IPTV system <b>100</b> via access network <b>192</b>, client gateway <b>147</b> verifies subscriber information by communicating with subscriber and system store <b>145</b> via private network <b>194</b>, APP switch <b>140</b>, and APP switch <b>141</b>. Further, client gateway <b>147</b> verifies billing information and status by communicating with OSS/BSS gateway <b>144</b> via private network <b>194</b> and APP switch <b>140</b>. OSS/BSS gateway <b>144</b> transmits a query across APP switch <b>140</b>, to APP switch <b>141</b>, and APP switch <b>141</b> communicates the query across public network <b>196</b> to an OSS/BSS server <b>164</b> (described below). After the client gateway <b>147</b> confirms subscriber and/or billing information, client gateway <b>147</b> allows set-top box device <b>114</b> access to IPTV system <b>100</b> content and VOD server <b>136</b> content. If client gateway <b>147</b> cannot verify subscriber information for set-top box <b>114</b>, such as when set-top box <b>114</b> is connected to a different twisted pair, or when set-top box <b>114</b> is stolen, client gateway <b>147</b> denies transmissions to and from set-top box device <b>114</b> beyond access network <b>192</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Domain controller <b>146</b> communicates with public network <b>196</b> via APP switch <b>141</b>. Domain controller <b>146</b> includes a web portal that allows a subscriber to access IPTV system <b>100</b> using a personal computer <b>198</b>. Domain controller <b>146</b> also communicates with a data network <b>172</b> that is connected to a wireless access point <b>174</b>. Wireless access point <b>174</b> communicates with a subscriber's wireless device <b>176</b> to provide wireless access to IPTV system <b>100</b>. A non-limiting example of a wireless device <b>176</b> includes a cellular telephone, a personal digital assistant, a mobile e-mail device, a portable digital video device, another wireless device, or any combination thereof. Wireless device <b>176</b> includes a display device <b>178</b> for displaying information from IPTV system <b>100</b>. Display device <b>178</b> includes a text display, a picture display, a video display or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Acquisition tier <b>106</b> includes an acquisition tier (AQT) switch <b>150</b>, a live acquisition server <b>152</b>, a broadcast service <b>154</b>, and a video-on-demand importer server <b>156</b>. AQT switch <b>150</b> manages communication with CF tier <b>104</b> and application tier <b>104</b> through private network <b>194</b>, and with application tier <b>104</b> and OM tier <b>108</b> through public network <b>196</b>. AQT switch <b>150</b> is coupled to live acquisition server <b>152</b>, and video-on-demand importer server <b>156</b>. Live acquisition server <b>152</b> acquires television content from broadcast service <b>154</b>. Live acquisition server <b>152</b> sends the television content to AQT switch <b>150</b> for transmission to CF tier <b>102</b> via private network <b>194</b>. The television content is further encoded at data server <b>132</b>, and sent to client equipment <b>110</b> via access network <b>192</b>. Set-top box <b>114</b> receives the television content from modem <b>112</b>, decodes the television content, and transmits the information to display device <b>116</b> according to commands from remote control device <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Additionally, VOD importer server <b>156</b> receives content from one or more video-on-demand sources that are outside IPTV system <b>100</b>, such as movie studios and programmers of non-live content. VOD importer server <b>156</b> transmits the video-on-demand content to AQT switch <b>150</b>, and AQT switch <b>150</b> communicates the material to CFT switch <b>130</b> via private network <b>194</b>. The video-on-demand content is stored on VOD server <b>136</b>. When a subscriber issues a request for VOD content to set-top box <b>114</b> through remote control <b>118</b>, the request is transmitted over access network <b>192</b> to VOD server <b>136</b> via CFT switch <b>130</b>. Upon receiving such a request, VOD server <b>136</b> retrieves the requested VOD content and transmits the content to set-top box or <b>114</b> across access network <b>192</b> via CFT switch <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">OM tier <b>108</b> includes an OM tier (OMT) switch <b>160</b>, a TV2 server <b>162</b>, the OSS/BSS server <b>164</b>, and a simple network management protocol (SNMP) monitor server <b>166</b>. OMT switch <b>160</b> manages the communication between OM tier <b>108</b> and public network <b>196</b>. OMT switch <b>160</b> is coupled to TV2 server <b>162</b>, OSS/BSS server <b>164</b>, and SNMP monitor server <b>166</b> that monitors network devices. TV2 server <b>162</b> receives television content from live acquisition server <b>152</b>, or video-on-demand content from VOD importer server <b>156</b> through public network <b>196</b>. The television and video-on-demand content is sent by TV2 server <b>162</b> to OMT switch <b>160</b> and forwarded to a subscriber of IPTV system <b>100</b> who accesses public network <b>196</b> through personal computer <b>198</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows third party content and service providers <b>200</b> for IPTV system <b>100</b>. Content and service providers <b>200</b> include a content provider <b>210</b>, a live stream provider <b>220</b>, and a hosted application provider <b>230</b>. Content provider <b>210</b> includes an interface system <b>212</b>, a firewall <b>214</b>, and a provider network <b>216</b>. Live stream provider <b>220</b> includes an interface system <b>222</b>, a firewall <b>224</b>, and provider network <b>226</b>. Hosted application provider <b>230</b> includes an interface system <b>232</b>, a firewall <b>234</b>, and provider network <b>236</b>. IPTV system <b>100</b> is illustrated as including application tier <b>104</b>, acquisition tier <b>106</b>, and operations and maintenance tier <b>108</b>. In a particular embodiment, providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b> are connected to one or more of application tier <b>104</b>, acquisition tier <b>106</b>, and operations and maintenance tier <b>108</b> to provide the associated content and receive requests or status and maintenance information. In another embodiment (not illustrated), providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b> are also connected to client-facing tier <b>102</b> or to client equipment <b>110</b> to provide content or other status and maintenance information to IPTV system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Content provider <b>210</b> is connected to IPTV system <b>100</b> through interface system <b>212</b> to provide content to IPTV system <b>100</b>, to receive requests for content, and to exchange status event and alert information with IPTV system <b>100</b>. For example content provider <b>210</b> can be connected via a primary link (not illustrated) to acquisition tier <b>106</b> to provide content to IPTV system <b>100</b>, and content provider <b>210</b> can be connected via a secondary link (not illustrated) to operations and maintenance tier <b>108</b> to receive a request from IPTV system <b>100</b> for the content or to share status event and alert information. In a particular embodiment, the content provided by content provider <b>210</b> is pushed to IPTV system <b>100</b> at a predetermined time interval. For example, content provider <b>210</b> can represent a premium content channel such as Home Box Office, Starz, another premium content channel, or a combination thereof. Here, content provider <b>210</b> can distribute content to IPTV system <b>100</b> in advance of a programmed viewing interval, such as for a day of programming, at some time prior to the programmed day. In another embodiment, IPTV system <b>100</b> makes a request to content provider <b>210</b> for content. Thus, for example, content provider <b>210</b> can represent a source of on-demand content.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Live stream provider <b>220</b> is connected to IPTV system <b>100</b> through interface system <b>222</b> to provide live content streams to IPTV system <b>100</b> and to exchange status event and alert information with IPTV system <b>100</b>. For example live stream provider <b>220</b> can be connected via a primary link (not illustrated) to acquisition tier <b>106</b> to provide streaming content to IPTV system <b>100</b>, and via a secondary link (not illustrated) to operations and maintenance tier <b>108</b> to share status event and alert information. For example, live stream provider <b>220</b> can represent a local network affiliate that can distribute live content to IPTV system <b>100</b> such as live newscasts or sporting events.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Hosted application provider <b>230</b> is connected to IPTV system <b>100</b> through interface system <b>232</b> to provide applications and services to IPTV system <b>100</b>, to receive requests for the applications and services, and to exchange status event and alert information with IPTV system <b>100</b>. For example hosted application provider <b>230</b> can be connected via a primary link (not illustrated) to application tier <b>104</b> to provide applications and services to IPTV system <b>100</b>, and can be connected via a secondary link (not illustrated) to operations and maintenance tier <b>108</b> to receive requests for the applications and services or status event and alert information. In a non-limiting example, hosted application provider <b>230</b> provides Internet based services, music applications, traffic information, other applications and services, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In operation, interface systems <b>212</b>, <b>222</b>, and <b>232</b> provide interfaces between IPTV system <b>100</b> and providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b>, respectively. Interface systems <b>212</b>, <b>222</b>, and <b>232</b> are maintained and managed by the respective providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b>, and include status event and alert hooks that are used by IPTV system <b>100</b>. Providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b> each maintain their respective firewalls <b>214</b>, <b>224</b>, and <b>234</b> in front of provider networks <b>216</b>, <b>226</b>, and <b>236</b>. The status event and alert hooks provide a mechanism whereby problems with provider networks <b>216</b>, <b>226</b>, and <b>236</b> are identified to IPTV system <b>100</b>, or problems with IPTV system <b>100</b> in receiving content from providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, or <b>230</b> are identified to the affected provider <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, or <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Table 1 illustrates an example of status events and alerts that can be provided by interface systems <b>212</b>, <b>222</b>, and <b>232</b>. Various events are listed in the first column. The events may relate to a video content system, as listed in the second column, or to a backend system as listed in the third column. A threshold level can be associated with each event that defines when an alert is sent to IPTV system <b>100</b>, as listed in the fourth column. The threshold can be defined by the presence of a condition, indicated as &#x201c;If YES&#x201d; in the threshold column. For example, the event labeled &#x201c;Server Down (cold/warm boot) can generate an alert if a server in either the video system or the backend system is not operational. The threshold can also be defined by a percent level or an absolute level, indicated as &#x201c;&#x3e;80%&#x201d; or &#x201c;&#x3e;N&#x201d; in the threshold column. For example, the event labeled &#x201c;Server CPU Utilization&#x201d; can generate an alert if a server in either the video system or the backend system exceeds 80% CPU utilization, or the event labeled &#x201c;Server Excess Process&#x201d; can generate an alert if a server in either the video system or the backend system is running more than &#x201c;N&#x201d; processes.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Third Party Events</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="91pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Video </entry>
<entry>Backend </entry>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Event</entry>
<entry>System</entry>
<entry>System</entry>
<entry>Threshold</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server Down (cold/warm boot)</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server CPU Utilization</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>&#x3e;80%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server RAM Utilization</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>&#x3e;80%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server HDD Utilization</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>&#x3e;80%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server High Temperature</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server Fan Failure</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server Software Error (OS,</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Server Excess Process</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>&#x3e;N</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Network Link Down</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Network Node Down</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>DNS Error</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Database Read/Write Error</entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>File System Outage</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Source Media Streaming Error</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Authentication Failure</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Application Custom Event</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>If YES</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b> can also provide alerts for custom events, as indicated in the row labeled &#x201c;Application Custom Event.&#x201d; In a particular embodiment, hosted application provider <b>230</b> can operate an interactive television application where clients of IPTV system <b>100</b> can interact with a set-top box to receive the application's content. For example, a provider can operate a &#x201c;Santa Tracker&#x201d; channel during the Christmas season, a fantasy sports channel during the regular season for the sport, a stock trading channel, another type of interactive application, or a combination thereof. Screens associated with the application can include text, still and video images, music, or other media information. Custom events associated with an application can generate alerts for errors in retrieving, loading, or displaying the media information. Screens can also include interactive content, and custom events can generate alerts for errors in sending information to the provider or in receiving results from the provider.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a maintenance system <b>300</b> for managing status events and alerts in IPTV system <b>100</b>. Maintenance system <b>300</b> includes an alert logger module <b>310</b>, a ticketing module <b>320</b>, an operations module <b>330</b>, a mobile device interface module <b>332</b>, a social network interface module <b>334</b>, a network <b>340</b>, and one or more provider alert modules <b>350</b>. Alert logger module <b>310</b> is connected to ticket generating module <b>320</b>, to operations module <b>330</b>, and to network <b>340</b>. Ticketing module <b>320</b> is also connected to operations module <b>330</b>. Operations module <b>330</b> is also connected to mobile device interface module <b>332</b>, and to social network interface module <b>334</b>. Network <b>340</b> is also connected to provider alert module <b>350</b>. Alert logger module <b>310</b>, ticketing module <b>320</b>, operations module <b>330</b>, mobile device interface module <b>332</b>, social network interface module <b>334</b>, and provider alert module <b>350</b> can be implemented in hardware, software, or any combination thereof. Each module may include one or more computer systems. When a module includes more than one computer system, the functions of the module can be distributed across the multiple computer systems in a symmetric manner, where each computer system performs the same type of tasks, or in an asymmetric manner, where two computer systems of the module may perform different tasks.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Alert logger module <b>310</b> receives event alerts for IPTV system <b>100</b>. The alerts include internal events generated by the elements of IPTV system <b>100</b>, and external events generated by provider alert module <b>350</b>. In a particular embodiment, the elements of IPTV system <b>100</b> and provider alert module <b>350</b> include an event agent (not illustrated) that monitors for alerts generated by the associated element or module. Upon occurrence of an event, the agent sends the alert to alert logger module <b>310</b>. In another embodiment, the elements of IPTV system <b>100</b> and provider alert module <b>350</b> include an event log (not illustrated) that logs the alerts generated by the associated element or module. Then, alert logger module <b>310</b> periodically requests the alert logs from the elements of IPTV system <b>100</b> and from provider alert module <b>350</b>. A non-limiting example of an alert logger module <b>310</b> includes a server running Microsoft System Center Operations Manager (SCOM) software, Linux or Unix alert logging software, Mac OS alert logging software, another alert logging software, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Alert logger module <b>310</b> sends information related to some or all of the logged alerts to ticketing module <b>320</b> and to operations module <b>330</b>. As such, alert logger module <b>310</b> can function to filter the alerts received from the elements of IPTV system <b>100</b> and from provider alert module <b>350</b>, determine that certain alerts relate to routine matters in IPTV system <b>100</b>, and that other alerts relate to problems in IPTV system <b>100</b>. Thus alert logger module <b>310</b> can send the information related to problems in IPTV system <b>100</b> to ticketing module <b>320</b> and to operations module <b>330</b>, and not send the information related to routine matters in IPTV system <b>100</b>. For example, alert logger module <b>310</b> can receive an alert every time a packet is dropped in IPTV system <b>100</b>. Below a predetermined level of dropped packets in IPTV system <b>100</b>, the alerts can be deemed to be routine. However, if more packets are dropped in IPTV system <b>100</b> than the predetermined level, then alert logger module <b>310</b> can send summary information related to the number and character of the dropped packets to ticketing module <b>320</b> and to operations module <b>330</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Ticketing module <b>320</b> receives the information from alert logger module <b>310</b> and automatically generates work tickets (not illustrated) based upon the alert information. As such, ticketing module <b>320</b> applies business rules to the received alert information to determine an urgency for the events associated with the alerts, and to prioritize the work tickets based upon the urgency of the events. For example, alert information indicating an excessive number of dropped packets in IPTV network <b>100</b> can be deemed less urgent than a link failure between IPTV system <b>100</b> and one or more of providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, or <b>230</b>. Thus ticketing module <b>320</b> can give the ticket associated with the link failure a higher priority than the ticket associated with the excessive number of dropped packets. Ticketing module <b>320</b> also includes a correlation engine (not shown) to determine if two or more of the alerts received from alert logger module <b>310</b> correlate to indicate a problem that may not otherwise be indicated by the presence of the individual alerts, and to generate a work ticket based upon the correlation. For example, a lone alert indicating that set-top box <b>114</b> failed to receive content for a particular application can generate a ticket to repair set-top box <b>114</b>, and a lone alert indicating that set-top box application <b>143</b> failed to receive an acknowledgement of receipt of the content from set-top box application <b>143</b> can generate a ticket to repair set-top box application <b>143</b>. However, these alerts taken together can generate a ticket to repair switches <b>130</b> and <b>140</b> that transport the content between set-top box application <b>143</b> and set-top box <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Operations module <b>330</b> receives the work tickets from ticketing module <b>320</b> and automatically allocates resources to dispose of the work tickets. As such, operations module <b>330</b> can represent a service and repair system in an operations department of IPTV system <b>100</b>. Disposing of the work tickets involves assigning the work tickets to one or more operations technicians that evaluate the work ticket, determine a root cause for the event, and repair the problem at the root cause of the event. As such, operations module <b>330</b> operates to determine if a particular operations technician is available to work on a work ticket. Upon determining that the particular operations technician is available, operations module <b>330</b> sends a text message or a voice mail to mobile device module <b>332</b> for distribution to a mobile device (not illustrated) associated with the particular operations technician. Operations module <b>330</b> also posts a description of the work ticket to social network interface module <b>334</b> for posting on a public or a proprietary operations department social network (not illustrated), and sends a message to the particular operations technician's account on the operations department social network. Operations module <b>330</b> also has access to the alerts logged in alert logger module <b>310</b> in order to identify new business rules and correlations to implement in ticketing module <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Provider alert module <b>350</b> generates alerts based upon the occurrence of events within service providers <b>200</b>. In a particular embodiment, provider alert module <b>350</b> generates alerts for providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b> based upon the events associated with the content, applications, and services from providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b>. In another embodiment, one or more provider alert modules <b>350</b> is associated with each of providers <b>210</b>, <b>220</b>, and <b>230</b>. When an event occurs, provider alert module <b>350</b> sends an alert to alert logger module <b>310</b> through network <b>340</b>. An example of network <b>340</b> includes the Internet, a proprietary network established by the operator of IPTV system <b>100</b> for providing secure communication of alerts, another network, or a combination thereof. In this way, alerts from service providers <b>200</b> are communicated to maintenance system <b>300</b> for logging, ticketing, and disposition by event logger module <b>310</b>, ticketing module <b>320</b>, and operations module <b>330</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In another embodiment (not illustrated), ticketing module <b>320</b> is connected to network <b>340</b>, and alerts from provider alert module <b>350</b> are also sent to ticketing module <b>320</b>. In this embodiment, provider alert modules <b>350</b> has an event agent that includes the ability to filter the alerts such that routine alerts are not sent to ticketing module <b>320</b>. In another embodiment (not illustrated), operations module <b>330</b> is connected to network <b>340</b>. Here, operations module <b>330</b> includes an operations interface module that permits alerts generated from provider alert module <b>350</b> to be sent to a particular operations technician's mobile device through mobile device interface module <b>332</b>, or to the operations technician's account on the operations department social network through social network interface module <b>334</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow chart illustrating an embodiment of a method for alert tracking in an IPTV system. The method starts in block <b>402</b> where an event condition occurs and an alert is generated. For example, a server in provider network <b>216</b> can exhibit a high temperature condition, and provider alert module <b>350</b> can log the event in an event log. The alert is received in block <b>404</b>. Thus, alert logger module <b>310</b> can send a request for alerts from provider alert module <b>350</b> and can receive the alert from provider alert module <b>350</b>. A decision is made as to whether or not the alert is the result of a routine event in decision block <b>406</b>. Here, alert logger module <b>310</b> can determine whether or not the alert provided by provider alert module <b>350</b> constitutes it the result of a routine event and filter out routine alerts while forwarding non-routine alerts to ticketing module <b>320</b>. If the alert is the result of a routine event, then the &#x201c;YES&#x201d; branch of decision block <b>406</b> is taken, and the method ends in block <b>424</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">If the alert is not the result of a routine event, the &#x201c;NO&#x201d; branch of decision block <b>406</b> is taken, and the alert information is sent in block <b>408</b>. For example, alert logger module <b>310</b> can send the alert information to ticking module <b>320</b>. The alert is correlated with other alerts received to determine if the combination of alerts indicates a different root cause of the event in block <b>410</b>. For example, ticketing module <b>320</b> can apply business rules and the correlation engine to determine the root cause of the event associated with the alert. A work ticket is generated in block <b>412</b>, the work ticket is prioritized in block <b>414</b>, and the work ticket is sent in block <b>416</b>. Thus ticketing module <b>320</b> can generate a work ticket based upon the alert information, use the business rules and the correlation engine to determine an urgency of the event that resulted in the alert, prioritize the work ticket based upon the urgency of the event, and send the work ticket to operations module <b>430</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The work ticket is disposed of in block <b>418</b>. For example, operations module <b>330</b> can determine that a particular operations technician is available to work on the work ticket, and can assign the work ticket to the operations technician. The operations technician can evaluate the work ticket, determine a root cause for the event, and repair the problem at the root cause of the event. A phone message is sent in block <b>420</b>. Thus operations module <b>330</b> can send a text or voice mail message to a mobile device associated with the assigned operations technician through mobile device interface module <b>332</b>. The work ticket is posted to a social network in block <b>422</b>, and processing ends in block <b>424</b>. Here, operations module <b>330</b> can post a description of the work ticket to an operations department social network through social network interface module <b>334</b>, and can send a message to an account on the operations department social network associated with the assigned operations technician.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an illustrative embodiment of a general computer system <b>500</b> in accordance with at least one embodiment of the present disclosure. Computer system <b>500</b> includes a set of instructions that can be executed to cause computer system <b>500</b> to perform any one or more of the methods or computer based functions disclosed herein. Computer system <b>500</b> can operate as a standalone device or can be connected via a network to other computer systems or peripheral devices.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In a networked deployment, computer system <b>500</b> operates in the capacity of a server or as a client computer in a server-client network environment, or as a peer computer system in a peer-to-peer (or distributed) network environment. Computer system <b>500</b> can also be implemented as or incorporated into various devices, such as a personal computer (PC), a tablet PC, a set-top box, a personal digital assistant (PDA), a mobile device, a palmtop computer, a laptop computer, a desktop computer, a communications device, a wireless telephone, a land-line telephone, a control system, a camera, a scanner, a facsimile machine, a printer, a pager, a personal trusted device, a web appliance, a network router, switch or bridge, or any other machine capable of executing a set of instructions (sequential or otherwise) that specify actions to be taken by that machine. In a particular embodiment, computer system <b>500</b> is implemented using electronic devices that provide voice, video or data communication. Further, while computer system <b>500</b> is illustrated as a single system, the term &#x201c;system&#x201d; shall also be taken to include any collection of systems or sub-systems that individually or jointly execute a set, or multiple sets, of instructions to perform one or more computer functions.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Computer system <b>500</b> includes a processor <b>502</b> such as a central processing unit (CPU), a graphics processing unit (GPU), or both. Moreover, computer system <b>500</b> includes a main memory <b>504</b> and a static memory <b>506</b> that communicate with each other via a bus <b>508</b>. Computer system <b>500</b> further includes a video display unit <b>510</b>, such as a liquid crystal display (LCD), an organic light emitting diode (OLED), a flat panel display, a solid state display, or a cathode ray tube (CRT). Additionally, computer system <b>500</b> includes an input device <b>512</b>, such as a keyboard, and a cursor control device <b>514</b>, such as a mouse. Computer system <b>500</b> also includes a disk drive unit <b>516</b>, a signal generation device <b>518</b>, such as a speaker or remote control, and a network interface device <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In a particular embodiment, disk drive unit <b>516</b> includes a computer-readable medium <b>522</b> in which one or more sets of instructions <b>524</b> are embedded. Instructions <b>524</b> embody one or more of the methods or logic as described herein. In a particular embodiment, instructions <b>524</b> reside completely, or at least partially, within main memory <b>504</b>, static memory <b>506</b>, and/or within processor <b>502</b> during execution by computer system <b>500</b>. Main memory <b>504</b> and processor <b>502</b> also include computer-readable media. Network interface device <b>520</b> provides connectivity to a network <b>526</b> such as a wide area network (WAN), a local area network (LAN), or other network. The present disclosure contemplates a computer-readable medium that includes instructions <b>524</b> or receives and executes instructions <b>524</b> responsive to a propagated signal, so that a device connected to network <b>526</b> can communicate voice, video or data over network <b>526</b>. Further, instructions <b>524</b> can be transmitted or received by network <b>526</b> via network interface device <b>520</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In an alternative embodiment, dedicated hardware implementations such as application specific integrated circuits, programmable logic arrays and other hardware devices can be constructed to implement one or more of the methods described herein. Applications that include the apparatus and systems of various embodiments can broadly include a variety of electronic and computer systems. One or more embodiments described herein can implement functions using two or more specific interconnected hardware modules or devices with related control and data signals that can be communicated between and through the modules, or as portions of an application-specific integrated circuit. Accordingly, the present system encompasses software, firmware, or hardware implementations, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In accordance with various embodiments of the present disclosure, the methods described herein can be implemented by software code executable by a computer system. Further, in an exemplary, non-limited embodiment, implementations can include distributed processing, component/object distributed processing, and parallel processing. Alternatively, virtual computer system processing can be constructed to implement one or more of the methods or functionality as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">While the computer-readable medium is shown to be a single medium, the term &#x201c;computer-readable medium&#x201d; includes a single medium or multiple media, such as a centralized or distributed database, and/or associated caches and servers that store one or more sets of instructions. The term &#x201c;computer-readable medium&#x201d; shall also include any medium that is capable of storing, encoding or carrying a set of instructions for execution by a processor or that cause a computer system to perform any one or more of the methods or operations disclosed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In a particular non-limiting, exemplary embodiment, the computer-readable medium can include a solid-state memory such as a memory card or other package that houses one or more non-volatile read-only memories. Further, the computer-readable medium can be a random access memory or other volatile re-writable memory. Additionally, the computer-readable medium can include a magneto-optical or optical medium, such as a disk or tapes or other storage device to capture carrier wave signals such as a signal communicated over a transmission medium. A digital file attachment to an e-mail or other self-contained information archive or set of archives can be considered a distribution medium that is equivalent to a tangible storage medium. Accordingly, the disclosure is considered to include any one or more of a computer-readable medium or a distribution medium and other equivalents and successor media, in which data or instructions can be stored.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The illustrations of the embodiments described herein are intended to provide a general understanding of the structure of the various embodiments. The illustrations are not intended to serve as a complete description of all of the elements and features of apparatus and systems that utilize the structures or methods described herein. Many other embodiments can be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reviewing the disclosure. Other embodiments can be utilized and derived from the disclosure, such that structural and logical substitutions and changes can be made without departing from the scope of the disclosure. Additionally, the illustrations are merely representational and may not be drawn to scale. Certain proportions within the illustrations may be exaggerated, while other proportions may be minimized. Accordingly, the disclosure and the figures are to be regarded as illustrative rather than restrictive.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The Abstract of the Disclosure is provided to comply with 37 C.F.R. &#xa7;1.72(b) and is submitted with the understanding that it will not be used to interpret or limit the scope or meaning of the claims. In addition, in the foregoing Detailed Description of the Drawings, various features may be grouped together or described in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an intention that the claimed embodiments require more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter may be directed to less than all of the features of any of the disclosed embodiments. Thus, the following claims are incorporated into the Detailed Description of the Drawings, with each claim standing on its own as defining separately claimed subject matter.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The above disclosed subject matter is to be considered illustrative, and not restrictive, and the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications, enhancements, and other embodiments which fall within the true spirit and scope of the present disclosed subject matter. Thus, to the maximum extent allowed by law, the scope of the present disclosed subject matter is to be determined by the broadest permissible interpretation of the following claims and their equivalents, and shall not be restricted or limited</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by a system comprising a processor, an alert from equipment of a service provider, wherein the alert is directed to an internet protocol television network, and wherein the alert is associated with a fault event occurring at the equipment of the service provider;</claim-text>
<claim-text>correlating, by the system, the alert with other alerts received by the system to determine whether a root cause of the fault event is related to the equipment of the service provider that generated the alert or other equipment providing services to the equipment of the service provider;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the system, an urgency for the fault event according to business rules and a result of correlating the alert with other alerts;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating, by the system, a work ticket associated with the alert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning, by the system, a first priority to the work ticket based upon the urgency for the fault event to generate a prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>allocating, by the system, the prioritized work ticket; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the system, to a mobile device a first message regarding the prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>posting, by the system, the prioritized work ticket and a description thereof at a social network; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the system, a second message to an account associated with the social network.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first message comprises a text message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first message comprises a voice mail message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the account is further associated with an operations technician.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein determining the urgency further comprises determining from the result of the correlation that the other equipment providing services to the equipment of the service provider is the root cause of the fault event associated with the equipment of the service provider, and wherein the first priority has a lower priority than a second priority assigned to another work ticketed generated for the other equipment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fault event includes a server fault condition on a server associated with the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fault event includes a fault associated with an application provided by the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by a system comprising a processor, an alert from equipment of a service provider, wherein the alert is directed to an internet protocol television network, and wherein the alert is associated with a fault event;</claim-text>
<claim-text>correlating, by the system, the alert with other alerts received by the system to determine whether a root cause of the fault event is related to the equipment of the service provider that generated the alert or other equipment providing services to the equipment of the service provider;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the system, an urgency for the fault event;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a work ticket associated with the alert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning, by the system, a first priority to the work ticket that is lower in priority than a second priority assigned to another work ticket generated for the other equipment to generate a prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the system, the prioritized work ticket to an operations module;</claim-text>
<claim-text>allocating the prioritized work ticket; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the system, to a mobile device a first message regarding the prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>posting, by the system, the prioritized work ticket and a description thereof at a social network; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending, by the system, a second message to an account associated with the social network.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first message comprises a text message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first message comprises a voice mail message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the account is further associated with an operations technician.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the equipment of the service provider comprises a server associated with the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the fault event is associated with an application provided by the equipment of the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. Machine-executable code embedded within a tangible device comprising instructions, which responsive to being executed by a processor, cause the processor to perform operations comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an alert from a service provider, wherein the alert is directed to an internet protocol television network, and wherein the alert is associated with a fault event;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining from a correlation of the alert and other alerts that a root cause of the fault event is related to equipment of the service provider that generated the alert or other equipment providing services to the equipment of the service provider;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an urgency for the fault event according to the correlation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a work ticket associated with the alert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>assigning a priority to the work ticket based upon the urgency for the fault event to generate a prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>allocating the prioritized work ticket; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending to a mobile device a message regarding the prioritized work ticket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>posting the prioritized work ticket and a description thereof at a social network; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending a message to an account associated with the social network.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The machine-executable code of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the account is further associated with a technician.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The machine-executable code of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the fault event is a server fault condition on a server associated with the equipment of the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The machine-executable code of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the fault event is a fault associated with an application supplied by the equipment of the service provider.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
