<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623063-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623063</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13179114</doc-number>
<date>20110708</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>80</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>61</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>067</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 89</main-classification>
<further-classification>607 88</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Medical treatment apparatus using laser beams</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3990300</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kossoff</name>
<date>19761100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73640</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0007078</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yayama</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>607 89</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0028558</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ozawa et al.</name>
<date>20100200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>427558</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11-276606</doc-number>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-187157</doc-number>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-329474</doc-number>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>20-0407524</doc-number>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2009-0117544</doc-number>
<date>20091100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>607 88- 90</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>18</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130013029</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Soung Don</first-name>
<address>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Soung Don</first-name>
<address>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>IP &#x26; T Group LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Soung-Don</first-name>
<role>04</role>
<address>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Thomson</last-name>
<first-name>Bill</first-name>
<department>3769</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Lipitz</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Provided is a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, which is used for treating arthritis, myositis, chronic pains and so on. A medical treatment apparatus using laser beams includes: a body; a main laser unit irradiating a main laser beam in a direction perpendicular to an area to be treated; a plurality of auxiliary laser units irradiating auxiliary laser beams to form a focus on a central axis of the main laser beam; and an angle adjustment unit adjusting a focal distance by rotating the auxiliary laser units. The medical treatment apparatus using laser beams is capable of easily varying the angle and distance of the focus of irradiated laser beams. In addition, a treatment effect can be enhanced by the laser beams having different intensities, and the absorption rates of the laser beams can be controlled based on the color of light which is separately irradiated onto the skin of an affected area.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="169.76mm" wi="102.02mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.19mm" wi="175.01mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="121.92mm" wi="121.24mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="100.92mm" wi="132.84mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="130.89mm" wi="157.23mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="166.20mm" wi="152.40mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="83.14mm" wi="106.85mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="132.00mm" wi="159.68mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="84.33mm" wi="114.38mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="155.87mm" wi="115.49mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="114.38mm" wi="158.07mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="145.29mm" wi="172.80mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="190.67mm" wi="202.95mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="157.31mm" wi="189.31mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="113.11mm" wi="111.84mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="155.36mm" wi="112.52mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="165.52mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00017" num="00017">
<img id="EMI-D00017" he="99.31mm" wi="146.56mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00017.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00018" num="00018">
<img id="EMI-D00018" he="182.03mm" wi="107.19mm" file="US08623063-20140107-D00018.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention relate to a medical treatment apparatus; and, more particularly, to a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, which is used for treating arthritis, myositis, chronic pains and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Diseases such as arthritis and myositis may be treated or relieved by laser beams. Specifically, when laser beams are irradiated onto an affected area, energy is transferred to mitochondria, and cells are smoothly activated and restored. This may speed up metabolism. Furthermore, blood vessels at the laser-beam-irradiated area are expanded, and blood circulation is promoted. Accordingly, the increase of white blood cells is accompanied. As a result, a sterilizing action for the affected area is activated to promote the infection treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">As an example of a conventional medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, Korean Patent Laid-open Publication No. 10-2009-0117544 discloses an arthritis treatment apparatus. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the arthritis treatment apparatus includes a body <b>10</b>, an ultrasonic generator <b>20</b>, a plurality of laser diodes <b>30</b>, and a handle <b>40</b>. The ultrasonic generator <b>20</b> is provided in the body <b>10</b> and serves to generate ultrasonic waves toward the center under the body <b>10</b>. The plurality of laser diodes <b>30</b> are installed at even intervals along the outer circumference of a lower portion of the body <b>10</b>, and emits laser beams at a constant angle toward the inside of the lower portion of the body. The laser beams are focused on one point on the center line of the ultrasonic waves generated from the ultrasonic generator. The handle <b>40</b> is provided at one side of the body <b>10</b>, and includes a switch for switching the operations of the ultrasonic generator and the laser diodes.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The above-described arthritis treatment apparatus is characterized in that an affected area is minutely vibrated by ultrasonic waves to promote the cartilage reconstruction of a joint, and laser beams are simultaneously used to perform the above-described infection treatment.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, the body <b>10</b> should be closely attached to an affected area, in order to normally apply ultrasonic waves to the affected area. Therefore, the arthritis treatment apparatus may cause an additional pain for a patient having a severe arthritis pain. Furthermore, the arthritis treatment apparatus has a structure in which the focus of laser beams is fixed. Therefore, in order to move the focus, the arthritis treatment apparatus should be moved in a state in which the body is closely attached to an affected area as described above. Furthermore, a concave portion <b>11</b> of the body <b>10</b> from which laser beams and ultrasonic waves are outputted has a hemispheric shape which reflects the joint portions of a human body, in particular, a knee and an elbow. Therefore, the movement of the body is further limited.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Furthermore, since laser beams irradiated from the arthritis treatment apparatus have the same intensity (power), they may have an undesirable effect upon the surroundings of a core area which is to be treated.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An embodiment of the present invention is directed to a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, which is capable of easily varying the focus of laser beams by using a main laser element and a plurality of auxiliary laser elements of which the angle may be changed, such that the laser beams are smoothly and effectively irradiated onto an affected area such as a curved joint.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another embodiment of the present invention is directed to a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, which sets the intensity of a main laser beam differently from that of auxiliary laser beams such that the penetration depths thereof differ from each other, thereby increasing a treatment effect.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another embodiment of the present invention is directed to a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams, which is capable of controlling the absorption rate of laser beams by adjusting the color of light irradiated onto the skin of an affected area.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams includes: a body; a main laser unit irradiating a main laser beam in a direction perpendicular to an area to be treated; a plurality of auxiliary laser units irradiating auxiliary laser beams to form a focus on a central axis of the main laser beam; and an angle adjustment unit adjusting a focal distance by rotating the auxiliary laser units.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The auxiliary laser beams may have a lower intensity that the main laser beam. The main laser unit may be positioned in the center of a front surface of the body. The auxiliary laser units may be radially positioned in the front surface with the main laser beam unit set to the center thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The main laser unit may include a main laser element and a condensing lens condensing the main laser beam outputted from the main laser element. The auxiliary laser units may include: four auxiliary laser elements positioned in a radial form, with the main laser element set to the center thereof; and condensing lenses condensing auxiliary laser beams outputted from the auxiliary laser elements.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The medical treatment apparatus may further include a color adjustment unit irradiate a color, which is adjusted by the intensities of red and blue colors, on the skin of the affected area. The color adjustment unit may include at least one pair of red light emitting diode and blue light emitting diode which are positioned on a front surface of the body. The medical treatment apparatus may further include a control unit controlling the main laser unit, the auxiliary laser units, and the angle adjustment unit. The medical treatment apparatus may further include a control unit controlling the color adjustment unit.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a conventional medical treatment apparatus using laser beams.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram illustrating the functional configuration of a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are diagrams explaining a body and a support member in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a plan view of the support member in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram illustrating the detailed structure of a main laser unit in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram illustrating a focus formed by auxiliary laser units in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a diagram illustrating the detailed structure of the auxiliary laser unit in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram illustrating a main laser unit and auxiliary laser elements positioned in the support member in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a diagram illustrating the rotation of the auxiliary laser element in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a diagram illustrating the detailed structure of an angle adjustment unit in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref> are diagrams illustrating a focus and a focal distance change by the main laser unit and the auxiliary laser units in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a diagram illustrating the detailed structure of the color adjustment unit in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a diagram illustrating a modification of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</figref> are diagrams illustrating additional components in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a diagram illustrating a state in which a joint is treated by the medical treatment apparatus using laser beams in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF SPECIFIC EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Exemplary embodiments of the present invention will be described below in more detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. The present invention may, however, be embodied in different forms and should not be constructed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the present invention to those skilled in the art. Throughout the disclosure, like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the various figures and embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a functional configuration diagram of a medical treatment apparatus using laser beams in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. The medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b> includes a main laser unit <b>110</b>, a plurality of auxiliary laser units <b>120</b>, an angle adjustment unit <b>130</b>, a color adjustment unit <b>140</b>, and a control unit <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The main components <b>110</b> to <b>150</b> for implementing the medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b> are provided in a body <b>101</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The embodiment of the present invention is not limited to the shape or exterior of the body illustrated in the drawing. The control unit <b>150</b> may be separated from the body <b>101</b>. That is, the control unit <b>150</b> may be formed in an external type. The shape of the control unit <b>150</b> will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The main laser unit <b>110</b>, the auxiliary laser units <b>120</b>, and the color adjustment unit <b>140</b> are supported by a support member <b>102</b> provided on a front surface of the body <b>101</b>, from which laser beams are irradiated. In this embodiment of the present invention, the support member <b>102</b> is provided as a component integrated with the body <b>101</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, however, the support member <b>102</b> may be separated from the body <b>101</b>. Therefore, the support member <b>102</b> described in this embodiment of the present invention may be considered to be the front surface of the body <b>101</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a plan view of the support member <b>102</b>. The main laser unit <b>110</b> is installed in a center hole <b>102</b><i>a </i>of the support member <b>102</b> and irradiates a laser beam (hereinafter, referred to as a main laser beam for convenience of description) in a direction perpendicular to the front surface. The main laser beam has a wavelength of 880&#x2dc;970 nm and an intensity (power) of 500 mW&#x2dc;5 W. The wavelength and the intensity are controlled by the control unit <b>150</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the main laser unit <b>110</b> includes a main laser element <b>112</b> and a condensing lens <b>114</b>. The condensing lens <b>114</b> serves to increase the power by condensing the main laser beam outputted from the main laser element <b>112</b>, that is, performs an amplification function.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the auxiliary laser units <b>120</b> are installed in auxiliary holes <b>102</b> arranged in a radial form, with the main hole <b>102</b><i>a </i>set to the center thereof. The auxiliary laser units <b>120</b> irradiate auxiliary laser beams toward the main laser beams, the auxiliary laser beams having a wavelength of 750&#x2dc;830 nm and an intensity (power) of 500 mW&#x2dc;1 W. That is, the irradiated auxiliary laser beams form a focus f on a propagation line (hereinafter, referred to as a central axis) of the main laser beam (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). At this time, the focal distance (distance from the main laser unit) may be varied by the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> which will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, each of the auxiliary laser units <b>120</b> includes an auxiliary laser element <b>122</b> and a condensing lens <b>124</b>, similar to the main laser unit <b>110</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram illustrating the main laser element <b>112</b> and the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b> which are provided on the support member <b>102</b>. In this embodiment, the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b><i>a </i>to <b>122</b><i>d </i>are installed in four auxiliary holes <b>102</b><i>b</i>, respectively. As described above, the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b><i>a </i>to <b>122</b><i>d </i>form a focus on the central axis. Here, the variation of the focus means that the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b> are installed in the support member <b>102</b> so as to rotate or pivot in a predetermined range.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Specifically, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, a ring-shaped elastic member <b>103</b> is provided in the auxiliary hole <b>102</b><i>b </i>of the support member <b>102</b>, which houses the auxiliary laser element <b>122</b>. The auxiliary laser element <b>122</b> is inserted into a hole <b>103</b><i>a </i>of the elastic member <b>103</b>. Therefore, the auxiliary laser element <b>122</b> may be rotated in a predetermined range in a state in which the auxiliary laser element <b>122</b> is held by the elastic member <b>103</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Meanwhile, as briefly described above, the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> serves to vary the focal distance by adjusting the angle of the auxiliary laser element <b>122</b> with respect to the central axis. The angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> may be simply considered to be a unit for rotating the auxiliary laser element. Furthermore, it will be easily understood by those skilled in the art that a specific unit for rotation may be designed and modified in various manners. In this embodiment, however, one example is disclosed as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a diagram illustrating the detailed structure of the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention. The auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b> are connected to connection members <b>131</b>, respectively, which are provided under the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b>. For example, wires may be used as the connection members <b>131</b>. Extended ends of the connection members <b>131</b> are inserted into the body <b>101</b> and connected to a rod <b>132</b> which may vertically reciprocate with respect to the support member <b>102</b>. That is, when the rod <b>132</b> is pulled or pushed, the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b> are simultaneously rotated (pivoted) in the same range within the respective auxiliary holes <b>102</b><i>b </i>by the movement of the connection members <b>131</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, when the rod <b>132</b> is pushed to the maximum, the focal distance is minimized, and when the rod <b>132</b> is pulled to the maximum, the focal distance is maximized.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">For reference, the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is based on a manual manipulation method. However, the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> may be implemented according to an automatic manipulation method. For example, gear teeth (not illustrated) may be formed at one side of the rod <b>132</b>, and a motor-based gear box (not illustrated) for moving the gear teeth may be formed to implement the automatic manipulation method. In this case, the gear box is controlled by the control unit <b>150</b>. Alternatively, motor-based gear boxes may be installed on the respective auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b>, in order to individually rotate the auxiliary laser elements <b>122</b>. As described above, the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> may be implemented in various manners.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As described above, the intensity (power) of the laser beam outputted from the main laser unit <b>110</b> is different from that of the laser beams outputted from the auxiliary laser units <b>120</b>. The intensity of the main laser beams is set to be higher than that of the auxiliary laser beams. For example, when the intensity of the main laser beam is set to 5 W, the intensity of the auxiliary laser beam may be set to 1 W. When the number of auxiliary laser beams is four as described above, the total intensity at the focus corresponds to 9 W. As well known, the penetration depth of laser beams with respect to a human body may differ depending on the intensity of the laser beams. As the intensity of the laser beams increases, the penetration depth increases. When the intensity of the laser beam outputted from the main laser unit <b>110</b> is set to be different from that of the laser beams outputted from the auxiliary laser units <b>120</b>, it is possible to increase the treatment effect and the stability. This will be specifically described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref>. Although the structure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref> is illustrated in a two-dimensional manner, the auxiliary laser beams are irradiated onto an affected area in a conical shape, with the main laser beam set to the center thereof. The apex of the conical shape corresponds to the focus f. The auxiliary laser beams serve to activate the surrounding tissues of the affected area before arriving at the affected area. When the surrounding tissues are activated, the metabolism of cells is sped up, and the infection treatment effect at the treated area increases. Furthermore, the auxiliary laser beams having passed through the surrounding tissues converge into the main laser beam (focus f) at the affected area, and the total intensity becomes 9 W. Therefore, a concentrated treatment is performed on the focus area, that is, the affected area. When the focal distance is reduced by the angle adjustment unit <b>130</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the range of the auxiliary laser beams passing through the surrounding tissues increases. On the other hand, when the focal distance is increased as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the range of the auxiliary laser beams passing through the surrounding tissues decreases.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In this embodiment of the present invention, it has been described that the total intensity at the focus area is 9 W, but this is only a numerical value for convenience of description. That is, the loss of laser beams caused by absorption into the human body is excluded. Furthermore, the reason that the intensity of the main laser beam is set to be five times larger than that of the auxiliary laser beams may be described as follows. First, a case in which the intensity of the main laser beam is equal to that of the auxiliary laser beams may be assumed. In this case, when the intensity of each laser beam is set to 5 W, the maximum intensity at the focus area becomes 25 W. This intensity corresponds to such a level that is dangerous to a human body. On the other hand, when the intensity of each beam is reduced to 1 W, the maximum intensity at the focus area becomes 5 W. In this case, although the intensity corresponds to a level safe for a human body, the treatment effect may not be exhibited. In order to set the intensity to 9 W, nine laser elements may be used. However, laser beams having an intensity of 1 W penetrates to a small thickness, and the loss of the laser beams caused by the absorption into a human body increases before the laser beams arrives at the focus area. As a result, the total intensity at the focus area inevitably decreases. That is, laser beams include a technical contradiction in which the intensity thereof should be high and low at the same time in consideration of the treatment effect and the stability. In this embodiment of the present invention, in order to overcome such a technical contradiction, the intensity of the main laser beam is set to be different from that of the auxiliary layer beams, and a basic intensity at the focus area is secured through the main laser element.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">For reference, as the wavelength is small, the directness becomes strong. Therefore, the wavelength has an effect upon the penetration depth. The wavelength of the auxiliary laser beam having an intensity of 1 W may be set to 830 nm, and the wavelength of the main laser beam having an intensity of 5 W may be set to 808 nm. Such numerical values are only examples which were obtained while the present inventor was designing the present invention. Therefore, the wavelengths of the laser beams are not limited to such numerical values. Furthermore, a main parameter of the penetration depth is the intensity (power). That is, the main laser beam and the auxiliary laser beam may have the same wavelength.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The above-described embodiment of the present invention may be applied to TRIZ which is a problem solving principle. That is, the embodiment of the present invention includes a segmentation principle in which laser beams are segmented into the main laser beam and the auxiliary laser beams, a local quality principle in which the intensity of the main laser beam is set to be different from that of the auxiliary laser beams, a dynamicity principle in which the irradiation angle of the auxiliary laser beams is adjusted, and a preliminary action principle in which the auxiliary laser beams are used to activate the surrounding tissues. In addition, a principle of changing color is applied to the embodiment of the present invention. This will be described below through the color adjustment unit <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The color adjustment unit <b>140</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> serves to irradiates a color, of which the color is adjusted by controlling the intensities of red light and blue light, onto the skin of an affected area. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the color adjustment unit <b>140</b> is provided in through-holes <b>102</b><i>c </i>of the support member <b>102</b>, similar to the main laser unit <b>110</b> and the auxiliary laser unit <b>120</b>. In order to implement the color adjustment unit <b>140</b>, at least one pair of red light emitting diode <b>142</b><i>a </i>and blue light emitting diode <b>142</b><i>b </i>is required as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> illustrates two pairs of light emitting diodes as an example. Furthermore, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> illustrates that the red light emitting diode <b>142</b><i>a </i>and the blue light emitting diode <b>142</b><i>b </i>are installed separately from each other on the support member <b>102</b>. However, this is only an example. For example, the red and blue light emitting diodes may be formed in a package type. In other words, the red and blue light emitting diodes may be provided within a single package.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When the intensities of the light emitting diodes <b>142</b><i>a </i>and <b>142</b><i>b </i>are adjusted (color concentration adjustment), a variety of colors may be created by the color mixing principle. The mixed color is irradiated onto the skin of an affected area, and the absorption rates of the main laser beam and the auxiliary laser beam may be adjusted by the concentration of the mixed color. As the concentration of the mixed color increases, the absorption rate of the laser beams at the skin increases. At this time, the mixed color and the concentration thereof may be considered according to the skin color.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Meanwhile, the control unit <b>150</b> serves to control the operations of the main laser unit, the auxiliary laser units, the angle adjustment unit, and the color adjustment unit. Furthermore, the control unit <b>150</b> includes a function of supplying and controlling power required for the operations.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The above descriptions of the medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b> in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention have been focused on the functions thereof. The detailed structure of the medial treatment apparatus <b>100</b> may be modified in various manners. For example, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, the control unit <b>150</b> may be implemented in an external type which is separated from the body <b>101</b> of the medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b>. The body <b>101</b> may be supported by the control unit <b>150</b> through a separate support member <b>10</b>, and a plurality of bodies <b>101</b> each including the respective components <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and <b>140</b> may be provided and controlled by the single control unit <b>150</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>. That is, a mono-bi-poly principle may be applied, if necessary.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</figref> are diagrams illustrating additional components provided in the medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b>. The medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b> additionally includes a spacer positioned at the front surface of the support member <b>102</b>, a transparent protection member <b>105</b> positioned at the front surface of the spacer <b>102</b>, and a cylindrical coupling member <b>106</b> for coupling the spacer <b>104</b> and the transparent protection member <b>105</b> to the body <b>101</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> conceptually illustrates a state in which a joint is treated by the medical treatment apparatus <b>100</b> using laser beams.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In accordance with the embodiment of the present invention, the focus of the laser beams may be easily changed, a treatment effect may be enhanced by the laser beams having different intensities, and the absorption rates of the laser beams may be controlled based on the color of light which is separately irradiated onto the skin of an affected area.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">While the present invention has been described with respect to the specific embodiments, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A medical treatment apparatus, comprising:
<claim-text>a body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a main laser unit, associated with the body, to irradiate a near infrared (IR) main laser beam in a direction perpendicular to a target area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of auxiliary laser units, associated with the body, to irradiate near IR auxiliary laser beams to intersect a central axis of the near IR main laser beam at a focal distance;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an angle adjustment unit, associated with the body, to adjust the focal distance by rotating the plurality of auxiliary laser units; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a color adjustment unit, positioned at a front surface of the body, to irradiate variable intensity red light and blue light on the target area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the near IR auxiliary laser beams have a lower intensity than an intensity of the near IR main laser beam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the main laser unit is positioned at a center of a front surface of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of auxiliary laser units are radially positioned, at a front surface of the body, around the main laser unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the main laser unit comprises:
<claim-text>a main laser element to irradiate the near IR main laser beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a condensing lens to condense the near IR main laser beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of auxiliary laser units comprises four auxiliary laser units, and wherein each auxiliary laser unit comprises:
<claim-text>an auxiliary laser element to irradiate an auxiliary laser beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a condensing lens to condense the auxiliary laser beam.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the color adjustment unit comprises:
<claim-text>at least one pair of red light emitting diodes and at least one pair of blue light emitting diodes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The medical treatment apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a control unit to control the main laser unit, the plurality of auxiliary laser units, color adjustment unit, and the angle adjustment unit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
