<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624600-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624600</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13017604</doc-number>
<date>20110131</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-017876</doc-number>
<date>20100129</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2010-152685</doc-number>
<date>20100705</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>403</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324354</main-classification>
<further-classification>324348</further-classification>
<further-classification>324347</further-classification>
<further-classification>320119</further-classification>
<further-classification>320132</further-classification>
<further-classification>320136</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e90">Current detecting device</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8142237</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Condamin et al.</name>
<date>20120300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439762</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0030208</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Aratani</name>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>A-2008-39571</doc-number>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324 7611</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324348</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324357</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>324354</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320119</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320132</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>320136</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110187346</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110804</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Teramoto</last-name>
<first-name>Toshiyo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Okazaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ozawa</last-name>
<first-name>Jyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiryu</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Teramoto</last-name>
<first-name>Toshiyo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Okazaki</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ozawa</last-name>
<first-name>Jyun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiryu</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oliff &#x26; Berridge, PLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Denso Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Kariya</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Vazquez</last-name>
<first-name>Arleen M</first-name>
<department>2858</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Allgood</last-name>
<first-name>Alesa</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A current detecting device includes a second fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected, a bus bar as a resistor inserted between a first fixed part and the second fixed part, a circuit board in which a current detection circuit is mounted, the current detection circuit detecting current flowing through the bus bar based on a potential difference between two points along an energizing direction of the bus bar, and a case accommodating the bus bar and the circuit board. The second fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected is disposed within a battery upper surface area.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="151.64mm" wi="166.37mm" file="US08624600-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="245.96mm" wi="159.43mm" file="US08624600-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="256.79mm" wi="164.85mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624600-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="176.61mm" wi="165.61mm" file="US08624600-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="191.69mm" wi="171.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624600-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="209.80mm" wi="175.77mm" file="US08624600-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="236.05mm" wi="140.72mm" file="US08624600-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is based on and claims the benefit of priority from earlier Japanese Patent Applications No. 2010-17876 filed Jan. 29, 2010 and No. 2010-152685 filed Jul. 5, 2010, the descriptions of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to a current detecting device equipped in a passenger car, a truck, etc. that detects charging/discharging current of a battery.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A current sensor has been known that is provided with a current detection circuit accommodated within a case in an intermediate portion of a flat bus bar in the length direction (refer to, for example, JP-A-2008-39571).</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the current sensor, the bus bar configures a ground terminal. The current sensor is attached to the negative terminal side of a battery and detects the charging/discharging currents of the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The bus bar of the current sensor disclosed in JP-A-2008-39571 has a long, flat shape to ensure current detection accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Because a first connecting section and a second connecting section connected to respective attached members are formed at the tips of the bus bar in the length direction, when the distance between the first and second connecting sections is long, moment force is generated against the attached member connected to the first connecting section with the second connecting section as a point of action.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In particular, when a battery terminal is considered as the attached member connected to the first connecting section, excessive moment force is applied to the battery terminal, leading to reduced fastening strength of the battery terminal and damage to the battery terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A problem occurs in that quality and vibration-resistance of the battery terminal may deteriorate during vehicle assembly.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">An embodiment provides a current detecting device capable of improving quality and vibration-resistance of a battery terminal during vehicle assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In a current detecting device that detects a current flowing through a battery terminal to a harness according to a first aspect, the current detecting device includes a fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected; a resistor inserted between the battery terminal and the fixed part; a circuit board in which a current detection circuit is mounted, the current detection circuit detecting current flowing through the resistor based on a potential difference between two points along an energizing direction of the resistor; and a case housing the resistor and the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected is disposed within a battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As a result of the fixed part being disposed on the battery upper surface area, even when a load is applied when the harness is fixed to the fixed part, the amount of deflection of the fixed part in the load direction can be reduced. Therefore, excessive moment can be prevented from being applied to the battery terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As a result, reduction in fastening strength of the battery terminal and damage to the battery terminal can be prevented, and the quality and vibration-resistance of the battery terminal during vehicle assembly can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Furthermore, because the overall current detecting device including the fixed part or the main section thereof is contained within the battery upper surface area, the space on the battery upper surface can be effectively used, and mounting properties are enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the current detecting device according to a second aspect, the above-described resistor preferably has a non-linear shape. Specifically, the non-linear shape is a shape that is folded back midway and of which at least a portion is overlapping. Alternatively, the non-linear shape is a C-shape or an L.-shape.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As a result, distance between the battery terminal and the fixed part can be shortened, and moment force applied to the battery terminal when the harness is fixed to the fixed part can be further reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the current detecting device according to a third aspect, the above-described fixed part is preferably disposed within a circular area that is within the battery upper surface area and has a radius from the center of the battery terminal that is a radius of the battery terminal multiplied by a predetermined value.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Specifically, the above-described predetermined value is preferably 3.5. The moment force applied to the battery terminal when a predetermined fastening force is applied to the fixed part is proportional to the distance between the battery terminal and the fixed part.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">On the other hand, when the same moment force is applied as described in the present disclosure, the moment force can be dispersed and received in proportion to a battery terminal diameter. Therefore, reduction in the fastening strength of the battery terminal and damage to the battery terminal can be prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Therefore, as a result of limiting the ratio of the battery terminal diameter to the distance between the battery terminal and the fixed part, the moment force applied to the battery terminal during fastening of the fixed part can be dispersed. The quality and vibration-resistance of the battery terminal can be improved with certainty.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In the current detecting device according to a fourth aspect, the above-described fixed part is preferably any of a bolt that is attached and fixed, an attaching hole that is formed in a penetrating manner, and a crimped terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As a result of forming the fixed part by any of the bolt, the attaching hole, and the crimped terminal, variation of the harness position on the vehicle side can be increased, and attaching properties can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In the current detecting device according to a fifth aspect, attachment is preferably performed in a state in which the lower surface of the above-described fixed section is in contact with the battery upper surface.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As a result, the amount of deflection of the fixed part when the harness is fixed to the fixed part can be kept to a minimum, and the moment force applied to the battery terminal can be minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Therefore, the quality and vibration-resistance of the battery terminal during vehicle mounting can be further improved.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the current detecting device according to a sixth aspect, a cut-out section is preferably formed in the above-described case within the battery upper surface area. The battery terminal and the fixed part are each preferably provided such as to oppose the cut-out section.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A terminal provided in the battery within the battery upper surface area is preferably disposed in the cut-out section. Specifically, the battery terminal and the fixed part are each preferably provided in a position adjacent to the cut-out section.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As a result of the cut-out section being provided in the case of the current detecting device, and the terminal of the battery, and the battery terminal and the fixed part of the current detecting device being collectively disposed within or near the cut-out section in this way, the distance between each fastening section thereof can be shortened.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Therefore, the moment force applied during fastening or during use can be reduced.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the accompanying drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a configuration of a current detecting device according to an embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line II-II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of a specific example of a circuit in the current detecting device, and an example of connection with a battery or the like;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a configuration of a variation example of the current detecting device;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a planar view of another variation example of the current detecting device;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref> are diagrams of overall configurations of other variation examples of the current detecting device; and</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> are diagrams of another variation example of the current detecting device.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A current detecting device according to an embodiment in which the present disclosure is applied will hereinafter be described in detail with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The current detecting device according to the embodiment is, for example mounted on and fixed to a negative-side terminal of a lead battery for a vehicle, and can be used to detect charge and discharge currents of the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a configuration of the current detecting device according to the embodiment, showing a state in which the current detecting device is attached to the battery. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line II-II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A current detecting device <b>100</b> according to the embodiment shown in the drawings includes: a bus bar <b>110</b> serving as a resistor (shunt resistor) formed using a conductive material; a circuit board <b>120</b> on which a current detection circuit is mounted, the current detection circuit detecting a current flowing through the bus bar <b>110</b> based on a potential difference between two points along the energizing direction of the bus bar <b>110</b>; a case <b>130</b> housing the bus bar <b>110</b> and the circuit board <b>120</b>; a connector <b>140</b>, inside of which a plurality of connector terminals <b>142</b> are exposed, the connector terminals <b>142</b> being electrically connected with the circuit board <b>120</b>; and a lid <b>150</b> that seals an opening of a recess in the case <b>130</b> housing the circuit board <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The bus bar <b>110</b> is shaped such as to be folded back and overlapping within the case <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">One end of the bus bar <b>110</b> forms a first fixed section <b>112</b> that is fixed to an attachment fitting serving as a connection terminal on the battery <b>200</b> side and electrically connected.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The other end of the bus bar <b>110</b> forms a second fixed section <b>114</b> that is fixed to a harness and electrically connected. The bus bar <b>110</b> is formed by press-molding a single plate-shaped member.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">According to the present embodiment, the main section (the section housing the circuit board <b>120</b>) of the case <b>130</b> having an overall rectangular shape is disposed near a side surface of the battery <b>200</b> (the side surface closest to a terminal <b>202</b> of the battery <b>200</b> to which the current detecting device <b>100</b> is attached) such as to project vertically.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The remaining section (the section in which the first and second fixed parts <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> are formed) is disposed on an upper surface <b>200</b>A of the battery <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The first fixed part <b>112</b> has a flat shape. A through-hole is formed in a portion of the flat shape. A nut <b>112</b>A is fixed to the upper side of the through-hole. On the other hand, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an attachment fitting <b>210</b> is attached to the negative-side terminal <b>202</b> of the battery <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The attachment fitting <b>210</b> serves both to attach the current detecting device <b>100</b> and as a wiring between the negative-side terminal <b>202</b> and the first fixed part <b>112</b>. A through-hole for inserting a bolt <b>211</b> in the upward direction is provided in the end of the attachment fitting <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">According to the embodiment, the bolt <b>211</b> is inserted upward through the through-hole in the attachment fitting <b>210</b>. The bolt <b>211</b> is then inserted into the nut <b>112</b>A in a state in which the attachment fitting <b>210</b> and the flat-shaped portion of the first fixed part <b>112</b> are sandwiched therebetween, and the first fixed part <b>112</b> is fastened and fixed to the attachment fitting <b>210</b>. Then, the attachment fitting <b>210</b> is attached to the negative-side terminal <b>202</b> of the battery <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In addition, a through-hole is provided near the end of the second fixed part <b>114</b>. A bolt <b>115</b> is inserted into the through-hole. On the other hand, a terminal <b>302</b> having a through-hole is provided at the end of a harness <b>300</b> that is electrically connected to the second fixed part <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The bolt <b>115</b> provided in the second fixed part <b>114</b> is inserted into the through-hole in the terminal <b>302</b>. The terminal <b>302</b> is fastened with a nut (not shown), thereby fixing the terminal <b>302</b> to the second fixed part <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">According to the present embodiment, the case <b>130</b> is formed by a resin material having favorable insulation and heat-transmission properties, such as PPS (Polyphenylenesulfide). The bus bar <b>110</b> is insert-molded using the resin material.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Next, the position of the second fixed part <b>114</b> will be described. As described above, the second fixed part <b>114</b> is disposed within an area (battery upper surface area) of the upper surface <b>200</b>A of the battery <b>200</b> in which the harness <b>300</b> is fixed and electrically connected. The second fixed part <b>114</b> is disposed in a position overlapping the first fixed part <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As a result of the second fixed part <b>114</b> being disposed on the battery upper surface area in this way, even when a load is applied to the second fixed part <b>114</b> when the harness <b>300</b> is fixed, the amount of deflection of the second fixed part <b>114</b> in the load direction can be suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Therefore, excessive moment can be prevented from being applied to the first fixed part <b>112</b> serving as a battery terminal. As a result, reduction in the fastening strength of the first fixed part <b>112</b> and damage to the first fixed part <b>112</b> can be prevented, and quality and vibration-resistance of the battery terminal during vehicle assembly can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Further, because the overall current detecting device <b>100</b> including the second fixed part <b>114</b> or the main section thereof is contained within the battery upper surface area, space on the battery upper surface <b>200</b>A can be effectively used, and mounting properties are improved.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Furthermore, although workability, such as battery replacement, deteriorates when auxiliary machines are mounted in the space on the battery upper surface <b>200</b>A, when the current detecting device <b>100</b> is mounted, the attachment fitting <b>210</b> is removed when battery replacement or the like is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Therefore, the current detecting device <b>100</b> can be removed at the same time, and deterioration of workability does not particularly occur.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram of a specific example of the circuit in the current detecting device <b>100</b>, and an example of connection with the battery <b>200</b> or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the circuit board <b>120</b> of the current detecting device <b>100</b> includes: a differential amplifier <b>10</b> connected to both ends of a shunt resistor <b>100</b>&#x2032; serving as a resistor formed by a portion of the bus bar <b>110</b>; a differential amplifier <b>12</b> connected to the positive terminal and the negative terminal of the battery <b>200</b>; a temperature detecting section <b>20</b>; a current detection processing section <b>30</b>; a voltage detection processing section <b>32</b>; a temperature detection processing section <b>34</b>; a battery status detecting section <b>36</b>; a charge controlling section <b>40</b>; communication input and output section (communication I/O) <b>50</b> and <b>52</b>; a CAN interface (CAN I/F) <b>60</b> that transmits and receives data based on CAN protocol; and a LIN interface (LIN I/F)<b>62</b> that transmits and receives data based on LIN protocol.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">One differential amplifier <b>10</b> amplifies the voltage across the shunt resistor <b>100</b>&#x2032;. The current detection processing section <b>30</b> detects the current flowing to the shunt resistor <b>100</b>&#x2032; based on the output voltage of the differential amplifier <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The differential amplifier <b>10</b> and the current detection processing section <b>30</b> configure a current detection circuit. The other differential amplifier <b>12</b> converts the voltage across the battery <b>200</b> (battery voltage) to an appropriate level. The voltage detection processing section <b>32</b> detects the battery voltage based on the output voltage of the differential amplifier <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The temperature detecting section <b>20</b> is configured by a voltage divider circuit composed of a resistor and a thermistor. The resistance value of the thermistor changes depending on the temperature and the divided voltage of the voltage divider circuit changes.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The temperature detection processing section <b>34</b> detects the temperature of the current detecting device <b>100</b> (temperature of the battery <b>200</b>) based on the output voltage (divided voltage) of the temperature detecting section <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The battery status detecting section <b>36</b> loads the detection values of the current detection processing section <b>30</b>, the voltage detection processing section <b>32</b>, and the temperature detection processing section <b>34</b>, and generates a battery status signal.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The current detection processing section <b>30</b>, the voltage detection processing section <b>32</b>, the temperature detection processing section <b>34</b>, and the battery status detecting section <b>36</b> configure a status detection sensor <b>38</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The charge controlling section <b>40</b> controls a power generation state of a vehicle power generator (G) <b>80</b> based on the battery status signal generated by the battery status detecting section <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The power generation control is performed by an instruction being sent to a power generation controlling device <b>82</b> mounted in the vehicle power generator <b>80</b>, via the communication I/O <b>52</b> and the LIN I/F <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The battery status signal generated by the battery status detecting section <b>36</b> is sent to a vehicle system via the communication I/O <b>50</b> and the CAN I/F <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The vehicle system <b>70</b> performs integrated control of an engine and various electrical loads based on the received battery status signal and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The differential amplifier <b>10</b> and the current detection processing section <b>30</b>, described above, configure the current detection circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">According to the above-described embodiment, the second fixed part <b>114</b> and the first fixed part <b>112</b> are disposed in positions such as to overlap with each other in the up-down direction. However, the positions may be shifted within a predetermined range.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Furthermore, the first fixed part <b>112</b> may be directly attached to the negative side terminal <b>220</b> of the battery <b>200</b> without the attachment fitting <b>210</b> therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a configuration of a variation example of the current detecting device. A current detecting device <b>100</b>A shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> differs from the current detecting device <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in that the attachment fitting <b>210</b> and the first fixed part <b>112</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> are integrally formed and, as a whole, form a first fixed part <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">In the current detecting device <b>100</b>A, when a fastening force is applied to the bolt <b>115</b> of the second fixed part <b>114</b> and a load is applied in the vertical direction when the harness <b>300</b> is attached, the second fixed part <b>114</b> becomes a point of action, and the first fixed part <b>212</b> attached to the negative side terminal <b>202</b> of the battery <b>200</b> becomes a point of support.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The respective positions of the first and second fixed parts <b>212</b> and <b>114</b> are set such that the center of the second fixed part <b>114</b> is disposed within a circular area that, from the center of the first fixed part <b>212</b>, has a radius that is the radius of the first fixed part <b>212</b> (radius of the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>) multiplied by a predetermined value. Specifically, the predetermined value is preferably 3.5.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">When a predetermined fastening force is applied to the second fixed part <b>114</b>, the moment force applied to the first fixed part <b>212</b> is proportional to the distance between the first fixed part <b>212</b> and the second fixed part <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">On the other hand, when the same moment force is applied, the moment force can be dispersed and received in proportion to the diameter of the first fixed part <b>212</b> (diameter of the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">Therefore, reduction in the fastening strength of the first fixed part <b>212</b> and damage to the first fixed part <b>212</b> can be suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Therefore, by limiting the ratio of the diameter of the first fixed part <b>212</b> to the distance between the first fixed part <b>212</b> and the second fixed part <b>114</b>, the moment force applied to the first fixed part <b>212</b> when the second fixed part <b>114</b> is fastened can be dispersed.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">As a result, quality and vibration-resistance of the first fixed part <b>212</b> can be improved with certainty.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">With the distance between the first fixed part <b>212</b> and the second fixed part <b>114</b> set to L, when the moment applied to the battery terminal in relation to (distance L/battery terminal radius) is actually determined, the moment becomes greater in proportion to (distance L/battery terminal radius).</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">It has been confirmed that, when (distance L/battery terminal radius) exceeds 3.5, the allowable moment in relation to damage to the battery terminal is exceeded.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a planar view of another variation example of the current detecting device. A current detecting device <b>100</b>B shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is disposed such that a large portion of the case <b>130</b>, excluding the connector <b>140</b>, and a circuit board <b>120</b>A accommodated therewithin are each parallel with the upper surface <b>200</b>A of the battery <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Unlike the bus bar <b>110</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and the like, a bus bar <b>110</b>A serving as a resistor has a C-shape rather than the folded shape. A current detecting circuit of the circuit board <b>120</b>A detects the current flowing to the bus bar <b>110</b>A based on the electrical potential at two points near both ends of the C-shaped bus bar <b>110</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In the current detecting device <b>100</b>B, the respective positions of the first and second fixed parts <b>212</b> and <b>114</b> are set such that the center of the second fixed part <b>114</b> is disposed within a circular area that, from the center of the first fixed part <b>212</b> is the radius of the second fixed part <b>114</b> multiplied by a predetermined value (preferably 3.5, as described above).</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">As a result, the moment force applied to the first fixed part <b>212</b> when the harness <b>300</b> is attached to the second fixed part <b>114</b> can be reduced, and quality and vibration-resistance of the first fixed part <b>212</b> can be improved with certainty. In particular, as a result of the bus bar <b>11</b>A being formed into the C-shape, the distance between the first and second fixed parts <b>212</b> and <b>114</b> can be shortened.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref> are diagrams of overall configurations of other variation examples of the current detecting device. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, the positional relationship between the first and second fixed parts, and a rough shape of the bus bar serving as a resistor are shown.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>, a current detecting device <b>100</b>C having an L-shaped bus bar <b>110</b>C is attached to the attachment fitting <b>210</b> attached to the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>. The first and section fixed parts <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> are both disposed on the battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref>, a current detecting device <b>100</b>D having an L-shaped bus bar <b>110</b>D is directly attached to the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>. The first and second fixed parts <b>212</b> and <b>114</b> are both disposed on the battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, a current detecting device <b>100</b>E having a linear bus bar <b>110</b>E that is folded back at two points is attached to the attachment fitting <b>210</b> attached to the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>. The first and second fixed parts <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> are both disposed on the battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> are diagrams of another variation example of the current detecting device. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> is a perspective view of the variation example of the current detecting device. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> is a diagram of the variation example of the current detecting device viewed from the upper surface <b>200</b>A of the battery <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>, a cut-out section <b>132</b> is provided in the case <b>130</b> of a current detecting device <b>100</b>F of the variation example, in a position corresponding to the interior of the battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">The first fixed part <b>112</b> and the second fixed part <b>114</b> are disposed in an area opposing the cut-out section <b>132</b> (adjacent area). In addition, the negative-side terminal <b>202</b> of the battery <b>200</b> is disposed within the cut-out section <b>132</b>. The second fixed part <b>114</b> and the negative-side terminal <b>202</b> are connected with the attachment fitting <b>210</b> therebetween (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">As a result of the cut-out section <b>132</b> being provided in the case <b>130</b> of the current detecting device <b>100</b>F, and the negative-side terminal <b>202</b>, the first fixed part <b>112</b>, and the second fixed part <b>114</b> being collectively disposed within or near the cut-out section <b>132</b> in this way, the distances between each fastening section thereof becomes short.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Therefore, the moment force applied to each section of the current detecting device <b>100</b>F during fastening or during use can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">The present disclosure is not limited to the above-described embodiment. Various modifications can be made without departing from the spirit of the present disclosure. According to the above-described embodiment, when the bus bar <b>100</b> or the like is integrated with a resistor is described. However, a resistor separate from the bus bar <b>100</b> or the like may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">According to the above-described embodiment, the second fixed part <b>114</b> to which the bolt <b>115</b> is attached and fixed is described. However, the present disclosure can also be applied to when the second fixed part is formed by an attachment hole being formed in a penetrating manner, or when the second fixed part is formed by a crimped terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">According to the above-described embodiment, when a portion of the current detecting device <b>100</b> or the like is disposed in an area other than the upper surface <b>200</b>A of the battery <b>200</b> is described. However, the entire current detecting device <b>100</b> or the like may be disposed on the battery upper surface area.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Furthermore, attachment may be performed in a state in which the lower surface of the second fixed part <b>114</b> (the lower surface of a head portion of the bolt <b>211</b> of the attachment fitting <b>210</b> to which the first fixed part <b>112</b> directly below the second fixed part <b>114</b> is attached, in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) is in contact with the battery upper surface <b>200</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">As a result, the amount of deflection of the second fixed part <b>114</b> to the lower side when the harness <b>300</b> is fixed to the second fixed part <b>114</b> can be kept to a minimum, and the moment force applied to the first fixed part <b>112</b> can be minimized.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">As a result, further improvement in the quality and vibration-resistance of the first fitting section <b>112</b> can be achieved.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">[Industrial Applicability]</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">As described above, in the present disclosure, as a result of the second fixed part <b>114</b> being disposed on the battery upper surface area, even when a load is applied when the harness <b>300</b> is fixed to the second fixed part <b>114</b>, the amount of deflection of the second fixed part <b>114</b> in the load direction can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">Therefore, excessive moment can be prevented from being applied to the first fitting section <b>112</b>. As a result, reduction in fastening strength of the first fixed part <b>112</b> and damage to the first fixed part <b>112</b> can be prevented, and the quality and vibration-resistance of the second fixed part <b>114</b> during vehicle assembly can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">Furthermore, because the overall current detecting device <b>100</b> including the second fixed part <b>114</b> or the main section thereof is contained within the battery upper surface area, the space on the battery upper surface <b>200</b>A can be effectively used, and mounting properties are enhanced.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A current detecting device that detects a current flowing through a battery terminal to a harness comprising: a fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected; a resistor inserted between the battery terminal and the fixed part; a circuit board in which a current detection circuit is mounted, the current detection circuit detecting current flowing through the resistor based on a potential difference between two points along an energizing direction of the resistor; and a case housing the resistor and the circuit board, wherein, the fixed part to which the harness is fixed and electrically connected is disposed within a battery upper surface area, and the fixed part is disposed within a circular area that is within the battery upper surface area and has a radius from the center of the battery terminal that is a radius of the battery terminal multiplied by a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, the predetermined value is 3.5.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the fixed part is any of a bolt that is attached and fixed, an attaching hole that is formed in a penetrating manner, and a crimped terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>attachment is performed in a state in which the lower surface of the fixed section is in contact with the battery upper surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the resistor has a non-linear shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the non-linear shape is a shape that is folded back midway and of which at least a portion is overlapping.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the non-linear shape is a C-shape or an L-shape.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>a cut-out section is formed in the case within the battery upper surface area,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the battery terminal and the fixed part are each provided such as to oppose the cut-out section, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a terminal provided in the battery within the battery upper surface area is disposed in the cut-out section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The current detecting device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein,
<claim-text>the battery terminal and the fixed part are each provided in a position adjacent to the cut-out section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
