<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623152-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623152</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13671459</doc-number>
<date>20121107</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>08</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>134 32</main-classification>
<further-classification>134 18</further-classification>
<further-classification> 15  1</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Reduction of entrance and exit marks left by a substrate-processing meniscus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0069326</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Woods et al.</name>
<date>20040400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>134 32</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0176252</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Goodman et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438692</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>18</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12725422</doc-number>
<date>20100316</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8317932</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13671459</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11612868</doc-number>
<date>20061219</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7703462</doc-number>
<date>20100427</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12725422</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11537501</doc-number>
<date>20060929</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7946303</doc-number>
<date>20110524</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11612868</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130061879</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130314</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Donnell</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ravkin</last-name>
<first-name>Mike</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>de Larios</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Donnell</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ravkin</last-name>
<first-name>Mike</first-name>
<address>
<city>Sunnyvale</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="003" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>de Larios</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<address>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Martine Penilla Group, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lam Research Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Golightly</last-name>
<first-name>Eric</first-name>
<department>1714</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A substrate is moved in a linear direction simultaneously between a processing face of an upper proximity head and a processing face of a lower proximity head. As the substrate is moved, a first meniscus of processing liquid is generated between the processing face of the upper proximity head and a top surface of the substrate, and a second meniscus of processing liquid is generated between the processing face of the lower proximity head and a bottom surface of the substrate. The first meniscus has a meniscus protrusion extending in the linear direction in which the substrate is moved and positioned on a trailing side of the first meniscus relative to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved. The meniscus protrusion is centered on the substrate relative to a diameter of the substrate as measured perpendicular to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.14mm" wi="161.12mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.33mm" wi="158.07mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="240.45mm" wi="168.23mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="247.31mm" wi="156.72mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="235.71mm" wi="167.56mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="178.48mm" wi="160.10mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="239.10mm" wi="170.26mm" file="US08623152-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="238.42mm" wi="163.49mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623152-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="222.76mm" wi="91.27mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08623152-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CLAIM OF PRIORITY</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/725,422, filed on Mar. 16, 2010, entitled &#x201c;Reduction of Entrance and Exit Marks Left by a Substrate-Processing Meniscus,&#x201d; issued as U.S. Pat. No. 8,317,932, on Nov. 27, 2012, which is a divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/612,868, filed on Dec. 19, 2006, entitled &#x201c;Reduction of Entrance and Exit Marks Left by a Substrate-Processing Meniscus,&#x201d; issued as U.S. Pat. No. 7,703,462, on Apr. 27, 2010, which is a continuation-in-part application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/537,501, filed on Sep. 29, 2006, entitled &#x201c;Carrier For Reducing Entrance And/Or Exit Marks Left By A Substrate-Processing Meniscus,&#x201d; issued as U.S. Pat. No. 7,946,303, on May 24, 2011. Each of the above-identified patent applications is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present Application is related to the following U.S. patents and U.S. patent applications, all of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety: U.S. Pat. No. 6,488,040, issued on Dec. 3, 2002 to De Larios, et al. and entitled, &#x201c;Method And Apparatus For Drying Semiconductor Wafer Surfaces Using A Plurality Of Inlets And Outlets Held In Close Proximity To The Wafer Surfaces;&#x201d; U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/330,843, filed on Dec. 24, 2002 and entitled, &#x201c;Meniscus, Vacuum, IPA Vapor Drying Manifold;&#x201d; U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/330,897, also filed on Dec. 24, 2002, entitled, &#x201c;System For Substrate Processing With Meniscus, Vacuum, IPA Vapor, Drying Manifold;&#x201d; U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/404,692, filed Mar. 31, 2003 and entitled, &#x201c;Methods And Systems For Processing A Substrate Using A Dynamic Liquid Meniscus;&#x201d; and U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/817,620, which was filed on Apr. 1, 2004, entitled, &#x201c;Substrate Meniscus Interface And Methods For Operation.&#x201d;</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the semiconductor chip fabrication industry, it is necessary to clean and dry a substrate after a fabrication operation has been performed that leaves unwanted residues on the surfaces of the substrate. Examples of such a fabrication operations include plasma etching (e.g., tungsten etch back (WEB)) and chemical mechanical polishing (CMP). In CMP, a substrate is placed in a holder that pushes a substrate surface against a polishing surface. The polishing surface uses a slurry which consists of chemicals and abrasive materials. Unfortunately, the CMP process tends to leave an accumulation of slurry particles and residues on the substrate surface. If left on the substrate, the unwanted residual material and particles may defects. In some cases, such defects may cause devices on the substrate to become inoperable. Cleaning the substrate after a fabrication operation removes unwanted residues and particulates.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">After a substrate has been wet cleaned, the substrate must be dried effectively to prevent water or cleaning fluid, (hereinafter, &#x201c;fluid&#x201d;) remnants from leaving residues on the substrate. If the cleaning fluid on the substrate surface is allowed to evaporate, as usually happens when droplets form, residues or contaminants previously dissolved in the fluid will remain on the substrate surface after evaporation and can form spots. To prevent evaporation from taking place, the cleaning fluid must be removed as quickly as possible without the formation of droplets on the substrate surface. In an attempt to accomplish this, one of several different drying techniques are employed such as spin-drying, IPA, or Marangoni drying. All of these drying techniques utilize some form of a moving liquid/gas interface on a substrate surface, which, if properly maintained, results in drying of a substrate surface without the formation of droplets. Unfortunately, if the moving liquid/gas interface breaks down, as often happens with all of the aforementioned drying methods, droplets form and evaporation occurs resulting in contaminants being left on the substrate surface.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In view of the foregoing, there is a need for improved cleaning systems and methods that provide efficient cleaning while reducing the likelihood of marks from dried fluid droplets.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Broadly speaking, the present invention fills these needs by providing various techniques for reduction of entrance and exit marks caused by dried fluid droplets left by a substrate-processing meniscus.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It should be appreciated that the present invention can be implemented in numerous ways, including as a process, an apparatus, a system, a device, or a method. Several inventive embodiments of the present invention are described below.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one embodiment, a proximity head for generating and maintaining a meniscus for processing a substrate is provided. The proximity head includes a plurality of meniscus nozzles formed on a face of the proximity head, the nozzles being configured to supply liquid to the meniscus, a plurality of vacuum ports formed on the face of the proximity head, the vacuum ports being arranged to completely surround the plurality of meniscus nozzles. A plurality of main gas nozzles may be formed on the face of the proximity head, the main gas nozzles at least partially surrounding the vacuum ports. The proximity head further includes means for reducing a size and frequency of entrance and/or exit marks at a leading edge and a trailing edge on the substrate by aiding and encouraging liquid from the meniscus to evacuate a gap between the substrate and the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another embodiment, a method for processing a substrate using a meniscus formed by upper and lower proximity heads is provided. In the method the substrate is placed on a carrier, which is passed through a meniscus generated between upper and lower proximity heads. The carrier has an opening sized for receiving the substrate and a plurality of support pins for supporting the substrate within the opening, the opening being slightly larger than the substrate such that a gap exists between the substrate and the opening. Each of the upper and lower proximity heads include a plurality of meniscus nozzles formed on a face of the proximity head, the nozzles being configured to supply liquid to the meniscus; a plurality of vacuum ports formed on the face of the proximity head, the vacuum ports being arranged to completely surround the plurality of meniscus nozzles; and a plurality of main gas nozzles formed on the face of the proximity head, the main gas nozzles at least partially surrounding the vacuum ports. The method further includes a step for reducing a size and frequency of at least one of entrance or exit marks on substrates by encouraging liquid from the meniscus to evacuate the gap using the upper and lower proximity heads.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Since introduction by the present Assignee of the use of a moving meniscus generated by a proximity head for use in cleaning, processing, and drying semiconductor wafers, it has become possible to wet and dry a substrate with a very low risk of droplets forming on the substrate surface. This technology has been very successful at preventing any droplets from being left on the active device region of the wafer after the meniscus is removed. However, the meniscus does occasionally tend to leave a small droplet at the entrance and exit points at the leading and trailing edges of the substrate on the exclusion zone as the substrate passes through the meniscus. The exclusion zone is a margin that extends from the active device region to the edge of the substrate, where microelectronic structures are not formed. On occasion, entrance and exit marks can become mains surface marks, especially on hydrophilic wafers. Therefore, it is preferable that instances of such entrance and exit marks are reduced or eliminated.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, illustrating by way of example the principles of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The present invention will be readily understood by the following detailed description in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, and like reference numerals designate like structural elements.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a perspective view of an exemplary implementation of a proximity head apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a schematic representation of an upper proximity head.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</figref>, <b>3</b>B, <b>3</b>C, and <b>3</b>D illustrate a substrate exiting a meniscus generated by upper and lower proximity heads.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a perspective view of a gap between a carrier and a substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a cross section view of a meniscus as it is completing transition onto a carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> shows a top view of the lower proximity head having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6B</figref>, <b>6</b>C, and <b>6</b>D illustrate various meniscus protrusion sizes and shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a plan view of a carrier, substrate, and meniscus perimeter.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A</figref>, <b>8</b>B, and <b>8</b>C show an exemplary embodiment of a proximity head having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</figref> show an exemplary embodiment of a proximity head having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows another embodiment of a proximity head having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. However, it will be apparent to one skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without some of these specific details. In other instances, well known process operations and implementation details have not been described in detail in order to avoid unnecessarily obscuring the invention. The term, &#x201c;meniscus,&#x201d; as used herein, refers to a volume of liquid bounded and contained in part by surface tension of the liquid. The meniscus is also controllable and can be moved over a surface in the contained shape. In specific embodiments, the meniscus is maintained by the delivery of fluids to a surface while also removing the fluids so that the meniscus remains controllable. Furthermore, the meniscus shape can be controlled by precision fluid delivery and removal systems that are in part interfaced with a controller a computing system, which may be networked.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an exemplary implementation of a proximity head apparatus <b>100</b>. In this example, substrate <b>160</b> is positioned within a carrier <b>150</b> which passes between upper proximity head <b>110</b> and lower proximity head <b>120</b> in the direction of arrow <b>152</b>. Upper and lower proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, form a meniscus of fluid between them. Carrier <b>150</b> may be connected to some apparatus (not shown) for causing carrier <b>150</b> to move between upper and lower proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> in the direction of arrow <b>166</b>. In one embodiment, a substrate <b>160</b> is deposited on carrier <b>150</b> at a first location on one side of proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, and removed when carrier <b>150</b> arrives at a second location on an opposite side of proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>. Carrier <b>150</b> may then pass back through proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, or over, under, or around proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, back to the first location, where a next substrate is deposited, and the process is repeated.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It should be noted that, while in the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the substrate moves through proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> in the direction of arrow <b>152</b>, it is also possible for the substrate to remain stationary while the proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, pass over and under the substrate, so long as the substrate moves with respect to the proximity heads. Furthermore, the orientation of the substrate as it passes between the proximity heads is arbitrary. That is, the substrate is not required to be oriented horizontally, but can instead be vertically oriented or at any angle.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In certain embodiments, a controller <b>130</b>, which may be a general purpose or specific purpose computer system whose functionality is determined by logic circuits or software, or both, controls the movement of carrier <b>150</b> and the flow of fluids to upper and lower proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a schematic representation of upper proximity head <b>110</b>. Proximity head includes a plurality of central meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> formed in face <b>111</b> of proximity head <b>110</b> through which a liquid is supplied that forms meniscus <b>200</b>. The liquid may be deionized water, a cleaning solution, or other liquid designed to process, clean, or rinse substrate <b>160</b>. A plurality of ports <b>114</b> apply a vacuum at a perimeter of meniscus <b>200</b>. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> aspirate liquid from meniscus <b>200</b> and surrounding fluid, such as air or other gas supplied by main gas nozzles <b>112</b>. In certain embodiments, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> surround vacuum ports <b>114</b> and supply isopropyl alcohol vapor, nitrogen, a mixture thereof, or other gas or gases or gas/liquid fluids. Depending on the implementation, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> and fluid supplied therefrom may be provided to aid in maintaining a coherent liquid/gas interface at the surface of meniscus <b>200</b>. In one embodiment, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> are absent or are not used. In another embodiment, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> supply carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>) or a mixture of N<sub>2 </sub>and isopropyl alcohol (IPA) vapor. The lower proximity head <b>120</b>, not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, may be provided as a minor image to the upper proximity head, and may operate in a similar manner. More details relating to proximity head structure and operation are incorporated by reference in the Cross Reference to Related Art section above. In particular, U.S. patent application Ser. Nos. 10/261,839, 10/330,843, and 10/330,897 are referenced for additional details relating to proximity head structure and operation.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3D</figref> illustrate a substrate <b>160</b> exiting meniscus <b>200</b> generated by upper and lower proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, substrate <b>160</b> extends all the way through meniscus <b>200</b> such that its leading edge <b>162</b> and trailing edge <b>164</b> lie on opposite sides of meniscus <b>200</b>. It should be noted that, typically, substrate <b>160</b> will be circular and while carrier <b>150</b> is shown outside of meniscus <b>200</b>, parts of carrier <b>150</b> may be in contact with meniscus <b>200</b>, although not visible in this Figure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref>, meniscus <b>200</b> is transitioning from substrate <b>160</b> to carrier <b>150</b>. Carrier <b>150</b> may be slightly thicker in cross section than substrate <b>160</b>. For example, substrate <b>160</b> may be about 0.80 mm thick whereas the carrier may be about 1.5 mm thick. Thus, as meniscus <b>200</b> transitions onto carrier <b>150</b>, a certain amount of meniscus liquid is displaced by carrier <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref>, meniscus <b>200</b> is transitioning completely off substrate <b>160</b> and onto carrier <b>150</b>. At this time, the trailing edge of meniscus <b>200</b> is still in contact with trailing edge <b>164</b> of substrate <b>160</b>. Forces acting on meniscus <b>200</b> at this point in time is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> below.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</figref>, the meniscus has completely transitioned off of substrate <b>160</b>, leaving a small droplet <b>202</b> of meniscus liquid on the exclusion zone of substrate <b>160</b> at the trailing edge <b>164</b> of substrate <b>160</b>. Droplet <b>202</b>, if allowed to dry can leave a spot formed of dissolved or entrained elements, the spot being referred to herein as an exit mark. If the substrate surface is hydrophilic, droplet <b>202</b> can migrate to the active device region of the substrate, which can cause defects in devices formed thereon. A number of factors are believed to contribute to the presence and size of small droplet <b>202</b> at the trailing edge <b>164</b> of substrate <b>160</b>. It should be noted that an entrance mark at leading edge <b>162</b> can be formed in a similar manner as leading edge <b>162</b> exits meniscus <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a perspective view of a gap <b>158</b> between a carrier <b>150</b> and a substrate <b>160</b>. Meniscus perimeter <b>204</b> shows the area of contact of the meniscus with carrier <b>150</b> and substrate <b>160</b>. The meniscus is traveling in the direction indicated by arrow <b>208</b>. As the meniscus transitions off of waver <b>160</b>, meniscus fluid in gap <b>158</b> is swept by the edge of the meniscus along the direction of arrows <b>206</b>. As the trailing edge <b>210</b> of meniscus perimeter <b>204</b> reaches trailing edge <b>164</b> of substrate <b>160</b>, fluid is directed toward a point <b>212</b> in gap adjacent to the substrate's trailing edge <b>164</b>. It should be recognized that fluid in gap <b>158</b> is constantly flowing out of gap <b>158</b> as the meniscus transitions onto carrier <b>150</b>. Therefore, the fluid is not expected to literally follow arrows <b>206</b>, but rather that a vector component of the direction of flow lies on arrows <b>206</b>, resulting in a build-up of fluid at point <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a cross section view of meniscus <b>200</b> at point <b>212</b> as it is completing transition onto carrier <b>150</b>. At this point, meniscus <b>200</b> is still attached to trailing edge <b>164</b> of substrate <b>160</b>. Carrier <b>150</b> may be somewhat thicker than substrate <b>160</b>, inhibiting the flow of liquid away from substrate <b>160</b> along arrows <b>214</b>. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> draw fluid including meniscus liquid and surrounding gas, exerting a force on meniscus liquid indicated by arrows <b>216</b>. An additional force may be exerted by fluid exiting main gas nozzles <b>112</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) which, if provided, push inward against the gas/liquid interface of meniscus <b>200</b> as shown by arrows <b>218</b>. A gravitational force <b>221</b> is also exerted against meniscus <b>200</b>. And, if substrate <b>160</b> is hydrophilic, then an attraction to meniscus liquid can cause hydrogen bonding forces to pull water back onto substrate <b>160</b>, as represented by arrows <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref> shows a face <b>121</b> of lower proximity head <b>120</b> having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency by enhancing the flow of meniscus liquid from the carrier-substrate gap as the meniscus transitions off of the substrate. As described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, lower proximity head <b>120</b> includes a plurality of centrally disposed meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> for supplying meniscus liquid, a plurality of vacuum ports <b>114</b> disposed so that they completely surround meniscus nozzles <b>116</b>. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> aspirate meniscus liquid and surrounding gas. Optionally, a plurality of main gas nozzles <b>112</b> at least partially surround vacuum ports <b>114</b> and supply a gas or gas/liquid mixture to help maintain the integrity of the gas/liquid interface of the meniscus. Meniscus nozzles <b>116</b>, vacuum ports <b>114</b>, and, optionally, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> are formed in face <b>121</b> of proximity head <b>120</b>. In one embodiment, a means for reducing the size and frequency of entrance and exit marks is provided by a centrally located protrusion on the trailing side <b>122</b> of the meniscus. The arrangement of vacuum ports <b>114</b> determines the shape of the meniscus. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows lower proximity head <b>120</b> forming the centrally located protrusion by positioning vacuum ports <b>114</b> and adjacent main gas nozzles <b>112</b> farther from an axis defined by meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> at a center portion <b>125</b> of lower proximity head <b>120</b>. A corresponding central protrusion is formed on an upper proximity head <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) so that they both generate a centrally located meniscus protrusion on the trailing side of the meniscus.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</figref> shows an outline of exemplary meniscus configuration formed by the proximity head of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</figref>. The meniscus includes a main portion <b>225</b> and a protrusion <b>220</b>. The protrusion <b>220</b> may have various shapes. For example, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, the protrusion <b>220</b>A has straight leading, the protrusion <b>220</b>B has two convex leading edges extending smoothly from the meniscus to a central point, the protrusion <b>220</b>C has concave leading edges, and the protrusion <b>220</b>D has a complex leading edge shape. In one embodiment, the leading edges are concave as presented in <b>220</b>C, with the leading edges having the same radius of curvature as the substrate <b>160</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</figref>, a minimum protrusion size is shown having a protrusion extension <b>224</b> equal to the distance between two adjacent vacuum ports and a protrusion width <b>226</b> equal to the distance between three adjacent vacuum ports. However, the protrusion can be of any suitable size. In one embodiment, for example, the protrusion has an extension equal to a length defined by the distance of 6 adjacent vacuum ports and a width defined by the distance of 12 vacuum ports, with each vacuum port being about 0.06 inches in diameter and having a 0.12 inch pitch (center-to-center spacing).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a plan view of carrier <b>150</b>, substrate <b>160</b>, and meniscus perimeter <b>204</b> at a first position <b>230</b> and at a second position <b>232</b>. Carrier <b>150</b> moves in a direction indicated by arrow <b>166</b> and/or meniscus moves in a direction indicated by arrow <b>208</b>. Carrier <b>150</b> includes a plurality of support pins <b>153</b>, each having substrate support and centering features (not shown), to ensure a uniform substrate-carrier gap <b>158</b> between substrate <b>160</b> and carrier <b>150</b>. In one embodiment, carrier <b>150</b> has sloped edges at the leading side <b>154</b> and trailing side <b>156</b> to prevent abrupt changes in the volume of meniscus liquid as carrier <b>150</b> enters and exits the meniscus. For example, carrier <b>150</b> has six sides with two leading edges <b>155</b> each at an angle &#x3b8; from transverse and together forming a centrally-located point, and corresponding trailing edges <b>159</b> each forming an angle &#x3b8; to the transverse direction and together forming a centrally-located point. In one embodiment, &#x3b8; is about 15 degrees. Other shapes that don't result in a rapid displacement of meniscus liquid are also possible, such as a trapezoid or parallelogram, wherein leading and trailing edges are at an angle other than a right angle to the direction of travel of the carrier or are at an angle to (i.e., not parallel with) the leading and trailing edges of the meniscus.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At a certain point in time, the meniscus is located at position <b>230</b> and traveling in a direction <b>208</b> with respect to carrier <b>150</b>. At a later time, the meniscus is located at position <b>232</b>. At position <b>232</b>, protrusion <b>220</b> extends across gap <b>158</b>. Because of protrusion <b>220</b>, the trailing edge <b>210</b> of meniscus perimeter <b>204</b> is not a straight line tangent to gap <b>158</b>. As a result, fluid exiting point <b>212</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) has additional time to escape from gap <b>158</b> due to the presence of protrusion <b>220</b>. Since the fluid has additional time to escape from gap <b>158</b>, it is less likely to remain attached to substrate <b>160</b> and leave a mark.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Protrusion <b>220</b> can also be effective in reducing an entrance mark formed at a leading edge <b>162</b> of substrate <b>160</b>. In one embodiment, a centrally-located indentation is formed on the leading edge of the meniscus (not shown) to further reduce instances of entrance marks. It should be noted that the shape of protrusion <b>220</b>, including the width of protrusion <b>220</b> and the depth of protrusion <b>220</b>, that is the amount of extension of protrusion <b>220</b>, may vary depending on implementation, but in one embodiment, is sufficiently narrow and provides sufficient extension to improve the flow of meniscus liquid from the carrier-substrate gap.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A</figref>, <b>8</b>B, and <b>8</b>C show an exemplary embodiment of a proximity head <b>250</b> having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency by enhancing the flow of meniscus liquid from the carrier-substrate gap as the meniscus transitions off of the substrate. In particular, proximity head <b>250</b>, which can be an upper or lower proximity head, includes centrally disposed gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b> formed on face <b>251</b> to provide additional supply of gas to push against meniscus <b>200</b> as it transitions completely off of substrate <b>160</b>, as best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</figref>. As mentioned above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the meniscus touching substrate <b>160</b> and substrate-carrier gap <b>158</b> is subject to competing forces, including surface tension forces that both draw the meniscus onto the substrate and inhibit transitioning onto the carrier, suction forces drawing the meniscus off of both the substrate and carrier, and gravity, which pulls the meniscus liquid into substrate-carrier gap <b>158</b>. In addition, a gas flow can exert positive pressure on meniscus <b>200</b>, and therefore help counter surface tension forces which can result in entrance and exit marks. Main gas nozzles <b>112</b> deliver carbon dioxide or nitrogen and/or isopropyl alcohol vapor to the meniscus to aid in meniscus containment and wafer drying. However, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> cannot readily be used to aid in entrance and exit mark elimination because main gas nozzles <b>112</b>, which are arranged around at least a portion of vacuum ports <b>114</b>, affect the entire meniscus, or a substantial volume thereof. One or more gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b>, on the other hand, provide a localized &#x201c;fan,&#x201d; or &#x201c;curtain&#x201d; of gas flow, which can be independently controlled, and therefore be selectively applied to the substrate/meniscus interface only in the areas of entrance and exit mark formation. By applying additional pressure against meniscus <b>200</b> just as the trailing edge of meniscus <b>200</b> transitions on or off of substrate <b>160</b> using gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b> meniscus liquid exiting gap <b>158</b> is pushed back into the meniscus so that it does not stick to the wafer, thereby reducing the size and likelihood of entrance and exit mark formation, and prevent wafer defects.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In certain embodiments, a plurality of central fluid port zones provide for additional pressure during just prior and during transition by the trailing edge of the meniscus between substrate <b>160</b> and carrier <b>150</b>. In this embodiment, one or more centrally disposed gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b> are surrounded by one or more additional zones tertiary nozzles <b>254</b>, visible in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A and 8B</figref>. Any number of zones can be provided, each being independently controlled by controller <b>130</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) to supply gas pressure against meniscus <b>200</b> at appropriate times during meniscus transition. Controller <b>130</b> may include a mechanical or computer initiated timing mechanism. For example, a mechanical timing mechanism may employ a proximity sensor (not shown) to activate gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b> (or gap evacuation gas nozzles <b>252</b> and secondary gap evacuation nozzles <b>254</b>), wherein the proximity sensor responds to a position of carrier <b>150</b> with respect to upper and lower proximity heads <b>110</b>, <b>120</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). A computer initiated timing mechanism may include position information from a robotic actuating mechanism (not shown) used to convey carrier <b>150</b> through the meniscus.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</figref> show an exemplary embodiment of a proximity head <b>260</b> having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency by enhancing the flow of meniscus liquid from the carrier-substrate gap as the meniscus transitions off of the substrate. In particular, proximity head <b>260</b> includes a partitioned vacuum manifold to provide a plurality of vacuum port zones, each connected to an independent vacuum source. By providing an independent vacuum source to a central zone <b>262</b>, which has vacuum ports formed into face <b>216</b> at a location corresponding to the trailing edge of the meniscus, vacuum shunting is minimized, which enhances flow of meniscus liquid exiting the carrier-substrate gap <b>158</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Vacuum shunting occurs when a few vacuum ports are overrun with liquid. In such cases, the pressure drop across faceplate <b>265</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</figref>) may be insufficient to clear the liquid, causing gases and fluid from the meniscus to divert to nearby vacuum ports. When a significant volume of water is trapped between the wafer and carrier, vacuum shunting can occur just as the meniscus is transitioning completely off the substrate. This reduces the available suction at the exact spot where is most needed: at the trailing edge of the substrate as the substrate exits the meniscus. This reduced availability of vacuum can therefore reduce the removal of liquid from the substrate-carrier gap, which can lead to exit mark formation. A similar effect can occur at the leading edge of the substrate, which can cause an entrance mark to form.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">By providing an independent vacuum source to a central zone <b>262</b> of vacuum ports centrally positioned on the trailing edge of the meniscus, vacuum shunting is minimized, which enhances flow of meniscus liquid exiting the carrier-substrate gap <b>158</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A and 9B</figref>, a plurality of meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> formed into face <b>261</b> provide meniscus liquid to the meniscus <b>200</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Surrounding meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> are vacuum ports <b>114</b>, which aspirate a mixture of meniscus liquid and surrounding gas. At least partially surrounding vacuum ports <b>114</b>, main gas nozzles <b>112</b> may be provided to supply gas or gas/liquid mixture, which can aid in maintaining meniscus integrity. In one embodiment, vacuum ports <b>114</b> are divided into a plurality of zones, including a first zone <b>262</b> centrally disposed along the trailing edge <b>204</b> of proximity head <b>260</b> and at least one additional zone <b>263</b>, <b>264</b> comprising the remaining vacuum ports <b>114</b>. The additional zone(s) can include a secondary zone <b>264</b> comprising a plurality of vacuum ports <b>114</b> on either side of first zone <b>262</b>, and tertiary zone <b>263</b> comprising the remaining vacuum ports <b>114</b>. Each zone <b>263</b>, <b>262</b>, <b>264</b> has a corresponding dedicated, independent manifold <b>271</b>, <b>272</b>, <b>274</b>, and each manifold <b>271</b>, <b>272</b>, <b>274</b>, is in fluid communication with a corresponding connection <b>281</b>, <b>282</b>, <b>284</b> to a vacuum source <b>280</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows another embodiment of a proximity head having means for reducing entrance and exit mark size and frequency by enhancing the flow of meniscus liquid from the carrier-substrate gap as the meniscus transitions off of the substrate. Proximity head <b>290</b> includes a plurality of meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> formed into face <b>291</b> for supplying meniscus liquid. Surrounding meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> on face <b>291</b> is a plurality of vacuum ports <b>114</b> for aspirating meniscus liquid and surrounding gases. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> includes a first row <b>293</b> of vacuum ports <b>114</b> that completely surrounds meniscus nozzles <b>116</b> and row <b>295</b> of vacuum ports <b>114</b> adjacent a central portion of the trailing edge <b>298</b> of proximity head <b>290</b>. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> lying in first row <b>293</b> are connected to a common manifold as described above for zone <b>263</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</figref>. Vacuum ports <b>114</b> lying in second row <b>295</b> are connected to one of one or more additional manifolds. In one embodiment, ports <b>114</b> in row <b>295</b> at zone <b>292</b> centrally disposed on the trailing side of proximity head <b>290</b> are connected to one manifold (not shown), and ports <b>114</b> in row <b>295</b> in zones <b>294</b> are connected to another manifold (not shown). Each manifold includes an independent connection to a vacuum source as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">It should be noted that either or both the upper and lower proximity heads and the carrier can be controlled by a computer system such that the rate of travel of the carrier with respect to the proximity heads may be constant or vary depending on the position of the carrier with respect to the proximity heads. In some embodiments, for example, the rate of travel of the carrier may be slower as the meniscus transitions on and off the substrate, thereby providing additional time for meniscus liquid to be flow out of the carrier-substrate gap. In addition, the gas flow through gas nozzles <b>112</b>, <b>252</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8C</figref>) and vacuum supplied to vacuum ports <b>114</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A-10</figref>) can be mechanically and/or computer controlled, either to time the activation/deactivation of suction, or to vary the flow rates depending on the relative position of the carrier with respect to the proximity heads. The computer control can be implemented using hardware logic or in conjunction with a multipurpose computer processor, using a computer program written to control the movement and/or application of suction. In certain embodiments, a computer program also controls the volume and/or constituents of fluid supplied to the meniscus. Therefore, the computer program can define fluid recipes specifically tailored to each of a plurality of given applications.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">With the above embodiments in mind, it should be understood that the invention can employ various computer-implemented operations involving data stored in computer systems. These operations are those requiring physical manipulation of physical quantities. Usually, though not necessarily, these quantities take the form of electrical or magnetic signals capable of being stored, transferred, combined, compared and otherwise manipulated. Further, the manipulations performed are often referred to in terms such as producing, identifying, determining, or comparing.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Any of the operations described herein that form part of the invention are useful machine operations. The invention also relates to a device or an apparatus for performing these operations. The apparatus can be specially constructed for the required purpose, or the apparatus can be a general-purpose computer selectively activated or configured by a computer program stored in the computer. In particular, various general-purpose machines can be used with computer programs written in accordance with the teachings herein, or it may be more convenient to construct a more specialized apparatus to perform the required operations.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The invention can also be embodied as computer readable code on a computer readable medium. The computer readable medium is any data storage device that can store data, which can be thereafter be read by a computer system. The computer readable medium also includes an electromagnetic carrier wave in which the computer code is embodied. Examples of the computer readable medium include hard drives, network attached storage (NAS), read-only memory, random-access memory, CD-ROMs, CD-Rs, CD-RWs, magnetic tapes and other optical and non-optical data storage devices. The computer readable medium can also be distributed over a network-coupled computer system so that the computer readable code is stored and executed in a distributed fashion.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Embodiments of the present invention can be processed on a single computer, or using multiple computers or computer components which are interconnected. A computer, as used herein, shall include a standalone computer system having its own processor(s), its own memory, and its own storage, or a distributed computing system, which provides computer resources to a networked terminal. In some distributed computing systems, users of a computer system may actually be accessing component parts that are shared among a number of users. The users can therefore access a virtual computer over a network, which will appear to the user as a single computer customized and dedicated for a single user.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail for purposes of clarity of understanding, it will be apparent that certain changes and modifications may be practiced within the scope of the appended claims. Accordingly, the present embodiments are to be considered as illustrative and not restrictive, and the invention is not to be limited to the details given herein, but may be modified within the scope and equivalents of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for processing a substrate, comprising:
<claim-text>moving a substrate in a linear direction simultaneously between a processing face of an upper proximity head and a processing face of a lower proximity head; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>as the substrate is moved in the linear direction simultaneously between the processing faces of the upper and lower proximity heads, generating a first meniscus of processing liquid between the processing face of the upper proximity head and a top surface of the substrate, and generating a second meniscus of processing liquid between the processing face of the lower proximity head and a bottom surface of the substrate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first meniscus is generated to have a first meniscus protrusion that extends in the linear direction in which the substrate is moved and is positioned on a trailing side of the first meniscus relative to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first meniscus protrusion is centered on the substrate relative to a diameter of the substrate as measured perpendicular to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the processing face of the upper proximity head is positioned substantially parallel to the top surface of the substrate, and wherein the processing face of the lower proximity head is positioned substantially parallel to the bottom surface of the substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>applying vacuum from the upper proximity head along a trailing side of the first meniscus relative to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved to confine the first meniscus.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the vacuum is applied from the upper proximity head to have a protrusion shape in a corresponding vacuum force at a position centered on the substrate relative to a diameter of the substrate as measured perpendicular to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved, whereby the protrusion shape in the vacuum applied from the upper proximity head enables generation of the first meniscus protrusion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>disposing gas from the upper proximity head in a substantially uniform manner within a first region that completely and conformally surrounds an outer periphery of the vacuum applied from the upper proximity head.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>disposing additional gas from the upper proximity head in a first localized area outside of the first region in which gas is disposed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the first localized area is centered on the substrate relative to a diameter of the substrate as measured perpendicular to the linear direction in which the substrate is moved.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>placing the substrate on a carrier having an opening sized for receiving the substrate and a plurality of support pins for supporting the substrate within the opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving the carrier in the linear direction to cause moving of the substrate in the linear direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>evacuating processing liquids of the first and second meniscuses from a gap between a radial perimeter of the substrate and the carrier as the substrate is moved in the linear direction simultaneously between the processing face of the upper proximity head and the processing face of the lower proximity head.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first meniscus is generated such that the trailing side of the first meniscus is not a straight line tangent to a radial perimeter of the substrate when the first meniscus protrusion crosses the radial perimeter of the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
