<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622621-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622621</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13598817</doc-number>
<date>20120830</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2011-213014</doc-number>
<date>20110928</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>32</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384445</main-classification>
<further-classification>384490</further-classification>
<further-classification>384512</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Rolling bearing apparatus, manufacture method thereof, and hard disk apparatus</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5882122</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Noguchi et al.</name>
<date>19990300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>384490</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6010247</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mouri et al.</name>
<date>20000100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>384517</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7056029</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Mori et al.</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>384517</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8221003</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Smith et al.</name>
<date>20120700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>384504</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11182543</doc-number>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>360 9908</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>360244</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3602346</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384490</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384504</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384520</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384543</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384517</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384518</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384563</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384584</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384445</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>384604</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130077192</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130328</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kosaka</last-name>
<first-name>Takayuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiba</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ozawa</last-name>
<first-name>Akio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiba</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kosaka</last-name>
<first-name>Takayuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiba</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ozawa</last-name>
<first-name>Akio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiba</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Adam &#x26; Wilks</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Seiko Instruments Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Neyzari</last-name>
<first-name>Ali</first-name>
<department>2686</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">To prevent a problem due to gas produced from an adhesive and to improve the productivity of a rolling bearing apparatus. The present invention provides a method of manufacturing a rolling bearing apparatus, including fitting a first rolling bearing and a second rolling bearing to a first member each in a pressed state, pressing the inner races of the first and second rolling bearings in a direction in which they are closer to each other in the axial direction with a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first and second rolling bearings, and welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the pressed second rolling bearing in the axial direction to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="142.49mm" wi="133.27mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="180.09mm" wi="150.03mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="238.93mm" wi="139.70mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="172.55mm" wi="138.51mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="245.28mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="228.60mm" wi="172.04mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="226.82mm" wi="148.34mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="203.71mm" wi="152.40mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="210.06mm" wi="172.04mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="242.99mm" wi="167.39mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="200.83mm" wi="159.85mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="201.42mm" wi="157.56mm" file="US08622621-20140107-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a rolling bearing apparatus and a method of manufacturing the same, and a hard disk apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Background Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A method of manufacturing a rolling bearing apparatus is conventionally known which includes a pair of rolling bearings, a rotation shaft fitted to an inner race, and a housing for fitting of an outer race of the rolling bearing (see, for example, JP-A-11-182543).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the manufacture method described in JP-A-11-182543, the inner race of the rolling bearing is pressed to the rotation shaft, and the inner race is fixed to an outer peripheral face of the rotation shaft with an adhesive force using an adhesive while a predetermined pre-load is applied to the pressed inner race.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Since the adhesive requires a long time for curing, the fixing of the rolling bearing under the pre-load requires that the rolling bearing should be maintained on an apparatus for applying the pre-load or a jig for maintaining the bearing under the pre-load until the adhesive is completely cured. This presents the problem of poor productivity. In addition, especially for an anaerobic adhesive, gas (outgas) produced from the adhesive may disadvantageously cause a problem in an apparatus (for example, a hard disk apparatus) including the rolling bearing.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The present invention has been made in view of such circumstances, and it is an object thereof to provide a rolling bearing apparatus capable of preventing a problem due to gas produced from an adhesive and improving the productivity, a method of manufacturing the rolling bearing, and a hard disk apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To achieve the abovementioned object, the present invention provides the following.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to a first aspect, the present invention provides a method of manufacturing a rolling bearing apparatus including a first pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a first rolling bearing to an outer face of a first member of an axial shape in a pressed state and performing pressing until an end face of the inner race abuts on a collar portion provided for the first member, a second pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a second rolling bearing to the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at a position at an interval from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction, a pre-loading step of pressing the inner races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing in a direction in which they are closer to each other in the axial direction with a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing, and a first welding step of welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction pressed in the pre-loading step to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the first aspect of the present invention, the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing are fitted to the first member in the pressed states in the first pressing step and the second pressing step, the inner races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing are pressed in the direction in which they are closer to each other in the axial direction with the second member sandwiched between the outer races in the pre-loading step, and at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race of the pressed second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light. This can manufacture the rolling bearing apparatus maintained under the proper pre-load.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In this case, since the inner races fitted to the first member in the pressed state are pressed to be closer to each other in the pre-loading step, the pre-loading can be maintained by the inner races and the first member in the pressed state even after the pressing force is removed. Thus, the welding step can be performed immediately after the pre-loading step. Since it is possible to prevent a problem due to gas produced from the adhesive and it is unnecessary to wail for curing of the adhesive as compared with the case where the adhesive is used, thereby improving the productivity.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the aspect described above, the second member may include a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In the configuration described above, a second welding step may be included which includes welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">This can securely fix the second rolling bearing to the second member to prevent a displacement of the second rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the configuration described above, a bonding step may be included which includes bonding the outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing, the outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing, and an outer face of the second member to a third member.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the aspect described above, a third welding step may be included which includes welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the first rolling bearing in the axial direction to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">This can securely fix the first rolling bearing to the first member to prevent a displacement of the first rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the aspect described above, the second pressing step may include fitting the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to an protruding fitting portion provided for the outer face of the first member, and a position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion may be a position close to the peripheral portion.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">This allows the protruding fitting portion to receive a force produced from curing and contraction of metal melted by the irradiation with laser light (a force with which the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing is pulled toward the first member) to prevent deformation of the second rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the configuration described above, the second pressing step may include fitting the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to an protruding fitting portion provided for the outer face of the first member, and a position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion may be a position not close to the peripheral portion.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">This reduces the distance from the collar portion provided for the first member to the protruding fitting portion. Thus, in fitting the second rolling bearing to the first member in the pressed state, the second rolling bearing is inserted to the first member more easily. This facilitates the assembly operation of the rolling bearing apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In the configuration described above, the second pressing step may include fitting the entire region of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the outer face of the first member.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">This can securely fit the second rolling bearing to the first member in the pressed state to maintain the pressed state sufficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to a second aspect, the present invention provides a rolling bearing apparatus including a first member of an axial shape provided with a collar portion, a first rolling bearing abutting on the collar portion and having an inner race with an inner face fitted to an outer face of the first member in a pressed state, a second rolling bearing having an inner race with an inner face fitted to the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at an interval from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction, and a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing, wherein at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to the second aspect of the present invention, the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing are fitted to the first member in the pressed states, and the second member is sandwiched between the outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing, so that the pre-load is applied to the inner races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing. Since at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light, the state of the inner races of the first and second rolling bearings under the pre-load can be maintained without using an adhesive. Thus, it is possible to prevent a problem due to gas produced from the adhesive and it is unnecessary to wail for curing of the adhesive as compared with the case where the adhesive is used, thereby improving the productivity.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the aspect described above, the second member may include a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In the configuration described above, at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction may be welded to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">This can securely fix the second rolling bearing to the second member to prevent a displacement of the second rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the aspect described above, the outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing, the outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing, and an outer face of the second member may have shapes fitted to a third member.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the aspect described above, at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the first rolling bearing in the axial direction may be welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">This can securely fix the first rolling bearing to the first member to prevent a displacement of the first rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the aspect described above, the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing may be fitted to an protruding fitting portion provided for the outer face of the first member in a pressed state, and a position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion may be a position close to the peripheral portion.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">This allows the protruding fitting portion to receive a force produced from curing and contraction of metal melted by the irradiation with laser light (a force with which the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing is pulled toward the first member) to prevent deformation of the second rolling bearing.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the aspect described above, the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing may be fitted to an protruding fitting portion provided for the outer face of the first member in a pressed state, and a position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion may be a position not close to the peripheral portion.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">This reduces the distance from the collar portion provided for the first member to the protruding fitting portion. Thus, in fitting the second rolling bearing to the first member in the pressed state, the second rolling bearing is inserted to the first member more easily. This facilitates the assembly operation of the rolling bearing apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the aspect described above, the entire region of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing may be fitted to the outer face of the first member.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">This can securely fit the second rolling bearing to the first member in the pressed state to maintain the pressed state sufficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">According to the present invention, it is possible to provide the rolling bearing apparatus capable of preventing a problem due to gas produced from an adhesive and improving the productivity of the rolling bearing apparatus, the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus, and the hard disk apparatus.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a rolling bearing apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded longitudinal section view showing the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view showing welding points in an inner race of one of rolling bearings and a shaft of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a longitudinal section view for describing a step of pressing one of the rolling bearings to the shaft in the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> shows before the pressing and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> shows after the pressing.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a longitudinal section view for describing a step of pressing the other of the rolling bearings to a sleeve in the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in which <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows before the pressing and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> shows after the pressing.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a longitudinal section view for describing a step of pressing the other of the rolling bearings to the shaft in the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a longitudinal section view showing a modification of the rolling bearing apparatus in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">A rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention and a method of manufacturing the same will hereinafter be described with reference to the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment includes two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B having a plurality of balls <b>4</b> each placed between an inner race <b>2</b> and an outer race <b>3</b> of an annular shape, a shaft (first member) <b>6</b> fitted to an inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of each of the inner races <b>2</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, and a sleeve (second member) <b>8</b> having a fitting hole <b>7</b> in which an outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of each of the outer races <b>3</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B is fitted.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the shaft <b>6</b> is a member of a generally cylindrical shape having an outer circumferential face with a first outer diameter dimension d<b>1</b> almost throughout its length, the dimension d<b>1</b> being slightly smaller than an inner diameter of the inner race <b>2</b> of each of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B. The shaft <b>6</b> is provided with fitting portions <b>9</b> and <b>10</b> at two positions to which the inner faces <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner races <b>2</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted, and a collar portion <b>11</b> on which an end face of the inner race <b>2</b><i>a </i>of one rolling bearing <b>5</b>A abuts.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The fitting portion <b>9</b> and the fitting portion <b>10</b> are placed at an interval between them in an axial direction of the shaft <b>6</b>. The fitting portion <b>9</b> is provided with a protrusion (protruding fitting portion) <b>9</b><i>a </i>formed by protruding part of the outer circumferential face of the shaft <b>6</b> all around outward in a radius direction. The fitting portion <b>10</b> is provided with a protrusion (protruding fitting portion) <b>10</b><i>a </i>formed by protruding part of the outer circumferential face of the shaft <b>6</b> all around outward in the radius direction.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The outermost diameter dimension of the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>is set to a second outer diameter dimension d<b>2</b> slightly larger than the inner diameter dimension of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A. Thus, in fitting the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>to the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A, they are fitted in a pressed state. The outermost diameter dimension of the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is set to the second outer diameter dimension d<b>2</b> slightly larger than the inner diameter dimension of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B. Thus, in fitting the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>to the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B, they are fitted in a pressed state.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the inner race <b>2</b> of the one rolling bearing <b>5</b>A inserted from an end of the shaft <b>6</b> is inserted to the position abutting on the collar portion <b>11</b>, and is fitted to the one fitting portion <b>9</b> at that position. Since the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>is provided for the fitting portion <b>9</b>, the inner race <b>2</b> of the bearing <b>5</b>A is fitted to the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>in the pressed state. The inner race <b>2</b> of the other rolling bearing <b>5</b>B inserted from the end of the shaft <b>6</b> is fitted to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>in the pressed state as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The sleeve <b>8</b> is a member of a generally cylindrical shape having the fitting hole <b>7</b> into which the outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted. An inner face of the fitting hole <b>7</b> is provided with a stepped portion <b>13</b> having an inner diameter dimension sufficiently smaller than the outer diameters <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B placed at a generally central position of the sleeve <b>8</b> in the axial direction and fitting portions <b>14</b> and <b>15</b> at two positions placed on both sides of the stepped portion <b>13</b> in the axial direction, with the stepped portion <b>13</b> being interposed therebetween, to which the outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Both end faces of the stepped portion <b>13</b> in the axial direction form abutment faces <b>13</b><i>a </i>on which end faces of the outer races <b>3</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B fitted to the fitting portions <b>14</b> and <b>15</b> abut. The fitting portions <b>14</b> and <b>15</b> have recess portions (recess fitting portions) <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>a </i>having bottom faces with a first inner diameter dimension slightly larger than the outer diameter dimension of the outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B and protrusions (protruding fitting portions) <b>14</b><i>b </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>placed on the sides of the recess portions <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>a </i>in the axial direction, with the recess portions <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>a </i>being interposed therebetween, and having a second inner diameter dimension slightly smaller than the outer dimension of the outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Since the inner diameter dimension of the protrusion <b>14</b><i>b </i>is slightly smaller than the outer diameter dimension of the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A, the protrusion <b>14</b><i>b </i>is fitted to the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A in a pressed state. Similarly, since the inner diameter dimension of the protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>is slightly smaller than the outer diameter dimension of the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B, the protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>is fitted to the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in a pressed state.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is welded to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the shaft <b>6</b> at a welding point W. In this case, the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is fitted to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, and the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is fitted to the protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>of the sleeve <b>8</b> in the pressed state. A laser light irradiating unit <b>16</b> irradiates a plurality of welding points W with laser light to weld a peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>which is the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the welding points W are provided at points at equal angular intervals of 45 degrees on the entire circumference.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Thus, the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment includes the shaft <b>6</b> provided with the collar portion <b>11</b>, the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A abutting on the collar portion <b>11</b> and having the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> fitted to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B placed at an interval from the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A in the axial direction and having the inner face of the inner race fitted to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, and the sleeve <b>8</b> sandwiched between the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, and the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> through the irradiation with laser light at the eight points in the peripheral portion of the inner race in the axial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Next, description is made of the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention. The method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment includes a first pressing step of fitting the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, a second pressing step of fitting the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, a pre-loading step of pressing the inner races of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B in a direction in which they are closer to each other in the axial direction with the sleeve <b>8</b> sandwiched between the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, and a first welding step of welding at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> through the irradiation with laser light.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, the first pressing step includes fitting the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A from the end side of the shaft <b>6</b>. When the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A is inserted until it passes the fitting portion <b>10</b> on the end side and the end face of the inner race <b>2</b> abuts on the collar portion <b>11</b>, the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> is fitted to the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>formed on the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state in the fitting portion <b>9</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Next, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, the outer race <b>3</b> of the other rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is fitted into the fitting hole <b>7</b> of the sleeve <b>8</b> from the end closer to the fitting portion <b>15</b> where the recess portion <b>15</b><i>a </i>is placed. Since the outer diameter of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is larger than the inner diameter of the protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>of the fitting portion <b>15</b>, the outer race <b>3</b> is compressed by the protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>inward in the radius direction and inserted as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Then, in the second pressing step, the sub-assembly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> and the sub-assembly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> are coupled together. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, pressing forces are applied by a jig to positions indicated by arrows to perform simultaneously the fitting of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the fitting portion <b>10</b> of the shaft <b>6</b> and the fitting of the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A to the fitting portion <b>14</b> of the fitting hole <b>7</b> of the sleeve <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">This causes the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to fit to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>formed on the fitting portion <b>10</b> of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state. Simultaneously, the outer face <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A is fitted to the protrusion <b>14</b><i>b </i>formed on the inner face of the fitting hole <b>7</b> of the sleeve <b>8</b> in the pressed state.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Then, in the pre-loading step, the inner races <b>2</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are pressed by a jig, not shown, in the direction in which they are closer to each other, thereby applying the pre-load to the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B. Since the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, the pressing force applied in the pre-loading step is maintained with the pre-load applied by the inner races and the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state for a while even after the jig is removed from the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b>. Under the pre-load applied by the inner races and the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> in the welding step.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The first welding step includes irradiating the welding point W of the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> maintained under the pre-load applied in the pre-loading step with laser light from the laser light irradiating unit <b>16</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The welding point W corresponds to the peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction and the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b>. In the first welding step, while the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> is placed on a rotation stage (not shown) and is rotated at a certain rotation speed around the axis of the shaft <b>6</b>, the laser light is sequentially applied from the laser light irradiating unit <b>16</b> fixedly placed for a certain irradiation time (for example, 0.5 msec). For the eight welding points W at the equal angular intervals as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the laser light is sequentially applied each time the shaft <b>6</b> is rotated by an angle of 45 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">This realizes the welding of the welding points W in the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> maintained under the pre-load in the pre-loading step, so that the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> maintained under the pre-load is manufactured.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">According to the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment manufactured in this manner, the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed states in the first pressing step and the second pressing step, the inner races of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are pressed in the direction in which they are closer to each other in the axial direction with the sleeve <b>8</b> sandwiched between the outer races in the pre-load step, and at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race of the pressed rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> through the irradiation with the laser light, so that the following advantages can be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">According to the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment, since the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are fitted to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed states, and the sleeve <b>8</b> is sandwiched between the outer races of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, the inner races of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are under the pre-load. Since at least a portion of the peripheral portion of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> through the irradiation with the laser light, the state of the inner races of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B under the pre-load can be maintained without using an adhesive. Thus, it is possible to prevent a problem due to gas produced from the adhesive and it is unnecessary to wait for curing of the adhesive as compared with the case where the adhesive is used, thereby improving the productivity.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment, the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is fitted to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>formed on the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, and the fitting position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is close to the peripheral portion of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction. This allows the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>to receive a force produced from curing and contraction of metal melted in the welding (a force with which the inner face of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is pulled toward the shaft <b>6</b>) to prevent deformation of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">While the present embodiment has shown the example of the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> having the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, the shaft <b>6</b>, and the sleeve <b>8</b>, it is possible to use a rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> in which two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B are supported on a shaft <b>6</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> instead. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a spacing member <b>21</b> of a cylindrical shape is sandwiched between outer races <b>3</b> of the two rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B to allow the application of a pre-load toward an inner race <b>2</b>. In this case, a manufacture method may further include a bonding step of bonding outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B and an outer face of the spacing member <b>21</b> to another member (a third member) after a first welding step. For example, when the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> is used as a support apparatus for a swing arm of a hard disk apparatus, the bonding step includes applying an adhesive to the outer faces <b>3</b><i>a </i>of the outer races <b>3</b> of the rolling bearings <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B and the outer face of the spacing member <b>21</b> or an inner face of a fitting hole formed in the swing arm and bonding the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> to the swing arm.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">While the present embodiment has shown the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> in which the peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b>, it is possible to use a manufacture method in which a peripheral portion of the outer race <b>3</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to an inner face of the sleeve <b>8</b>. In this case, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, a second welding step includes irradiating a welding point W&#x2032; with laser light from a laser light irradiating unit <b>17</b> simultaneously with or after the first welding step. The second welding step is the same as the first welding step except for the unit for applying laser light and the welding point. According to the manufacture method including the second welding step, the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B can be securely fixed to the sleeve <b>8</b> to prevent a displacement of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">While the present embodiment has shown the method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> in which the peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b>, it is possible to use a manufacture method in which a peripheral portion of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A is welded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b>. In this case, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a third welding step includes irradiating a welding point W&#x2033; with laser light from the laser light irradiating unit <b>16</b> after the first welding step described above. The third welding step is the same as the first welding step except for the welding point. According to the manufacture method including the third welding step, the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A can be securely fixed to the shaft <b>6</b> to prevent a displacement of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">While the present embodiment has shown the fitting position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>close to the peripheral portion of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction, the position may not be close to the peripheral portion. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows an example in which the fitting position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is spaced from, and in this example, spaced somewhat above the central position of, the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows another example in which the fitting position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is spaced from the central position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a</i>, in this example at a lower end of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">When the fitting position of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is set to the position not close to the peripheral portion of the inner race of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B in the axial direction in this manner, the distance from the collar portion <b>11</b> of the shaft <b>6</b> to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>is reduced. In other words, the distance from the upper end face of the shaft <b>6</b> to the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>in the axial direction of the shaft <b>6</b> is increased. Thus, in fitting the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to the shaft <b>6</b> in the pressed state, the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is inserted to the shaft <b>6</b> more easily. This facilitates the assembly operation of the rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">While the present embodiment has shown the shape of the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>fitted to a partial region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B, the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>may have a shape fitted to the entire region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> shows an example in which the protrusion <b>10</b><i>a </i>has a shape fitted to the entire region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B. This allows the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B to fit to the shaft <b>6</b> reliably in the pressed state to maintain the pressed state sufficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">While the present embodiment has shown the shape of the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>fitted to a partial region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A, the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>may have a shape fitted to the entire region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> shows an example in which the protrusion <b>9</b><i>a </i>has a shape fitted to the entire region of the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A. This allows the rolling bearing <b>5</b>A to fit to the shaft <b>6</b> reliably in the pressed state to maintain the pressed state sufficiently.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The rolling bearing apparatus <b>1</b> according to the present embodiment is preferably used for supporting the swing arm of the hard disk apparatus (not shown) to be swingable. The swing arm has, at its tip, a pickup for writing and reading data to and from a magnetic disk (storage medium) provided for the hard disk apparatus. As described above, since the inner face <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the inner race <b>2</b> of the rolling bearing <b>5</b>B is bonded to the outer face of the shaft <b>6</b> without using an adhesive, it is possible to prevent deterioration of the magnetic disk due to gas produced from the adhesive.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">While the present embodiment has shown the welding points W provided at the points at the equal angular intervals of 45 degrees on the entire circumference as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, they may be provided at points at arbitrary equal angular intervals of 30 degrees or 60 degrees.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing a rolling bearing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a first rolling bearing to an outer face of a first member in a pressed state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a second rolling bearing to a protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at a position spaced from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pre-loading step of pressing the inner races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing towards each other in the axial direction with a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first welding step of welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction pressed in the pre-loading step to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member is a position at or close to the peripheral portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second member includes a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a second welding step of welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A method of manufacturing a rolling bearing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a first rolling bearing to an outer face of a first member in a pressed state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pressing step of fitting an inner face of an inner race of a second rolling bearing to a protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at a position spaced from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pre-loading step of pressing the inner races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing towards each other in the axial direction with a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first welding step of welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction pressed in the pre-loading step to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member is a position axially spaced from and not close to the peripheral portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A rolling bearing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rolling bearing having an inner race with an inner face fitted to an outer face of the first member in a pressed state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second rolling bearing having an inner race with an inner face fitted to a protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at a position spaced from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member is a position at or close to the peripheral portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the second member includes a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A rolling bearing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first rolling bearing having an inner race with an inner face fitted to an outer face of the first member in a pressed state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second rolling bearing having an inner race with an inner face fitted to a protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member in a pressed state at a position spaced from the first rolling bearing in an axial direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second member sandwiched between outer races of the first rolling bearing and the second rolling bearing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the inner race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to the outer face of the first member through irradiation with laser light, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the position of the fitting of the inner face of the inner race of the second rolling bearing to the protruding fitting portion of the outer face of the first member is a position axially spaced from and not close to the peripheral portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A hard disk apparatus comprising a swing arm supported to be swingable by the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> and a pickup for writing and reading data to and from a storage medium at a tip of the swing arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the second member includes a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer face of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of manufacturing the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a second welding step of welding at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second member includes a stepped portion sandwiched between the outer race of the first rolling bearing and the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction, and a fitting portion to which an outer face of the outer race of the first rolling bearing and an outer face of the outer race of the second rolling bearing are fitted.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein at least a portion of a peripheral portion of the outer race of the second rolling bearing in the axial direction is welded to an inner face of the fitting portion of the second member through irradiation with laser light.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A hard disk apparatus comprising a swing arm supported to be swingable by the rolling bearing apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> and a pickup for writing and reading data to and from a storage medium at a tip of the swing arm. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
