<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624631-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624631</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13782498</doc-number>
<date>20130301</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>327 33</main-classification>
<further-classification>327 37</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e51">Programmable pulse width discriminator</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5815690</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kowert et al.</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7017069</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kudo et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7362152</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Figoli</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7714626</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kris</name>
<date>20100500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8410819</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Himpe</name>
<date>20130400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>327 33</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>21</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12980834</doc-number>
<date>20101229</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8410819</doc-number>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13782498</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130176057</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130711</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>STMicroelectronics, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>Coppell</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Himpe</last-name>
<first-name>Vincent</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Gardere Wynne Sewell LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>STMicroelectronics, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Coppell</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Cox</last-name>
<first-name>Cassandra</first-name>
<department>2816</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is a programmable pulse width discriminator circuit operable to receive a set of parameters from a user and indicate when an input signal satisfies conditions set by the user-defined parameters. The input signal is sampled by the pulse width discriminator circuit to detect a desired state of the input signal. The user may set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is (i) greater than a first threshold value, (ii) less than a second threshold value, or (iii) between the first and second threshold values. In these embodiments, the user sets the first and second threshold values and selects which set of conditions are indicated by the output of the circuit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="183.64mm" wi="257.30mm" file="US08624631-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="273.39mm" wi="205.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624631-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="199.90mm" wi="167.81mm" file="US08624631-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="267.12mm" wi="197.70mm" file="US08624631-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="275.00mm" wi="206.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624631-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="278.47mm" wi="214.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624631-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="273.73mm" wi="199.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624631-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="266.78mm" wi="175.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624631-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">PRIORITY CLAIM</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a continuation of U.S. application for patent Ser. No. 12/980,834 filed Dec. 29, 2010, the disclosure of which is incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to integrated circuits designed to detect an input signal and, more specifically, to an integrated circuit having programmable criteria for receiving an input signal and determining whether the amount of time that the input signal is high is less than a value, longer than a value, or within a range of values.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A pulse width discriminator circuit measures the pulse width of an incoming signal and determines whether or not the pulse width is within an acceptable range. Conventional pulse width discriminator circuitry depends on monostable circuits often using R-C time constants which require analog components that are difficult to integrate within the conventional pulse width discriminator circuits. Such monostable circuitry provides limited functionality and has a narrow range of applicability. Therefore, there exists a need for a pulse width discriminator circuit that provides a more flexible approach that is fully operable in the digital domain.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present disclosure provides a programmable pulse width discriminator circuit operable to receive a set of parameters from a user and indicate when a received input signal satisfies conditions set by the user-defined parameters. The input signal is sampled by the pulse width discriminator circuit to detect a desired state of the input signal. In one embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is greater than a first threshold value. In another embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is less than a second threshold value. In yet another embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is between the first threshold value and the second threshold value. In the aforementioned embodiments, the user sets the first and second threshold values and determines which set of conditions will be indicated by the output of the pulse width discriminator circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In an embodiment, a pulse width discriminator circuit comprises: a first circuit configured to receive a pulsing logic signal and count a value indicative of a number of clock cycles that said pulsing logic signal has a first logic state; and a second circuit configured to compare said counted value to a threshold and generate an output signal when said value satisfies said threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In an embodiment, a method comprises: receiving a pulsing logic signal; incrementing a counter value when said pulsing logic signal has a first logic state; resetting said counter value when said pulsing logic signal has a second logic state; comparing said counter value to a threshold; and generating an output signal when said value satisfies said threshold.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The foregoing and other features and advantages of the present disclosure will become further apparent from the following detailed description of the embodiments, read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. The detailed description and drawings are merely illustrative of the disclosure, rather than limiting the scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims and equivalents thereof.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Embodiments are illustrated by way of example in the accompanying figures, in which like reference numbers indicate similar parts, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a circuit diagram representing an example embodiment of the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a flowchart generally describing operation of a first portion of the pulse width discriminator circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a flowchart generally describing operation of a second portion of the pulse width discriminator circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C illustrate waveform drawings of example embodiments of the pulse width discriminator circuit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a circuit diagram representing an additional embodiment of the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit having a deglitcher coupled to its input.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The present disclosure provides a programmable pulse width discriminator circuit operable to receive a set of parameters from a user and indicate when a received input signal satisfies conditions set by the user-defined parameters. The input signal is sampled by the pulse width discriminator circuit to detect a desired state of the input signal. In one embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is greater than a first threshold value. In another embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is less than a second threshold value. In yet another embodiment, the user can set the parameters such that the pulse width discriminator circuit indicates the condition wherein the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state is between the first threshold value and the second threshold value.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example embodiment of a pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> in accordance with the present disclosure, wherein the desired state of the input signal is logic high. The pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> samples a received input signal <b>102</b>, counts the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state (i.e., logic high), and produces an output signal <b>104</b> indicating whether or not the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is high satisfies a set of conditions defined by the user. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that although the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is designed to count the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is logic high, in other embodiments, the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit may be designed to count the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is logic low. As such, it should be understood that the subsequent disclosure is also applicable to such other embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">For purposes of explaining operation of the disclosed pulse width discriminator, the circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is divided into two sections. The first section <b>150</b> is primarily designed to measure the pulse width of the sampled input signal <b>102</b> (i.e., count the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal is the desired state), and is explained in conjunction with the flowchart <b>200</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The second section <b>180</b> is primarily designed to interpret the pulse width measured by the first section <b>150</b> in accordance with the parameters provided by the user to indicate whether the measured pulse width satisfies the conditions dictated by the user-defined parameters. The second section <b>180</b> is explained in conjunction with the flowchart <b>300</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In accordance with the example embodiment provided by the circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an input signal <b>102</b> is coupled to the control input of a multibit input multiplexer <b>106</b>. The input multiplexer <b>106</b> is coupled to a first register <b>108</b> through a multibit bus and, responsive to the input signal <b>102</b>, loads a value into the first register <b>108</b>. In this particular example embodiment, the desired state of the input signal <b>102</b> is logic high. Therefore, when the input signal <b>102</b> is logic high, the input multiplexer <b>106</b> loads an incrementation <b>110</b> of the value stored in the first register <b>108</b>; and when the input signal <b>102</b> is logic low, the input multiplexer <b>106</b> loads a reference value <b>112</b> into the register <b>108</b>. In the example embodiment described herein, the reference value <b>112</b> is zero, but it should be understood that the reference value <b>112</b> may be any value determined by the user.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The first register <b>108</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is controlled by a clock signal <b>114</b>, wherein the clock signal <b>114</b> sets the time scale for sampling the input signal <b>102</b>. For example, if the desired sampling interval, or resolution, is 1 us, then the clock signal <b>114</b> is set to 1 MHz. When activated by the clock signal <b>114</b>, the register <b>108</b> stores the multibit value received from the input multiplexer <b>106</b> and presents this value on a data bus <b>116</b>. Thus, the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled on the clock signal <b>114</b>, wherein for each sample for which the input signal <b>102</b> is logic high, the value stored in the register <b>108</b> is incremented, and for each sample for which the input signal <b>102</b> is logic low, the reference value <b>112</b> is stored in the register <b>108</b>. In essence, the first register <b>108</b> counts the number of consecutive samples of the input signal <b>102</b> for which the input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state (i.e., high), thereby measuring the pulse width of the sampled input signal <b>102</b>. When the sampled input signal <b>102</b> is not the desired state, the value in the register <b>108</b> is reset to the reference value <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The first register <b>108</b> may have any value preloaded into it upon reset (i.e., clock cycle <b>0</b>) of the circuit <b>100</b>. When the value preloaded in the first register <b>108</b> is zero, the value in the register <b>108</b> represents the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state. When the value preloaded in the first register <b>108</b> is greater than zero, the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state is the difference between the value currently stored in the first register <b>108</b> and the preloaded register value. Similarly, when the reference value <b>112</b> loaded into the first register <b>108</b> is greater than zero, the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state (i.e., the measured pulse width) is the difference between the value currently stored in the first register <b>108</b> and the reference value <b>112</b>. This may be beneficial to the user because the user may effectively shift the pulse width comparison window or range, as described in greater detail below, without changing the first and second threshold values simply by adjusting the reference value <b>112</b> loaded in the register <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the data bus <b>116</b> is connected to a first comparator <b>118</b>, a second register <b>120</b>, and is also fed back to the high input of the input multiplexer <b>106</b> where it is incremented to provide the aforementioned incremented first register value <b>110</b>. It should be appreciated that in embodiments wherein the desired sampled input signal state is logic low, the data bus <b>116</b> would be fed back to the low input of the input multiplexer <b>106</b>, and the reference value <b>112</b> would be connected to the high input of the input multiplexer <b>106</b>. The first comparator <b>118</b> receives both the reference value <b>112</b> and the value stored in the register <b>108</b> (from the data bus <b>116</b>). The first comparator <b>118</b> compares the two values and produces a first comparator output signal <b>122</b>. When the value stored in the register <b>108</b> is greater than the reference value <b>112</b>, first comparator output signal <b>122</b> is logic high; otherwise, the first comparator output signal <b>122</b> is logic low. The first comparator output signal <b>122</b> is received at an AND gate <b>124</b> along with an inverted state <b>126</b> of the input signal <b>102</b>. When the input signal <b>102</b> goes low and the value stored in the register <b>108</b> is greater than the reference value <b>112</b>, the output of the AND gate <b>124</b> goes high, which sets the enable bit of the second register <b>120</b>. When the enable bit is set, the second register <b>120</b> stores the value received from the data bus <b>116</b> at the next clock cycle. Thus, when activated by the clock signal <b>114</b>, the second register <b>120</b> stores the value that was stored in the register <b>108</b> at the previous clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The foregoing disclosure provides a detailed description of the operation of the first section <b>150</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. A more general description of the operation of the first section <b>150</b> of the circuit <b>100</b> is provided by the flowchart <b>200</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. At step <b>202</b>, the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled, and step <b>204</b> determines whether or not the sampled input signal <b>102</b> is the desired state (i.e., logic high). If the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at the desired state, then the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> is incremented in step <b>206</b>. If the input signal <b>102</b> is not sampled at the desired state, the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> is compared to the reference value <b>112</b> in step <b>208</b>. If the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> is greater than the reference value <b>112</b>, then the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> is then stored in the second register <b>120</b> in step <b>210</b>, and then the reference value <b>112</b> is stored in the first register <b>108</b> in step <b>212</b>. It should be understood that the comparison occurring in step <b>208</b> happens regardless of whether or not the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at the desired state. However, if the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at the desired state, then the result of the comparison occurring in step <b>208</b> is irrelevant because the AND gate <b>124</b> is not set. Therefore, this comparison is not illustrated in the flowchart <b>200</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> when the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at the desired state.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the value stored in the second register <b>120</b> is the measured pulse width of the sampled input signal <b>102</b>, and is output on a multibit bus as the measured pulse width <b>128</b>. The measured pulse width <b>128</b> is then analyzed by the circuitry included in the second section <b>180</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is received at a first threshold comparator <b>130</b> and a second threshold comparator <b>132</b>, wherein the inputs to the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> and the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> are received on multibit buses. In addition to the measured pulse width <b>128</b>, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> receives a first threshold value <b>134</b>. The first threshold value <b>134</b> is a user-programmable input (also referred to herein as a parameter) that is compared to the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to determine whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> satisfies a set of conditions indicated by the parameters set by the user (e.g., whether the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>). Thus, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the first threshold value <b>134</b>, and produces a high first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>; otherwise, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> produces a low first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b>. Accordingly, the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The second threshold comparator <b>132</b> receives both the measured pulse width <b>128</b> and a second threshold value <b>138</b>. The second threshold value <b>138</b> is a user-programmable input that is compared to the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to determine whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> satisfies a set of conditions indicated by the parameters set by the user (e.g., whether the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>). Thus, the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the second threshold value <b>138</b>, and produces a high second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>; otherwise, the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> produces a low second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b>. Accordingly, the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are received as inputs at both an XNOR gate <b>142</b> and a threshold multiplexer <b>144</b>. The threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> is controlled by a threshold input signal <b>146</b>, wherein the value of the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is a user-programmable input. When the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is logic high, the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> couples the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> to a low input of a window multiplexer <b>148</b>. When the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is logic low, the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> couples the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> to the low input of the window multiplexer <b>148</b>. Thus, when the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is logic high, the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selects the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> as its output, wherein this output would indicate whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>. When the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is logic low, the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selects the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> as its output, wherein this output would indicate whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The XNOR gate <b>142</b> is coupled to the high input of the window multiplexer <b>148</b> and produces a high XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> when the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are the same. If the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are different, the XNOR gate <b>142</b> produces a low XNOR gate signal <b>150</b>. The XNOR gate <b>142</b> is intended to produce a high XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is within a range defined by the first threshold value <b>134</b> and the second threshold value <b>138</b>. The foregoing description appears to suggest that the measured pulse width <b>128</b> must be less than the first threshold value <b>134</b> and greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b> (i.e., both the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are high) for the output of the XNOR gate <b>142</b> to be true. However, due to the logic of an XNOR gate, the XNOR gate <b>142</b> also produces a high XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> if the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are low. However, for this condition to be true, the second threshold value <b>138</b> would have to be a value greater than or equal to the first threshold value <b>134</b>. Therefore, regardless of whether the first threshold value <b>134</b> is less than, greater than, or equal to the second threshold value <b>138</b>, the XNOR gate <b>142</b> will still produce a high XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> falls within the range (window) defined by the first threshold value <b>134</b> and the second threshold value <b>138</b>. As such, the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is within the range defined by the first threshold value <b>134</b> and the second threshold value <b>138</b>. It should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that, in an alternate embodiment, an AND gate may be used in place of the XNOR gate <b>150</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> provided that the first threshold value <b>134</b> is always greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The window multiplexer <b>148</b> is controlled by a user-programmable window input signal <b>152</b> and, based on the window input signal <b>152</b>, selects one of its inputs as the output signal <b>104</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. Thus, when the window input signal <b>152</b> is logic high, the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> is selected by the window multiplexer <b>148</b> as the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b>. When the window input signal <b>152</b> is logic low, the signal selected by the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> is selected by the window multiplexer <b>148</b> as the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In accordance with the present disclosure, the user inputs a set of runtime parameters to the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>, wherein the parameters include at least the following: (i) the first threshold value <b>134</b>, (ii) the second threshold value <b>138</b>, (iii) the threshold input signal <b>146</b>, and (iv) the window input signal <b>152</b>. It should be understood that the parameters mentioned above are provided by the user to control operation of the pulse width discriminator circuit, and as such, how the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b> should be interpreted. However, the user may also provide other data used to control the operation of the pulse width discriminator. Such other data may include, but is not limited to, the reference value <b>112</b>, a value stored (i.e., preloaded) in the first register <b>108</b> at clock cycle <b>0</b>, and a value stored in the second register <b>120</b> at clock cycle <b>0</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In summary, when the user inputs a logic high window input signal <b>152</b>, the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> is programmed to output a high output signal <b>104</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is within the range, or window, defined by the first threshold value <b>134</b> and the second threshold value <b>138</b>. When the user inputs a logic low window input signal <b>152</b> and a logic low threshold input signal <b>146</b>, the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> is programmed to output a high output signal <b>104</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>. When the user inputs a logic low window input signal <b>152</b> and a logic high threshold input signal <b>146</b>, the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> is programmed to output a high output signal <b>104</b> when the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>. Accordingly, by setting these parameters (i.e., the threshold input signal <b>146</b> and window input signal <b>152</b>), the user is controlling the condition that is indicated by the output signal <b>104</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>, and thus, how the pulse width discriminator circuit output signal <b>104</b> should be interpreted.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The foregoing disclosure provides a detailed description of the operation of the second section <b>180</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. A more general description of the operation of the second section <b>180</b> of the circuit <b>100</b> is provided by the flowchart <b>300</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is received in step <b>302</b>, and is compared to the first threshold value <b>134</b> in step <b>304</b>. If the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>, then the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> produces a high first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> in step <b>306</b>. Otherwise, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> produces a low first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> in step <b>308</b>. In step <b>310</b>, the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is compared to the second threshold value <b>138</b>. If the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>, then the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> produces a high second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> in step <b>312</b>. Otherwise, the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> produces a low second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> in step <b>314</b>. In step <b>316</b>, first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> is compared to the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b>. If the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> is equal to the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b>, then the XNOR gate <b>142</b> produces a high XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> in step <b>318</b>. Otherwise, the XNOR gate <b>142</b> produces a low XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> in step <b>320</b>. In the example embodiments described herein, the parameters provided by the user are set before operation of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> begins. However, it should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the user-defined parameters may be changed during operation of the pulse width discriminator without departing from the scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Step <b>322</b> checks if the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is high. If the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is high, then the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selects the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> as its output in step <b>324</b>. If the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is low, then the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selects the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> as its output is step <b>326</b>. Step <b>328</b> checks if the window input signal <b>152</b> is high. If the window input signal <b>152</b> is high, then the window multiplexer <b>148</b> selects the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> as its output in step <b>330</b>, and thus, the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is within the range defined by the first and second threshold values <b>134</b> and <b>138</b>. If the window input signal <b>152</b> is low, then, in step <b>332</b>, the window multiplexer <b>148</b> selects as its output the threshold comparator output signal selected by the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b>. If the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selected the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> as its output in step <b>324</b>, then the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>. If the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b> selected the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> as its output in step <b>326</b>, then the pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width <b>128</b> is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Reference is now made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C for purposes of discussing example implementations further illustrating the operation of the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as discussed above. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C each illustrate a waveform drawing <b>400</b> of an example input signal <b>102</b>, clock signal <b>114</b>, first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b>, second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b>, XNOR gate signal <b>150</b>, threshold input signal <b>146</b>, window input signal <b>152</b>, and the corresponding pulse width discriminator output signal <b>104</b>. Additionally, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C each illustrate the reference value <b>112</b>, the value stored in the first register <b>108</b>, the value stored in the second register <b>120</b> (measured pulse width <b>128</b>), the first threshold value <b>134</b>, and the second threshold value <b>138</b>. For <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C, the reference value <b>112</b> is zero, the first threshold value <b>134</b> is set to ten, and the second threshold value <b>138</b> is set to seven. Additionally, both the first register <b>108</b> and the second register <b>120</b> are presumed to be preloaded with a value of zero upon reset (i.e., clock cycle <b>0</b>). As such, the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> is set to high at clock cycle <b>0</b>, the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> is set to low, and the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> is also set to low.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As illustrated in the waveforms <b>400</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C, the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at a logic low state for clock cycles <b>0</b> and <b>1</b> before being sampled at a logic high state at clock cycle <b>2</b>. Since the logic high state is the desired state of the input signal <b>102</b>, the first register <b>108</b> begins counting the number of consecutive samples for which the input signal <b>102</b> is logic high. The input signal <b>102</b> remains high for nine consecutive samples. As such, the first register <b>108</b> reaches a value of nine before the input signal <b>102</b> goes low between clock cycles <b>10</b> and <b>11</b>. At clock cycle <b>10</b>, the value in the first register <b>108</b> is greater than the reference value <b>112</b> (zero). Therefore, when the input signal <b>102</b> goes low, the inverted input signal <b>126</b> goes high causing the AND gate <b>124</b> to set the enable bit of the second register <b>120</b>. At the next clock cycle (clock cycle <b>11</b>), the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> is stored in the second register before reference value <b>112</b> is stored in the first register <b>108</b>. Thus, the value in the first register <b>108</b> is reset to zero (the reference value <b>112</b>) at clock cycle <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The measured pulse width <b>128</b> is now set to nine at clock cycle <b>11</b>. Therefore, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the first threshold value <b>134</b> (ten). The first threshold value <b>134</b> is greater than the measured pulse width <b>128</b>, so the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> remains high. Additionally, the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the second threshold value <b>138</b> (seven). The second threshold value <b>138</b> is less than the measured pulse width <b>128</b>, so the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> goes high at clock cycle <b>11</b>. Since both the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are high, the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> goes high at clock cycle <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Between clock cycles <b>12</b> and <b>13</b> the reference value <b>112</b> is changed to eight. Therefore, when the low input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at clock cycle <b>13</b>, the reference value <b>112</b> is loaded into the first register <b>108</b>. At clock cycle <b>15</b>, the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at a high state, and the first register <b>108</b> begins counting, starting at the reference value <b>112</b>, eight. Since the input signal <b>102</b> is sampled at a high state for four consecutive samples, the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> reaches twelve at clock cycle <b>18</b>. The input signal <b>102</b> goes low again between clock cycles <b>18</b> and <b>19</b>, so the first register value (twelve) is stored in the second register <b>120</b> at clock cycle <b>19</b> before the first register <b>108</b> is reset to the reference value <b>112</b>, eight.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The measured pulse width <b>128</b> is now set to twelve at clock cycle <b>19</b>. Therefore, the first threshold comparator <b>130</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the first threshold value <b>134</b>. The first threshold value <b>134</b> is less than the measured pulse width <b>128</b>, so the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> goes low at clock cycle <b>19</b>. Additionally, the second threshold comparator <b>132</b> compares the measured pulse width <b>128</b> to the second threshold value <b>138</b>. The second threshold value <b>138</b> is less than the measured pulse width <b>128</b>, so the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> remains high. Since the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> and the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> are different, the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> goes low at clock cycle <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">It should be noted that, in the example embodiments disclosed in accordance with the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the values in the first register <b>108</b> and the second register <b>120</b> are stored at the rising edge of the clock signal <b>114</b>. Therefore, an incremented first register value <b>110</b> is only loaded into the first register <b>108</b> during the current clock cycle and, thus, is not stored in the first register <b>108</b> until the rising edge of the next clock cycle. Similarly, the value stored in the first register <b>108</b> and output on the data bus <b>116</b> is only loaded in the second register <b>120</b> during the current clock cycle, and is not stored until the next clock cycle in which the enable bit of the second register <b>120</b> is set, as discussed above. Although the present embodiment illustrates a pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> synchronized with the rising edge of the clock signal <b>114</b>, the present disclosure is not limited to this, or other, user-defined preferences provided herein. Therefore, various changes and alternate implementations of the present disclosure may be made without departing from the scope of the disclosure as set forth in the claims below. For example, the value loaded in the first register <b>108</b> during a clock cycle may be stored in the first register <b>108</b> at the end of the current clock cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In order to illustrate operation of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b> for different input parameters, the waveforms <b>400</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C are identical except for the threshold input signal <b>146</b>, the window input signal <b>152</b>, and the output signal <b>104</b>. As such, the waveforms illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A</figref>, <b>4</b>B, and <b>4</b>C show how the output signal <b>104</b> changes when the different parameters are provided to the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. In the example embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>, the window input signal <b>152</b> is logic high. Therefore, the XNOR gate signal <b>150</b> is selected by the window multiplexer <b>148</b> as the output signal <b>104</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. As such, the output signal <b>104</b> of the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width falls within a range defined by the first and second threshold values.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the example embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, the window input signal <b>152</b> is logic low. Therefore, the output signal <b>104</b> is determined based upon the comparator output signal selected by the threshold multiplexer <b>144</b>. Since the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is low, the second threshold comparator output signal <b>140</b> is selected as the output signal <b>104</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. Therefore, the output signal <b>104</b> of the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width is greater than the second threshold value <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Finally, in the example embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4C</figref>, the window input signal <b>152</b> is also low, and thus, the output signal <b>104</b> is determined based upon the value of the threshold input signal <b>146</b>. Since the threshold input signal <b>146</b> is high, the first threshold comparator output signal <b>136</b> is selected as the output signal <b>104</b> of the pulse width discriminator circuit <b>100</b>. Therefore, the output signal <b>104</b> of the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4C</figref> indicates whether or not the measured pulse width is less than the first threshold value <b>134</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In other embodiments, such as that illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the disclosed pulse width discriminator circuit <b>500</b> may include deglitcher circuitry <b>510</b> for filtering the input signal <b>502</b>, thus providing a glitch-free input signal <b>504</b> to the first section of the pulse width discriminator circuit. In this embodiment, the deglitcher circuitry <b>510</b> may be any deglitcher circuit designed to receive an input signal <b>502</b> and produce an output signal <b>504</b> that is a glitch-free reconstruction of the input signal <b>502</b>, and may include, for example, a chain of flip-flops clocked on a fixed time interval, or any other deglitcher circuitry known in the art. In embodiments having spatial limitations, the deglitcher circuitry <b>510</b> may include a deglitcher circuit that uses a reduced amount of memory, such as the deglitcher circuit having a programmable hysteresis disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 12/980,534, entitled &#x201c;Deglitcher with Programmable Hysteresis,&#x201d; and filed Dec. 29, 2010, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference. In this embodiment, the deglitcher circuit <b>510</b> uses a register to reduce the number of memory elements required to sample an input signal <b>502</b>, and produces a time-shifted, glitch-free reconstruction <b>504</b> of the input signal <b>502</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A pulse width discriminator circuit, comprising:
<claim-text>a first circuit configured to receive a pulsing logic signal and count a value indicative of a number of clock cycles that said pulsing logic signal has a first logic state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second circuit configured to compare said counted value to a threshold and generate an output signal when said value satisfies said threshold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first circuit comprises an incrementing circuit configured to increment said counted value in response to each clock cycle while said pulsing logic signal has the first logic state and reset to a reset value when said pulsing logic signal has a second logic state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said first circuit further comprises a register circuit configured to store the counted value in response to said pulsing logic signal having the second logic state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second circuit comprises a comparator circuit configured to compare said counted value to a first threshold value and generate a first output signal when the counted value is less than the first threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second circuit comprises a comparator circuit configured to compare said counted value to a second threshold value and generate a second output signal when the counted value is greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said second circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a first comparator circuit configured to compare said counted value to a first threshold value and generate a first output signal when the counted value is less than the first threshold value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second comparator circuit configured to compare said counted value to a second threshold value and generate a second output signal when the counted value is greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said second circuit further comprises a logic circuit configured to logically combine the first and second output signals to generate a third output signal when said counted value is less than the first threshold value and greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, where said second circuit further comprises a selection circuit configured to select one of said first, second or third output signals as a fourth output signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a first multiplexer operable to receive an incrementing value and load the incrementing value in a first memory when said pulsing logic signal is in the first logic state, and load the reset value in said first memory when said pulsing logic signal is in the second logic state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first comparator operable to compare a value stored in the first memory to said reset value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second memory operable to receive said value stored in the first memory value and store said value stored in the first memory as the counted value when said stored first memory value is greater than said reset value and said input signal is said second logic state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first circuit comprises an incrementing circuit having an input receiving the value stored in the first memory and an output generating the incrementing value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the second circuit comprises:
<claim-text>a second comparator operable to compare said counted value to a first threshold value and output a second comparator signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third comparator operable to compare said counted value to a second threshold value and output a third comparator signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising logic circuitry operable to generate an output signal indicative of a relationship between said counted value and at least one of said first and second threshold values.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The circuit of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of said reset value, said first threshold value, and said second threshold value is a user-programmable value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a pulsing logic signal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>incrementing a counter value when said pulsing logic signal has a first logic state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>resetting said counter value when said pulsing logic signal has a second logic state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing said counter value to a threshold; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating an output signal when said value satisfies said threshold.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, incrementing comprises incrementing said counter value in response to a clock signal while said pulsing logic signal has the first logic state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further including storing the counter value in response to said pulsing logic signal having the second logic state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein comparing comprises comparing said counter value to a first threshold value and generating a first output signal when the counter value is less than the first threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein comparing comprises comparing said counter value to a second threshold value and generating a second output signal when the counter value is greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein comparing comprises:
<claim-text>comparing said counter value to a first threshold value and generating a first output signal when the counter value is less than the first threshold value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing said counter value to a second threshold value and generate a second output signal when the counter value is greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, further comprising logically combining the first and second output signals to generate a third output signal when said counter value is less than the first threshold value and greater than the second threshold value.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, further comprising selecting one of said first, second or third output signals as a fourth output signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
