<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622478-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622478</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12985185</doc-number>
<date>20110105</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>550</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>297484</main-classification>
<further-classification>2972501</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Child car seat with adjustable harness system</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3910634</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Morris</name>
<date>19751000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>297467</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4040664</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tanaka et al.</name>
<date>19770800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>297467</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4880277</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takahashi et al.</name>
<date>19891100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>297467</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6030047</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kain</name>
<date>20000200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>297484</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6189970</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Rosko</name>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2972501</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6623074</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Asbach et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6623075</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Baloga et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2972501</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7188897</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Patrizi et al.</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2972501</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7547065</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Barger</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>8087725</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hutchinson et al.</name>
<date>20120100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2972501</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0103229</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fransen et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>297484</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>297484</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2972501</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2972561</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>29725611</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120169098</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120705</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Spence</last-name>
<first-name>Scott R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Spence</last-name>
<first-name>Scott R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lempia Summerfield Katz LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Graco Children's Products Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Atlanta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dunn</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<department>3636</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Lowry</last-name>
<first-name>Richard</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A child safety seat has a seat back with an upper end, a back side, and a front facing side. A harness system has a pair of safety straps each with a back portion on the back side and a shoulder strap portion on the front facing side. A router is on the back side and has a fixed upper guide, a fixed lower guide spaced below the upper guide, and a slider vertically movable therebetween. The back portions are routed from the respective shoulder strap portions through the slider, up to the upper guide, down to the lower guide, and back up to the slider. The slider is vertically adjustable between a raised position and a lowered position and determines the height of the shoulder strap portions.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="207.43mm" wi="175.68mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="213.36mm" wi="165.35mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="217.17mm" wi="176.28mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="236.90mm" wi="168.40mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="198.29mm" wi="171.53mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="190.42mm" wi="171.53mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="200.66mm" wi="172.30mm" file="US08622478-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Disclosure</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention is generally directed to children's car seats, and more particularly to a safety seat harness system that can be height adjusted without having to undo and rethread the harness belts or straps.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A typical car seat or child safety seat has a seat shell and a harness system. The harness system typically has a pair of shoulder straps, a portion of which extend over the shoulders and downward over the chest of the seat occupant and latch to a buckle on a crotch strap. These types of seats are often configured to accommodate children of different size or to accommodate a growing child. A larger child requires a higher shoulder strap position than a smaller child seated at seat.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Conventional car seats of this type have employed a plurality of slots formed in the seat back of the shell. The shoulder straps can be threaded through a lower pair of the slots for a smaller child. As the child grows, the harness system must typically be undone from the seat shell and then rethreaded through a different, higher positioned pair of slots to adjust or raise the shoulder strap height.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Some manufacturers have tried to address the problem of having to undo and rethread a harness system on a car seat. One manufacturer has produced a seat with a harness that is routed over a rod on the back side of the seat back. In order to adjust the shoulder strap height, the rod is manually disengaged from the seat, moved to a different position, and then reengaged with the seat. Another manufacturer has produced a similar seat except that the harness routing rod is disengaged from the seat shell when the headrest is moved and moves as the headrest height position is adjusted. Yet another manufacturer has attached the harness straps to a trolley on the seat shell. Cords are employed to hold the trolley in place at a selected shoulder strap height. Elaborate or complex latching mechanisms are typically required to secure the above-mentioned types of height adjustment devices and solutions. Such solutions thus typically increase the cost and complexity of such car seats or safety seats.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one example according to the teachings of the present invention, a child safety seat has a seat back with an upper end, a back side, and a front facing side. The seat has a seat bottom with a forward end, a top side, and an underside. The seat has a harness system with a pair of safety straps, each with a shoulder strap portion extending forward and downward along the front facing side and an excess portion extending rearward from the shoulder strap portion behind the back side. The harness system also has an adjustment strap coupled to the excess portions and extending from the back side to the forward end. A router is on the back side and has an upper guide, a lower guide, and a slider movably positioned vertically between the upper and lower guides. The excess portions are routed from the shoulder strap portions through the slide, up to and over the upper guide, down to and under the lower guide, back up to and through the slider, and down to the adjustment strap. The height of the shoulder strap portions along the front facing side is adjustable and determined by a vertical position of the slider.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one example, the child safety seat can have a splitter plate connected between the excess portions of the safety straps and the adjustment strap.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one example, the adjustment strap can extend along the back side and along the underside of the seat bottom and can have a free end extending from an aperture in the forward end.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one example, the height of the shoulder strap portions can be adjusted from a raised position downward by increasing tension on the adjustment strap.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In one example, the child safety seat can have a headrest coupled to the seat back near the upper end. The position of the headrest can be vertically adjustable in concert with the shoulder strap portions.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In one example, the child safety seat can have a headrest coupled to the seat back near the upper end. The shoulder strap portions can be threaded through part of the headrest and through the seat back whereby vertical movement of the slider can also move the shoulder strap portions and the headrest.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In one example, the upper and lower guides can be elongate bars fixed to the back side of the seat back.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In one example, the slider can be a plate and can have upper slots and lower slots.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In one example, the excess portions of the safety straps can each have an upper segment between the slider and the upper guide, an intermediate segment between the upper and lower guides, and a lower segment between the lower guide and the slider.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In one example, the adjustment strap can be releasably clamped and restrained from being adjusted, whereby pulling forward on the shoulder strap portions does not raise or lower the slider or the height of the shoulder strap portions.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In one example according to the teachings of the present invention, a child safety seat has a seat back with an upper end, a back side, a front facing side, and two vertically elongate pass through slots formed through the seat back. The child safety seat has a harness system with a pair of safety straps each with a back portion on the back side and a shoulder strap portion on the front facing side. The pair of safety straps is threaded through a respective one of the pass through slots. A router is on the back side of the seat back and has a fixed upper guide, a fixed lower guide spaced below the upper guide, and a slider vertically movable therebetween. The back portions can be routed from the respective shoulder strap portions through the slider, up to the upper guide, down to the lower guide, and back up to the slider. The slider is vertically adjustable between a raised position and a lowered position and determines the height of the shoulder strap portions.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one example, the child safety seat can have an adjustment strap connected to the safety straps below the slider. The adjustment strap can have a free end that can be pulled to adjust the slider and shoulder strap portions from the raised position toward the lowered position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one example, the child safety seat can have a seat bottom with an underside and an adjustment strap can be routed beneath the underside with a free end protruding through an aperture in a forward end of the seat bottom. A clamping mechanism can be located at the aperture to releasably clamp the adjustment strap.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In one example, the child safety seat can have a headrest coupled to the seat back near the upper end. The shoulder strap portions can be threaded through part of the headrest whereby a height of the headrest is adjustable in concert with the slider and shoulder strap portions.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In one example, the child safety seat can have a biasing element coupled to the slider and bias the slider toward the raised position.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In one example, the child safety seat can have a seat bottom with an underside and a forward end and an adjustment strap coupled to the back portions of the safety straps. The adjustment strap can be routed beneath the underside and have a free end protruding from the forward end. A crotch strap can extend up from the seat bottom and the shoulder strap portions can be connectable to the crotch strap. A clamping mechanism can be located at the forward end to releasably clamp the adjustment strap.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In one example, a free end of an adjustment strap can be pulled outward from a forward free end of a seat bottom in order to adjust the height of the slider and shoulder strap portions from the raised position toward the lowered position.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In one example, a biasing element can be coupled to the slider or to a headrest and bias the slider and should strap portions toward the raised position, along with the headrest.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In one example, a device can be provided on the back side to create a tactile or audible feedback as the slider is moved between the raised and lowered positions.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent upon reading the following description in conjunction with the drawing figures, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a front perspective view of one example of a car seat constructed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a partial cut away view of the car seat and harness system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a rear perspective cut-away view of the car seat and harness system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a side schematic view of the car seat shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> with the shoulder straps of the harness system in a raised position.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the car seat depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> with the shoulder straps in a lowered position.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows an alternate example of a car seat similar to the car seat depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A child safety seat is disclosed and described herein that solves or improves upon one or more of the above-noted and/or other problems and disadvantages with prior known child safety seats. In one example, the child seat has a harness system guided by a router that can be manipulated to adjust the shoulder strap height of the harness. In one example, the harness height can be adjusted on the child seat without having to re-thread or undo the harness system from the seat. In one example, the harness system and router can be configured in such a way so that forward tension at the shoulder straps does not alter or affect the height position of the shoulder straps. In one example, the router is configured to distribute forward load or tension applied to the shoulder straps to different segments of the harness system and router in equal and opposite vertical directions so that the height position is not altered. Other objects, features, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent to those having ordinary skill in the art upon reading this disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Turning now to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows one example of a child safety seat or seat assembly <b>20</b> constructed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. In the disclosed example, the seat assembly <b>20</b> generally has a seat back <b>22</b> and a seat bottom <b>24</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the seat back <b>22</b> and seat bottom <b>24</b> can be provided as part of a unitary or contiguous seat shell <b>28</b>, which may be formed of a molded plastic. The seat shell <b>28</b> is then typically covered with soft goods <b>30</b> to provide a padded seating surface for the occupant and to create a pleasing aesthetic appearance for the product. The typical seat assembly also has a variety of other features and components for structural rigidity, safety, performance, convenience, and the like. These aspects of the seat assembly <b>20</b> are not pertinent to the invention and are not discussed herein. Thus, the drawings provided herewith show a somewhat generic child safety seat or car seat.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the seat assembly <b>20</b> has an on-board or dedicated safety harness system <b>32</b>. Exposed portions of the harness system <b>32</b> are presented for use over a seating surface <b>34</b> defined by the seat back <b>22</b> and seat bottom <b>24</b>. The exposed portions of the harness system are configured to secure a seat occupant in the seat assembly <b>20</b> as is known in the art. The harness system <b>32</b> in this example generally has an adjustment strap <b>36</b> with a free end <b>37</b> protruding forward through an aperture <b>38</b> in a forward end <b>39</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b>. The adjustment strap <b>36</b> is releasably held or clamped in place at the aperture <b>38</b> by a conventional strap clamping device <b>41</b> (shown only generically herein). The strap <b>36</b> can be released by depressing a release button <b>40</b> adjacent the aperture <b>38</b>, as is known in the art. In the disclosed example, the adjustment strap <b>36</b> extends along and beneath an underside <b>42</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b>. A top side <b>44</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b> defines a bottom portion of the seating surface <b>34</b>. Also in this example, the adjustment strap <b>36</b> extends rearward until terminating at a splitter plate <b>46</b> to which it is coupled. The splitter plate <b>46</b> can be located either beneath the underside <b>42</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b>, behind a back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>, or in a seat bight region (as shown) therebetween. The back side <b>48</b> is opposite a forward facing side <b>50</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>. The forward facing side <b>50</b> defines a back portion of the seating surface <b>34</b> on the seat assembly <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The harness system <b>32</b> in this example has a crotch strap <b>52</b> connected to and extending up from the seat bottom <b>22</b> as is known in the art. A buckle housing <b>54</b> is carried on the distal end of the crotch strap <b>52</b>. Though not shown or described in any detail herein, the harness system <b>32</b> can include a pair of lap belts or lap straps that extend upward and forward from opposed sides of the seating surface <b>34</b>. The lap belts can connect to the buckle housing <b>54</b> as part of a well known five-point harness configuration. Such lap belts or straps are not shown herein merely to simplify the images for ease of description of the invention. The harness system <b>32</b> also includes a pair of safety straps <b>56</b>. Each safety strap <b>56</b> has a shoulder strap portion <b>58</b> that extends forward and downward relative to the back portion of the seating surface <b>34</b>. Lower ends of the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> terminate at and are coupled to buckle connectors <b>60</b> in this example. The connectors <b>60</b> are configured to releasably engage the buckle housing <b>54</b> as is known in the art. In a common example (not shown herein), the lap belts can be an integral continuation of the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> threaded through slots in the connectors <b>60</b>. The shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> are configured to go over the shoulder and chest of a seat occupant. The shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> can also each carry a section of a releasable chest clip <b>62</b>, commonly used to control the spacing of the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> during use.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The seat assembly <b>20</b> also has an optional headrest <b>70</b> on an upper end <b>64</b> of the seat back <b>22</b> that, in one example, is vertically adjustable. The safety straps <b>56</b> can extend through strap slots <b>72</b> formed near a lower edge of the headrest <b>70</b>. In this manner, the position of the headrest <b>70</b> and safety straps <b>56</b>, and particularly the height thereof, can be controlled and manipulated in concert with one another. The soft goods <b>30</b> and the seat back <b>22</b> of the seat shell <b>28</b> can be formed having respective vertical slots <b>74</b>, <b>76</b> (shown generically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>). The slots <b>74</b>, <b>76</b> are provided to allow vertical sliding movement and adjustment of the harness system safety straps <b>56</b> and, optionally, the headrest <b>70</b>, along the shell <b>28</b> in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. The soft goods <b>30</b> can be configured in numerous different ways, not discussed herein, to allow the straps <b>58</b> to pass through the soft goods materials and yet hide or mask the slots <b>76</b> in the shell <b>28</b>, while still allowing vertical adjustment of the straps.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> show various components of the disclosed safety harness system <b>32</b>. In the disclosed example, the harness system <b>32</b> has a router <b>80</b> or routing components configured to guide the safety straps <b>56</b> along a predetermined belt path in accordance with the teachings of the invention. Each of the safety straps <b>56</b> has an excess portion or back portion <b>82</b> that is a rearward continuation of the corresponding shoulder strap portion <b>58</b>. As described herein, the shoulder strap portion <b>58</b> of each safety strap <b>56</b> is the part extending to the forward facing side <b>50</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>. The excess portion <b>82</b> of each safety strap <b>56</b> is that portion extending behind and to the back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The router <b>80</b> and the routing of the excess portions <b>82</b> of the safety straps <b>56</b> are discussed first with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. The router <b>80</b> generally has an upper guide <b>84</b> fixedly secured to the back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>. The router also has a lower guide <b>86</b> that is also fixedly secured to the back side <b>48</b> in a position spaced below the upper guide <b>84</b>. In this example, the upper and lower guides <b>84</b>, <b>86</b> are each provided as a horizontal bar or rod mounted on the seat back <b>22</b>. However, the upper and lower guides can differ from the example shown and yet function as intended to route portions of the safety straps <b>56</b>. Also, the means by which the guides or rods are secured to the back side <b>48</b> on the seat back <b>22</b> can also vary considerably.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The router <b>80</b> also includes a slider <b>90</b> positioned vertically between the upper and lower guides <b>84</b>, <b>86</b>. The slider <b>90</b> in this example has a plurality of slots including a pair of upper slots <b>92</b> and a pair of lower slots <b>94</b>. Each pair of slots <b>92</b>, <b>94</b> is laterally spaced apart on opposite sides of the slider <b>90</b> in this example. The lateral slot spacing defines spacing of the safety straps <b>56</b>, and particularly the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b>. The spacing of the pass through slots <b>76</b> in the shell <b>28</b> should match and laterally coincide with the spacing of the slots <b>92</b>, <b>94</b> in the slider <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The configuration and construction of the slider portion of the router <b>80</b> can also vary with the spirit and scope of the present invention. In this example, the slider <b>90</b> is generally a wide flat plate. However, the slider <b>90</b> can have contours and a perimeter shape that are significantly different from the simplistic example shown and described herein. The slider <b>90</b> can have side edges <b>96</b> that are received or captured in guides or tracks (not shown) formed in the back side <b>48</b> on the seat back <b>22</b>. Such tracks could help guide the slider <b>90</b> along a predetermined or desired path along the seat back <b>22</b>. Alternatively, the slider <b>90</b> could be sandwiched within or between layers of the seat assembly or seat shell, if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-5</figref>, the excess portions <b>82</b> of the safety straps <b>56</b> are defined in segments in order to describe the routing or belt path of the straps created by the router <b>80</b>. Each of the straps <b>56</b> has essentially the same segments and thus only the routing for one of the straps is described in detail herein. The routing of the other strap is essentially identical to the one described below in this example.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The shoulder strap portion <b>58</b> of the safety strap <b>56</b> extends rearward, first through the strap slots <b>72</b> in the headrest <b>70</b>. The strap portion <b>58</b> then passes through the slot <b>74</b> in the soft goods and the pass through slot <b>76</b> in the seat shell <b>28</b>. On the back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>, the shoulder strap portion <b>58</b> then is identified as the excess strap portion <b>82</b> as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The excess portion <b>82</b> passes through a corresponding upper slot <b>92</b> in the slider <b>90</b>. An upper segment <b>100</b> of the excess portion <b>82</b> extends upward and is defined between the upper slot <b>92</b> in the slider <b>90</b> and the upper guide <b>84</b>. The excess portion <b>82</b> of the safety strap <b>56</b> is then routed over, around, and down from the upper guide <b>86</b> forming an intermediate segment <b>102</b>. The segment <b>102</b> extends vertically downward from the upper guide <b>84</b> to the lower guide <b>86</b>. The excess portion <b>82</b> of the safety strap <b>56</b> is then routed under and around the lower guide <b>86</b> and then back up from the lower guide <b>86</b> to form a lower segment <b>104</b>. The lower segment of the excess portion <b>82</b> passes through a corresponding lower slot <b>94</b> in the slider <b>90</b> and then is routed back downward adjacent the back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b>. This segment of the excess portion <b>82</b> is defined herein as the tensioning segment <b>106</b>. The terminal end of the tensioning segment <b>106</b> is joined with or coupled to a portion of the splitter plate <b>46</b>. The tensioning segment <b>106</b> is oriented generally parallel to a plane of the slider <b>90</b> whereas the shoulder strap portion <b>58</b> of the safety strap <b>56</b> extending forward from the slider is generally normal or perpendicular to the slider.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">As represented by the vertical arrows Su (up) or Sd (down) in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the slider <b>90</b> can move vertically up or down. Moving the slider <b>90</b> will alter the positioning of the upper slots <b>92</b>, as well as the lower slots <b>94</b>. Adjusting the position of the slider <b>90</b> will thus also adjust the vertical position of the safety straps <b>56</b> and, particularly, the location along the seat back <b>22</b> where the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> protrude from the seat back.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In one example, the position of the slider <b>90</b> could be manually adjusted upward in the Su direction by direct access from the back side <b>48</b> of the seat back <b>22</b> and then by grasping and moving the slider. The slider <b>90</b> can be manually adjusted downward in the Sd direction by tugging on the free end <b>37</b> of the adjustment strap <b>36</b> protruding from the forward end <b>39</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b>. By tugging on the adjustment strap end <b>37</b>, the splitter plate <b>46</b> and tensioning segments <b>106</b> of the excess portions <b>82</b> will be drawn downward. This in turn will draw or pull the slider <b>90</b> downward.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The clamping device <b>41</b> at the aperture <b>38</b> is typically a one-way clamp. The device allows the strap <b>36</b> to be pulled outward or withdrawn from the forward end <b>39</b> of the seat bottom <b>24</b>, but does not allow the strap to return or retract inward until the release button <b>40</b> is actuated. The clamping device <b>41</b> can be utilized to maintain a selected shoulder strap height and tension in the harness system <b>32</b>. If the user wishes to move the height position of the strap portions upward, in one example the user can manually release the clamping device <b>41</b> via the button <b>40</b> and then grasp and raise the slider <b>90</b> in the direction Su. This will pay out additional length of the adjustment strap rearward toward the seat back <b>22</b>. In another example shown generically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a biasing element or spring <b>108</b> can be coupled between the slider <b>90</b> and the seat back <b>22</b>. The spring can be positioned and configured to bias the slider <b>90</b> in the upward Su direction. If the user were to press the release button <b>40</b> at the aperture <b>38</b>, the clamping device <b>41</b> would release the adjustment strap <b>36</b>. The slider <b>90</b> would then be free to move upward in the Su direction, and would automatically do so under the spring <b>108</b> biasing force. In another example (not shown herein), the headrest <b>70</b> can be spring biased upward, which in turn could draw the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> and slider plate <b>90</b> upward when tension in the harness system is released.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When a user tugs on the free end <b>37</b> of the adjustment strap <b>36</b> and obtains a desired harness height position, the user can simply release the strap. The clamping mechanism <b>41</b> at the aperture <b>38</b> will retain the adjustment strap and thus the harness system <b>32</b> under the selected tension. This will result in the slider <b>90</b> remaining in the selected height position as well. No other engagement means or latching components are required to retain the slider <b>90</b>, and thus the shoulder strap height, in the set position. The upper and lower guides <b>84</b>, <b>86</b> are both fixed to the seat back <b>22</b> and need not be moved or readjusted in order to alter the harness height. The router <b>80</b> as disclosed and described herein and the resultant belt path routing achieve these function. The router <b>80</b> retains the selected harness height while still allowing adjustment when needed without having to undo or rethread the harness from the seat shell.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">With the clamping device <b>41</b> at the aperture <b>38</b> engaged, a seat occupant may move forward or rise up or a caregiver may tug forward or pull on the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b>, resulting in an applied force or load L (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). This load L will be transferred through the upper segment <b>100</b> and the intermediate segment <b>102</b> of the excess portions <b>82</b> in the shoulder straps in an upward direction according to the arrow F in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. However, an equal and opposite force in the direction of the arrow FO will resist the force F via the lower segment <b>104</b> and intermediate segment <b>102</b> because the adjustment strap <b>36</b> is clamped at the aperture <b>38</b> by the clamping mechanism or device <b>41</b>. Thus, the slider <b>90</b> will not move up or down. This is so, even though there are no particular mechanisms or components provided to latch or positively retain the slider in position. Only the conventional harness system straps, crotch belt, and adjuster clamp <b>41</b>, along with the router <b>80</b> and resultant belt path routing, are needed to achieve these results.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The clamping mechanism <b>41</b> at the aperture <b>38</b> is released by pressing the release button <b>40</b>. When released, slack can be added or paid out to the adjustment strap <b>36</b> by pulling on the shoulder straps <b>56</b>. A user can manually raise the position of the slider <b>90</b> simply by lifting and pulling up on the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> when the adjustment strap <b>36</b> is released. As noted above, the slider <b>90</b> and/or headrest <b>70</b> can be biased by a biasing element, such as the spring <b>108</b>. If utilized, the spring <b>108</b> can automatically return or raise the slider <b>90</b> and/or headrest <b>70</b> upon release of the adjustment strap <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a side view of the harness system <b>32</b> and the seat assembly <b>20</b>. The shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> of the safety straps <b>56</b> and the headrest <b>70</b> are shown therein in an uppermost or raised position. As noted above, a user can tug in the direction of the arrow T on the free end <b>37</b> of the adjustment strap <b>36</b>, which will apply tension to the harness system <b>32</b>. This tension will draw the slider <b>90</b>, and thus the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> of the safety straps <b>56</b> downward as described above. The adjustment strap <b>36</b> can be released or dropped when the appropriate tension and/or desired harness height of the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> s is achieved. In the disclosed example, the headrest <b>70</b> is connected to the shoulder straps <b>56</b> through the strap slots <b>72</b>. Thus, the headrest <b>70</b> will also be adjusted downward to a suitable position to accommodate a smaller occupant. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a side view of the harness system and seat assembly <b>20</b> with the shoulder strap portions <b>58</b> and the headrest <b>70</b> in a lower most or lowered height position.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an alternative example of a seat assembly <b>120</b> that is essentially identical in construction to the seat assembly <b>20</b> described above. However, in this example the headrest <b>122</b> is not connected to any part of the harness system <b>32</b>. The headrest can be provided in a fixed position or can be constructed so that it is manually adjustable to different vertical positions separate from any adjustment of the harness system or shoulder straps <b>56</b>. Many car seats employ specific headrest release actuators and biasing mechanisms for manual, independent adjustment of the headrest. Such actuators and mechanisms could be employed on the seat assembly <b>120</b> if desired.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates another optional feature that can be employed on the car seat of the invention. A tactile and/or audible feedback device <b>130</b> can be employed on the seat assembly <b>20</b>. The device <b>130</b> can be configured to provide tactile and/or audible feedback to a user when the slider <b>90</b> is raised or lowered. In one example, the slider <b>90</b> or seat back <b>22</b> can include a resilient or biased element and the other of the two components can include a plurality of raised ribs, detents, depressions, recesses, nubs, bumps, or the like. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the seat back <b>22</b> in this example has a plurality of elongate, horizontal depressions <b>132</b> spaced vertically along the back side <b>48</b>. The depressions <b>132</b> can be positioned to denote the maximum raised position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the minimum lowered position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, and a plurality of intermediate positions between the raised and lowered positions. A flexible tab <b>134</b> is coupled to the bottom edge <b>136</b> of the slider <b>90</b> in this example. The tab <b>134</b> has a portion that can align with and seat in the depressions <b>132</b> when aligned with any one of them. The tab <b>134</b> is resilient and flexible and biased toward the back side <b>48</b> in order to seat in one of the depressions.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As the slider <b>90</b> moves or is moved up (Su) or down (Sd) during adjustment, the tab <b>134</b> will slide along the array of depressions <b>132</b> and bend as it passes each depression. This will create a tactile and audible &#x201c;click&#x201d; or &#x201c;snap&#x201d; as the slider is moved, which can indicate to a user that the slider is moving, i.e., that adjustment is under way. The tab <b>134</b> can also seat in any one of the depressions <b>132</b>, which can define or help define a plurality of finite positions for the slider along the seat back <b>48</b>, if desired. The tactile and audible features can also be provided to help retain the slider <b>90</b> in a particular position until the harness system is released or readjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In the disclosed seat assembly, the desired shoulder strap height can be maintained without having to employ an elaborate or complex latching system. Instead, the routing of the safety strap excess portions <b>82</b> created by the router <b>80</b> maintains the desired adjusted height of the shoulder straps. When the harness system is adjusted and clamped at the aperture <b>38</b> by the clamping device <b>41</b>, the forces applied to the shoulder strap portions result in equal and opposite forces being applied by the router <b>80</b> and the routing of the straps. When the clamping device <b>41</b> is released or disengaged at the aperture <b>38</b>, the design of the router <b>80</b> allows for easy and simple harness height adjustment without having to rethread or undo any portion of the harness system from the shell or seat assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Although certain car seat assemblies, harness systems, harness routing, and router features have been described herein in accordance with the teachings of the present disclosure, the scope of coverage of this patent is not limited thereto. On the contrary, this patent covers all embodiments of the teachings of the disclosure that fairly fall within the scope of permissible equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A child safety seat comprising:
<claim-text>a seat back having an upper end, a back side, and a front facing side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a seat bottom having a forward end, a top side, and an underside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a harness system having
<claim-text>a pair of safety straps each with a shoulder strap portion extending forward and downward along the front facing side and an excess portion extending rearward from the shoulder strap portion behind the back side, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment strap coupled to the excess portions of the safety straps and extending from the back side to the forward end; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a router on the back side having an upper guide, a lower guide, and a slider movably positioned vertically between the upper and lower guides,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the excess portions are routed from the shoulder strap portions through the slider, up to and over the upper guide, down to and under the lower guide, back up to and through the slider, and down to the adjustment strap, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the height of the shoulder strap portions along the front facing side is adjustable and determined by a vertical position of the slider.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a splitter plate connected between the excess portions of the safety straps and the adjustment strap.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the adjustment strap extends along the back side and along the underside of the seat bottom and has a free end extending from an aperture in the forward end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the height of the shoulder strap portions can be adjusted from a raised position downward by increasing tension on the adjustment strap thereby lowering the slider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a headrest coupled to the seat back near the upper end, the position of the headrest being vertically adjustable in concert with the shoulder strap portions, wherein the shoulder strap portions are threaded through part of the headrest and through the seat back whereby vertical movement of the slider also moves the shoulder strap portions and the headrest.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the upper and lower guides are elongate bars fixed to the back side of the seat back.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the slider is a plate with upper slots and lower slots.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the excess portions of the safety straps each have an upper segment between the slider and the upper guide, an intermediate segment between the upper and lower guides, and a lower segment between the lower guide and the slider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the adjustment strap can be clamped and restrained from being adjusted, whereby pulling forward on the shoulder strap portions does not raise or lower the slider or the height of the shoulder strap portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A child safety seat comprising:
<claim-text>a seat back having an upper end, a back side, a front facing side, and two vertically elongate pass through slots formed through the seat back;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a harness system having a pair of safety straps each with a back portion on the back side, a shoulder strap portion on the front facing side, and threaded through a respective one of the pass through slots;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a router on the back side having a fixed upper guide, a fixed lower guide spaced below the upper guide, and a slider vertically movable therebetween,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the back portions are routed from the respective shoulder strap portions through the slider, up to the upper guide, down to the lower guide, and back up to the slider,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the slider is vertically adjustable between a raised position and a lowered position and determines the height of the shoulder strap portions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising an adjustment strap connected to the safety straps below the slider, the adjustment strap having a free end that can be pulled to adjust the slider and shoulder strap portions from the raised position toward the lowered position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a seat bottom having an underside, the adjustment strap routed beneath the underside with the free end protruding through an aperture in a forward end of the seat bottom; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamping mechanism located at the aperture to releasably clamp the adjustment strap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a headrest coupled to the seat back near the upper end, the shoulder strap portions threaded through part of the headrest whereby a height of the headrest is adjustable in concert with the slider and shoulder strap portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a biasing element coupled to the slider and biasing the slider toward the raised position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the upper and lower guides are elongate rods fixed to the back side of the seat back.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a seat bottom having an underside and a forward end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment strap coupled to the back portions of the safety straps, routed beneath the underside, and having a free end protruding from the forward end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crotch strap extending up from the seat bottom, the shoulder strap portions connectable to the crotch strap; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamping mechanism located at the forward end to releasably clamp the adjustment strap.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the free end can be pulled outward from the forward end to adjust the height of the slider and shoulder strap portions from the raised position toward the lowered position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a biasing element coupled to the slider and biasing the slider and should strap portions toward the raised position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A child safety seat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a device to create a tactile or audible feedback as the slider is moved between the raised and lowered positions.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
