<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08627121-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08627121</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13078850</doc-number>
<date>20110401</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2010 1 0591308</doc-number>
<date>20101216</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>359</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>26</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713300</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">USB-on-the-go bi-directional protection circuit</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0261788</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>May</name>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>323273</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0119159</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ruff et al.</name>
<date>20080500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4553431</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2010/0064153</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gk et al.</name>
<date>20100300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>713310</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>713300</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120153908</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20120621</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Hai-Zhou</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Hai-Zhou</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Shenzhen Futaihong Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shenzhen</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Chi Mei Communication Systems, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<department>2115</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Chan</last-name>
<first-name>Danny</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A power management circuit for managing power of an electronic device includes a regulator and a protection circuit. The regulator converts an input voltage into a corresponding rated voltage and includes an enable pin and an output pin. The enable pin receives a voltage signal to enable or disable the regulator, and the output pin selectively outputs the rated voltage. When the electronic device is implemented as a slave universal serial bus (USB) device and the enable pin receives a low voltage signal, the regulator is disabled, and the protection circuit receives an output voltage. When the electronic device is implemented as a USB host and the enable pin receives a high voltage signal, the regulator is enabled, and the output protection circuit outputs the rated voltage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="137.75mm" wi="176.53mm" file="US08627121-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="210.90mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08627121-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.86mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US08627121-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure generally relates to power management technology, and more particularly to a power management circuit used in an electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Universal serial bus (USB) can be used to establish communication between a USB host (usually a desktop or notebook computer) and a slave USB device (e.g., a digital audio player or mobile phone), but two slave USB devices cannot be used in this method. Thus, USB on-the go (OTG) technology is used to allow communication devices that generally fulfill the role of being slave USB devices to be USB hosts when paired with another USB device. For example, a digital camera can be directly connected to a printer through the USB OTG.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">To prevent over voltage and protect charging circuits, over voltage protection (OVP) integrated circuits (ICs) are commonly used in the slave USB devices. However, many OVP ICs are not compatible with the USB OTG, and so communication between the two slave devices cannot be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, there is room for improvement within the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Many aspects of an exemplary power management circuit and electronic device employing the same can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the exemplary power management circuit and electronic device employing the same. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers are used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like elements of an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of an electronic device including a power management circuit, according to an exemplary embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a circuit view of the power management circuit of the electronic device, according to the exemplary embodiment of the disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an electronic device <b>100</b> including a power management circuit <b>10</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the disclosure. The electronic device <b>100</b> can be a mobile phone, a personal digital assistant, or other electronic device. The electronic device <b>100</b> further includes a universal serial bus (USB) circuit <b>30</b>, a central processing unit (CPU) <b>50</b>, a battery <b>70</b>, and a USB interface <b>90</b>. The power management circuit <b>10</b> is in electrical connection with the USB circuit <b>30</b>, the CPU <b>50</b>, the battery <b>70</b> and the USB interface <b>90</b>. The electronic device <b>100</b> has USB on-the-go (OTG) function, and can be implemented as a USB host to provide power for other electronic device (not shown) or be implemented as a slave USB device to receive power from other electronic device.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The power management circuit <b>10</b> includes a regulator <b>11</b> and a protection circuit <b>13</b> electrically connected to the regulator <b>11</b>. The regulator <b>11</b> is electrically connected to the USB circuit <b>30</b>, the battery <b>70</b>, and the CPU <b>50</b>. The protection circuit <b>13</b> is electrically connected to the USB interface <b>90</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the regulator <b>11</b> can be a constant voltage regulator, when the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a USB host, the regulator <b>11</b> outputs a rated voltage (e.g., 5V) to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and to a slave USB device, such as a mobile phone, through the USB interface <b>90</b>. When the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a slave USB device, the protection circuit <b>13</b> receives and transmits an output voltage (e.g., 5V) from a USB host such as a mobile phone to the USB circuit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Also referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the regulator <b>11</b> is capable of converting an output voltage of the battery <b>70</b> into a corresponding rated voltage (e.g., 5V) for the USB circuit <b>30</b> and maintaining a constant voltage level. In this exemplary embodiment, the electronic device <b>100</b> is a mobile phone, and the output voltage of the battery <b>70</b> can be about 3.7V. The regulator <b>11</b> can be a TPS61026 direct current (DC)/DC integrated circuit (IC), which can step up voltages. For example, the regulator <b>11</b> steps up the output voltage (e.g., 3.7V) of the battery <b>70</b> to a rated voltage (e.g., 5V), powering the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the protection circuit <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The regulator <b>11</b> includes an enable pin EN, a power pin VBAT, two ground pins PGND and GND, and an output pin VOUT. The enable pin EN is electrically connected to the CPU <b>50</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the enable pin EN is activated by a high level signal (e.g., logical 1) and can enable or disable the regulator <b>11</b>. For example, when the enable pin EN receives a low voltage signal such as logical 0 from the CPU <b>50</b>, the regulator <b>11</b> is disabled. When the enable pin EN receives a high voltage signal, such as logical 1, the regulator <b>11</b> is enabled and activated.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The power pin VBAT is electrically connected to the battery <b>70</b> to receive and transmit power, the output pin VOUT is electrically connected to the protection circuit <b>13</b> to output a constant voltage. The ground pins PGND and GND are electrically connected to ground. In this exemplary embodiment, the output pin VOUT can output a 5V rated voltage to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the protection circuit <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The protection circuit <b>13</b> includes a first field effect transistor (FET) <b>131</b>, a second FET <b>132</b>, a plurality of resistors, a first transistor Q<b>1</b>, and a second transistor Q<b>2</b>. The resistors includes a first bias resistor R<b>1</b>, a second bias resistor R<b>2</b>, a third bias resistor R<b>3</b>, a fourth bias resistor R<b>4</b>, and a fifth bias resistor R<b>5</b>. The first FET <b>131</b> can be a p-type metal oxide semiconductor (PMOS) FET and includes a drain D, a source S and a gate G. When the voltage at the drain D is greater than the voltage at the gate G, the first FET <b>131</b> is switched on. The drain D of the first FET <b>131</b> is electrically connected to the output pin VOUT, and the second bias resistor R<b>2</b> is electrically connected between the source S and the gate G of the first FET <b>131</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The second FET <b>132</b> can be a PMOSFET and includes a drain D, a source S, and a gate G. When the voltage at the drain D is greater than at the gate G of the second FET <b>132</b>, the second FET <b>132</b> is switched on. The drain D of the second FET <b>132</b> is electrically connected to the source S of the first FET <b>131</b>, the source S of the second FET <b>132</b> is electrically connected to the USB interface <b>90</b>, and the second bias resistor R<b>2</b> is electrically connected between the drain D and the gate G of the second FET <b>132</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The first transistor Q<b>1</b> can be an npn transistor and includes an emitter E, a base B, and a collector C. The base B is electrically connected to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the output pin VOUT through the first bias resistor R<b>1</b>. The collector C of the first transistor Q<b>1</b> is electrically connected to the second bias resistor R<b>2</b> and the gates G of the first FET <b>131</b> and the second FET <b>132</b>. The third bias resistor R<b>3</b> is electrically connected between the base B and the emitter E of the first transistor Q. The second transistor Q<b>2</b> can be an npn transistor and includes a base B, an emitter E, and a collector C. The collector C of the second transistor Q<b>2</b> is electrically connected to the emitter E of the first transistor Q<b>1</b>. The base B of the second transistor Q<b>2</b> is electrically connected to the CPU <b>50</b> and the enable pin EN through the fourth bias resistor R<b>4</b>. The emitter E of the second transistor Q<b>2</b> is electrically connected to ground, and the fifth bias transistor R<b>5</b> is electrically connected between the base B and the emitter E of the second transistor Q<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The USB circuit <b>30</b> includes inductors, capacitors and resistors, and is capable of filtering noise signals and protecting the power management circuit <b>10</b>. The CPU <b>50</b> carries out each operation instruction of the electronic device <b>100</b> in sequence, to perform the basic arithmetic, logical and input/output (I/O) operations. In this exemplary embodiment, the CPU <b>50</b> is capable of carrying out operation instruction to control and enable the electronic device <b>100</b> to be a USB host or a slave USB device, and transmitting a high or low voltage signal to the enable pin EN of the regulator <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The USB interface <b>90</b> includes a power pin VBUS and an identification pin ID. The power pin VBUS is electrically connected to the source S of the second FET <b>132</b> to transfer electrical energy. The identification pin ID electrically connects the CPU <b>50</b> and is capable of communicating with electronic device and transmitting an identification signal to the CPU <b>50</b> to implement the electronic device <b>100</b> as a slave USB device or a USB host.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">For example, when the identification signal is a high voltage signal such as logical 1, the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a slave USB device, the CPU <b>50</b> sends a low voltage signal (e.g., logical 0) to the enable pin EN, the regulator <b>11</b> is disabled. When the identification signal is a low voltage signal such as logical 0, the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a USB host, the CPU <b>50</b> sends a high voltage signal (e.g., logical 1) to the enable pin EN, the regulator <b>11</b> then is enabled and outputs a rated voltage (e.g., 5V) to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the protection circuit <b>13</b> through the output pin VOUT.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Further referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in use, the USB interface <b>90</b> is electrically connected to another electronic device such as a mobile phone, when the CPU <b>50</b> detects a high voltage signal (e.g., logical 1) from the identification pin ID, the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a slave USB device, and the other electronic device is implemented as a USB host. The CPU <b>50</b> sends a low voltage signal to the enable pin EN, disabling the regulator <b>11</b>, the first transistor Q<b>1</b> and the second transistor Q<b>2</b> are turned off, and the first FET <b>131</b> and the second FET <b>132</b> are turned on. The protection circuit <b>13</b> receives an output voltage (e.g., 5V) through the USB interface <b>90</b> from the USB host to provide power to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the electronic device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">When the CPU <b>50</b> detects a low voltage signal, such as logical 0, from the identification pin ID, the electronic device <b>100</b> is implemented as a USB host, and the other electronic device is implemented as a slave USB device. The CPU <b>50</b> sends a high voltage signal to the enable pin EN, enabling and activating the regulator <b>11</b>. The regulator <b>11</b> steps up the output voltage (e.g., 3.7V) of the battery <b>70</b> to a rated voltage (e.g., 5V), powering the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the protection circuit <b>13</b>. The first transistor Q<b>1</b> and the second transistor Q<b>2</b> are turned on by a bias voltage, and the first FET <b>131</b> and the second FET <b>132</b> are turned on by a bias voltage. Thus, the rated voltage (e.g., 5V) from the output pin VOUT is transmitted to the USB circuit <b>30</b> and the slave USB device through the protection circuit <b>13</b> and the USB interface <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In summary, the electronic device <b>100</b> can be implemented as a slave USB device or a USB host based on the USB OTG, so the electronic device <b>100</b> can be charged and provide communication with other electronic devices. Additionally, the power management circuit <b>10</b> can adjust and control the changes of voltage that charge the electronic device <b>100</b>, which can prevent overvoltage protection and protect a charging circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the exemplary disclosure have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the exemplary disclosure, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of exemplary disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A power management circuit for an electronic device, comprising:
<claim-text>a regulator that converts an input voltage into a corresponding rated voltage, the regulator comprising:
<claim-text>an enable pin that receives a voltage signal to enable or disable the regulator according to the voltage signal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output pin that selectively outputs the rated voltage; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a protection circuit electrically connected to the output pin, wherein when the electronic device is implemented as a slave universal serial bus (USB) device and the enable pin receives a low voltage signal, the regulator is disabled, and the protection circuit receives an output voltage; when the electronic device is implemented as a USB host and the enable pin receives a high voltage signal, the regulator is enabled, and the output protection circuit outputs the rated voltage; the protection circuit comprises a first field effect transistor (FET), a second FET, a first bias resistor, and a second bias resistor, the drain of the first FET is electrically connected to the output pin, the second bias resistor is electrically connected between the source and the gate of the first FET, the drain of the second FET is electrically connected to the source of the first FET, and the second bias resistor is electrically connected between the drain and the gate of the second FET.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is a direct current (DC)/DC integrated circuit and is capable of converting a voltage into the corresponding rated voltage and maintaining a constant voltage level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator further comprises a power pin and two ground pins, the enable pin is activated by a high voltage signal, the power pin is electrically connected to a battery to receive power, and the ground pins are electrically connected to ground.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the protection circuit further comprises a first transistor and a third bias resistor, the base is electrically connected to the output pin through the first bias resistor, the collector of the first transistor is electrically connected to the second bias resistor and the gates of the first FET and the second FET, the third bias resistor is electrically connected between the base and the emitter of the first transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the protection circuit further comprises a second transistor, a fourth resistor and a fifth resistor, the collector of the second transistor is electrically connected to the emitter of the first transistor, the base of the second transistor is electrically connected to the enable pin through the fourth bias resistor, the emitter of the second transistor is electrically connected to ground, and the fifth bias transistor is electrically connected between the base and the emitter of the second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein when the enable pin receives a low voltage signal, the regulator is disabled, the first transistor and the second transistor are turned off, and the first FET and the second FET are turned on; when the enable pin receives a high voltage signal, the regulator is enabled and activated, the regulator steps up the output voltage to the rated voltage, the first transistor and the second transistor are turned on, and the first FET and the second FET are turned on.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power management circuit as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is a constant voltage regulator, the first FET and the second FET are p-type metal oxide semiconductor FETs (PMOSFETs), and the first transistor and the second transistor are npn transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An electronic device, comprising:
<claim-text>a central processing unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a USB interface; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power management circuit that manages power of the electronic device, the power management circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a regulator that converts a voltage into a corresponding rated voltage, the regulator comprising:
<claim-text>an enable pin that electrically connects the CPU, the enable pin receiving a voltage signal to activate or disable the regulator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output pin that selectively outputs the rated voltage; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a protection circuit electrically connected to the output pin, wherein the USB interface electrically connects the other electronic device and sends a voltage signal to the CPU, when the CPU detects a high voltage signal, the electronic device is used as a slave USB device and sends a low voltage signal to the enable pin, the regulator is disabled, and the protection circuit receives an voltage through the USB interface from the other electronic device; when the CPU detects a low voltage signal from the USB interface, the electronic device is used as a USB host and sends a high voltage signal to the enable pin, the regulator is activated, and the output protection circuit outputs the rated voltage to the USB interface to the other electronic device; the protection circuit comprises a first field effect transistor (FET), a second FET, a first bias resistor, and a second bias resistor, the drain of the first FET is electrically connected to the output pin, the second bias resistor is electrically connected between the source and the gate of the first FET, the drain of the second FET is electrically connected to the source of the first FET, the source of the second FET is electrically connected to the USB interface, and the second bias resistor is electrically connected between the drain and the gate of the second FET.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is a direct current (DC)/DC integrated circuit and is capable of converting an output voltage of a battery of the electronic device into the corresponding rated voltage and maintaining a constant voltage level.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator further comprises a power pin and two ground pins, the enable pin is activated by a high voltage signal, the power pin is electrically connected to the battery to receive and transmit power, and the ground pins are electrically connected to ground.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the protection circuit further comprises a first transistor and a third bias resistor, the base is electrically connected to the output pin through the first bias resistor, the collector of the first transistor is electrically connected to the second bias resistor and the gates of the first FET and the second FET, the third bias resistor is electrically connected between the base and the emitter of the first transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the protection circuit further comprises a second transistor, a fourth resistor and a fifth resistor, the collector of the second transistor is electrically connected to the emitter of the first transistor, the base of the second transistor is electrically connected to the CPU and the enable pin through the fourth bias resistor, the emitter of the second transistor is electrically connected to ground, and the fifth bias transistor is electrically connected between the base and the emitter of the second transistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein when the enable pin receives a low voltage signal from the CPU, the regulator is disabled, the first transistor and the second transistor are turned off, and the first FET and the second FET are turned on; when the enable pin receives a high voltage signal from the CPU, the regulator is enabled and activated, the regulator steps up the output voltage to the rated voltage, the first transistor and the second transistor are turned on, and the first FET and the second FET are turned on.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the regulator is a constant voltage regulator, the first FET and the second FET are p-type metal oxide semiconductor FETs (PMOSFETs), and the first transistor and the second transistor are npn transistors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a USB circuit electrically connected to the regulation unit and the protection circuit, wherein the USB circuit is capable of filtering noise signals and protecting the power management circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the USB interface comprises a power pin and an identification pin, the power pin is electrically connected to the source of the second FET to transfer power, the identification pin electrically connects the CPU and is capable of transmitting an identification signal to the CPU to implement the electronic device as a slave USB device or a USB host.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein when the identification signal is a high voltage signal, the electronic device is implemented as a slave USB device, the CPU sends a low voltage signal to the enable pin EN, the regulator is disabled; when the identification signal is a low voltage signal, the electronic device is implemented as a USB host, the CPU sends a high voltage signal to the enable pin, the regulator is activated and outputs a rated voltage to the protection circuit through the output pin.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the high voltage signal and low voltage signal correspond to logical 1 and logical 0, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
