<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624144-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624144</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13400193</doc-number>
<date>20120220</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100120783 A</doc-number>
<date>20110614</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>139</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>70</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200345</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Push button cap mounting details</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5380970</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mizuno et al.</name>
<date>19950100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200523</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5399824</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chen</name>
<date>19950300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200534</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5938009</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200517</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6242705</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200520</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7649151</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li</name>
<date>20100100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200344</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7964813</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ting et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>200344</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200  5 A</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200341</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200345</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>200344</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<us-classifications-ipcr>G06F 3/0202</us-classifications-ipcr>
<us-classifications-ipcr>H01H 3/12</us-classifications-ipcr>
<us-classifications-ipcr>H01H 3/125</us-classifications-ipcr>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>7</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120318651</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121220</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chiang</last-name>
<first-name>Po-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chiang</last-name>
<first-name>Po-Ching</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Girardi</last-name>
<first-name>Vanessa</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A button or key structure includes a cap, a base and a connecting member. The cap includes at least two stopper portions. The base includes at least two hooks. The connecting member includes a resilient part. The connecting member is engaged between the at least two hooks and located between the cap and the base. The resilient part is configured for driving the cap away from the base. Each of the at least two hooks is engaged with each of the at least two stopper portions to prevent the cap from disengaging from the base.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="217.85mm" wi="319.11mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="231.90mm" wi="166.45mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.56mm" wi="176.28mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="209.72mm" wi="159.34mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="203.54mm" wi="185.76mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="162.90mm" wi="151.05mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="177.72mm" wi="173.74mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="164.08mm" wi="152.91mm" file="US08624144-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to push buttons, and particularly to a push button for a computer keyboard.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A push button on a computer keyboard may have at least the following five components including a cap, a base, a circuit board and at least two connecting member. The push button with such a structure is complex and the manufacturing cost may be high.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Therefore, there is room for improvement within the art.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Many aspects of the embodiments can be better understood with reference to the drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily drawn to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the embodiments. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded, isometric view of an embodiment of a push button.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an isometric view of a cap of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an assembled view of a base and a connecting member of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an assembled view of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, taken along the line V-V.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, taken along the line VI-VI.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the push button of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, taken along the line VII-VII.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The disclosure is illustrated by way of example and not by way of limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings in which like references indicate similar elements. It should be noted that references to &#x201c;an&#x201d; or &#x201c;one&#x201d; embodiment in this disclosure are not necessarily to the same embodiment, and such references mean at least one.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a push button or key in accordance with an embodiment comprises a cap <b>10</b>, a base <b>30</b> and a connecting member <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the cap <b>10</b> comprises a cover <b>11</b>. In one embodiment, the cover <b>11</b> is substantially rectangular. Four posts <b>12</b> extend from the cover <b>11</b>. In one embodiment, the four posts <b>12</b> are arranged at four corners of the cover <b>11</b>; each of the four positioning portions <b>121</b> is substantially columnar and perpendicular to the cover <b>11</b>. Four stopper portions <b>13</b> are located on the cover <b>11</b>. The four stopper portions <b>13</b> and the four posts <b>12</b> are both on the underside of the cover <b>11</b>. The four stopper portions <b>13</b> substantially have the same configuration. Each of the four stopper portions <b>13</b> comprises a first limiting portion <b>131</b> extending from the cover <b>11</b>, a second limiting portion <b>132</b> extending from the cover <b>11</b>, and a blocking portion <b>133</b> connecting the first limiting portion <b>131</b> and the second limiting portion <b>132</b>. The first limiting portion <b>131</b>, the second limiting portion <b>132</b> and the blocking portion <b>133</b> together define a receiving hole <b>134</b>. In one embodiment, the first limiting portion <b>131</b> is substantially parallel to the second limiting portion <b>132</b>, the first limiting portion <b>131</b> is substantially perpendicular to the cover <b>11</b>, and the blocking portion <b>133</b> is substantially parallel with the cover <b>11</b>. The stopper portions <b>13</b> comprise a first stopper portion <b>135</b>, a second stopper portion <b>136</b>, a third stopper portion <b>137</b> and a fourth stopper portion <b>138</b>. In one embodiment, a first line <b>80</b> connecting the first stopper portion <b>135</b> and the second stopper portion <b>136</b> is substantially perpendicular to a second line <b>70</b> connecting the third stopper portion <b>137</b> and the fourth stopper portion <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the base <b>30</b> includes a supporting board <b>31</b>. In one embodiment, the supporting board <b>31</b> is substantially rectangular. Four installation portions <b>32</b> are located on the supporting board <b>31</b>. In one embodiment, the four installation portions <b>32</b> are arranged at four corner of the supporting board <b>31</b>. Each of the four installation portions <b>32</b> defines an installation hole <b>321</b>. In one embodiment, each of the four installation portions <b>32</b> is substantially perpendicular to the supporting board <b>31</b>. Four hooks <b>33</b> are located on the supporting board <b>31</b>. The four hooks <b>33</b> have the same configurations. Each of the four hooks <b>33</b> comprises a positioning portion <b>331</b> extending from the supporting board <b>31</b>, and a latching portion <b>332</b> extending from the positioning portion <b>331</b>. In one embodiment, the positioning portion <b>331</b> is substantially perpendicular to the supporting board <b>31</b>, and the positioning portion <b>331</b> is substantially perpendicular to the latching portion <b>332</b>. The four hooks <b>33</b> comprise a first hook <b>333</b>, a second hook <b>334</b>, a third hook <b>335</b> and a fourth hook <b>336</b>. An extension direction of the latching portion <b>332</b> of the first hook <b>333</b> is opposite to an extension direction of the latching portion <b>332</b> of the second hook <b>334</b>. An extension direction of the latching portion <b>332</b> of the third hook <b>335</b> is opposite to an extension direction of the latching portion <b>332</b> of the fourth hook <b>336</b>. In one embodiment, a third line <b>40</b> connecting the first hook <b>333</b> and the second hook <b>334</b> is substantially perpendicular to a fourth line <b>60</b> connecting the third hook <b>335</b> and the fourth hook <b>336</b>. Four openings <b>35</b> are defined in the supporting board <b>31</b>. The connecting portion <b>331</b> of each of the four hooks <b>33</b> extends from an edge of each of the four openings <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the connecting member <b>50</b> comprises a circuit board <b>51</b> and a resilient part <b>53</b> located on the circuit board <b>51</b>. The resilient part <b>53</b> comprises a supporting portion <b>531</b>, a connecting portion <b>533</b> extending from the supporting portion <b>531</b>, and an abutting portion <b>535</b> extending from the connecting portion <b>533</b>. In one embodiment, a cross-sectional area of the supporting portion <b>531</b> is greater than that of the connecting portion <b>533</b> and the abutting portion <b>535</b>, and a cross-sectional area of the connecting portion <b>533</b> is greater than that of the abutting portion <b>535</b>. Four extending portions <b>511</b> extend from the circuit board <b>51</b>. In one embodiment, the circuit board <b>51</b> resembles a cross.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-7</figref>, in assembly, the connecting member <b>50</b> is placed on the base <b>30</b>, and each of the four extending portions <b>511</b> is engaged between adjacent two of the four hooks <b>33</b> to prevent the connecting member <b>50</b> from moving relative to the base <b>30</b>. The cover <b>11</b> of the cap <b>10</b> is aligned with the base <b>30</b>, and each of the four posts <b>12</b> is engaged into the installation hole <b>321</b> of each of the four installation portions <b>32</b>. The latching portion <b>332</b> of each of the four hooks <b>33</b> is engaged into the receiving hole <b>134</b> to keep the cap <b>10</b> captive on the base <b>30</b>. The cover <b>11</b> abuts the resilient part <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In use, the cover <b>11</b> of the cap <b>10</b> is pressed to elastically deform the resilient part <b>53</b>, and the resilient part <b>53</b> is moved towards the supporting board <b>31</b> until the cap <b>10</b> makes contact with the circuit board <b>51</b>. The circuit board <b>51</b> can send a signal, and the cap <b>10</b> is in a first position. When the cover <b>11</b> is released, the resilient part <b>53</b> repulses the cap <b>10</b> to an original position.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Although numerous characteristics and advantages have been set forth in the foregoing description of embodiments, together with details of the structures and functions of the embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only and changes may be made in detail, especially in the matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A push button comprising:
<claim-text>a cap, the cap comprising a cover, at least two stopper portions located on the cover;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a base, the base comprising a supporting board, at least two hooks located on the supporting board;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a planar connecting member comprising a circuit board on which is mounted a resilient part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the connecting member is located between the cover and the supporting board, the resilient part is configured to move the cap away from the base, and each of the at least two hooks is engaged with each of the at least two stopper portions to prevent the cap from disengaging from the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least two hooks comprise a first hook, a second hook, a third hook and a fourth hook; and a third line connecting the first hook and the second hook is substantially perpendicular to a fourth line connecting the third hook and the fourth hook.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein four installation portions are arranged at four corners of the supporting board, and each of the four installation portions defines a installation hole, four posts are arranged at four corners of the cover, and each of the four posts is engaged in the installation hole of each of the four installation portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four posts is substantially perpendicular to the cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting member further comprises a circuit board, the circuit board comprises four extending portions, and each of the four extending portions is engaged with adjacent two of the first hook, the second hook, the third hook, and the fourth hook.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the resilient part comprises a supporting portion extending from the circuit board, a connecting portion extending from the supporting portion, and an abutting portion extending from the connecting portion; a cross-sectional area of the supporting portion is larger than a cross-sectional area of the connecting portion; and the cross-sectional area of the connecting portion is larger than a cross-sectional area of the abutting portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least two hooks have same configurations, and each of the at least two hooks comprises a positioning portion extending from the supporting board and a latching portion extending from the positioning portion, and the latching portion is substantially perpendicular to the positioning portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the at least two stopper portions have same configurations, and each of the at least two stopper portions comprises a first limiting portion, a second limiting portion parallel to the first limiting portion, and a blocking portion connecting the first limiting portion and the second limiting portion; the first limiting portion, the second limiting portion and the blocking portion together define a receiving hole; and the latching portion is engaged in the receiving hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein each of the at least two stopper portions comprise a first stopper piece, a second stopper piece, a third stopper piece and a fourth stopper portion, a first line connecting the first stopper portion and the second stopper portion, a second line connecting the third stopper portion and the fourth stopper portion, and the first line is substantially perpendicular to the second line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein at least two openings are defined in the supporting board, and each of the at least two hooks extends from an edge of each of the at least two openings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A push button comprising:
<claim-text>a cap, the cap comprising a cover, four stopper portions and four posts located on the cover;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a base, the base comprising a supporting board, four hooks and four installation portions located on the supporting board;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting member engaged between the four hooks, the connecting member comprising a resilient part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the connecting member is located between the cover and the supporting board, each of the four posts is slidably engaged in each of the four installation portions, the resilient part is configured to drive the cap to move relative to the base, and each of the four hooks engages with each of the four stopper portions to prevent the cap from disengaging from the base.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the four stopper portions comprise a first stopper piece, a second stopper piece, a third stopper piece and a fourth stopper portion; and a first line connecting the first stopper portion and the second stopper portion is substantially perpendicular to a second line connecting the third stopper portion and the fourth stopper portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein four openings are defines on the supporting board, and each of the four hooks extends from each of the four openings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four posts is substantially perpendicular to the cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting member further comprises a circuit board, the circuit board comprises four extending portions, each of the four extending portions is engaged with adjacent two of the four hooks.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the resilient part comprises a supporting portion extending from the circuit board, a connecting portion extending from the supporting portion, and a abutting portion extending from the connecting portion; a cross-sectional area of the supporting portion is larger than a cross-sectional area of the connecting portion; and the cross-sectional area of the connecting portion is larger than a cross-sectional area of the abutting portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein each of the four hooks has the same configuration, and comprises a positioning portion extending from the supporting board, and a latching portion extending from the positioning portion; the latching portion is substantially perpendicular to the positioning portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the four hooks comprise a first hook, a second hook, a third hook and fourth hook; a third line connecting the first hook and the second hook is substantially perpendicular to a fourth line connecting the third hook and the fourth hook.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein each of the fourth stopper portions has the same configuration, and comprises a first limiting portion extending from the cover, a second extending from the cover, and a blocking portion connecting the first limiting portion and the second limiting portion; the first limiting portion, the second limiting portion and the blocking portion together define a receiving hole; and the latching portion is engaged in the receiving hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The push button of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the first limiting portion is substantially parallel with the second limiting portion, the first limiting portion is substantially perpendicular to the cover, and the blocking portion is substantially parallel with the cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A push button comprising:
<claim-text>a cap, the cap comprising a cover, at least two stopper portions located on the cover;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a base, the base comprising a supporting board, at least two hooks located on the supporting board;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a planar connecting member comprising a circuit board on which is mounted a resilient part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the connecting member is located between the cover and the supporting board, the resilient part is configured to move the cap away from the base, and each of the at least two hooks is engaged with each of the at least two stopper portions to prevent the cap from disengaging from the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least two hooks have same configuration, and each of the at least two hooks comprises a positioning portion extending from the supporting board and a latching portion extending from the positioning portion, and the latching portion is substantially perpendicular to the positioning portion; and the</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two stopper portions each define a receiving hole; and the respective latching portion is engaged in the respective receiving hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
