<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08623496-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08623496</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12614237</doc-number>
<date>20091106</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>693</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>32</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>428172</main-classification>
<further-classification>428131</further-classification>
<further-classification>428132</further-classification>
<further-classification>264400</further-classification>
<further-classification>20440301</further-classification>
<further-classification>438  1</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e53">Laser drilling technique for creating nanoscale holes</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6758961</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Vogel et al.</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>2057775</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0009171</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Fertig et al.</name>
<date>20050100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0049156</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Mulloy et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>Fertig, N., George, M., Klau, M., Meyer, C., Tilke, A., Sobotta, C., Blick, R., Behrends, J.; &#x201c;Microstructured Apertures in Planar Glass Substrates for Ion Channel Research&#x201d;: Taylor and Francis (2003).</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00005">
<othercit>Kaplan, Steven M. (2004). Wiley Electrical and Electronics Engineering Dictionary. Wiley&#x2014;IEEE Press. Online version available at: http://www.knovel.com/web/portal/browse/display?<sub>&#x2014;</sub>EXT<sub>&#x2014;</sub>KNOVEL<sub>&#x2014;</sub>DISPLAY<sub>&#x2014;</sub>bookid=3663&#x26;VerticalID=0.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00006">
<othercit>Kopitkovas, G,; Lippert, T.; David, C.; Wokaun, A.; Gobrecht, J., &#x201c;Fabrication of microoptical elements in quartz by laser indued backside wet etching&#x201d;: Microelectronic Engineering (2003), 67-68, 438-444.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Yu, M., Kim, H, Blick, R.; &#x201c;Laser Drilling of Nano-pores in Sandwiched Thin Glass Membranes&#x201d;: Optcs Express (03132009). vol. 17, No. 12.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Fertig, N., et al, Whole Cell Patch Clamp Recording Performed on a Planar Glass Chip, Jun. 2002, Biophysical Journal, vol. 82, pp. 3056-3062.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Fertig, Niels, et al., Microstructured Apertures in Planar Glass Substrates for Ion Channel Research, Receptors and Channels, 9, pp. 29-40, 2003, Taylor &#x26; Francis, Oxford, UK.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>Fertig, N., et al., Microstructured Glass Chip for Ion-Channel Electrophysiology, Physical Review E., Vo. 64, 040901(R), pp. 1-4, American Physical Society, College Park, MD, USA, 2001.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00011">
<othercit>Fertig, Niels et al., Whole Cell Patch Clamp Recording Performed on a Planar Glass Chip, Biophysical Journal, Vo. 82, Jun. 2002, pp. 3056-3062, Biophysical Society, Bethesda, MD, USA.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00012">
<othercit>Fertig, Niels, et al., Activity of Single Ion Channel Proteins Detected with a Planar Microstructure, Applied Physics Letters, vol. 81, No. 25, pp. 4865-4867, Dec. 16, 2002, American Institute of Physics, College Park, MD, USA.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00013">
<othercit>Fertig, N., et al., Stable Integration of Isolated Cell Membrane Patches in a Nanomachined Aperture, Applied Physics Letters, vol. 77, No. 8, pp. 1218-1220, Aug. 21, 2000, American Institute of Physics, College Park, MD, USA.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00014">
<othercit>U.S. Appl. No. 12/277,900, filed Nov. 25, 2008; First Named Inventor Robert H. Blick; Entitled: Retro-Percussive Technique for Creating Nanoscale Holes.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00015">
<othercit>Yu, Minrui et al., Laser Drilling of Nano-pores in Sandwiched Thin Glass Membranes, Optical Society of America, Jun. 8, 2009, vol. 17, No. 12, pp. 10044-10049.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<nplcit num="00016">
<othercit>Lehnert, T., et al.,Glass Reflow on 3-Dimensional Micro-Apertures for Electrophysical Measurements On-Chip Aug. 18, 2006.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>428172</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>21912185</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>13</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20110111179</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20110512</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Blick</last-name>
<first-name>Robert H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Minrui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Blick</last-name>
<first-name>Robert H.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="002" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yu</last-name>
<first-name>Minrui</first-name>
<address>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Boyle Fredrickson S.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Madison</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ewald</last-name>
<first-name>Maria Veronica</first-name>
<department>1783</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Handville</last-name>
<first-name>Brian</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of forming extremely small pores in a substrate that is used, for example, in patch clamp applications is provided that employs an energy absorbing material beyond a back side of the substrate to allow a laser to be focused adjacent the exit side of the substrate so as to generate a pore through the substrate and can also form a crater in the back side of the substrate and in which the pore may propagate from the crater in a drilling direction that can oppose a laser transmission direction.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="92.37mm" wi="65.28mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="240.88mm" wi="152.06mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.69mm" wi="148.67mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="215.05mm" wi="150.45mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="211.50mm" wi="196.77mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="209.63mm" wi="184.40mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="201.85mm" wi="190.67mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="211.24mm" wi="192.19mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="211.24mm" wi="191.77mm" file="US08623496-20140107-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?GOVINT description="Government Interest" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention was made with United States government support awarded by the following agency: NSF 0520527. The United States government has certain rights in this invention.</p>
<?GOVINT description="Government Interest" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">N/A.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to electrophysiology and &#x201c;patch clamping&#x201d; for investigating ionic and molecular transport through cellular membranes via ion channels and, in particular, to a substrate providing a set of nano to microscale pores that may be readily sealed to cellular membranes. Ion channel investigation using patch clamps often plays an important role in drug discovery and preliminary drug screening or evaluation, for example, by providing a model that shows an effect of a drug on ion channels. Doing so can be useful for either avoiding adverse effects or for creating a positive therapeutic effect for the treatment of ion channel related diseases.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Drug screening can require a large number of ion channel measurements. Accordingly, in current practice, planar patch clamps are preferable because they allow parallelization of multiple samples on a substrate, often referred to as a wafer, chip, or well-plate, and facilitate measurement automation. Each sample has a cell or cell wall that is positioned so that an ion channel in the cell or cell wall is aligned with a pore at the sample site. The cell or cell wall is sealed to the patch clamp substrate in a manner that allows a small amount of electrical current to be used in performing ion channel investigations, typically by way of an extremely high resistance seal between the patch clamp substrate and the cell wall (a gigaohm seal or gigaseal). Gigaohm seals achieved using on-chip patch clamp procedures usually have electrical resistance values of about 1 gigaohm, with resistance values of up to about 5 gigaohms being achieved in some relatively rare instances.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Planar patch clamp substrates can be made from, for example, silicon, Teflon&#xae;, PDMS (polydimethylsiloxane), PSG (phosphosilicate glass), or glass. While such materials prove suitable for many planar patch clamp implementations, a single crystal quartz (quartz) material can be a particularly desirable for making planar patch clamp substrates. Quartz exhibits particularly high electrical insulating properties and is piezoelectric. Its unique electrical characteristics allow it to be used as a patch clamp substrate by providing very low levels of background noise while performing ion channel investigations. Furthermore, quartz exhibits particularly good mechanical characteristics such as, for example, good hardness, thermal stability, and chemical stability characteristics. Despite a general recognition of quartz's suitability for use as a patch clamp substrate, many of its desirable characteristics, such as hardness, make fabricating (micromachining) the pores in a quartz substrate rather difficult and/or time consuming.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Traditionally, micromachining of quartz is performed using a combination of lithography and reactive ion etching (RIE). However, RIE techniques require multiple steps and are relatively slow processes.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Another method of micromachining quartz is by way of direct laser beam ablation. During direct laser beam ablation, a high power density, short pulse width femtosecond laser beam is irradiated directly onto quartz. The nonlinear interaction between the ultrafast laser pulses and quartz, which has a band gap of about 9 eV, results in a cyclic multiphoton absorption and electron excitation between the ground and excited states. During this process, the initial excited electrons induce an avalanche ionization and generate a microplasma which ablates the quartz. However, since quartz has a wide band gap, this approach is also slow and is limited in terms of pore diameter and material thickness that can be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Recently, numerous advances have been made in micromachining of pores in non-quartz substrates, for example, by utilizing nanosecond lasers, such as excimer lasers instead of femtosecond lasers. Excimer lasers, which emit ultraviolet (UV) light, have been successfully implemented in relatively fast drilling procedures in non-quartz materials. However, quartz has excellent optical transmission over a large spectrum, from UV to infrared (IR), whereby it is transparent to light(s) in this spectrum. Since quartz is transparent to and therefore substantially unaffected by UV light(s), it has been widely accepted that excimer lasers are not usable for micromachining quartz.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Furthermore, although various patch clamping and other techniques have been developed and, at least to some extent, standardized for successfully modeling and investigating ion channel function voltage-sensitive (or voltage-gated) ion channels, in-depth investigation of yet other types of ion channels, such as mechanosensitive ion channels, remains at least somewhat frustrating and/or impracticable. Accordingly, numerous molecular mechanisms and their functionalities within mechanosensitive ion channels remain unknown, whereby cellular responses to mechanical stimuli remain some of the least understood of the known sensory mechanisms.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention provides an improved technique for the generation of nanoscale-sized pores, for example, pores having diameters of nearly 200 nm, using a laser through a substrate that is substantially transparent to the laser's emitted wavelength and therefore tends to be unaffected by the laser using previously known practices. In the technique, the substrate is backed by an energy absorbing material that has relatively high coefficients of thermal expansion and UV absorption. The laser light is transmitted through the substrate and focused adjacent a back side of the substrate, for example, at or immediately in front of or behind an interface defined between the substrate and energy-absorbing material. Doing so can increase a temperature of the energy-absorbing material which, in turn, heat the substrate from beyond its back side. Heating the energy-absorbing material in this manner increases the temperature of the substrate to an extent that melts the substrate, and correspondingly facilitates melting-type formation of small diameter smooth pores and can also lead to formation of a crater(s) at the back side of the substrate. According to some aspects of the invention, the crater can be formed by a shock wave that results from thermal expansion of the energy absorbing material, but in any event, is formed by ablation or other thermal related removal of material from the back side of the substrate. The pore and/or crater are therefore created by a sandwich drilling or sandwich drilling-like technique that can give the pore and/or crater, of the quartz chip, surface characteristics that are similar to surface characteristics of pipettes that have been fire-polished with open flame procedures. In other words, the pore(s) and/or crater(s) formed according to aspects of the present invention have surfaces that are substantially smooth, their surface irregularities having been removed or attenuated by surface tension induced flowing of melted material in such irregularities which tends to smooth the same.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Specifically then, the present invention provides a method of creating nanoscale holes by using steps including creating a multi-layered assembly that comprises a substrate material and an energy absorbing material. The substrate material receives the nanoscale hole and defines a front side and an opposing back side. The energy absorbing material is adjacent the back side of the substrate material. A laser is applied through the multi-layered assembly, by initially passing through the substrate material and being focused at and absorbed by the energy absorbing material, increasing a temperature of the back side of the substrate material to a greater extent than an increase in temperature of the front side of the substrate material. Continued application of such laser stimulus to the energy absorbing material may correspondingly heat and/or pressurize the back side of the substrate, which can initiate a drilling of or establishing a pore through the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">It is therefore an object of at least one embodiment of the invention to utilize a laser to drill a pore in a substrate by indirectly heating the substrate by focusing the laser at or near an interface between the substrate and an energy absorbing material. This allows for laser micromachining of a material that might otherwise be transparent to light of a wavelength emitted by the laser.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The method can further include a step of producing a crater at the back side of the substrate material which, in some embodiments, can be produced by a shock wave that increases both a temperature and a pressure at an interface defined between the back side of the substrate material and the energy absorbing material. The crater formation can be an initiating step for drilling of the pore and the pore, in some embodiments, is drilled in a drilling direction that opposes a direction of laser transmission through the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It is thus an object of at least one embodiment of the invention to provide a method for forming craters in back sides of substrates and/or drilling pores from the crater toward the front side of the substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The substrate material may be a single crystal quartz material and the laser can be a UV emitting excimer laser or other lasers, e.g., CO2 lasers, and/or others.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is therefore an object of at least one embodiment of the invention to generate pores and/or craters in a single crystal quartz wafer or chip and may be a further object of at least one embodiment of the invention to perform laser micromachining on a substrate that is substantially transparent to a wavelength of light that is emitted by the laser.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The energy absorbing material may be a liquid media, for example, an ultraviolet radiation absorbing organic liquid such as acetone and/or fluorescence immersion oil. Such liquid media can have a thermal expansion coefficient of at least about 700&#xd7;10&#x2212;6 K<sup>&#x2212;1 </sup>and an ultraviolet absorption coefficient of at least about 1.46 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>, for example, an ultraviolet absorption coefficient of between about 1.46 cm<sup>&#x2212;1 </sup>to 1.65 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It is thus an object of at least one embodiment of the invention to provide a liquid medium for use as an energy absorbing material that can be placed under the substrate for performing a laser induce backside etching of the back side of the substrate. The backside etching may be performed on a quartz chip that has been pre-etched or thinned from an initially thick substrate. The initially thick substrate may be about 100-500 microns thick and can be either laser or wet etched, for example, with a buffered oxide etchant (BOE) or hydrofluoric (HF) etchant, in a pre-thinning procedure, down to about 20-50 microns in thickness before the nanopore laser drilling is initiated, which may improve suction and reduce series resistance.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The pore can have a smaller diameter than the crater which it intersects, and the pore diameter can be generally constant along its length or a major portion thereof, and a crater sidewall can include an undercut or groove extending thereinto.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is thus an object of at least one embodiment of the invention to provide a patch clamp chip that has a smooth pore that opens into a relatively larger diameter crater. This configuration can provide suitable structure to which a cell can be mounted.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of an apparatus used for producing a planar patch clamp chip or wafer per from a multi-layered assembly one embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a pictorial view of the multi-layered assembly used in the machine of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-section along line <b>3</b>-<b>3</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> showing a spacing of a substrate from a backer plate by a gap filled with an energy absorbing material;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a figure similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> showing an initial stage of laser micromachining in which a laser beam is focused toward an interface between the substrate and energy absorbing material;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a figure similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> showing transmission of energy through the substrate into the energy absorbing material after a crater has been formed in a back side of the substrate;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a figure similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> showing an initiation of a pore drilling procedure;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a figure similar to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> showing the pore after completion of the drilling procedure;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an enlarged scanning electron microscope image of a substrate after focused ion beam milling to show a cross-section of a first embodiment of a substrate that was laser micromachined according to methods of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an enlarged scanning electron microscope image of a pictorial view of a variant of the substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an enlarged scanning electron microscope image of a pictorial view of another variant of the substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an enlarged scanning electron microscope image of a pictorial view of a second embodiment of a substrate that was laser micromachined according to methods of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a simplified representation of the use of the substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> in a patch clamp application; and</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a simplified representation of another use of the substrate of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> in a patch clamp application that incorporates piezoelectric actuation controls.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the present invention may use an ArF excimer laser <b>10</b> having collimating and focusing optics <b>11</b> to direct a narrow collimated beam <b>12</b> of light along an axis <b>15</b> toward a back surface of a sandwich-like, multi-layered assembly <b>14</b> that is held on a mechanical stage <b>16</b>. The laser may, for example, have a wavelength range of about 155 nm to about 195 nm and is preferably operated to emit a beam <b>12</b> of light having a wavelength of about 193 nm. In other embodiments, laser <b>10</b> may be yet other types of lasers, such as CO2 lasers, and/or others, depending on, for example, a desired wavelength that is selected based on particular characteristics of components within the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, in other words, how the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b> reacts to exposure to light having such wavelength(s), and/or other factors.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The laser <b>10</b> may include a variable attenuating mirror for controlling how much of the laser beam is to be transmitted, and a stencil metal mask with an adjustable aperture that allows production of different laser beam shapes and sizes. Laser <b>10</b> may further include a stage <b>16</b> that can be controlled by an automated controller <b>18</b> of the type well known in the art for providing control signals <b>22</b> to the laser <b>10</b>, controlling its output power in a series of pulses as will be described and providing control signals <b>22</b> to actuator motors <b>24</b> providing x-y control of the stage <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b> may include a substrate <b>26</b>, an underlying energy absorbing material <b>34</b>, and a backer plate <b>32</b> that supports the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> and substrate <b>26</b>. The energy absorbing material <b>34</b> cooperates with the substrate <b>26</b> to perform a one-step micromachining process in which the laser <b>10</b> drills through the substrate <b>26</b>, forming small diameter smooth holes therethrough, while causing a nominal amount of surface roughness to the substrate <b>26</b>. For example, a synergistic relationship between the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> and the substrate <b>26</b> allow for using the laser <b>10</b> to perform a one-step micromachining process to create holes or pores that have diameters as small as 200 nm, while resulting in an end-of-procedure surface roughness of merely tens of nanometers as measured from the respective surface(s) of the substrate <b>26</b>. Furthermore, submicrometer holes, bores, or pores may be formed in the substrate <b>26</b> along with crater-shaped depressions that are formed in a surface of the substrate that faces a direction of back from the substrate. Such relationships between the components of multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, and techniques for forming such hole, pores, and craters in the one-step micromachining procedure, are discussed in greater detail elsewhere herein.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, within the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, substrate <b>26</b> can be, for example, a clear solid material that is transparent to the UV light emitted by laser <b>10</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), preferably a single crystal quartz chip or wafer. A suitable such single crystal quartz wafer for use as substrate <b>26</b> is the 350 &#x3bc;m thick quartz wafer that is readily available from the University Wafer Company of South Boston, Mass.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A front surface of the upper substrate <b>26</b> may have a series of depressions or wells <b>28</b> formed at regular x-y grid locations <b>29</b>. The wells <b>28</b> provide a thinned portion <b>30</b> at the locations <b>29</b> measured along axis <b>15</b> having a thickness of 100 to 1000 g and may be molded, ground, or etched in the substrate <b>26</b>. The diameter of the wells <b>28</b> may be relatively large, for example, 5.0 mm, and serve simply to permit a generally thicker substrate <b>26</b> in regions outside of the locations <b>29</b> for structural convenience. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the substrate <b>26</b> can define a single, unitary structure with multiple wells <b>28</b> formed therein. However, it is also contemplated that substrate <b>26</b> can be an assembly of multiple, relatively smaller, individual quartz wafers or chips, each having only a single well <b>28</b> formed therein.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Referring yet further to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, in some embodiments, backer plate <b>32</b> is positioned as a lowermost component of the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b> and can serve as, for example, a structural base or part of a structural frame thereto. Backer plate <b>32</b> may be a supportive slide that is incorporated into the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, underlying and being spaced vertically below the substrate <b>26</b>. Optional spacer <b>31</b> is one suitable structure that can be used to establish such vertical spacing between the substrate <b>26</b> and backer plate <b>32</b>. The spacer <b>31</b> can be formed out of, for example, polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS). The PDMS may be cast on the rear surface of the substrate <b>26</b> through a mold produced using integrated circuit techniques to provide precisely controlled spacer thickness or may be spun-coated and selectively removed except at the edges of the substrate <b>26</b>. Regardless of the particular manner in which the PDMS is incorporated into the multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, it is preferably configured to form a chamber defined by the PDMS at its outer perimeter and defining a space between the substrate <b>26</b> and backer plate <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The space between the substrate <b>26</b> and the backer plate <b>32</b> is filled with energy absorbing material <b>34</b> which can be a liquid media and, in some embodiments, a UV absorbing organic liquid. The energy absorbing material <b>34</b> has thermal expansion and/or UV absorption coefficients that are large enough to heat and/or squeeze the substrate <b>26</b> to an extent that facilitates, catalyzes, or initiates laser drilling of the substrate <b>26</b>. The energy absorbing material <b>34</b> can have a thermal expansion coefficient of at least about 700&#xd7;10<sup>&#x2212;6</sup>K<sup>&#x2212;1 </sup>and a UV absorption coefficient of at least about 1.46 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>, preferably being within a range of between about 1.46 cm<sup>&#x2212;1 </sup>to 1.65 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>. Suitable UV absorbing organic liquids for use as energy absorbing material <b>34</b> include, for example, acetone and fluorescence immersion oil, along with other suitable materials that may increase temperature when exposed to UV radiation to an extent that may correspondingly heat the substrate material, interfacing therewith, so as to melt the substrate material. Examples of other suitable energy absorbing materials <b>34</b> include, but are not limited to, pyrene, naphthalene, and toluene, and/or other materials.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the particular amount of volume of energy absorbing material <b>34</b> is selected based on the intended configuration of multi-layered assembly <b>14</b>, and laser drilling techniques that are implemented, and intended end-use configuration and characteristics of substrate <b>26</b> for its use in a patch clamping setup. In some embodiments, a relatively small amount of energy absorbing material <b>34</b> is used by sandwiching a thin layer of the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> between backer plate <b>32</b> and substrate <b>26</b>, without incorporating spacers <b>31</b>. In other embodiments, such as the one illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a relatively greater volume of energy absorbing material <b>34</b> is provided, with the particular volume being a function of the space between the backer plate <b>32</b> and substrate <b>26</b> as dictated by spacer <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Regardless of whether the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> is implemented as a thin layer that is tightly sandwiched between the substrate <b>26</b> and a backer plate <b>32</b> substantially adjacent and below the substrate <b>26</b>, or implemented as a thicker layer that fills a larger space between the substrate <b>26</b> and backer plate <b>32</b> as dictated by spacer <b>31</b>, the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> and substrate <b>26</b> are preferably in a face-to-face or an abutting relationship with respect to each other. In such configuration, the substrate <b>26</b> and energy absorbing material <b>34</b> define an interface <b>35</b> therebetween. Interface <b>35</b> allows the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> to transmit heat and/or pressure to the substrate <b>26</b> with relatively little energy loss in so doing.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</figref>, the laser <b>10</b> may be positioned above a first location <b>29</b> and pulsed by the controller <b>18</b> to produce a series of controlled light pulses <b>40</b> of laser beam <b>12</b> that is focused at the interface <b>35</b> or substantially adjacent or proximate thereto. The light pulses <b>40</b> are directed toward a front side <b>46</b>, passing through an outer surface <b>47</b> thereof. Since substrate <b>26</b> is substantially transparent to UV light, the light pulses <b>40</b> pass through the entire thickness of the substrate <b>26</b>, leaving the substrate <b>26</b> through an outer surface <b>49</b> of a back side <b>48</b> of the substrate <b>26</b>. At this point, the substrate <b>26</b> is substantially unheated or otherwise affected by the light pulses <b>40</b>, at least compared to the temperature increase, thermal expansion, and/or other responses of the energy absorbing material to the stimulus of the light pulses <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</figref>, the laser <b>10</b> indirectly heats the substrate <b>26</b> by primarily heating the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> which, in turn, secondarily heats the substrate <b>26</b> at its back side <b>48</b> or from below. In particular, the light pulses <b>40</b> that are focused at the interface <b>35</b>, heat the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> and therefore also the outer surface <b>49</b> of the back side <b>48</b> of substrate <b>26</b> to establish rapid increases temperature and pressure at the interface <b>35</b>. This correspondingly leads to rapid thermal expansion of the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> and/or exit side <b>48</b> of substrate <b>26</b> that can lead to an ablation of material from the exit side <b>48</b> or, in some embodiments, create a shock wave <b>52</b> at the interface <b>35</b>. In any event, a one-step emission of the laser <b>10</b> may be used for wholly fabricating a crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> in the substrate <b>26</b>, explained in greater detail elsewhere herein. The particular configuration and characteristics of the crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> are influenced by, amongst other things, the particular setup of the laser <b>10</b> and its output qualities, described in greater detail elsewhere herein, whereby the craters <b>53</b> and/or pores <b>54</b> are give desired sizes, shapes, and/or other characteristics by selecting a corresponding setup and output qualities of the laser <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref>, shows an embodiment of crater <b>53</b> that can be a disc-shaped depression extending into the back side <b>48</b> of the substrate. Crater <b>53</b> has a relatively flat bottom wall <b>102</b> that can have a circular perimeter shape and extend generally parallel to the outer surface <b>49</b> of back side <b>48</b>. Seen best in the SEM (scanning electron microscope) image of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, crater <b>53</b> of this embodiment includes a sidewall <b>105</b> that may taper slightly inwardly toward the bottom wall <b>102</b>. An upper portion of sidewall <b>105</b>, in its orientation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, transitions into the outer surface <b>49</b> of back side <b>58</b> by way of an arcuate surface that may have been at least partially smoothed during its formation. The smoothing is analogous to the smoothing achieved on an exponentially larger scale with open flame fire polishing, for example, while fire polishing a pipette or some other structure that is exponentially larger than the crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Intuitively, overall dimensions of the crater <b>53</b> are functions of dimensions and characteristics of the sidewall <b>105</b>. Stated another way, crater <b>53</b> defines a crater depth which corresponds to a height dimension of the sidewall <b>105</b>. A crater width or diameter is defined by a (greatest) distance measured between facing surfaces of the sidewall <b>105</b>. As can be extrapolated from the size scale provided in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, crater <b>53</b> may have a crater diameter of about 40 &#x3bc;m and a crater depth of about 10 &#x3bc;m.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In some embodiments, along at least part of the perimeter of crater <b>53</b>, an undercut <b>110</b> extends radially into the sidewall <b>53</b>, between the sidewall and the bottom wall <b>102</b>. Such undercut <b>110</b> may define a groove as an interlocking structure into which portions of a cell can flow under certain conditions, allowing parts of the cell's membrane to engage against, for example, a projecting shoulder defined between the undercut <b>110</b> and sidewall <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>, after completion of the laser micromachining of substrate <b>26</b>, a smoothed annular edge or shoulder can define an opening between the crater <b>53</b> and a pore <b>54</b>, such opening being labeled as a pore-crater opening <b>153</b>. Like various portions of the crater <b>53</b>, the pore-crater opening <b>153</b> can be fire polished and smoothed so as to eliminate substantially all surface irregularities. Seen best in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the pore-crater opening <b>153</b> maybe located in the middle of bottom wall <b>102</b> of the crater.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The pore <b>54</b> extends between the pore-crater opening <b>153</b> and a pore-surface opening <b>147</b> that opens into the pore <b>54</b> from the outer surface <b>47</b> of the front side <b>46</b> of substrate <b>26</b>. Accordingly, in embodiments of substrate <b>26</b> that include a crater <b>53</b> formed thereinto, pore <b>54</b> extends between the crater <b>53</b> and the front side <b>46</b>. In embodiments of substrate that do not include a crater <b>53</b>, the pore <b>54</b> extends between the front and exit sides <b>46</b>, <b>48</b>, in other words, through the entire thickness dimension of the substrate <b>26</b>. Regardless of the particular end-use configuration of substrate <b>26</b>, pore <b>54</b> has a substantially constant diameter along at least a major portion of its length. Accordingly, the pore-surface and pore-crater openings <b>147</b>, <b>153</b> may define opening diameters that are about the same size, for example with the larger of the two openings being no more than about 50% greater than the smaller of the two openings. As another example, the pore <b>54</b> can define minimum diameter and maximum diameter segments along its length, with the maximum diameter segment being no more than about 50% greater in magnitude than the smaller diameter segment.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-8</figref>, a crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> may be formed into substrate <b>26</b> of the multi-layered stack <b>14</b> in the following way. The multi-layered stack <b>14</b> is assembled and the laser <b>10</b> is set up to based on intended characteristics of the crater <b>53</b> and/or <b>54</b>, such as pore diameter and/or others. As discussed above, light pulses <b>40</b> are focused away from the front side <b>46</b> of the substrate <b>26</b> and toward its interface <b>35</b> with the energy absorbing material <b>34</b>. Doing so causes a thermal expansion and also pressure increase of the affected material(s) within the multi-layered stack <b>14</b>, which may be largely the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> at this early stage. Correspondingly, the interface <b>35</b> and the back side <b>48</b> of the substrate <b>26</b> may be secondarily affected by the changes occurring within the energy absorbing material <b>34</b>. Such secondary affects may be an indirect heating characteristic of laser <b>10</b>, by way of the substrates' <b>26</b> intimate interaction with the energy absorbing material <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">For example, by focusing the light pulses proximate the interface <b>35</b>, increasing temperature and pressure of the energy absorbing material <b>34</b> can be transmitted to the substrate <b>26</b>, establishing a localized zone of increasing temperature and pressure of the back side <b>48</b> nearest the point of focus of the light pulses <b>40</b>. This may cause temperature and pressure differentials between the front and exit sides <b>46</b>, <b>48</b> of the substrate <b>26</b> but in any event will increase temperature and pressure at the back side <b>48</b>. When such values increase enough, a crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> can be established by way of this a one-step micromachining procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-7</figref>, although the Applicant does not wish to be bound by a particular theory, it is contemplated that the formation of crater <b>53</b> may be an initiator of the drilling of pore <b>54</b>. In such embodiments, once crater <b>53</b> is formed, the near molten material of bottom wall <b>102</b> is more receptive to accepting energy from or, in other words, is less transparent to the UV from laser <b>10</b> than material in a room temperature at-rest substrate <b>26</b>. Accordingly, due to the preheating of bottom wall <b>102</b> during establishment of the crater <b>53</b>, the light pulses <b>40</b> are able to further ablate material at their point of interaction with the preheated bottom wall <b>102</b>, allowing the light pulses <b>40</b> to pierce therethrough and begin formation of the columnar pore <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, while the emission of light pulses <b>40</b> continues, so does the ablation or melting away of more material at the particular location which the light pulses <b>40</b> pass through the material of the substrate (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>). In this regard, the pore <b>54</b> may propagate upwardly toward the front side <b>46</b> of the substrate so as to define a drilling direction &#x201c;D&#x201d; that opposes the direction of the light pulses <b>40</b> passing through the substrate <b>26</b>. In yet other embodiments, the pore <b>54</b> is not formed in the drilling direction &#x201c;D&#x201d; but instead, the drilling direction can extend in the same direction as the light pulses <b>40</b> passing through the substrate <b>26</b>, whereby the pore <b>54</b> drilling may originate at the outer surface <b>47</b> of the front side <b>46</b>. Although the terms &#x201c;front&#x201d; and &#x201c;back&#x201d; in describing various portions of the substrate <b>26</b> have been implemented in a convenient sense, it is fully contemplated that the by, for example, inverting the arrangement of the components of stack <b>14</b>, or positioning the laser <b>10</b> on the opposing side of the stack <b>14</b>, such terms might then assume generally opposite means. In other words, regardless of the particular orientation of the stack <b>14</b> and/or relative positions between the stack <b>14</b> and laser <b>10</b>, in preferred embodiments, the drilling direction &#x201c;D&#x201d; extends from the interface <b>35</b> between the energy absorbing and substrate materials <b>34</b>, <b>26</b>, toward the side or outer surface of the substrate <b>26</b> that opposes the energy absorbing material. That is, the drilling direction &#x201c;D&#x201d; typically extends away from the location where the shock wave <b>52</b> occurred, whether such direction is the same as or opposite to the direction of laser <b>10</b> emission.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Regardless of how the pore <b>54</b> is created in a particular embodiment, the pore characteristics such as, for example, pore diameter, may be controlled or manipulated at least to some extent by adjusting the set up and controls of the laser <b>10</b>. For some crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> formation procedures, the laser output power may be fixed at 5 W and a variable attenuator of the laser <b>10</b> can be set to allow about 70%, for example, 73% of total beam transmission, and operated for 2500 pulses at a 100 Hz repetition rate for the light pulses <b>40</b>. Yet other set ups are contemplated, again, based on the intended characteristics of the crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b> that are being formed.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">For example, Table 1 below illustrates how pore diameter can be influenced by changing transmission rate or repetition rate of the emitted light pulses <b>40</b>, from 50 Hz pulses to 100 Hz pulses during their emission from the laser <b>10</b>. To establish such data of Table 1, laser energy was fixed at 50 mJ and six drilling schemes (Recipes) were tested to show various combinations of the two transmission rates, and the corresponding influence on pore diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE I</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Drilling Recipes for Two Different Transmission</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Rates and Their Results</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>Pore Diameter</entry>
<entry>Pore Diameter</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>50 Hz</entry>
<entry>100 Hz</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bc;m) at 83%</entry>
<entry>(&#x3bc;m) at 87%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Recipe</entry>
<entry>Pulses</entry>
<entry>Pulses</entry>
<entry>Transmission Rate</entry>
<entry>Transmission Rate</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="63pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="63pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>3000</entry>
<entry>0</entry>
<entry>0.216<sup>a</sup></entry>
<entry>3.841</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>500</entry>
<entry>2000</entry>
<entry>0.621</entry>
<entry>4.168</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>1000</entry>
<entry>4000</entry>
<entry>0.342</entry>
<entry>4.455</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>1500</entry>
<entry>3000</entry>
<entry>0.395</entry>
<entry>4.511</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>2000</entry>
<entry>2500</entry>
<entry>1.594</entry>
<entry>5.270</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>2000</entry>
<entry>4000</entry>
<entry>3.210</entry>
<entry>5.421</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="left" id="FOO-00001"><sup>a</sup>Note:</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="left" id="FOO-00002">This approaches the laser wavelength limit of 193 nm.</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring generally to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-11</figref>, the different configurations of these different embodiments show that, similar to the data in Table 1, influencing output characteristics of laser <b>10</b> may be used to form craters <b>53</b> and/or pores <b>54</b> that have different features, configurations, and/or other characteristics, as desired. Namely, using (relatively) higher transmission rates for laser <b>10</b>, for example, transmission rates of greater than about 80%, produces craters <b>53</b> with flat bottom walls <b>102</b>, like those seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>. Using (relatively) lower transmission rates for laser <b>10</b>, for example, transmission rates that are less than about 80%, produces craters <b>53</b> that have tapering sidewalls and substantially no discernable bottom wall, like that seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Specifically regarding the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>, of the embodiments of craters <b>53</b> that have flat bottom walls <b>102</b> or semispherical configurations, crater depth and sidewall configuration can also be controlled by the transmission rate or power of laser <b>10</b>. Of the three different embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>, the embodiment of crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> has the most shallow crater depth and also has a semicircular or concave-up, arcuate transition between the bottom wall <b>102</b> and the sidewall <b>105</b>. The crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> that was formed with a transmission rate of laser <b>10</b> of about 83%.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Again comparing the embodiments of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>, the crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> has a deeper crater depth than that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> but is shallower than that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. The crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> has a similar semicircular or concave-up, configuration to that seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, with a somewhat flatter bottom wall <b>102</b> when compared thereto. The crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> was formed with a transmission rate that is between 83% and 87% which was used in making craters <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 8</figref>, respectively. The crater of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> has been previously discussed and, when compared to the craters <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, has the deepest crater depth and the flattest bottom wall <b>102</b>, deviating the most from a semicircular cross-sectional configuration. As discussed elsewhere in greater detail, the crater <b>53</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> includes an undercut <b>110</b> that is defined between the bottom and sidewalls <b>102</b> and <b>105</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, this embodiment of crater <b>53</b> is made by setting the laser <b>10</b> to a relatively low transmission rate, for example, a rate of about 74%. This sub-80% transmission rate forms a crater <b>53</b> that appears trumpet-like or arcuately tapering in cross-section, such that the sidewall <b>105</b> tapers conically down to where it connects to the pore <b>54</b>. The sidewall <b>105</b> can also, in some related embodiments, have scales or patterned discontinuities across surfaces thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Referring now generally to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12-13</figref>, regardless of the particular configuration of crater <b>53</b> and pore <b>54</b>, after the substrate <b>26</b> has been laser micromachined into a usable wafer or chip having a crater <b>53</b> and/or pore <b>54</b>, it can be implemented into a suitable investigative tool or instrument, depending on the particular intended end-use research or study that will be performed. It has already been shown that the craters <b>53</b> of the invention can provide gigaohm seals that are not only satisfactory in performance, but may be notably superior when compared to currently known techniques. For example, whereas known methods of glass chip production yield about 60% of produced units that can achieve 1.0-1.5 gigaohm seals, and a substantially lower percentage that can achieve about 5.0 gigaohm seals, preliminary mockup productions of glass chips using the inventive procedure(s) have already successfully produced a substantial percentage of produced units that have achieved 7.0 or greater gigaohm seals. In view of such promising preliminary results, it is fully contemplated and expected that the inventive methods disclosed herein are fully capable of producing chips that achieve or approach 15 gigaohm sealing capabilities.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">Referring specifically now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, in some embodiments, the substrate <b>26</b> can be used in a planar patch clamp apparatus to investigate ion channel performance. As one example of such investigation, the substrate <b>26</b>, shown having the same orientation as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> and therefore an inverted orientation with respect to that shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, may receive a cell <b>60</b> within the crater <b>53</b> to expose a portion of the cell wall <b>62</b> to be accessible through the pore <b>54</b>. A light suction applied by a pump <b>67</b> from the front side <b>46</b> may adhere the cell wall <b>62</b> to the surface of crater <b>53</b> with a 5 to 30 gigaohm resistance between a solution <b>64</b> on the side of the substrate <b>26</b> holding the cell <b>60</b> and a solution <b>66</b> on the side of the substrate <b>26</b> opposite solution <b>64</b>. The application of suction may correspondingly also pull a portion of the cell wall <b>62</b> into the undercut <b>110</b> in a manner that enhances the seal of the cell <b>60</b> to the substrate <b>26</b> by way of the mechanical interlocking relationship therebetween. Although the cell <b>60</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> as having its membrane or cell wall <b>62</b> ruptured over the pore <b>54</b>, it is, of course, contemplated that the cell wall <b>62</b> remains intact for various other types of studies or investigations.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">A sharp suction applied by a pump <b>67</b> at the outer surface <b>47</b> of the front side <b>46</b> or other means may be used to provide electrical connection to the interior of the cell <b>60</b> by a sensitive electrical detector <b>70</b> permitting measurement of electrical differences between the exterior and interior of the cell <b>60</b> through an electrode <b>72</b> communicating with the interior of the cell <b>60</b> referenced to solution <b>64</b> outside the cell <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, since preferred embodiments of substrate <b>26</b> are made from a single crystal quartz material, such embodiments may be incorporated into an apparatus to investigate mechanosensitive ion channel performance and function. The apparatus of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is largely analogous to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, only being configured to piezoelectrically actuate, stress, or otherwise stimulate the cell wall <b>62</b> so as to measure, by way of detector <b>70</b>, gating responses of the particular ion channel that cooperates with the pore <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Still referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, a bather <b>200</b> can be provided that acts as an enclosure, retaining the solution <b>64</b> therein. Ends of the substrate <b>26</b> extend through opposing sides of the barrier <b>200</b>. A power source <b>210</b> provides electrical stimulus for stimulating the piezoelectric behaviors of the substrate. A controller <b>220</b> sends and controls an electrical signal to the substrate, through conductors <b>225</b> that lead to the substrate. The actual connection(s) of the conductors <b>225</b> to the substrate <b>26</b> can be accomplished with suitable terminals. For example, terminals <b>230</b> and <b>235</b> are attached to the opposing outer surfaces <b>46</b> and <b>47</b> at a first end of the substrate <b>26</b>, appearing as a left end in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, and connected to the controller <b>220</b> by a first pair of conductors <b>225</b>. Terminals <b>240</b> and <b>245</b> are attached to the opposing outer surfaces <b>46</b> and <b>47</b> at a second end of the substrate <b>26</b>, appearing as a right end in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, and connected to the controller <b>220</b> by a second pair of conductors <b>225</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Referring yet further to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, in such an embodiment, the controller <b>220</b> may place the cell wall <b>62</b> under compressive and/or tensile stresses along multiple axes of movement or actuation. Depending on the particular cut of the crystal, controller <b>220</b> may establish a voltage across the thickness of the substrate <b>26</b>, specifically by establishing a voltage between the upper terminals <b>235</b>, <b>245</b> and the lower terminals <b>230</b>, <b>240</b>. Depending on the polarity of the signal, doing so will cause the substrate <b>26</b> to compress or elongate with respect to its thickness dimension which correspondingly compresses or stretches the cell wall <b>62</b> in such direction. Here too, depending on the particular cut of the crystal, controller <b>220</b> may establish a voltage across the length of the substrate <b>26</b>, specifically by establishing a voltage between the left end terminals <b>230</b>, <b>235</b> and the right end terminals <b>240</b>, <b>245</b>. Again depending on the polarity of the signal, doing so will cause the substrate <b>26</b> to compress or elongate, only this time with respect to its length dimension, compressing or stretching the cell wall <b>62</b> in a corresponding manner. While doing so, the detector <b>70</b>, senses notable gating and/or other responses of the particular ion channel or other portions of the cell <b>60</b>, depending on the particular configuration of detector <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Referring yet further to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, regardless of the particular configuration of the cell membrane investigating apparatus and its setup and controls, the substrate <b>26</b> according to the invention provides an &#x201c;on-chip&#x201d; piezoelectric system that may be used as a suitable alternative for imposing mechanical deformations to a membrane which to date has been primarily studied with pipettes and conventional patch clamping. Substrate <b>26</b> can be configured and implemented specifically for ones of, e.g., (i) lower frequency actuation of the ion channels, (ii) higher frequency mechanical probing, as well as (iii) static stress modulation of the membrane, as desired based on the particular investigation being performed.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">It is specifically intended that the present invention not be limited to the embodiments and illustrations contained herein, but include modified forms of those embodiments including portions of the embodiments and combinations of elements of different embodiments as come within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A patch clamp chip for electrophysiology comprising:
<claim-text>a homogenous substrate selected from a group consisting of glass and quartz having a first outer surface and an opposing second outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crater extending into one of the first and second outer surfaces and defining a crater diameter thereon; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pore extending between the crater and the other one of the first and second outer surfaces of the substrate, the pore defining a pore diameter that is smaller than the crater diameter and is generally constant along substantially the entire length of the pore, and wherein the length of the pore extends over a majority of a distance between the first outer surface and the opposing second outer surface of the substrate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one of the crater and the pore have a surface adapted to provide a gigaseal with respect to a cell membrane placed thereover.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The patch clamp chip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the single crystal quartz material has been pre-thinned by at least one of a laser etching and a wet etching procedure.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The patch clamp chip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a shoulder defined between the pore and a generally flat bottom wall of the crater, wherein the shoulder comprises an angle of approximately 90 degrees, and wherein the shoulder defines a minimum diameter of the crater between respective diameters of the crater and pore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The patch clamp chip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, the crater including (i) a crater depth being defined between a crater opening and the crater bottom wall, and (ii) a crater width being defined transversely across the crater bottom wall, and wherein crater width is at least two times greater than the crater depth in magnitude.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A patch clamp chip for electrophysiology comprising:
<claim-text>a substrate having a first outer surface and an opposing second outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crater extending into one of the first and second outer surfaces and defining a crater diameter thereon; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pore extending between the crater and the other one of the first and second outer surfaces of the substrate, the pore defining a pore diameter that is smaller than the crater diameter and is generally constant along a major portion of a length of the pore;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the crater includes (i) a bottom wall, (ii) a sidewall extending outwardly away from the bottom wall, and (iii) an undercut that extends into the sidewall so as to define a sidewall shoulder between the undercut and the sidewall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The patch clamp chip of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the substrate is a piezoelectric material and the patch clamp chip further comprises electrical conductors that attach to the piezoelectric material at locations that are spaced from each other, the electrical conductors directing an electrical current therebetween that establishes a voltage across the piezoelectric material so as to piezoelectrically deform at least one of the first outer surface of the substrate, the second outer surface of the substrate, the crater, and the pore.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A patch clamp chip for electrophysiology comprising:
<claim-text>a homogenous substrate selected from a group consisting of glass and quartz having a first outer surface and an opposing second outer surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a crater defined by a sidewall having opposing facing surfaces and the sidewall defining a depth of the crater, the crater extending into one of the first and second outer surfaces and defining a crater diameter thereon defined by a greatest distance between the facing surfaces of the sidewall; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pore extending between the crater diameter and the other one of the first and second outer surfaces of the substrate, the pore defining a pore diameter that is smaller than the crater diameter and is generally constant along substantially the entire length of the pore;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the pore further comprises (i) a pore-crater opening defining a pore-crater opening diameter defined at a location where the pore opens into the crater, and (ii) a pore-surface opening defining a pore-surface opening diameter defined at a location where the pore opens through an outer surface of the substrate material, and wherein the larger of the pore-crater and pore-surface opening diameters is no more than about 50% greater than the smaller of the pore-crater and pore-surface opening diameters;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one of the crater and the pore are adapted to provide a gigaseal with respect to a cell membrane placed thereover. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
