<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08624945-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08624945</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13798056</doc-number>
<date>20130312</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>101135989 A</doc-number>
<date>20120928</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>325</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347174</main-classification>
<further-classification>347176</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e61">Printing device for printing a stereograph and related method</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5528420</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Momochi</name>
<date>19960600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359463</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5557413</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ebihara et al.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358296</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5764266</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Azuma et al.</name>
<date>19980600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347171</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6133928</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kayashima et al.</name>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347171</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0064895</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ohtani et al.</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428 3239</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0074906</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Imai</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347218</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0075175</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Imai</name>
<date>20110300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>358  112</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0157293</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ohtani et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>347215</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-011406</doc-number>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-cpc-text>B41J 2/325</classification-cpc-text>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347171</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347172</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347174</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>347176</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>40012001</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>40012002</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>40012004</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>HiTi Digital, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Fu-Liang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hsu</last-name>
<first-name>Winston</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Margo</last-name>
<first-name>Scott</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>HiTi Digital, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Xindian Dist., New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Tran</last-name>
<first-name>Huan</first-name>
<department>2861</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A printing device for printing a stereograph is disclosed in the present invention. The printing device includes an actuating unit, a ribbon, a thermal print head and a controller. The actuating unit conveys a print medium. The ribbon includes a plurality of dye regions and at least a protecting layer. The thermal print head can transfer the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and further manufacture a lenticular lens structure on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner. The controller is coupled to the actuating unit and the thermal print head. The controller drives the actuating unit to convey the print medium according to a target image datum, further controls the thermal print head to respectively transfer the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and simultaneously manufactures the lenticular lens structure on the protecting layer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="136.06mm" wi="181.44mm" file="US08624945-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="245.87mm" wi="146.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624945-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="203.12mm" wi="134.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624945-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="246.89mm" wi="130.98mm" file="US08624945-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="221.74mm" wi="192.62mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624945-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="212.94mm" wi="160.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US08624945-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a printing device and a related printing method, and more particularly, to a printing device and a related printing method capable of simultaneously print images and manufacturing lenticular lens structure on a protecting layer of a ribbon, so as to rapidly form the stereograph.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A stereograph can transfer a viewer's view angle from two-dimensional space into three-dimensional space, so as to restore a scene with depth of field on the stereograph and to improve a sense of reality of the scene. Thus, the viewer can distinguish a distance and a depth of the scene on the stereograph. Method for producing three-dimensional vision utilizes parallax theory, such as adjusting radian of eyes for changing focal lengths of the eyes and adjusting view angles of the eyes. Because the stereograph shows images having different angles and distances on two eyes of the viewer, respectively, parallax is generated between the images viewed by the two eyes, and the images can be analyzed to generate the three-dimensional vision in the viewer's brain. Stereoscopic imaging technique includes holographic images, grating images, lens images, and so on. A method of applying an optical grating structure to image the stereograph is easier than other methods, and is utilized widespread.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generally, there are two types of common methods for generating the stereograph. One conventional method is printing the images processed by stereographic image processing technique on a back of the optical grating structure directly. The other conventional method is printing the images processed by the stereographic image processing technique on a common print medium, and then gluing the optical grating structure on the common print medium. However, process of gluing the optical grating structure on the print medium is complicated, spends working hours, and needs numerous glue to fix the optical grating structure on the print medium. The conventional methods print the stereograph slowly and increase manufacturing cost. Thus, design of a stereograph printing mechanism capable of printing the stereograph rapidly and having low cost is an important issue in the printing industry.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention provides a printing device and a related printing method capable of simultaneously print images and manufacturing lenticular lens structure on a protecting layer of a ribbon, so as to rapidly form the stereograph for solving above drawbacks.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to the claimed invention, a printing device for printing a stereograph is disclosed. The printing device includes an actuating unit, a ribbon, a thermal print head and a controller. The actuating unit conveys a print medium. The ribbon includes a plurality of dye regions and at least one protecting layer. The thermal print head respectively transfers the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and further manufactures a lenticular lens structure on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner. The controller is coupled to the actuating unit and the thermal print head. The controller drives the actuating unit to convey the print medium according to a target image datum, controls the thermal print head to respectively transfer the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and further controls the thermal print head to manufacture the lenticular lens structure on the protecting layer when the ribbon is transferred onto the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to the claimed invention, the controller sets correlation between the print medium and the lenticular lens structure of the protecting layer according to the target image datum.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to the claimed invention, the controller sets correlation between the print medium and the dye regions according to the target image datum.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the claimed invention, the dye regions includes a yellow dye region, a magenta dye region, a cyan dye region and a black dye region.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to the claimed invention, the ribbon includes a plurality of protecting layers, the thermal print head transfers the protecting layers onto the print medium in a sequential stacking manner.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to the claimed invention, the thermal print head manufactures the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer when the thermal print head transfers the protecting layer onto the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to the claimed invention, the thermal print head manufactures the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer after the thermal print head transfers the ribbon onto the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to the claimed invention, the thermal print head includes a plurality of thermal units. The thermal units heat the surface of the protecting layer in a separated heating manner, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially perpendicular to a moving direction of the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to the claimed invention, the thermal print head includes a plurality of thermal units. The thermal units respectively heat the surface of the protecting layer according to a predetermined parameter in a continued heating manner, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially parallel to a moving direction of the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to the claimed invention, a method for printing a stereograph is disclosed. The method includes receiving a target image datum, moving a print medium, transferring a plurality of dye regions and at least one protecting layer of a ribbon onto the print medium according to the target image datum when the print medium moves, and manufacturing a lenticular lens structure on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner when the ribbon is transferred onto the print medium.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to the claimed invention, the printing device is a dye sublimation printer. The plurality of dye regions and the protecting layer of the ribbon are transferred onto the print medium in a thermal sublimated manner.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention can utilize the current dye sublimation printer to print the stereograph, an adhesive mechanism is unnecessary to adhere the lenticular lens structure on the print medium. The printing device of the present invention can manufacture the lenticular lens structure on the protecting layer of the conventional ribbon in the heat working manner according to the interlaced image datum when printing the stereograph, and transfer the protecting layer with the lenticular lens structure onto the print medium printed by the dye regions, so as to rapidly complete the stereograph. Therefore, the present invention has advantages of short printing period, low print cost and preferred operating convenience.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">These and other objectives of the present invention will no doubt become obvious to those of ordinary skill in the art after reading the following detailed description of the preferred embodiment that is illustrated in the various figures and drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram of a printing device according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram of a ribbon according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart of printing the stereograph according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> respectively are diagrams of a protecting layer and a lenticular lens structure according to different embodiments of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Please refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram of a printing device <b>10</b> according to an embodiment of the present invention. The printing device <b>10</b> can preferably be a dye sublimation printer for printing a stereograph. The printing device <b>10</b> includes an actuating unit <b>12</b>, a ribbon <b>14</b>, a thermal print head <b>16</b> and a controller <b>18</b>. The actuating unit <b>12</b> can include the driving mechanism, such as the motor and the roller, for conveying a print medium <b>20</b>, such as paper. The ribbon <b>14</b> includes a plurality of dye regions <b>22</b> and one or more protecting layers <b>24</b>. The protecting layer <b>24</b> is made of high transparency material, and the protecting layer <b>20</b> further can be made of protecting material having waterproof function, oilproof function, or anti-UV function, so as to prevent the dye regions from being oozed, faded, or polluted by moisture or oil sludge. In addition, the protecting layer <b>24</b> has thermoplastic property. The protecting layer <b>24</b> can be deformed by temperature variation to form the structural shape.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">For printing the stereograph, the thermal print head <b>16</b> of the printing device <b>10</b> can transfer the dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b> in a thermal sublimated manner. The controller <b>18</b> is coupled to the actuating unit <b>12</b> and the thermal print head <b>16</b>. The controller <b>18</b> can drive the actuating unit <b>12</b> to convey the print medium <b>20</b> according to a received target image datum, control the thermal print head <b>16</b> to transfer the dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> of the ribbon <b>14</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b> in sequence, and control the thermal print head <b>16</b> to manufacture a lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner. The print medium <b>20</b> can perform 3D impression via the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b>. The target image datum can be an interlaced image datum. For example, the interlaced image datum can be a set of images that is generated by photographing a scene at different view angles and is recorded on the print medium <b>20</b> with stripes.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Please refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram of the ribbon <b>14</b> according to the embodiment of the present invention. The ribbon <b>14</b> includes the plurality of dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b>. The dye regions <b>22</b> can include a yellow dye region Y, a magenta dye region M and a cyan dye region C, or include the yellow dye region Y, the magenta dye region M, the cyan dye region C and a black dye region B. The dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> are repeatedly arranged on the ribbon <b>14</b>. Because the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> can be formed on the protecting layer <b>24</b> by process of the thermal print head <b>16</b>, the protecting layer <b>24</b> can be a one-layer protection film capable of being deformed by heat, a one-layer cover film capable of manufacturing the lenticular lens structure in the heat working manner, or a two-layer structure which includes the protection film unable to be deformed by heat and the cover film capable of manufacturing the lenticular lens structure in the heat working manner. Compositive structure of the protecting layer <b>24</b> is not limited to the above-mentioned embodiment, and depends on actual demand.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Please refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a flow chart of printing the stereograph according to the embodiment of the present invention. The printing method includes following steps:</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Step <b>300</b>: The printing device <b>10</b> receives the target image datum. The target image datum can be the interlaced image datum.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Step <b>302</b>: The controller <b>18</b> sets correlation between the dye regions <b>22</b>, the protecting layer <b>24</b> and the print medium <b>20</b> according to the target image datum.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Step <b>304</b>: The controller <b>18</b> drives the actuating unit <b>12</b> to convey the print medium <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Step <b>306</b>: The thermal print head <b>16</b> transfers the dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b> according to the target image datum and the correlation.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Step <b>308</b>: The thermal print head <b>16</b> manufactures the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> on the surface of the protecting layer <b>24</b> in the heat working manner according to the said correlation.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Step <b>310</b>: End.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">A detailed description of the printing method is introduced as following. First, the printing device <b>10</b> receives the interlaced image datum. The controller <b>18</b> sets the correlation between the print medium <b>20</b>, the dye regions <b>22</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> according to the target image datum. After the set of the correlation, the controller <b>18</b> moves the print medium <b>20</b> passing through a valve (the thermal unit <b>161</b> of the thermal print head <b>16</b>, not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) of the thermal print head <b>16</b> at a predetermined speed. The thermal print head <b>16</b> can transfer the dye regions <b>22</b> of the ribbon <b>14</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b> as fringes, and then transfer the protecting layer <b>24</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b>. The thermal print head <b>16</b> further can manufacture the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> on the surface of the protecting layer <b>24</b> in the heat working manner, so as to complete print of the stereograph.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">It should be mentioned that the ribbon <b>14</b> can include a plurality of protecting layers <b>24</b>, which is arranged by the dye regions <b>22</b>. Before printing the stereograph, the thermal print head <b>16</b> can transfer the protecting layers <b>24</b> onto the print medium <b>20</b> in a sequential stacking manner, which means the protecting layers <b>24</b> are transferred onto the same place of the print medium <b>20</b>, so as to fat the protecting layer <b>24</b> on the print medium <b>20</b> and to provide a preferred base for the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b>. In process of printing the stereograph, manufacturing time of the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> can be designed according to parameters of the printing device <b>10</b>, material property of the protecting layer <b>24</b> or heat resistant of the dye regions <b>22</b>. For example, the thermal print head <b>16</b> can control variation of heat working temperature when the protecting layer <b>24</b> is transferred onto the print medium <b>20</b>, so as to simultaneously manufacture the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> on the protecting layer <b>24</b>. Further, the thermal print head <b>16</b> can drive the actuating unit <b>12</b> to convey the print medium <b>20</b> passing through the thermal print head <b>16</b> after the ribbon <b>14</b> is completely transferred onto the print medium <b>20</b>, so that the thermal print head <b>16</b> can heat the protecting layer <b>24</b> to form the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b>. The manufacturing time of the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> is not limited to the above-mentioned embodiment, and depends on design demand.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Besides, the thermal print head <b>16</b> of the present invention can manufacture the lenticular lens structures <b>241</b> with different directions on the protecting layer <b>24</b> according to the target image datum. Please refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> respectively are diagrams of the protecting layer <b>24</b> and the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> according to different embodiments of the present invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the thermal print head <b>16</b> can include a plurality of thermal units <b>161</b>. When the print medium <b>20</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> pass through the thermal print head <b>16</b> along a moving direction D<b>1</b>, the thermal units <b>161</b> can heat the surface of the protecting layer <b>24</b> in a separated heating manner to form the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b>. For example, the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> includes a plurality of lenticular lens units <b>243</b>, and each lenticular lens unit <b>243</b> includes a plurality of heating zones, such as the zones with oblique lines and the other zones without the oblique lines. All of the thermal units <b>161</b> can provide the same heat working temperature at every time interval, and each thermal unit <b>161</b> can further separately provide specific heat working temperature toward the corresponding heating zone at different time interval. Therefore, continued deformation is formed on the surface of the protecting layer <b>24</b>, so that a surface of the lenticular lens structure <b>243</b> can be the flat plane, and the opposite surface of the lenticular lens structure <b>243</b> can be the semicircle structures. The thermal print head <b>16</b> can manufacture the lenticular lens units <b>243</b> of the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> in sequence, and a structural direction D<b>2</b> of the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> can be substantially perpendicular to the moving direction D<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, when the print medium <b>20</b> and the protecting layer <b>24</b> pass through the thermal print head <b>16</b> along the moving direction D<b>1</b>, the thermal print head <b>16</b> of the present invention can drive the thermal units <b>161</b> to heat the surface of the protecting layer <b>24</b> in the continued heating manner according to a predetermined parameter (such as the correlation between the dye regions <b>22</b>, the protecting layer <b>24</b> and the print medium <b>20</b>). The thermal units <b>161</b> above different heating zones can respectively provide different heat working temperature, and all of the thermal units <b>161</b> can sequentially provide its specific heat working temperature toward the protecting layer <b>24</b> when the protecting layer <b>24</b> passes through the thermal print head <b>16</b>, so that a surface of the lenticular lens structure <b>243</b> can be formed as the flat plane, and the opposite surface of the lenticular lens structure <b>243</b> can formed as the semicircle structures. Thus, the structural direction D<b>2</b> of the lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> can be substantially parallel to the moving direction D<b>1</b>. The printing device <b>10</b> of the present invention can manufacture the corresponding lenticular lens structure <b>241</b> according to user's demand (design of the interlaced mage datum).</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Comparing to the prior art, the present invention can utilize the current dye sublimation printer to print the stereograph, an adhesive mechanism is unnecessary to adhere the lenticular lens structure on the print medium. The printing device of the present invention can manufacture the lenticular lens structure on the protecting layer of the conventional ribbon in the heat working manner according to the interlaced image datum when printing the stereograph, and transfer the protecting layer with the lenticular lens structure onto the print medium printed by the dye regions, so as to rapidly complete the stereograph. Therefore, the present invention has advantages of short printing period, low print cost and preferred operating convenience.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Those skilled in the art will readily observe that numerous modifications and alterations of the device and method may be made while retaining the teachings of the invention. Accordingly, the above disclosure should be construed as limited only by the metes and bounds of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A printing device for printing a stereograph, the printing device comprising:
<claim-text>an actuating unit for conveying a print medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ribbon, the ribbon comprising a plurality of dye regions and at least one protecting layer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a thermal print head for respectively transferring the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and further for manufacturing a lenticular lens structure on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller coupled to the actuating unit and the thermal print head, the controller driving the actuating unit to convey the print medium according to a target image datum, controlling the thermal print head to respectively transfer the dye regions and the protecting layer onto the print medium, and further controlling the thermal print head to manufacture the lenticular lens structure on the protecting layer when the ribbon is transferred onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the controller sets correlation between the print medium and the lenticular lens structure of the protecting layer according to the target image datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the controller sets correlation between the print medium and the dye regions according to the target image datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the dye regions comprises a yellow dye region, a magenta dye region, a cyan dye region and a black dye region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ribbon comprises a plurality of protecting layers, the thermal print head transfers the protecting layers onto the print medium in a sequential stacking manner.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal print head manufactures the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer when the thermal print head transfers the protecting layer onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal print head manufactures the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer after the thermal print head transfers the ribbon onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal print head comprises a plurality of thermal units, the thermal units heat the surface of the protecting layer in a separated heating manner, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially perpendicular to a moving direction of the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thermal print head comprises a plurality of thermal units, the thermal units respectively heat the surface of the protecting layer according to a predetermined parameter in a continued heating manner, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially parallel to a moving direction of the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The printing device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> being a dye sublimation printer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A method for printing a stereograph, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a target image datum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving a print medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring a plurality of dye regions and at least one protecting layer of a ribbon onto the print medium according to the target image datum when the print medium moves; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>manufacturing a lenticular lens structure on a surface of the protecting layer in a heat working manner when the ribbon is transferred onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein receiving the target image datum comprises receiving an interlaced image datum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>setting correlation between the print medium and the lenticular lens structure of the protecting layer according to the target image datum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>setting correlation between the print medium and the dye regions according to the target image datum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the dye regions comprises a yellow dye region, a magenta dye region, a cyan dye region and a black dye region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>transferring a plurality of protecting layers onto the print medium in a sequential stacking manner.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer in the heat working manner comprises:
<claim-text>manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer when the protecting layer is transferred onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer in the heat working manner comprises:
<claim-text>manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer after the ribbon is transferred onto the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer in the heat working manner comprises:
<claim-text>heating the surface of the protecting layer in a separated heating manner by a plurality of thermal unit, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially perpendicular to a moving direction of the print medium.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein manufacturing the lenticular lens structure on the surface of the protecting layer in the heat working manner comprises:
<claim-text>heating the surface of the protecting layer according to a predetermined parameter in a continued heating manner by a plurality of thermal unit, so that a structural direction of the lenticular lens structure is substantially parallel to a moving direction of the print medium. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
