<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08621691-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08621691</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13898445</doc-number>
<date>20130520</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5613</main-classification>
<further-classification>  5618</further-classification>
<further-classification>  5933</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e43">Chair/bed for the disabled</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2656876</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Larrick</name>
<date>19531000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2753920</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ranger</name>
<date>19560700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by applicant</category>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3284126</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Piazza</name>
<date>19661100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>296 20</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4787104</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Grantham</name>
<date>19881100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  5613</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7086108</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Litvak</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  5723</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5933</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5944</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5613</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  55031</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5618</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5600</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alsaffar</last-name>
<first-name>Abdulreidha Abdulrasoul</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mubarak Alkabeer</city>
<country>KW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alsaffar</last-name>
<first-name>Abdulreidha Abdulrasoul</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mubarak Alkabeer</city>
<country>KW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Litman</last-name>
<first-name>Richard C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Conley</last-name>
<first-name>Fredrick</first-name>
<department>3673</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The chair/bed for the disabled is a wheeled, medical appliance for disabled persons that can alternately convert from a chair to a bed when desired. The appliance incorporates structure for applying body massages and for moving the patient in a rollover motion. Ancillary features, such as a pillow, a night light, study and dining tables and a support for mounting a television or tablet are included on the appliance. A control module is provided to allow the appliance to be operated by a remote control device.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="219.54mm" wi="346.03mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="239.78mm" wi="174.41mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.58mm" wi="170.69mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="243.25mm" wi="180.68mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="231.31mm" wi="180.68mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.63mm" wi="176.95mm" file="US08621691-20140107-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention generally relates to medical appliances, and particularly to a chair/bed that can alternately function as a chair or bed for use by disabled persons.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Disabled patients in hospitals, nursing homes, or in-home are often required to be moved from a prone to a sitting position for various medical or therapeutic procedures. The patient may also require massaging or change of position to enhance blood circulation and to avoid problems such as bed sores and the like. Moving the patient is sometimes an arduous task for the nurse or caregiver especially if the patient is obese. In many instances, moving the patient results in strains or pulls to the muscles of the back and/or arms of the nurse or caregiver. The related art discloses many appliances that convert from a bed to a chair. Unfortunately, the related art appliances are cumbersome, often lack mobility and do not provide other desirable features. Thus, a chair/bed for the disabled solving the aforementioned problems is desired.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The chair/bed for the disabled is a wheeled medical appliance for disabled persons that can alternately convert from a chair to a bed when desired. The appliance incorporates structure for applying body massages and for moving the patient in a rollover motion. Ancillary features such as a pillow, a night light, study and dining tables and a support for mounting a television or tablet are included on the appliance. A control module is provided to allow the appliance to be operated by a remote control device.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, the invention presents a unique, convertible, medical appliance that allows a disabled person to move from a prone to a sitting position without assistance from another person. The appliance also provides structure for applying massages and for automatic movement of the patient periodically, to enhance circulation and prevent bed sores. The appliance is easy to use and incorporates features that are controllable by a remote device. The invention provides for improved elements thereof in an arrangement for the purposes described that are inexpensive, dependable and fully effective in accomplishing their intended purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">These and other features of the present invention will become readily apparent upon further review of the following specification and drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an environmental, perspective view of a chair/bed for the disabled according to the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the chair/bed of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> configured as a chair.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the chair/bed of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> configured as a bed.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of the chair/bed of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing positioning members arranged to roll a patient to the right.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of the chair/bed of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing positioning members arranged to roll a patient to the left.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Similar reference characters denote corresponding features consistently throughout the attached drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the chair/bed for the disabled is generally indicated at <b>10</b>. The chair/bed <b>10</b> is adapted for use with a mobile transport assembly T, shown in phantom lines. Mooring devices (not shown) may be provided to secure the transport assembly T to the chair/bed <b>10</b>. The assembly T is fully disclosed and claimed in the present inventor's co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 13/762,263, filed Feb. 7, 2013, and is not part of the presently claimed invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The chair/bed appliance <b>10</b> comprises three segments <b>14</b>, <b>16</b> and <b>18</b>. Segment <b>14</b> is adapted to support the head shoulders and back of the disabled patient P. To enhance patient comfort, a pillow <b>14</b><i>a </i>is disposed at one end of segment <b>14</b>. The other end of segment <b>14</b> is pivotally attached to an end of segment <b>16</b>. Segment <b>16</b> is arranged to support the lower back, buttocks and thighs of the patient. The other end of segment <b>16</b> is pivotally attached to an end of segment <b>18</b>. Segment <b>16</b> is provided with a pair of padded armrests at <b>16</b><i>a</i>. Segment <b>18</b> supports the legs and feet of the patient. Guard rails <b>20</b> are positioned along the sides of each segment to prevent the patient from accidently falling from the appliance. A post <b>22</b> is attached to one of the armrests <b>16</b><i>a</i>. The post <b>22</b> is utilized as an anchor for pivotally mounting upper and lower tables <b>24</b>, <b>24</b><i>a </i>thereon. The tables <b>24</b>, <b>24</b><i>a </i>may be employed as a support for food trays, books, beverage containers and the like. The post <b>22</b> can also support a night light <b>26</b> and any one of several removable electronic devices <b>28</b>, such as a small TV, computer, or tablet.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Four supporting legs <b>30</b> extend downward from the underside of segment <b>16</b>. Each leg terminates at its lower end in a wheel member <b>32</b> to provide mobility for the chair/bed appliance. Each wheel member <b>32</b> is equipped with a conventional brake <b>32</b><i>a </i>for safety purposes.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Each segment <b>14</b>, <b>16</b>, <b>18</b> has identically configured respective center panels <b>34</b>. Each center panel <b>34</b> comprises an array of soft beads <b>34</b><i>a</i>. The beads <b>34</b><i>a </i>are made to rotate and vibrate to effectively massage the entire body of the patient. Each center panel <b>34</b> is flanked on both sides by respective pivoting positioning panels <b>36</b>. As best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the positioning panels <b>36</b> can be pivoted along a longitudinal axis adjacent to the center panels <b>34</b> to provide an assist when adjusting the patient's position on the appliance. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the positioning panels <b>36</b> on one side have been pivoted upward to roll the patient to the right. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the positioning panels <b>36</b> on one side have been pivoted upward to roll the patient to the left. Movement of the segments <b>14</b>, <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, the massaging beads <b>34</b><i>a</i>, and the positioning panels <b>36</b> are all coordinated by way of an electronic control module <b>38</b>, which provides motive signals to conventional mechanisms (not shown). A remote device R is employed to provide selective signals to the electronic control module <b>38</b> to control selective operation of the segments <b>14</b>, <b>16</b>, <b>18</b>, massaging beads <b>34</b><i>a </i>and positioning panels <b>36</b>. The control module <b>38</b> can also be programmed to perform the functions automatically.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">It is to be understood that the present invention is not limited to the embodiments described above, but encompasses any and all embodiments within the scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A chair/bed appliance for the disabled consisting of:
<claim-text>a first segment having an upper surface with a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pillow disposed on said first segment adjacent the upper surface at the first end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the first segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the first segment being pivotally connected to the first end of the second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the second segment, said second segment has an undersurface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of leg members attached to the undersurface and extending downward therefrom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a respective armrest disposed on the right and left sides of said second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of tables mounted for pivoting movement in a horizontal plane and disposed above the upper surface of said second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustable night light mounted above the upper surface of said second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the second segment being pivotally connected to the first end of the third segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the third segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each said segment has respective right and left sides;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of respective pivoting positioning panels defining the right and left sides of each segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of respect guard rails extending along the right and left sides of each segment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a respective armrest disposed on the right and left sides of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A chair/bed appliance for the disabled comprising:
<claim-text>a first segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the first segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the first segment being pivotally connected to the first end of the second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second segment has an undersurface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of leg members attached to the undersurface and extending downward therefrom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the second segment being pivotally connected to the first end of the third segment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the third segment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further including a pillow disposed on the upper surface adjacent the upper end of said first segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each said segment has respective right and left sides, the appliance further including respective pivoting positioning panels defining the right and left sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each said segment has respective right and left sides, the appliance further including a respective armrest disposed on the right and left sides of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each said segment has respective right and left sides, the appliance further including guard rails extending along the right and left sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further including a plurality of tables mounted for pivoting movement in a horizontal plane and disposed above the upper surface of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further including an adjustable night light mounted above the upper surface of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A chair/bed appliance for the disabled comprising:
<claim-text>a first segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the first segment, the first array of soft beads being selectively movable in rotary and vibratory motions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pillow disposed on the upper surface adjacent the first end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second segment having an upper surface, an undersurface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the first segment being mounted for pivotal movement to the first end of the second segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the second segment, the second array of soft beads being selectively movable in rotary and vibratory motions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of leg members attached to the undersurface of the second segment and extending downward therefrom;</claim-text>
<claim-text>respective wheels defining the lower ends of each of the leg members;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third segment having an upper surface, a first end and a second end, the second end of the second segment being mounted for pivotal movement to the first end of the third segment; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third array of soft beads disposed on the upper surface of the third segment, the third array of soft beads being selectively movable in rotary and vibratory motions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein each said segment has respective right and left sides, the appliance further including respective pivoting positioning panels defining the right and left sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further including an electronic control module mounted on the appliance for selectively controlling rotary and vibratory motions of the first, second, and third array of soft beads and pivotal movement of the segments and the positioning panels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further including a respective arm rest disposed on the right and left sides of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further including guard rails extending along the right and left sides.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further including a plurality of tables mounted for pivoting movement in a horizontal plane and disposed above the upper surface of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The chair/bed appliance for the disabled according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further including an adjustable night light mounted above the upper surface of said second segment.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
