<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v44-2013-05-16.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.4 2013-05-16" file="US08622636-20140107.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20131224" date-publ="20140107">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>08622636</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20140107</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13214261</doc-number>
<date>20110822</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>100122095 A</doc-number>
<date>20110624</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>372</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>6</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20140107</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 89</main-classification>
<further-classification>385 88</further-classification>
<further-classification>385 91</further-classification>
<further-classification>385 93</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d2e71">Optical fiber connector</invention-title>
<us-references-cited>
<us-citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2011/0142401</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Lin et al.</name>
<date>20110600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 77</main-classification></classification-national>
</us-citation>
</us-references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20120328245</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20121227</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>I-Thun</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="001" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>I-Thun</first-name>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Altis Law Group, Inc.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>New Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Uyen Chau N</first-name>
<department>2874</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Smith</last-name>
<first-name>Chad</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An optical fiber connector includes optical fibers, a connector body, two first glue layers, and two second glue layers. The optical fibers are received in grooves and aligned with optical lenses formed on the connector body. The first and second glue layers fill in the recesses to hold the main portion and the front portion of the optical fibers securely in place.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="138.26mm" wi="163.49mm" file="US08622636-20140107-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="176.87mm" wi="162.90mm" file="US08622636-20140107-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="174.07mm" wi="169.84mm" file="US08622636-20140107-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="201.08mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US08622636-20140107-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to optics and, particularly, to an optical fiber connector.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An optical fiber connector is preferred for use in data transmission between electronic devices due to its high transmission speed and signal integrity. The optical fiber connector includes a connector body, optical fibers, blind holes defined in the connector body for receiving the optical fibers, a cover assembled in the connector body to fix the optical fibers, and optical lenses aligned with the respective optical fibers.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">When the optical fiber connector is assembled, the optical fibers are inserted into the respective blind holes, the cover is assembled into the connector body to contact the optical fibers, glue is dropped around the cover to fix the cover in the connector body while the cover is subjected to pressure. However, the cover is easily moved, disturbing the mass of optical fibers. This vulnerability may decrease transmission efficiency and degrade signal integrity.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Therefore, it is desirable to provide an optical fiber connector, which can overcome or at least alleviate the limitations described.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an isometric view of an optical fiber connector including a connector body, according to an exemplary embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an isometric view of the connector body of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of the optical fiber connector of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an optical fiber connector <b>100</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment, includes a connector body <b>10</b>, two optical fibers <b>30</b>, two first glue layers <b>40</b>, and two second glue layers <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2-3</figref>, the connector body <b>10</b> is substantially cuboid and transparent. The connector body <b>10</b> includes a first side surface <b>12</b>, a second side surface <b>14</b>, an upper surface <b>16</b>, a lower surface <b>17</b>, and two optical lenses <b>18</b>. The first side surface <b>12</b> is substantially parallel to the second side surface <b>14</b>. The upper surface <b>16</b> is substantially parallel to the lower surface <b>17</b>. The upper surface <b>16</b> is perpendicularly interconnected between the first side surface <b>12</b> and the second side surface <b>14</b>. The lower surface <b>17</b> is perpendicularly interconnected between the first side surface <b>12</b> and the second side surface <b>14</b>. The optical lenses <b>18</b> are formed on the first side surface <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The connector body <b>10</b> includes a top recess <b>20</b> defined in the upper surface <b>16</b>, and a bottom surface <b>22</b>, a inner front surface <b>24</b>, a first inner side surface <b>26</b>, and a second inner side surface <b>28</b>. The bottom surface <b>22</b>, the inner front surface <b>24</b>, the first inner side surface <b>26</b>, and the second inner side surface <b>28</b> are defined in the top recess <b>20</b>. The bottom surface <b>22</b> is substantially parallel to the upper surface <b>16</b>. The inner front surface <b>24</b>, the first inner side surface <b>26</b>, and the second inner side surface <b>28</b> perpendicularly extend from three edges of the bottom surface <b>22</b> and terminates at the upper surface <b>16</b>. The inner front surface <b>24</b> is substantially parallel to the first side surface <b>12</b> and is apart from the first side surface <b>12</b>. The first inner side surface <b>26</b> is substantially parallel to the second inner side surface <b>28</b>. The inner front surface <b>24</b> perpendicularly connects the first inner side surface <b>26</b> to the second inner side surface <b>28</b>. The bottom surface <b>22</b>, the first inner side surface <b>26</b>, and the second inner side surface <b>28</b> perpendicularly extend from the second side surface <b>14</b> and terminates at the inner front surface <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The bottom surface <b>22</b> defines two receiving grooves <b>220</b> for receiving the two optical fibers <b>30</b>, two first recesses <b>222</b>, and two second recesses <b>224</b>. Each receiving groove <b>220</b> is aligned with a first recess <b>222</b> and a second recess <b>224</b>. Each receiving groove <b>220</b> includes a first receiving groove portion <b>226</b> and a second receiving groove portion <b>228</b>. The first receiving groove portion <b>226</b>, the first recess <b>222</b>, the second receiving groove portion <b>228</b>, and the second recess <b>224</b> are arranged in sequence along a direction from the second side surface <b>14</b> to the first side surface <b>12</b>. The first receiving groove portion <b>226</b> passes through the second side surface <b>14</b>. The first recess <b>222</b> is in communication with the first receiving groove portion <b>226</b> and the second receiving groove portion <b>228</b>. The second recess <b>224</b> communicates with the second receiving groove portion <b>228</b> and is bounded by the inner front surface <b>24</b>. In this embodiment, the first recesses <b>222</b> and the second recesses <b>224</b> are cuboid, the first receiving groove portions <b>226</b> are semicircular in cross-section, and the second receiving groove portions <b>228</b> are V-shaped in cross-section.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In other embodiments, the first recesses <b>222</b> and the second recesses <b>224</b> may be other shapes in cross-section, such as arc-shaped. The second receiving groove portions <b>228</b> may be semicircular in cross-section.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The two optical fibers <b>30</b> are received in the two receiving grooves <b>220</b> respectively and are aligned with the two optical lenses <b>18</b>, respectively. Each optical fiber <b>30</b> includes a main portion <b>34</b> and a front portion <b>32</b>. The main portion <b>34</b> consists of a core portion and a cladding portion surrounding the core portion. The front portion <b>32</b> consists of an exposed core portion proximate to the main portion <b>34</b>. The front portion <b>32</b> is slightly shorter than the main portion <b>34</b>. The first receiving groove portion <b>226</b> conforms to the main portion <b>34</b> and is configured for receiving the main portion <b>34</b>. The second receiving groove portion <b>228</b> matches with the front portion <b>32</b> and is configured for receiving the front portion <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the material of the first glue layers <b>40</b> is ultraviolet (UV) curable resin. The first glue layers <b>40</b> fill in the first recesses <b>222</b> and engulf the respective optical fibers <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The second glue layers <b>50</b> are optical matching glue. The second glue layers <b>50</b> fills in the second recesses <b>224</b> and engulf the respective optical fibers <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">When the optical fibers <b>30</b> are assembled into the connector body <b>10</b>, the optical fibers <b>30</b> are received in the receiving grooves <b>220</b>. In particular, each main portion <b>34</b> is received in the first receiving groove portion <b>226</b>, each front portion <b>32</b> is received in the second receiving groove portion <b>228</b>, and a distal end surface <b>36</b> of the optical fiber <b>30</b> contacts the inner front surface <b>24</b> and coincides with the focal plane of the optical lens <b>18</b>. The second glue layers <b>50</b> then fill in the second recesses <b>224</b> and secure the respective optical fibers <b>30</b>, and the first glue layers <b>40</b> fill in the first recesses <b>222</b> and secure the respective optical fibers <b>30</b>, thereby the optical fibers <b>30</b> are fixed in the connector body <b>10</b> and cannot move. This reduces incidental light loss, increases transmission efficiency and enhances signal integrity.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In addition, by abutting the distal end surface <b>36</b> of the optical fiber <b>30</b> against the inner front surface <b>24</b>, the distal end surface <b>36</b> coincides precisely with the focal plane of the optical lens <b>18</b>, thereby the transmission accuracy is assured.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present embodiments have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structures and functions of the embodiments, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and the arrangement of parts within the principles of the disclosure to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An optical fiber connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of optical fibers;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector body comprising a first side surface, a second side surface parallel to the first side surface, an upper surface perpendicularly interconnected between the first side surface and the second side surface, and a plurality of optical lenses arranged at the first side surface, the connector body including a top recess defined in the upper surface, and a bottom surface in the top recess parallel to the upper surface, an inner front surface in the top recess parallel to the first side surface, a first inner side surface in the top recess, and a second inner side surface in the top recess parallel to the first inner side surface, the inner front surface perpendicularly connecting the first inner side surface to the second inner side surface, each of the bottom surface, the first inner side surface, and the second inner side surface extending from the second side surface toward and terminating at the inner front surface, the bottom surface defining a plurality of receiving grooves, a plurality of first recesses, and a plurality of second recesses, each first recess located between the second side surface and the corresponding second recess and connected with the corresponding receiving groove, each second recess arranged at a distal end of the corresponding receiving groove and bounded by the inner front surface, the optical fibers received in the receiving grooves and aligned with the optical lenses;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two first glue layers filling in the first recesses and engulfing the respective optical fibers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two second glue layers filling in the second recesses and engulfing the respective optical fibers.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The optical fiber connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each optical fiber comprising a main portion consisting of a core portion and a cladding portion surrounding the core portion, and a front portion consisting of an exposed core portion proximate to the main portion, each receiving groove comprises a first receiving groove portion located between the second side surface and the first recess for receiving the main portion and a second receiving groove portion located between the first recess and the second recess for receiving the front portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The optical fiber connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first receiving groove portion are semicircular in cross-section, and the second receiving groove portion are semicircular in cross-section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The optical fiber connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the first receiving groove portion are semicircular in cross-section, and the second receiving groove portion are V-shaped in cross-section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The optical fiber connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a distal end surface of each optical fiber contacts the inner front surface and coincides with the focal plane of the corresponding optical lens.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The optical fiber connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first glue layers are ultraviolet curable resin, and the second glue layers are optical matching glue. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
